<cards name="Eighth Edition">
  <item>
    <id>8ED0001</id>
    <name>Angel of Mercy</name>
    <text>Flying
When Angel of Mercy enters the battlefield, you gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>A song of life soars over fields of blood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0002</id>
    <name>Eager Cadet</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Training? Seeing my crops burnt to cinders was all the ‘training' I needed."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0003</id>
    <name>Angelic Page</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Target attacking or blocking creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>If only every message were as perfect as its bearer.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0004</id>
    <name>Vengeance</name>
    <text>Destroy target tapped creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Bitter as wormwood, sweet as mulled wine.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0005</id>
    <name>Ardent Militia</name>
    <text>Vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>Knights fight for honor and mercenaries fight for gold. The militia fights for hearth and home.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0006</id>
    <name>Giant Octopus</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Before my eyes was a horrible monster, worthy to figure in the legends of the marvellous. . . . Its eight arms, or rather feet, fixed to its head . . . were twice as long as its body, and were twisted like the furies' hair."
—Jules Verne, Twenty Thousand Leagues under the Sea, trans. Lewis</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0007</id>
    <name>Avatar of Hope</name>
    <text>If you have 3 or less life, Avatar of Hope costs {6} less to cast.
Flying
Avatar of Hope can block any number of creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0008</id>
    <name>Sea Eagle</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Where air meets water, fish meets talon.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0009</id>
    <name>Aven Cloudchaser</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
When Aven Cloudchaser enters the battlefield, destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0010</id>
    <name>Vizzerdrix</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>A bored wizard once created a vizzerdrix out of a bunny and a piranha. He never made that mistake again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0011</id>
    <name>Aven Flock</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
{W}: Aven Flock gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Just as each added feather steadies the wing, so does the flock grow stronger with each new member.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0012</id>
    <name>Enormous Baloth</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Its diet consists of fruits, plants, small woodland animals, large woodland animals, woodlands, fruit groves, fruit farmers, and small cities.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0013</id>
    <name>Blessed Reversal</name>
    <text>You gain 3 life for each creature attacking you.</text>
    <flavorText>Even an enemy is a valuable resource.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0014</id>
    <name>Silverback Ape</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>It does not wear a crown or sit on a throne of gold, but those who have witnessed its power hail it nonetheless.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0015</id>
    <name>Blinding Angel</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Whenever Blinding Angel deals combat damage to a player, that player skips his or her next combat phase.</text>
    <flavorText>"Their eyes will shrivel and blacken before faith's true light."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0016</id>
    <name>Chastise</name>
    <text>Destroy target attacking creature. You gain life equal to its power.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why do we pray to the Ancestor? Because She listens."
—Mystic elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0017</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Black</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a black source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0018</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Blue</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a blue source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0019</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Green</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a green source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0020</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Red</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a red source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0021</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: White</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a white source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0022</id>
    <name>Crossbow Infantry</name>
    <text>{T}: Crossbow Infantry deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"He can split a marshfly in two from halfway across the range."
—Onean sergeant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0023</id>
    <name>Demystify</name>
    <text>Destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0024</id>
    <name>Diving Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>To outrace the griffin
—Kipamu expression meaning
"to do the impossible"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0025</id>
    <name>Elite Archers</name>
    <text>{T}: Elite Archers deals 3 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>They fletch their arrows with the feathers of angels.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0026</id>
    <name>Elite Javelineer</name>
    <text>Whenever Elite Javelineer blocks, it deals 1 damage to target attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Precision is frequently more valuable than force."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0027</id>
    <name>Glorious Anthem</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>Each victory adds a new verse.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0028</id>
    <name>Glory Seeker</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The turning of the tide always begins with one soldier's decision to head back into the fray.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0029</id>
    <name>Healing Salve</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target player gains 3 life; or prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0030</id>
    <name>Holy Day</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The day of Spirits; my soul's calm retreat / Which none disturb"
—Henry Vaughan, "The Night"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0031</id>
    <name>Holy Strength</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0032</id>
    <name>Honor Guard</name>
    <text>{W}: Honor Guard gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is not a choice I make, to have this guard. It is the choice of my people, and my duty to them."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0033</id>
    <name>Intrepid Hero</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target creature with power 4 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>A fool knows no fear. A hero shows no fear.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0034</id>
    <name>Ivory Mask</name>
    <text>You have shroud. (You can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>Made from its wearer's hopes, the mask ensures that those hopes will be fulfilled.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0035</id>
    <name>Karma</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Karma deals damage to that player equal to the number of Swamps he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0036</id>
    <name>Master Decoy</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>A skilled decoy can throw your enemies off your trail. A master decoy can survive to do it again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0037</id>
    <name>Master Healer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 4 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Her heart holds the pain of every soldier she's ever healed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0038</id>
    <name>Noble Purpose</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control deals combat damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>Fighting for the right reason is itself a source of strength.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0039</id>
    <name>Oracle's Attendants</name>
    <text>{T}: All damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn by a source of your choice is dealt to Oracle's Attendants instead.</text>
    <flavorText>The future isn't sacred, but its speaker is.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0040</id>
    <name>Pacifism</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block.</text>
    <flavorText>For the first time in his life, Grakk felt a little warm and fuzzy inside.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0041</id>
    <name>Peach Garden Oath</name>
    <text>You gain 2 life for each creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"We three, though of separate ancestry, join in brotherhood. . . . We dare not hope to be together always but hereby vow to die the selfsame day."
—Peach Garden Oath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0042</id>
    <name>Rain of Blades</name>
    <text>Rain of Blades deals 1 damage to each attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Some say they are the weapons of heroes fallen in battle, eager for one last chance at glory.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0043</id>
    <name>Razorfoot Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying
First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0044</id>
    <name>Redeem</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt this turn to up to two target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let me redeem my brothers both from death."
—William Shakespeare, Titus Andronicus</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0045</id>
    <name>Rolling Stones</name>
    <text>Wall creatures can attack as though they didn't have defender.</text>
    <flavorText>"Trust me—the walls have more than just ears."
—Orcish spy</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0046</id>
    <name>Sacred Ground</name>
    <text>Whenever a spell or ability an opponent controls causes a land to be put into your graveyard from the battlefield, return that card to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The land will never betray those who gave their lives for it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0047</id>
    <name>Sacred Nectar</name>
    <text>You gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Over the silver mountains,
Where spring the nectar fountains,
There will I kiss
The bowl of bliss;
And drink my everlasting fill. . . ."
—Sir Walter Raleigh, "The Pilgrimage"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0048</id>
    <name>Samite Healer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Healers ultimately acquire the divine gifts of spiritual and physical wholeness. The most devout are also granted the ability to pass physical wholeness on to others.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0049</id>
    <name>Sanctimony</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent taps a Mountain for mana, you may gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The peasants labor for my profit. I approve."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0050</id>
    <name>Savannah Lions</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Even the brave are scared by a lion three times: first by its tracks, again by its roar, and one last time face to face.
—Somali proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0051</id>
    <name>Seasoned Marshal</name>
    <text>Whenever Seasoned Marshal attacks, you may tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>She reads the battlefield like a map, always seeking the shortest route to victory.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0052</id>
    <name>Serra Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
Vigilance (Attacking doesn't cause this creature to tap.)</text>
    <flavorText>When she flies above the good, they consider themselves blessed. When she flies above the wicked, they consider themselves dead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0053</id>
    <name>Solidarity</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +0/+5 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We must all hang together, or assuredly we shall all hang separately."
—Benjamin Franklin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0054</id>
    <name>Spirit Link</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>"I am bound to all my children. I share in their joys, I rage at their injuries."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0055</id>
    <name>Standing Troops</name>
    <text>Vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>The less you have, the harder you fight for it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0056</id>
    <name>Staunch Defenders</name>
    <text>When Staunch Defenders enters the battlefield, you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The key to winning any fight is simply staying alive.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0057</id>
    <name>Story Circle</name>
    <text>As Story Circle enters the battlefield, choose a color.
{W}: The next time a source of your choice of the chosen color would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0058</id>
    <name>Suntail Hawk</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Its eye the glaring sun, its cry the keening wind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0059</id>
    <name>Sunweb</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Flying
Sunweb can't block creatures with power 2 or less.</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes the wings of fallen dragons refuse to give up the sky.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0060</id>
    <name>Sword Dancer</name>
    <text>{W}{W}: Target attacking creature gets -1/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Most soldiers think of the sword as a weapon. In the hands of Zho monks, swords are also the strongest of shields.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0061</id>
    <name>Tundra Wolves</name>
    <text>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I heard their eerie howling, the wolves calling their kindred across the frozen plains."
—Onean scout</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0062</id>
    <name>Venerable Monk</name>
    <text>When Venerable Monk enters the battlefield, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Age wears the flesh but galvanizes the soul.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0063</id>
    <name>Wall of Swords</name>
    <text>Defender, flying (This creature can't attack, and it can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>Sharper than wind, lighter than air.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0064</id>
    <name>Worship</name>
    <text>If you control a creature, damage that would reduce your life total to less than 1 reduces it to 1 instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"Believe in the ideal, not the idol."
—Serra</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0065</id>
    <name>Wrath of God</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0066</id>
    <name>Air Elemental</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Pray that it doesn't seek the safety of your lungs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0067</id>
    <name>Archivist</name>
    <text>{T}: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Words—so innocent and powerless are they, as standing in a dictionary; how potent for good and evil they become to one who knows how to combine them"
—Nathaniel Hawthorne</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0068</id>
    <name>Aven Fisher</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
When Aven Fisher is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The same spears that catch their food today will defend their homes tomorrow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0069</id>
    <name>Balance of Power</name>
    <text>If target opponent has more cards in hand than you, draw cards equal to the difference.</text>
    <flavorText>"To empty your mind is to fill your grave."
—Lat-Nam teaching</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0070</id>
    <name>Boomerang</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Returne from whence ye came. . . ."
—Edmund Spenser, The Faerie Queene</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0071</id>
    <name>Bribery</name>
    <text>Search target opponent's library for a creature card and put that card onto the battlefield under your control. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>In Mercadia City, loyalties extend only as far as your purse can stretch.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0072</id>
    <name>Catalog</name>
    <text>Draw two cards, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Though those who study are as many as the hairs on an ox, those who succeed are as rare as unicorns' horns.
—Chinese proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0073</id>
    <name>Coastal Hornclaw</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a land: Coastal Hornclaw gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Jamuraan farmers fear three things above all else: droughts, floods, and hornclaws.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0074</id>
    <name>Coastal Piracy</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control deals combat damage to an opponent, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I don't like to think of myself as a pirate. I'm more like a stimulator of the local economy."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0075</id>
    <name>Concentrate</name>
    <text>Draw three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"The treasure in my mind is greater than any worldly glory."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0076</id>
    <name>Confiscate</name>
    <text>Enchant permanent (Target a permanent as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that permanent.)
You control enchanted permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is better to take what does not belong to you than to let it lie around neglected."
—Mark Twain, More Maxims of Mark</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0077</id>
    <name>Coral Eel</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Some fishers like to eat eels, and some eels like to eat fishers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0078</id>
    <name>Cowardice</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature becomes the target of a spell or ability, return that creature to its owner's hand. (It won't be affected by the spell or ability.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Cowards die many times before their deaths;
The valiant never taste of death but once."
—William Shakespeare, Julius Caesar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0079</id>
    <name>Curiosity</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage to an opponent, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"You know that secret? The one that wakes you up at night in a cold sweat? The one you think no one else in the world knows? Well, guess what."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0080</id>
    <name>Daring Apprentice</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Daring Apprentice: Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"I've seen my master do this a hundred times. How hard can it be?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0081</id>
    <name>Deflection</name>
    <text>Change the target of target spell with a single target.</text>
    <flavorText>The golden rule of revenge: Do unto others what they tried to do unto you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0082</id>
    <name>Dehydration</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>"Cry to the sun and watch as even your tears forsake you."
—Acolyte of Marit Lage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0083</id>
    <name>Evacuation</name>
    <text>Return all creatures to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>Which is more unsettling: the roar of battle or the silence that follows?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0084</id>
    <name>Fighting Drake</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Scholars in their ivory towers call them "sharks of the sky." Scholars on the road don't call them at all.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0085</id>
    <name>Flash Counter</name>
    <text>Counter target instant spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"So much for that bright idea"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0086</id>
    <name>Fleeting Image</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
{1}{U}: Return Fleeting Image to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Beware lest you lose the substance by grasping at the shadow."
—Aesop, Fables, trans. Jacobs</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0087</id>
    <name>Flight</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has flying. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0088</id>
    <name>Fugitive Wizard</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The College of Lat-Nam is often forced to expel students whose experiments grow too risky or too cruel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0089</id>
    <name>Hibernation</name>
    <text>Return all green permanents to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>The deep sleep of winter is not always restful.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0090</id>
    <name>Horned Turtle</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>It doesn't like having visitors . . . unless it's having them for lunch.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0091</id>
    <name>Index</name>
    <text>Look at the top five cards of your library, then put them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let's see . . . Mercadia, mercenary, merfolk . . . you know, I really need a better filing system."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0092</id>
    <name>Inspiration</name>
    <text>Target player draws two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Madness and genius are separated only by degrees of success.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0093</id>
    <name>Intruder Alarm</name>
    <text>Creatures don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.
Whenever a creature enters the battlefield, untap all creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>One footstep among many is silent. One footstep alone is deafening.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0094</id>
    <name>Invisibility</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't be blocked except by Walls.</text>
    <flavorText>Verick held his breath. Breathing wouldn't reveal his position, but it would force him to smell the goblins.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0095</id>
    <name>Mahamoti Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Of royal blood among the spirits of the air, the Mahamoti djinn rides on the wings of the winds. As dangerous in the gambling hall as he is in battle, he is a master of trickery and misdirection.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0096</id>
    <name>Mana Leak</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {3}.</text>
    <flavorText>The fatal flaw in every plan is the assumption that you know more than your enemy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0097</id>
    <name>Merchant of Secrets</name>
    <text>When Merchant of Secrets enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>To scrape out a living in Aphetto, wizards are reduced to selling rumors, lies, forgeries, or—if they get desperate enough—the truth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0098</id>
    <name>Merchant Scroll</name>
    <text>Search your library for a blue instant card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Lat-Nam wizards trade knowledge on scrolls made of magic so they can better guard against thieves and spies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0099</id>
    <name>Mind Bend</name>
    <text>Change the text of target permanent by replacing all instances of one color word with another or one basic land type with another. (For example, you may change "nonblack creature" to "nongreen creature" or "forestwalk" to "islandwalk." This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0100</id>
    <name>Phantom Warrior</name>
    <text>Phantom Warrior is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>It can pass through solid matter—but that doesn't mean it's harmless.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0101</id>
    <name>Puppeteer</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}: You may tap or untap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Getting people to do what you want is merely a matter of telling them what they want to hear."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0102</id>
    <name>Remove Soul</name>
    <text>Counter target creature spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0103</id>
    <name>Rewind</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. Untap up to four lands.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let's go over this one more time. . . ."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0104</id>
    <name>Sage of Lat-Nam</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice an artifact: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Within each device is a spark of its creator's soul. Within each sage is a lamp that awaits that spark.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0105</id>
    <name>Sage Owl</name>
    <text>Flying
When Sage Owl enters the battlefield, look at the top four cards of your library, then put them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0106</id>
    <name>Sea Monster</name>
    <text>Sea Monster can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.</text>
    <flavorText>It's easy to believe the monster is a myth—until you feel three hundred thousand pounds of myth crashing down on your ship.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0107</id>
    <name>Shifting Sky</name>
    <text>As Shifting Sky enters the battlefield, choose a color.
All nonland permanents are the chosen color.</text>
    <flavorText>Master the sky and you rule everything beneath it.
—Metathran saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0108</id>
    <name>Sneaky Homunculus</name>
    <text>Sneaky Homunculus can't block or be blocked by creatures with power 2 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>Keep watch only for the giants and you'll be eaten by the ants.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0109</id>
    <name>Spiketail Hatchling</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Sacrifice Spiketail Hatchling: Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1}.</text>
    <flavorText>It dodges waves of water to prepare for waves of magic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0110</id>
    <name>Steal Artifact</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact
You control enchanted artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0111</id>
    <name>Storm Crow</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Storm crow descending, winter unending. Storm crow departing, summer is starting.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0112</id>
    <name>Telepathy</name>
    <text>Your opponents play with their hands revealed.</text>
    <flavorText>"Secrets? What secrets?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0113</id>
    <name>Temporal Adept</name>
    <text>{U}{U}{U}, {T}: Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Of course she's at the head of her class. All of her classmates have disappeared."
—Tolarian renegade</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0114</id>
    <name>Thieving Magpie</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Whenever Thieving Magpie deals damage to an opponent, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Other birds collect twigs for their nests. Magpies steal jewels for theirs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0115</id>
    <name>Tidal Kraken</name>
    <text>Tidal Kraken is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>To merfolk, pirates are a nuisance. To pirates, merfolk are a threat. To the kraken, they're both appetizers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0116</id>
    <name>Trade Routes</name>
    <text>{1}: Return target land you control to its owner's hand.
{1}, Discard a land card: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The wise, the righteous, the mighty—the merchant feeds them all.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0117</id>
    <name>Treasure Trove</name>
    <text>{2}{U}{U}: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Wealth means power; the power to subdue, to crush, to exploit, the power to enslave, to outrage, to degrade."
—Emma Goldman, "Anarchism"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0118</id>
    <name>Twiddle</name>
    <text>You may tap or untap target artifact, creature, or land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0119</id>
    <name>Unsummon</name>
    <text>Return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0120</id>
    <name>Wall of Air</name>
    <text>Defender, flying (This creature can't attack, and it can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>When no falcons fly, beware the sky.
—Femeref aphorism</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0121</id>
    <name>Wind Drake</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"But high she shoots through air and light,
Above all low delay,
Where nothing earthly bounds her flight,
Nor shadow dims her way."
—Thomas Moore, "Oh that I had Wings"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0122</id>
    <name>Wrath of Marit Lage</name>
    <text>When Wrath of Marit Lage enters the battlefield, tap all red creatures.
Red creatures don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>"Marit Lage lies frozen in a glacier's heart. Still her dreams take form in our world, stealing the heat from our souls."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0123</id>
    <name>Zur's Weirding</name>
    <text>Players play with their hands revealed.
If a player would draw a card, he or she reveals it instead. Then any other player may pay 2 life. If a player does, put that card into its owner's graveyard. Otherwise, that player draws a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0124</id>
    <name>Abyssal Specter</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Abyssal Specter deals damage to a player, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>To gaze under its hood is to invite death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0125</id>
    <name>Ambition's Cost</name>
    <text>You draw three cards and you lose 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Knowledge demands sacrifice."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0126</id>
    <name>Bog Imp</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Think of it as a butcher knife with wings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0127</id>
    <name>Bog Wraith</name>
    <text>Swampwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Swamp.)</text>
    <flavorText>The bodies of its victims are the only tracks it leaves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0128</id>
    <name>Carrion Wall</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{1}{B}: Regenerate Carrion Wall.</text>
    <flavorText>A wall built from the bodies of the enemy will never lack building material in times of war.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0129</id>
    <name>Coercion</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You choose a card from it. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Human tenderness is simply weakness in a pretty package."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0130</id>
    <name>Dark Banishing</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Ha, banishment? Be merciful, say ‘death,'
For exile hath more terror in his look,
Much more than death."
—William Shakespeare, Romeo and Juliet</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0131</id>
    <name>Death Pit Offering</name>
    <text>When Death Pit Offering enters the battlefield, sacrifice all creatures you control.
Creatures you control get +2/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>"Kill them all and feed them to the new recruits."
—Crovax, ascendant evincar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0132</id>
    <name>Death Pits of Rath</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is dealt damage, destroy it. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Neither could I forget what I had read of these pits—that the sudden extinction of life formed no part of their most horrible plan."
—Edgar Allan Poe,
"The Pit and the Pendulum"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0133</id>
    <name>Deathgazer</name>
    <text>Whenever Deathgazer blocks or becomes blocked by a nonblack creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>Your entire life passes before its eyes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0134</id>
    <name>Deepwood Ghoul</name>
    <text>Pay 2 life: Regenerate Deepwood Ghoul.</text>
    <flavorText>They feed on the living to stay undead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0135</id>
    <name>Diabolic Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for a card and put that card into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The best ideas often come from the worst minds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0136</id>
    <name>Drudge Skeletons</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Drudge Skeletons. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The dead make good soldiers. They can't disobey orders, they never surrender, and they don't stop fighting when a random body part falls off."
—Nevinyrral, Necromancer's Handbook</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0137</id>
    <name>Dusk Imp</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>It despises humans and squirrels and beasts and dwarves and cephalids . . . well, it despises just about everything.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0138</id>
    <name>Eastern Paladin</name>
    <text>{B}{B}, {T}: Destroy target green creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is no worse enemy. His passion for death doesn't just border on insanity, it wallows in it."
—Southern paladin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0139</id>
    <name>Execute</name>
    <text>Destroy target white creature. It can't be regenerated.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Any fool who would die for honor is better off dead."
—Cabal Patriarch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0140</id>
    <name>Fallen Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
Sacrifice a creature: Fallen Angel gets +2/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why do you weep for the dead? I rejoice, for they have died for me."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0141</id>
    <name>Fear</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has fear. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The horror The horror"
—Joseph Conrad, Heart of Darkness</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0142</id>
    <name>Giant Cockroach</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Toren had stepped on a lot of bugs during his life, so he couldn't help feeling embarrassed when a bug stepped on him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0143</id>
    <name>Gluttonous Zombie</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>Greed and gluttony led him to death. Now they are his greatest assets.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0144</id>
    <name>Grave Pact</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, each other player sacrifices a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The bonds of loyalty can tie one to the grave."
—Crovax, ascendant evincar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0145</id>
    <name>Gravedigger</name>
    <text>When Gravedigger enters the battlefield, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>A full coffin is like a full coffer—both are attractive to thieves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0146</id>
    <name>Larceny</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control deals combat damage to a player, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Opportunity makes the thief.
—Roman proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0147</id>
    <name>Looming Shade</name>
    <text>{B}: Looming Shade gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>On darkness feeding, in nightmares breeding.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0148</id>
    <name>Lord of the Undead</name>
    <text>Other Zombie creatures get +1/+1.
{1}{B}, {T}: Return target Zombie card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"I confer with Death itself. What could you possibly do to injure me?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0149</id>
    <name>Maggot Carrier</name>
    <text>When Maggot Carrier enters the battlefield, each player loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"We do not suddenly fall on death, but advance towards it by slight degrees; we die every day."
—Seneca, Epistles, trans. Gummere</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0150</id>
    <name>Megrim</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent discards a card, Megrim deals 2 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>Memories cut from the mind can cut right back.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0151</id>
    <name>Mind Rot</name>
    <text>Target player discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>What wizards fear most is losing their minds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0152</id>
    <name>Mind Slash</name>
    <text>{B}, Sacrifice a creature: Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You choose a card from it. That player discards that card. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>"I can't think with all that screaming."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0153</id>
    <name>Mind Sludge</name>
    <text>Target player discards a card for each Swamp you control.</text>
    <flavorText>When you get into the swamp, the swamp gets into you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0154</id>
    <name>Murderous Betrayal</name>
    <text>{B}{B}, Pay half your life rounded up: Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>Which hurts more: a sword in the gut or a dagger in the back?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0155</id>
    <name>Nausea</name>
    <text>All creatures get -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>No fear. No sense. And soon, no lunch.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0156</id>
    <name>Nekrataal</name>
    <text>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)
When Nekrataal enters the battlefield, destroy target nonartifact, nonblack creature. That creature can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0157</id>
    <name>Nightmare</name>
    <text>Flying
Nightmare's power and toughness are each equal to the number of Swamps you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The thunder of its hooves beats dreams into despair.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0158</id>
    <name>Persecute</name>
    <text>Choose a color. Target player reveals his or her hand and discards all cards of that color.</text>
    <flavorText>"Of all the tyrannies on humane kind
The worst is that which persecutes the mind."
—John Dryden,
"The Hind and the Panther"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0159</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Arena</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you draw a card and you lose 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>A drop of humanity for a sea of power.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0160</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Plaguelord</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Phyrexian Plaguelord: Target creature gets -4/-4 until end of turn.
Sacrifice a creature: Target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The final stage of the illness: delirium, convulsions, and death."
—Phyrexian progress notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0161</id>
    <name>Plague Beetle</name>
    <text>Swampwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Swamp.)</text>
    <flavorText>No one knows whether they were named for the disease they carry or for the speed at which they multiply.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0162</id>
    <name>Plague Wind</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures you don't control. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"The second wind of ascension is Reaver, slaying the unworthy."
—Keld Triumphant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0163</id>
    <name>Primeval Shambler</name>
    <text>{B}: Primeval Shambler gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>His mind, like his body, is made up of the swamp's flotsam.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0164</id>
    <name>Raise Dead</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The earth cannot hold that which magic commands.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0165</id>
    <name>Ravenous Rats</name>
    <text>When Ravenous Rats enters the battlefield, target opponent discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Nothing is sacred to the rats. Everything is simply another meal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0166</id>
    <name>Royal Assassin</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target tapped creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Trained in the arts of stealth, royal assassins choose their victims carefully, relying on timing and precision rather than brute force.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0167</id>
    <name>Scathe Zombies</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"They groaned, they stirred, they all uprose,
Nor spake, nor moved their eyes;
It had been strange, even in a dream,
To have seen those dead men rise."
—Samuel Taylor Coleridge,
"The Rime of the Ancient Mariner"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0168</id>
    <name>Serpent Warrior</name>
    <text>When Serpent Warrior enters the battlefield, you lose 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>A hiss before dying.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0169</id>
    <name>Sever Soul</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated. You gain life equal to its toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>"The mortal world is a grove of sweet fruit, and I am ready to harvest it."
—Fallen angel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0170</id>
    <name>Severed Legion</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>No one in Aphetto answers a knock at the door after sundown.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0171</id>
    <name>Slay</name>
    <text>Destroy target green creature. It can't be regenerated.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The elves had the edge in guile, skill, and valor. But in the end, only sheer numbers mattered.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0172</id>
    <name>Soul Feast</name>
    <text>Target player loses 4 life and you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>You are who you eat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0173</id>
    <name>Spineless Thug</name>
    <text>Spineless Thug can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>What it lacks in backbone, it makes up for in cruelty.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0174</id>
    <name>Swarm of Rats</name>
    <text>Swarm of Rats's power is equal to the number of Rats you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Rats, rats, rats Hundreds, thousands, millions of them, and every one a life."
—Bram Stoker, Dracula</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0175</id>
    <name>Underworld Dreams</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent draws a card, Underworld Dreams deals 1 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>"In the drowsy dark cave of the mind, dreams build their nest with fragments dropped from day's caravan."
—Rabindranath Tagore</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0176</id>
    <name>Unholy Strength</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>Such power grows the body as it shrinks the soul.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0177</id>
    <name>Vampiric Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying
When Vampiric Spirit enters the battlefield, you lose 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0178</id>
    <name>Vicious Hunger</name>
    <text>Vicious Hunger deals 2 damage to target creature and you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Only the most ravenous soul feeds on the health of the weak.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0179</id>
    <name>Warped Devotion</name>
    <text>Whenever a permanent is returned to a player's hand, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"The spirit of the devout is easily crushed by the loss of hope."
—Fallen angel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0180</id>
    <name>Western Paladin</name>
    <text>{B}{B}, {T}: Destroy target white creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Expect nothing but scorn, flattery, and lies. And never turn your back on him."
—Northern paladin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0181</id>
    <name>Zombify</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"The first birth celebrates life. The second birth mocks it."
—Mystic elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0182</id>
    <name>Anaba Shaman</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}: Anaba Shaman deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Just try taking this bull by the horns.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0183</id>
    <name>Balduvian Barbarians</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"From the snowy slopes of Kaelor,
To the canyons of Bandu,
We drink and fight and feast and die
As we were born to do."
—Balduvian tavern song</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0184</id>
    <name>Blaze</name>
    <text>Blaze deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Fire never dies alone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0185</id>
    <name>Blood Moon</name>
    <text>Nonbasic lands are Mountains.</text>
    <flavorText>Heavy light flooded across the landscape, cloaking everything in deep crimson.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0186</id>
    <name>Bloodshot Cyclops</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a creature: Bloodshot Cyclops deals damage equal to the sacrificed creature's power to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>After their first encounter, the goblins named him Chuck.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0187</id>
    <name>Boil</name>
    <text>Destroy all Islands.</text>
    <flavorText>"When every reef is bared and every wave is dust—only then shall I rest."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0188</id>
    <name>Canyon Wildcat</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk</text>
    <flavorText>In the warrior kingdom of Keld, the cats used in the hunt are prized for their tracking sense and ability to climb walls.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0189</id>
    <name>Cinder Wall</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
When Cinder Wall blocks, destroy it at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"The smell of roasted flesh hung over the valley for hours."
—Onean sergeant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0190</id>
    <name>Demolish</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Pound the steel until it fits.
Doesn't work? Bash to bits."
—Dwarven forging song</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0191</id>
    <name>Dwarven Demolition Team</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target Wall.</text>
    <flavorText>Foolishly, Najib retreated to his castle at El-Abar; the next morning he was dead. In just one night, the dwarven forces had reduced the mighty walls to mere rubble.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0192</id>
    <name>Enrage</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"You wouldn't like me when I'm angry."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0193</id>
    <name>Flashfires</name>
    <text>Destroy all Plains.</text>
    <flavorText>Dry grass is tinder before the spark.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0194</id>
    <name>Furnace of Rath</name>
    <text>If a source would deal damage to a creature or player, it deals double that damage to that creature or player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>The furnace awaits the next master who would stoke the fires of apocalypse.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0195</id>
    <name>Goblin Chariot</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack the turn it comes under your control.)</text>
    <flavorText>The hardest part of his training is learning not to eat the boar.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0196</id>
    <name>Goblin Glider</name>
    <text>Flying
Goblin Glider can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>"What's got two arms, one wing, and no brains?"
—Ghitu riddle</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0197</id>
    <name>Goblin King</name>
    <text>Other Goblin creatures get +1/+1 and have mountainwalk. (They're unblockable as long as defending player controls a Mountain.)</text>
    <flavorText>To be king, Numsgil did in Blog, who did in Unkful, who did in Viddle, who did in Loll, who did in Alrok. . . .</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0198</id>
    <name>Goblin Raider</name>
    <text>Goblin Raider can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>He's smart for a goblin. He can do two things: hit and run.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0199</id>
    <name>Guerrilla Tactics</name>
    <text>Guerrilla Tactics deals 2 damage to target creature or player.
When a spell or ability an opponent controls causes you to discard Guerrilla Tactics, Guerrilla Tactics deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0200</id>
    <name>Hammer of Bogardan</name>
    <text>Hammer of Bogardan deals 3 damage to target creature or player.
{2}{R}{R}{R}: Return Hammer of Bogardan from your graveyard to your hand. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0201</id>
    <name>Hill Giant</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Bent on a quest for blood, a giant can storm through a fort's wall as if it were nothing more than a picket fence.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0202</id>
    <name>Hulking Cyclops</name>
    <text>Hulking Cyclops can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>Anyone can get around a cyclops, but few can stand in its way.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0203</id>
    <name>Inferno</name>
    <text>Inferno deals 6 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Some have said there is no subtlety to destruction. You know what? They're dead."
—Jaya Ballard, task mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0204</id>
    <name>Lava Axe</name>
    <text>Lava Axe deals 5 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Catch"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0205</id>
    <name>Lava Hounds</name>
    <text>Haste
When Lava Hounds enters the battlefield, it deals 4 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0206</id>
    <name>Lesser Gargadon</name>
    <text>Whenever Lesser Gargadon attacks or blocks, sacrifice a land.</text>
    <flavorText>"In some cultures, elephants are ridden by those in power. I don't think a mere elephant would even be noticed in Keld."
—Onean sergeant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0207</id>
    <name>Lightning Blast</name>
    <text>Lightning Blast deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those who fear the darkness have never seen what the light can do."
—Selenia, dark angel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0208</id>
    <name>Lightning Elemental</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)</text>
    <flavorText>"A flash of the lightning, a break of the wave,
He passes from life to his rest in the grave."
—William Knox, "Mortality"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0209</id>
    <name>Mana Clash</name>
    <text>You and target opponent each flip a coin. Mana Clash deals 1 damage to each player whose coin comes up tails. Repeat this process until both players' coins come up heads on the same flip.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0210</id>
    <name>Mogg Sentry</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a spell, Mogg Sentry gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Tortured with magic by their masters, the moggs are enflamed by the smell of sorcery.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0211</id>
    <name>Obliterate</name>
    <text>Obliterate can't be countered.
Destroy all artifacts, creatures, and lands. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"The enemy has been destroyed, sir. So have the forest, the city, your palace, your dog . . ."
—Keldon soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0212</id>
    <name>Ogre Taskmaster</name>
    <text>Ogre Taskmaster can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>Ogres learn how to smash stuff even before they learn how to walk.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0213</id>
    <name>Okk</name>
    <text>Okk can't attack unless a creature with greater power also attacks.
Okk can't block unless a creature with greater power also blocks.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0214</id>
    <name>Orcish Artillery</name>
    <text>{T}: Orcish Artillery deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"So they want to kill my men? Well two can play at that game."
—General Khurzog</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0215</id>
    <name>Orcish Spy</name>
    <text>{T}: Look at the top three cards of target player's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"You idiot Never let the spies mingle with the orcish regulars after completing a mission. Now we'll never get them to fight"
—General Khurzog</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0216</id>
    <name>Panic Attack</name>
    <text>Up to three target creatures can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes everyone decides to go for help at the same time.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0217</id>
    <name>Pyroclasm</name>
    <text>Pyroclasm deals 2 damage to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"When the air burns, only death breathes deep."
—Bogardan mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0218</id>
    <name>Pyrotechnics</name>
    <text>Pyrotechnics deals 4 damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>"Who says lightning never strikes twice?"
—Storm shaman</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0219</id>
    <name>Raging Goblin</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)</text>
    <flavorText>He raged at the world, at his family, at his life. But mostly he just raged.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0220</id>
    <name>Reflexes</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has first strike. (It deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Be as fast as lightning, and you will be just as deadly."
—Combat trainer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0221</id>
    <name>Relentless Assault</name>
    <text>Untap all creatures that attacked this turn. After this main phase, there is an additional combat phase followed by an additional main phase.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mercy? Mercy is for the playground, not the battleground."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0222</id>
    <name>Ridgeline Rager</name>
    <text>{R}: Ridgeline Rager gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>While armies battled across Jamuraa, beasts stalked the high places looking for victims.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0223</id>
    <name>Rukh Egg</name>
    <text>When Rukh Egg is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a 4/4 red Bird creature token with flying onto the battlefield at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>Called "stonefeathers" by many lowlanders, rukhs are thought to descend from a phoenix that sacrificed its flame for a body of stone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0224</id>
    <name>Sabretooth Tiger</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>To a sabretooth, all men are mice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0225</id>
    <name>Searing Wind</name>
    <text>Searing Wind deals 10 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"The first wind of ascension is Forger, burning away impurity."
—Keld Triumphant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0226</id>
    <name>Seismic Assault</name>
    <text>Discard a land card: Seismic Assault deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Earth arms itself with fire.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0227</id>
    <name>Shatter</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0228</id>
    <name>Shivan Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}: Shivan Dragon gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The undisputed master of the mountains of Shiv.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0229</id>
    <name>Shock</name>
    <text>Shock deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"I love lightning It's my best invention since the rock."
—Toggo, goblin weaponsmith</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0230</id>
    <name>Shock Troops</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Shock Troops: Shock Troops deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>War is a conflict that determines not who is right—but who is left.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0231</id>
    <name>Sizzle</name>
    <text>Sizzle deals 3 damage to each opponent.</text>
    <flavorText>"Of course you should fight fire with fire. You should fight everything with fire."
—Jaya Ballard, task mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0232</id>
    <name>Stone Rain</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0233</id>
    <name>Sudden Impact</name>
    <text>Sudden Impact deals damage equal to the number of cards in target player's hand to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>Most people know better. Goblins only know bigger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0234</id>
    <name>Thieves' Auction</name>
    <text>Exile all nontoken permanents. Starting with you, each player chooses one of the exiled cards and puts it onto the battlefield tapped under his or her control. Repeat this process until all those cards have been chosen.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0235</id>
    <name>Tremor</name>
    <text>Tremor deals 1 damage to each creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Where do you run when the earth becomes your enemy?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0236</id>
    <name>Two-Headed Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{R}: Two-Headed Dragon gets +2/+0 until end of turn.
Two-Headed Dragon can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.
Two-Headed Dragon can block an additional creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0237</id>
    <name>Viashino Sandstalker</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack the turn it comes under your control.)
At the beginning of the end step, return Viashino Sandstalker to its owner's hand. (Return it only if it's on the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Some believe sandstalkers to be illusions; those with scars know better."
—Zhalfirin Guide to the Desert</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0238</id>
    <name>Volcanic Hammer</name>
    <text>Volcanic Hammer deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Fire finds its form in the heat of the forge.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0239</id>
    <name>Wall of Stone</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</text>
    <flavorText>The ground itself lends its strength to these walls of living stone, which possess the stability of ancient mountains. These mighty bulwarks thwart ground-based troops, providing welcome relief for weary warriors who defend the land.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0240</id>
    <name>Birds of Paradise</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0241</id>
    <name>Blanchwood Armor</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 for each Forest you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"There's never been a dwarven smith who could match the marvels that Gaea herself forges."
—Elvish champion</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0242</id>
    <name>Call of the Wild</name>
    <text>{2}{G}{G}: Reveal the top card of your library. If it's a creature card, put it onto the battlefield. Otherwise, put it into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>From a whisper to a roar, the call is heard by all and refused by none.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0243</id>
    <name>Canopy Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>It keeps the upper reaches of the forest free of every menace . . . except for the spider itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0244</id>
    <name>Choke</name>
    <text>Islands don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>"One day we shall walk where once was water."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0245</id>
    <name>Collective Unconscious</name>
    <text>Draw a card for each creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"The beasts of the wild are my senses. It is through their eyes that all knowledge shall come to me."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0246</id>
    <name>Craw Wurm</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The most terrifying thing about the craw wurm is probably the horrible crashing sound it makes as it speeds through the forest. This noise is so loud it echoes through the trees and seems to come from all directions at once.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0247</id>
    <name>Creeping Mold</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact, enchantment, or land.</text>
    <flavorText>Mold crept over the walls and into every crevice until the gleaming white stone strained and burst.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0248</id>
    <name>Elvish Champion</name>
    <text>Other Elf creatures get +1/+1 and have forestwalk. (They're unblockable as long as defending player controls a Forest.)</text>
    <flavorText>"For what are leaves but countless blades
To fight a countless foe on high."
—Elvish hymn</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0249</id>
    <name>Elvish Lyrist</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}, Sacrifice Elvish Lyrist: Destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>Each pluck of the strings breaks the hold of the unnatural on the world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0250</id>
    <name>Elvish Pioneer</name>
    <text>When Elvish Pioneer enters the battlefield, you may put a basic land card from your hand onto the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>"Destruction is the work of an afternoon. Creation is the work of a lifetime."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0251</id>
    <name>Elvish Piper</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: You may put a creature card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>From Gaea grew the world, and the world was silent. From Gaea grew the world's elves, and the world was silent no more.
—Elvish teaching</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0252</id>
    <name>Elvish Scrapper</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}, Sacrifice Elvish Scrapper: Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>"The stories tell of a distant time when machines overran the forests, destroying everything that lived. That time will not come again."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0253</id>
    <name>Emperor Crocodile</name>
    <text>When you control no other creatures, sacrifice Emperor Crocodile.</text>
    <flavorText>The king of Yavimaya's waters pays constant attention to his subjects . . . and thrives on their adulation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0254</id>
    <name>Fecundity</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, that creature's controller may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Life is eternal. A lifetime is ephemeral.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0255</id>
    <name>Fertile Ground</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds one mana of any color to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>"The love of nature . . . is a furious, burning, physical greed. . . ."
—Mary Webb, The House in Dormer Forest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0256</id>
    <name>Foratog</name>
    <text>{G}, Sacrifice a Forest: Foratog gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Five hundred years to grow—barely a minute to eat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0257</id>
    <name>Fungusaur</name>
    <text>Whenever Fungusaur is dealt damage, put a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>Rather than sheltering her young, the female fungusaur often injures her own offspring, thereby ensuring their rapid growth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0258</id>
    <name>Fyndhorn Elder</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is useful to be able to speak to the trees. But it is truly wondrous to be able to listen to them."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0259</id>
    <name>Gaea's Herald</name>
    <text>Creature spells can't be countered.</text>
    <flavorText>The elves' battle cries cut paths through the Æther, guiding those who would stand in Gaea's defense.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0260</id>
    <name>Giant Badger</name>
    <text>Whenever Giant Badger blocks, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Disturb a sleeping badger and the snapping of your bones will awaken the countryside.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0261</id>
    <name>Giant Growth</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0262</id>
    <name>Giant Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>Watching the spider's web
—Llanowar expression meaning
"focusing on the wrong thing"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0263</id>
    <name>Grizzly Bears</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Don't try to outrun one of Dominaria's grizzlies; it'll catch you, knock you down, and eat you. Of course, you could run up a tree. In that case you'll get a nice view before it knocks the tree down and eats you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0264</id>
    <name>Horned Troll</name>
    <text>{G}: Regenerate Horned Troll.</text>
    <flavorText>Sword hilts jut from some trolls' bodies where wounds healed so fast that the weapons were trapped inside.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0265</id>
    <name>Hunted Wumpus</name>
    <text>When Hunted Wumpus enters the battlefield, each other player may put a creature card from his or her hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Just one can feed a dozen people for a month.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0266</id>
    <name>Lhurgoyf</name>
    <text>Lhurgoyf's power is equal to the number of creature cards in all graveyards and its toughness is equal to that number plus 1.</text>
    <flavorText>"Ach Hans, run It's the lhurgoyf"
—Saffi Eriksdotter, last words</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0267</id>
    <name>Living Terrain</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Enchanted land is a 5/6 green Treefolk creature that's still a land.</text>
    <flavorText>Some warriors walk the earth. Others are born of it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0268</id>
    <name>Llanowar Behemoth</name>
    <text>Tap an untapped creature you control: Llanowar Behemoth gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Most people can't build decent weapons out of stone or steel. Trust the elves to do it with only mud and vines."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0269</id>
    <name>Lone Wolf</name>
    <text>You may have Lone Wolf assign its combat damage as though it weren't blocked.</text>
    <flavorText>A wolf without a pack is either a survivor or a brute.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0270</id>
    <name>Lure</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
All creatures able to block enchanted creature do so.</text>
    <flavorText>"When the forest wants something, no mortal mind can resist her."
—Maro</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0271</id>
    <name>Maro</name>
    <text>Maro's power and toughness are each equal to the number of cards in your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>No two see the same Maro.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0272</id>
    <name>Might of Oaks</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +7/+7 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Guess where I'm gonna plant this"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0273</id>
    <name>Monstrous Growth</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Get in touch with your inner monster.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0274</id>
    <name>Moss Monster</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>After the battle, an eerie silence gripped the forest. The losers' remains were lightly dusted with green.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0275</id>
    <name>Nantuko Disciple</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Unanswered prayers are themselves answers.
—Nantuko teaching</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0276</id>
    <name>Natural Affinity</name>
    <text>All lands become 2/2 creatures until end of turn. They're still lands.</text>
    <flavorText>As long as the dryads are a part of the forest, the forest is a part of the army.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0277</id>
    <name>Naturalize</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"One touch of nature makes the whole world kin."
—William Shakespeare,
Troilus and Cressida</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0278</id>
    <name>Norwood Ranger</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The song of the forest is in perfect harmony. If a single note is out of place, the elves will find its source.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0279</id>
    <name>Plow Under</name>
    <text>Put two target lands on top of their owners' libraries.</text>
    <flavorText>To renew the land, plow the land.
To destroy the land, do nothing.
—Druids' saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0280</id>
    <name>Primeval Force</name>
    <text>When Primeval Force enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you sacrifice three Forests.</text>
    <flavorText>It has germinated in the earth for thousands of years. Finally it wakes to the battle's call.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0281</id>
    <name>Rampant Growth</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Nature grows solutions to her problems.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0282</id>
    <name>Regeneration</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
{G}: Regenerate enchanted creature. (The next time that creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Why should death always have the last word?"
—Llanowar druid</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0283</id>
    <name>Revive</name>
    <text>Return target green card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Even what is lost beyond recall returns when coaxed by a dryad's hand.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0284</id>
    <name>Rhox</name>
    <text>You may have Rhox assign its combat damage as though it weren't blocked.
{2}{G}: Regenerate Rhox. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0285</id>
    <name>Rushwood Dryad</name>
    <text>Forestwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Forest.)</text>
    <flavorText>To a dryad, every tree in the forest is both a doorway and a window.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0286</id>
    <name>Spined Wurm</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"I wouldn't stand in front of that wurm, son. 'Course, I wouldn't stand behind it neither. In fact, standing anywhere near that wurm's not much of a plan. Running, now that's a plan"
—Wandering mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0287</id>
    <name>Spitting Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)
Sacrifice a land: Spitting Spider deals 1 damage to each creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0288</id>
    <name>Spreading Algae</name>
    <text>Enchant Swamp
When enchanted land becomes tapped, destroy it.
When Spreading Algae is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Spreading Algae to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0289</id>
    <name>Stream of Life</name>
    <text>Target player gains X life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0290</id>
    <name>Thorn Elemental</name>
    <text>You may have Thorn Elemental assign its combat damage as though it weren't blocked.</text>
    <flavorText>Rain from this storm leaves you pinned to the ground like an insect.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0291</id>
    <name>Trained Armodon</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Armodons are trained to step on things. Enemy things.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0292</id>
    <name>Verduran Enchantress</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an enchantment spell, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Graceful? Yes. Beautiful? Absolutely. Harmless? Definitely not."
—Fyndhorn elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0293</id>
    <name>Vernal Bloom</name>
    <text>Whenever a Forest is tapped for mana, its controller adds {G} to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>The sun breaks, the beasts stir, and the forest awakens to stand against its enemies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0294</id>
    <name>Vine Trellis</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Nature twists knots stronger than any rope.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0295</id>
    <name>Wing Snare</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"We are the hands of the great trees, reaching out to ensnare what threatens their branches."
—Elvish hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0296</id>
    <name>Wood Elves</name>
    <text>When Wood Elves enters the battlefield, search your library for a Forest card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Every branch a crossroads, every vine a swift steed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0297</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Enchantress</name>
    <text>Yavimaya Enchantress gets +1/+1 for each enchantment on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Her roots connect her to the forest's wishes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0298</id>
    <name>Aladdin's Ring</name>
    <text>{8}, {T}: Aladdin's Ring deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"A good lamp will light your way. A good ring will clear it."
—Nervan, royal jeweler</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0299</id>
    <name>Beast of Burden</name>
    <text>Beast of Burden's power and toughness are each equal to the number of creatures on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The heavier the load, the harder it works.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0300</id>
    <name>Brass Herald</name>
    <text>As Brass Herald enters the battlefield, choose a creature type.
When Brass Herald enters the battlefield, reveal the top four cards of your library. Put all creature cards of the chosen type revealed this way into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.
Creatures of the chosen type get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0301</id>
    <name>Coat of Arms</name>
    <text>Each creature gets +1/+1 for each other creature on the battlefield that shares at least one creature type with it. (For example, if two Goblin Warriors and a Goblin Shaman are on the battlefield, each gets +2/+2.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Hup, two, three, four,
Dunno how to count no more."
—Mogg march</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0302</id>
    <name>Crystal Rod</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a blue spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Polished by a thousand waves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0303</id>
    <name>Defense Grid</name>
    <text>Each spell costs {3} more to cast except during its controller's turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"A good deal of tyranny goes by the name of protection."
—Crystal Eastman,
"Equality or Protection"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0304</id>
    <name>Dingus Egg</name>
    <text>Whenever a land is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, Dingus Egg deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>Legend has it that the world was hatched from a dingus egg.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0305</id>
    <name>Disrupting Scepter</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target player discards a card. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"True power is controlling not only the hearts of your subjects, but their minds as well."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0306</id>
    <name>Distorting Lens</name>
    <text>{T}: Target permanent becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Eye altering alters all."
—William Blake, "The Mental Traveller"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0307</id>
    <name>Ensnaring Bridge</name>
    <text>Creatures with power greater than the number of cards in your hand can't attack.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why build a bridge that needs to be guarded?"
—Elvish champion</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0308</id>
    <name>Flying Carpet</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Woven from strands of griffin mane and pegasus tail.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0309</id>
    <name>Fodder Cannon</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Fodder Cannon deals 4 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Step 1: Find your cousin.
Step 2: Get your cousin in the cannon.
Step 3: Find another cousin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0310</id>
    <name>Howling Mine</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's draw step, if Howling Mine is untapped, that player draws an additional card.</text>
    <flavorText>Legend has it that the mine howls out the last words of those who died inside.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0311</id>
    <name>Iron Star</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a red spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Forged by a thousand flames.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0312</id>
    <name>Ivory Cup</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a white spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Blessed by a thousand prayers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0313</id>
    <name>Jayemdae Tome</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Knowledge is power."
—Sir Francis Bacon, Meditationes Sacrae</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0314</id>
    <name>Millstone</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target player puts the top two cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>More than one mage has been driven insane by the sound of the millstone relentlessly grinding away.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0315</id>
    <name>Patagia Golem</name>
    <text>{3}: Patagia Golem gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Its wings were only designed to be ornamental, but it learned to use them on its own.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0316</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Colossus</name>
    <text>Phyrexian Colossus doesn't untap during your untap step.
Pay 8 life: Untap Phyrexian Colossus.
Phyrexian Colossus can't be blocked except by three or more creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0317</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Hulk</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>It doesn't think. It doesn't feel.
It doesn't laugh or cry.
All it does from dusk till dawn
Is make the soldiers die.
—Onean children's rhyme</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0318</id>
    <name>Planar Portal</name>
    <text>{6}, {T}: Search your library for a card and put that card into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>These devices have been known to pull entire worlds through the Æther.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0319</id>
    <name>Rod of Ruin</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Rod of Ruin deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>The rod is a relic from ancient times . . . cruel, vicious, mean-spirited times.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0320</id>
    <name>Skull of Orm</name>
    <text>{5}, {T}: Return target enchantment card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Though lifeless, the skull still possessed a strange power over the flow of magic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0321</id>
    <name>Spellbook</name>
    <text>You have no maximum hand size.</text>
    <flavorText>Knowledge knows no bounds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0322</id>
    <name>Star Compass</name>
    <text>Star Compass enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add to your mana pool one mana of any color a basic land you control could produce.</text>
    <flavorText>It doesn't point north. It points home.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0323</id>
    <name>Teferi's Puzzle Box</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's draw step, that player puts the cards in his or her hand on the bottom of his or her library in any order, then draws that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0324</id>
    <name>Throne of Bone</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a black spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Tainted by a thousand fears.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0325</id>
    <name>Urza's Armor</name>
    <text>If a source would deal damage to you, prevent 1 of that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>Urza protected his body well, but neglected his soul.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0326</id>
    <name>Vexing Arcanix</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target player names a card, then reveals the top card of his or her library. If it's the named card, the player puts it into his or her hand. Otherwise, the player puts it into his or her graveyard and Vexing Arcanix deals 2 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0327</id>
    <name>Wall of Spears</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
First strike</text>
    <flavorText>"A stick is your friend. A pointed stick is your good friend. An army of pointed sticks is your best friend."
—Onean sergeant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0328</id>
    <name>Wooden Sphere</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a green spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Strengthened by a thousand limbs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0329</id>
    <name>City of Brass</name>
    <text>Whenever City of Brass becomes tapped, it deals 1 damage to you.
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0330</id>
    <name>Coastal Tower</name>
    <text>Coastal Tower enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>A beacon in the night, a dream in the fog.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0331</id>
    <name>Elfhame Palace</name>
    <text>Elfhame Palace enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The elfhames are the closest thing to "civilization" the elves allow themselves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0332</id>
    <name>Salt Marsh</name>
    <text>Salt Marsh enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Only death breeds in stagnant water.
—Urborg saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0333</id>
    <name>Shivan Oasis</name>
    <text>Shivan Oasis enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Only the hardiest explorers survive to eat the fruit.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0334</id>
    <name>Urborg Volcano</name>
    <text>Urborg Volcano enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Deep in the heart of Urborg lie massive volcanoes whose thick black smoke covers the land with perpetual darkness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0335</id>
    <name>Urza's Mine</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool. If you control an Urza's Power-Plant and an Urza's Tower, add {2} to your mana pool instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0336</id>
    <name>Urza's Power Plant</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool. If you control an Urza's Mine and an Urza's Tower, add {2} to your mana pool instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0337</id>
    <name>Urza's Tower</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool. If you control an Urza's Mine and an Urza's Power-Plant, add {3} to your mana pool instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0338</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0339</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0340</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0341</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0342</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0343</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0344</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0345</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0346</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0347</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0348</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0349</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0350</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0351</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0352</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0353</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0354</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0355</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0356</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>8ED0357</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>