<cards name="Arabian Nights">
  <item>
    <id>ARN0001</id>
    <name>Abu Ja'far</name>
    <text>When Abu Ja'far is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, destroy all creatures blocking or blocked by it. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0002</id>
    <name>Aladdin</name>
    <text>{1}{R}{R}, {T}: Gain control of target artifact for as long as you control Aladdin.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0003</id>
    <name>Aladdin's Lamp</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: The next time you would draw a card this turn, instead look at the top X cards of your library, put all but one of them on the bottom of your library in a random order, then draw a card. X can't be 0.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0004</id>
    <name>Aladdin's Ring</name>
    <text>{8}, {T}: Aladdin's Ring deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"After these words the magician drew a ring off his finger, and put it on one of Aladdin's, saying: 'It is a talisman against all evil, so long as you obey me.'"The Arabian Nights, Junior Classics trans.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0005</id>
    <name>Ali Baba</name>
    <text>{R}: Tap target Wall.</text>
    <flavorText>"When he reached the entrance of the cavern, he pronounced the words, ‘Open, Sesame'"The Arabian Nights, Junior Classics trans.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0006</id>
    <name>Ali from Cairo</name>
    <text>Damage that would reduce your life total to less than 1 reduces it to 1 instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0007</id>
    <name>Army of Allah</name>
    <text>Attacking creatures get +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>On the day of victory no one is tired.Arab proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0008</id>
    <name>Army of Allah</name>
    <text>Attacking creatures get +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>On the day of victory no one is tired.Arab proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0009</id>
    <name>Bazaar of Baghdad</name>
    <text>{T}: Draw two cards, then discard three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0010</id>
    <name>Bird Maiden</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"Four things that never meet do here unite To shed my blood and to ravage my heart, A radiant brow and tresses that beguile And rosy cheeks and a glittering smile."The Arabian Nights, trans. Haddawy</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0011</id>
    <name>Bird Maiden</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"Four things that never meet do here unite To shed my blood and to ravage my heart, A radiant brow and tresses that beguile And rosy cheeks and a glittering smile."The Arabian Nights, trans. Haddawy</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0012</id>
    <name>Bottle of Suleiman</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice Bottle of Suleiman: Flip a coin. If you lose the flip, Bottle of Suleiman deals 5 damage to you. If you win the flip, put a 5/5 colorless Djinn artifact creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0013</id>
    <name>Brass Man</name>
    <text>Brass Man doesn't untap during your untap step.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {1}. If you do, untap Brass Man.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0014</id>
    <name>Camel</name>
    <text>Banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)
Prevent all damage that would be dealt to Camel or to creatures banded with Camel by Deserts.</text>
    <flavorText>Everyone knew Walid was a pious man, for he had been blessed with many sons, many jewels, and a great many Camels.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0015</id>
    <name>City in a Bottle</name>
    <text>Whenever a nontoken permanent from the Arabian Nights expansion other than City in a Bottle is on the battlefield, its controller sacrifices it.
Players can't play cards from the Arabian Nights expansion.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0016</id>
    <name>City of Brass</name>
    <text>Whenever City of Brass becomes tapped, it deals 1 damage to you.
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0017</id>
    <name>Cuombajj Witches</name>
    <text>{T}: Cuombajj Witches deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to target creature or player of an opponent's choice.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0018</id>
    <name>Cyclone</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a wind counter on Cyclone, then sacrifice Cyclone unless you pay {G} for each wind counter on it. If you pay, Cyclone deals damage equal to the number of wind counters on it to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0019</id>
    <name>Dancing Scimitar</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Bobbing merrily from opponent to opponent, the scimitar began adding playful little flourishes to its strokes; it even turned a couple of somersaults.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0020</id>
    <name>Dandân</name>
    <text>Dandân can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.
When you control no Islands, sacrifice Dandân.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0021</id>
    <name>Desert</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Desert deals 1 damage to target attacking creature. Activate this ability only during the end of combat step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0022</id>
    <name>Desert Nomads</name>
    <text>Desertwalk
Prevent all damage that would be dealt to Desert Nomads by Deserts.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0023</id>
    <name>Desert Twister</name>
    <text>Destroy target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0024</id>
    <name>Diamond Valley</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a creature: You gain life equal to the sacrificed creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0025</id>
    <name>Drop of Honey</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy the creature with the least power. It can't be regenerated. If two or more creatures are tied for least power, you choose one of them.
When there are no creatures on the battlefield, sacrifice Drop of Honey.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0026</id>
    <name>Ebony Horse</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Untap target attacking creature you control. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by that creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0027</id>
    <name>Elephant Graveyard</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Regenerate target Elephant.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0028</id>
    <name>El-Hajjâj</name>
    <text>Whenever El-Hajjâj deals damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0029</id>
    <name>Erg Raiders</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your end step, if Erg Raiders didn't attack this turn, Erg Raiders deals 2 damage to you unless it came under your control this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0030</id>
    <name>Erg Raiders</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your end step, if Erg Raiders didn't attack this turn, Erg Raiders deals 2 damage to you unless it came under your control this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0031</id>
    <name>Erhnam Djinn</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, target non-Wall creature an opponent controls gains forestwalk until your next upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0032</id>
    <name>Eye for an Eye</name>
    <text>The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, instead that source deals that much damage to you and Eye for an Eye deals that much damage to that source's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0033</id>
    <name>Fishliver Oil</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has islandwalk. (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls an Island.)</text>
    <flavorText>Then the maiden bade him cast off his robes and cover his body with fishliver oil, that he might safely follow her into the sea.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0034</id>
    <name>Fishliver Oil</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has islandwalk. (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls an Island.)</text>
    <flavorText>Then the maiden bade him cast off his robes and cover his body with fishliver oil, that he might safely follow her into the sea.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0035</id>
    <name>Flying Carpet</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0036</id>
    <name>Flying Men</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Saffiyah clapped her hands and twenty flying men appeared at her side, each well trained in the art of combat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0037</id>
    <name>Ghazbán Ogre</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if a player has more life than each other player, the player with the most life gains control of Ghazbán Ogre.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0038</id>
    <name>Giant Tortoise</name>
    <text>Giant Tortoise gets +0/+3 as long as it's untapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0039</id>
    <name>Giant Tortoise</name>
    <text>Giant Tortoise gets +0/+3 as long as it's untapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0040</id>
    <name>Guardian Beast</name>
    <text>As long as Guardian Beast is untapped, noncreature artifacts you control can't be enchanted, they're indestructible, and other players can't gain control of them. This effect doesn't remove Auras already attached to those artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0041</id>
    <name>Hasran Ogress</name>
    <text>Whenever Hasran Ogress attacks, it deals 3 damage to you unless you pay {2}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0042</id>
    <name>Hasran Ogress</name>
    <text>Whenever Hasran Ogress attacks, it deals 3 damage to you unless you pay {2}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0043</id>
    <name>Hurr Jackal</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature can't be regenerated this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0044</id>
    <name>Ifh-Bíff Efreet</name>
    <text>Flying
{G}: Ifh-Bíff Efreet deals 1 damage to each creature with flying and each player. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0045</id>
    <name>Island Fish Jasconius</name>
    <text>Island Fish Jasconius can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.
Island Fish Jasconius doesn't untap during your untap step.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {U}{U}{U}. If you do, untap Island Fish Jasconius.
When you control no Islands, sacrifice Island Fish Jasconius.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0046</id>
    <name>Island of Wak-Wak</name>
    <text>{T}: The power of target creature with flying becomes 0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Isle of Wak-Wak, home to a tribe of winged folk, is named for a peculiar fruit that grows there. The fruit looks like a woman's head, and when ripe speaks the word "Wak."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0047</id>
    <name>Jandor's Ring</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Discard the last card you drew this turn: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0048</id>
    <name>Jandor's Saddlebags</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Untap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Each day of their journey, Jandor opened the saddlebags and found them full of mutton, quinces, cheese, date rolls, wine, and all manner of delicious and satisfying foods.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0049</id>
    <name>Jeweled Bird</name>
    <text>Remove Jeweled Bird from your deck before playing if you're not playing for ante.
{T}: Put Jeweled Bird into the ante. If you do, put all other cards you own from the ante into your graveyard, then draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0050</id>
    <name>Jihad</name>
    <text>As Jihad enters the battlefield, choose a color and an opponent.
White creatures get +2/+1 as long as the chosen player controls a nontoken permanent of the chosen color.
When the chosen player controls no nontoken permanents of the chosen color, sacrifice Jihad.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0051</id>
    <name>Junún Efreet</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Junún Efreet unless you pay {B}{B}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0052</id>
    <name>Juzám Djinn</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Juzám Djinn deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"Expect my visit when the darkness comes. The night I think is best for hiding all."Ouallada</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0053</id>
    <name>Khabál Ghoul</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each end step, put a +1/+1 counter on Khabál Ghoul for each creature put into a graveyard from the battlefield this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0054</id>
    <name>King Suleiman</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target Djinn or Efreet.</text>
    <flavorText>"We made tempestuous winds obedient to Solomon . . . And many of the devils We also made obedient to him."The Qur'an, 21:81</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0055</id>
    <name>Kird Ape</name>
    <text>Kird Ape gets +1/+2 as long as you control a Forest.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0056</id>
    <name>Library of Alexandria</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Draw a card. Activate this ability only if you have exactly seven cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0057</id>
    <name>Magnetic Mountain</name>
    <text>Blue creatures don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.
At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player may choose any number of tapped blue creatures he or she controls and pay {4} for each creature chosen this way. If the player does, untap those creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0058</id>
    <name>Merchant Ship</name>
    <text>Merchant Ship can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.
Whenever Merchant Ship attacks and isn't blocked, you gain 2 life.
When you control no Islands, sacrifice Merchant Ship.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0059</id>
    <name>Metamorphosis</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Metamorphosis, sacrifice a creature.
Add X mana of any one color to your mana pool, where X is one plus the sacrificed creature's converted mana cost. Spend this mana only to cast creature spells.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0060</id>
    <name>Mijae Djinn</name>
    <text>Whenever Mijae Djinn attacks, flip a coin. If you lose the flip, remove Mijae Djinn from combat and tap it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0061</id>
    <name>Moorish Cavalry</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>Members of the elite Moorish Cavalry are very particular about their mounts, choosing only those whose bloodlines have been pure for generations.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0062</id>
    <name>Moorish Cavalry</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>Members of the elite Moorish Cavalry are very particular about their mounts, choosing only those whose bloodlines have been pure for generations.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0063</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0064</id>
    <name>Nafs Asp</name>
    <text>Whenever Nafs Asp deals damage to a player, that player loses 1 life at the beginning of his or her next draw step unless he or she pays {1} before that draw step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0065</id>
    <name>Nafs Asp</name>
    <text>Whenever Nafs Asp deals damage to a player, that player loses 1 life at the beginning of his or her next draw step unless he or she pays {1} before that draw step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0066</id>
    <name>Oasis</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0067</id>
    <name>Old Man of the Sea</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Old Man of the Sea during your untap step.
{T}: Gain control of target creature with power less than or equal to Old Man of the Sea's power for as long as Old Man of the Sea remains tapped and that creature's power remains less than or equal to Old Man of the Sea's power.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0068</id>
    <name>Oubliette</name>
    <text>When Oubliette enters the battlefield, exile target creature and all Auras attached to it. Note the number and kind of counters that were on that creature.
When Oubliette leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to the battlefield under its owner's control tapped with the noted number and kind of counters on it. If you do, return the exiled Aura cards to the battlefield under their owner's control attached to that permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0069</id>
    <name>Oubliette</name>
    <text>When Oubliette enters the battlefield, exile target creature and all Auras attached to it. Note the number and kind of counters that were on that creature.
When Oubliette leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to the battlefield under its owner's control tapped with the noted number and kind of counters on it. If you do, return the exiled Aura cards to the battlefield under their owner's control attached to that permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0070</id>
    <name>Piety</name>
    <text>Blocking creatures get +0/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Whoever obeys God and His Prophet, fears God and does his duty to Him, will surely find success."The Qur'an, 24:52</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0071</id>
    <name>Piety</name>
    <text>Blocking creatures get +0/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Whoever obeys God and His Prophet, fears God and does his duty to Him, will surely find success."The Qur'an, 24:52</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0072</id>
    <name>Pyramids</name>
    <text>{2}: Choose one — Destroy target Aura attached to a land; or the next time target land would be destroyed this turn, remove all damage from it instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0073</id>
    <name>Repentant Blacksmith</name>
    <text>Protection from red</text>
    <flavorText>"For my confession they burned me with fire And found that I was for endurance made."The Arabian Nights, trans. Haddawy</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0074</id>
    <name>Ring of Ma'rûf</name>
    <text>{5}, {T}, Exile Ring of Ma'rûf: The next time you would draw a card this turn, instead choose a card you own from outside the game and put it into your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0075</id>
    <name>Rukh Egg</name>
    <text>When Rukh Egg is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a 4/4 red Bird creature token with flying onto the battlefield at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0076</id>
    <name>Rukh Egg</name>
    <text>When Rukh Egg is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a 4/4 red Bird creature token with flying onto the battlefield at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0077</id>
    <name>Sandals of Abdallah</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target creature gains islandwalk until end of turn. When that creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield this turn, destroy Sandals of Abdallah.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0078</id>
    <name>Sandstorm</name>
    <text>Sandstorm deals 1 damage to each attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Even the landscape turned against Sarsour, first rising up and pelting him, then rearranging itself so he could no longer find his way.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0079</id>
    <name>Serendib Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice a land. If you sacrifice an Island this way, Serendib Djinn deals 3 damage to you.
When you control no lands, sacrifice Serendib Djinn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0080</id>
    <name>Serendib Efreet</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, Serendib Efreet deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0081</id>
    <name>Shahrazad</name>
    <text>Players play a MAGIC subgame, using their libraries as their decks. Each player who doesn't win the subgame loses half his or her life, rounded up.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0082</id>
    <name>Sindbad</name>
    <text>{T}: Draw a card and reveal it. If it isn't a land card, discard it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0083</id>
    <name>Singing Tree</name>
    <text>{T}: Target attacking creature's power becomes 0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0084</id>
    <name>Sorceress Queen</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature other than Sorceress Queen becomes 0/2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0085</id>
    <name>Stone-Throwing Devils</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes those with the most sin cast the first stones.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0086</id>
    <name>Stone-Throwing Devils</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes those with the most sin cast the first stones.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0087</id>
    <name>Unstable Mutation</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, put a -1/-1 counter on that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0088</id>
    <name>War Elephant</name>
    <text>Trample; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"When elephants fight it is the grass that suffers."Kikuyu Proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0089</id>
    <name>War Elephant</name>
    <text>Trample; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"When elephants fight it is the grass that suffers."Kikuyu Proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0090</id>
    <name>Wyluli Wolf</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"When one wolf calls, others follow. Who wants to fight creatures that eat scorpions?"Maimun al-Wyluli, Diary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0091</id>
    <name>Wyluli Wolf</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"When one wolf calls, others follow. Who wants to fight creatures that eat scorpions?"Maimun al-Wyluli, Diary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ARN0092</id>
    <name>Ydwen Efreet</name>
    <text>Whenever Ydwen Efreet blocks, flip a coin. If you lose the flip, remove Ydwen Efreet from combat and it can't block this turn. Creatures it was blocking that had become blocked by only Ydwen Efreet this combat become unblocked.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>