<cards name="Beatdown Box Set">
  <item>
    <id>BTD0001</id>
    <name>Air Elemental</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>As insubstantial, and as powerful, as the wind that carries it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0002</id>
    <name>Balduvian Horde</name>
    <text>When Balduvian Horde enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you discard a card at random.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0003</id>
    <name>Ball Lightning</name>
    <text>Trample (If this creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)
Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)
At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice Ball Lightning.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0004</id>
    <name>Blizzard Elemental</name>
    <text>Flying
{3}{U}: Untap Blizzard Elemental.</text>
    <flavorText>Students who had seen Rayne argue with Urza were certain she had summoned it to make him seem warmer by comparison.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0005</id>
    <name>Bloodrock Cyclops</name>
    <text>Bloodrock Cyclops attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>"He's big an' dumb an' ready to fight. A lot like ol' Hornhead here."
—Squee, goblin cabin hand,
scouting report</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0006</id>
    <name>Bone Harvest</name>
    <text>Put any number of target creature cards from your graveyard on top of your library.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"Only fools believe they will face my armies but once."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0007</id>
    <name>Brainstorm</name>
    <text>Draw three cards, then put two cards from your hand on top of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"I reeled from the blow, and then suddenly, I knew exactly what to do. Within moments victory was mine."
—Gustha Ebbasdotter
Kjeldoran royal mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0008</id>
    <name>Clockwork Avian</name>
    <text>Flying
Clockwork Avian enters the battlefield with four +1/+0 counters on it.
At end of combat, if Clockwork Avian attacked or blocked this combat, remove a +1/+0 counter from it.
{X}, {T}: Put up to X +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Avian. This ability can't cause the total number of +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Avian to be greater than four. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0009</id>
    <name>Clockwork Beast</name>
    <text>Clockwork Beast enters the battlefield with seven +1/+0 counters on it.
At end of combat, if Clockwork Beast attacked or blocked this combat, remove a +1/+0 counter from it.
{X}, {T}: Put up to X +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Beast. This ability can't cause the total number of +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Beast to be greater than seven. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0010</id>
    <name>Cloud Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying
Cloud Djinn can block only creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>As elusive as the footprint of a djinn
—Suq'Ata expression</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0011</id>
    <name>Cloud Elemental</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Cloud Elemental can block only creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"You know you've angered the gods when the clouds turn against you."
—Sisay, Captain of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0012</id>
    <name>Coercion</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You choose a card from it. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>"There's very little that escapes me, Greven. And you will escape very little if you fail."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0013</id>
    <name>Counterspell</name>
    <text>Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0014</id>
    <name>Crash of Rhinos</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>Love is like a rhino, short-sighted and hasty; if it cannot find a way, it will make a way.
—Femeref adage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0015</id>
    <name>Crashing Boars</name>
    <text>Whenever Crashing Boars attacks, defending player chooses an untapped creature he or she controls. That creature blocks Crashing Boars this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>Bores ruin a party. Boars are party to ruin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0016</id>
    <name>Dark Ritual</name>
    <text>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0017</id>
    <name>Deadly Insect</name>
    <text>Shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>With his newfound sense of self-importance, Squee set his sights on ever-bigger bugs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0018</id>
    <name>Death Stroke</name>
    <text>Destroy target tapped creature.</text>
    <flavorText>For a sharp second, Selenia froze, and Crovax's blade found home, As the angel shattered like glass, Crovax felt his mind collapse—the curse had been fulfilled.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0019</id>
    <name>Diabolic Edict</name>
    <text>Target player sacrifices a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Greven il-Vec lifted Vhati off his feet. "The fall will give you time to think on your failure."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0020</id>
    <name>Diabolic Vision</name>
    <text>Look at the top five cards of your library. Put one of them into your hand and the rest on top of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have seen the true path. I will not warm myself by the fire—I will become the flame."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0021</id>
    <name>Drain Life</name>
    <text>Spend only black mana on X.
Drain Life deals X damage to target creature or player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt, but not more life than the player's life total before Drain Life dealt damage or the creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0022</id>
    <name>Dwarven Ruins</name>
    <text>Dwarven Ruins enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Dwarven Ruins: Add {R}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0023</id>
    <name>Ebon Stronghold</name>
    <text>Ebon Stronghold enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Ebon Stronghold: Add {B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0024</id>
    <name>Erhnam Djinn</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, target non-Wall creature an opponent controls gains forestwalk until your next upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0025</id>
    <name>Fallen Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
Sacrifice a creature: Fallen Angel gets +2/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Angels are simply extensions of truth upon the fabric of life—and there is far more dark than light."Baron Sengir</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0026</id>
    <name>Feral Shadow</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"The nightstalkers are such a minor power in Urborg. Their sad eagerness to elevate themselves makes them willing tools in the plundering of little Femeref."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0027</id>
    <name>Fireball</name>
    <text>Fireball deals X damage divided evenly, rounded down, among any number of target creatures and/or players.
Fireball costs {1} more to cast for each target beyond the first.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0028</id>
    <name>Fog</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0029</id>
    <name>Fog Elemental</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
When Fog Elemental attacks or blocks, sacrifice it at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"I've seen fog so thick you could cut it, but none that could cut me."
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0030</id>
    <name>Force of Nature</name>
    <text>Trample (If this creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, Force of Nature deals 8 damage to you unless you pay {G}{G}{G}{G}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0031</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0032</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0033</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0034</id>
    <name>Gaseous Form</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's hard to hurt anyone when you're as transparent as your motives."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0035</id>
    <name>Giant Crab</name>
    <text>{U}: Giant Crab gains shroud until end of turn. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>During the giant crabs' mating season, Skyshroud nights are filled with the clatter of their skirmishes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0036</id>
    <name>Giant Growth</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0037</id>
    <name>Gravedigger</name>
    <text>When Gravedigger enters the battlefield, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>A full coffin is like a full coffer—both are attractive to thieves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0038</id>
    <name>Havenwood Battleground</name>
    <text>Havenwood Battleground enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Havenwood Battleground: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0039</id>
    <name>Hollow Dogs</name>
    <text>Whenever Hollow Dogs attacks, it gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A hollow dog is never empty. It is filled with thirst for the hunt.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0040</id>
    <name>Hulking Cyclops</name>
    <text>Hulking Cyclops can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>Anyone can get around a cyclops, but few can stand in its way.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0041</id>
    <name>Impulse</name>
    <text>Look at the top four cards of your library. Put one of them into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Controlling time ensures you need never look impulsive again."
—Teferi</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0042</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0043</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0044</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0045</id>
    <name>Killer Whale</name>
    <text>{U}: Killer Whale gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Hunger is like the sea: deep, endless, and unforgiving.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0046</id>
    <name>Kird Ape</name>
    <text>Kird Ape gets +1/+2 as long as you control a Forest.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0047</id>
    <name>Lava Axe</name>
    <text>Lava Axe deals 5 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Catch"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0048</id>
    <name>Leviathan</name>
    <text>Trample
Leviathan enters the battlefield tapped and doesn't untap during your untap step.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may sacrifice two Islands. If you do, untap Leviathan.
Leviathan can't attack unless you sacrifice two Islands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0049</id>
    <name>Lightning Bolt</name>
    <text>Lightning Bolt deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0050</id>
    <name>Llanowar Elves</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>One bone broken for every twig snapped underfoot.
—Llanowar penalty for trespassing</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0051</id>
    <name>Lowland Giant</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Faugh" snorted Tahngarth. "Why would it make a meal of something like you?" Squee looked relieved. "No," he continued, "you'd make a much better toothpick."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0052</id>
    <name>Mahamoti Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Of royal blood among the spirits of the air, the Mahamoti djinn rides on the wings of the winds. As dangerous in the gambling hall as he is in battle, he is a master of trickery and misdirection.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0053</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0054</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0055</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0056</id>
    <name>Plated Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>Most spiders wait patiently for their prey to arrive. Most spiders aren't forty feet tall.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0057</id>
    <name>Polluted Mire</name>
    <text>Polluted Mire enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0058</id>
    <name>Power Sink</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}. If he or she doesn't, that player taps all lands with mana abilities he or she controls and empties his or her mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0059</id>
    <name>Quirion Elves</name>
    <text>As Quirion Elves enters the battlefield, choose a color.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add one mana of the chosen color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0060</id>
    <name>Raging Goblin</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)</text>
    <flavorText>He raged at the world, at his family, at his life. But mostly he just raged.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0061</id>
    <name>Rampant Growth</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Rath forces plants from its surface as one presses whey from cheese.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0062</id>
    <name>Remote Isle</name>
    <text>Remote Isle enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0063</id>
    <name>Scaled Wurm</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Flourishing during the Ice Age, these wurms were the bane of all Kjeldorans. Their great size and ferocity made them the subject of countless nightmares—they embodied the worst of the Ice Age."
—Kjeldor: Ice Civilization</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0064</id>
    <name>Segmented Wurm</name>
    <text>Whenever Segmented Wurm becomes the target of a spell or ability, put a -1/-1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"If only we could so easily leave behind those parts of ourselves that pain us."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0065</id>
    <name>Sengir Vampire</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Whenever a creature dealt damage by Sengir Vampire this turn is put into a graveyard, put a +1/+1 counter on Sengir Vampire.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0066</id>
    <name>Shambling Strider</name>
    <text>{R}{G}: Shambling Strider gets +1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Freyalise forbid that any stranger should wander into the striders' territory.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0067</id>
    <name>Shivan Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}: Shivan Dragon gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>While it's true most dragons are cruel, the Shivan dragon seems to take particular glee in the misery of others, often tormenting its victims much like a cat plays with a mouse before delivering the final blow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0068</id>
    <name>Shock</name>
    <text>Shock deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Lightning tethers souls to the world.
—Kor saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0069</id>
    <name>Skittering Horror</name>
    <text>When you cast a creature spell, sacrifice Skittering Horror.</text>
    <flavorText>"This monstrosity will do—for now."
—Davvol, Evincar of Rath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0070</id>
    <name>Skittering Skirge</name>
    <text>Flying
When you cast a creature spell, sacrifice Skittering Skirge.</text>
    <flavorText>The imps' warbling cries echo through Phyrexia's towers like those of mourning doves in a cathedral.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0071</id>
    <name>Slippery Karst</name>
    <text>Slippery Karst enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0072</id>
    <name>Smoldering Crater</name>
    <text>Smoldering Crater enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0073</id>
    <name>Snapping Drake</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Drakes claim to be dragons—until the dragons show up.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0074</id>
    <name>Sonic Burst</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Sonic Burst, discard a card at random.
Sonic Burst deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Music scythes the savage beast.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0075</id>
    <name>Svyelunite Temple</name>
    <text>Svyelunite Temple enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Svyelunite Temple: Add {U}{U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0076</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0077</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0078</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0079</id>
    <name>Talruum Minotaur</name>
    <text>Haste</text>
    <flavorText>Don't insult a Talruum unless your mount is swift.
—Suq'Ata saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0080</id>
    <name>Tar Pit Warrior</name>
    <text>When Tar Pit Warrior becomes the target of a spell or ability, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>"The cyclops shrugged off savage blows, but casual insults made him weep."
—Azeworai, "The Cyclops who Couldn't"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0081</id>
    <name>Terror</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonartifact, nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0082</id>
    <name>Thunderbolt</name>
    <text>Choose one — Thunderbolt deals 3 damage to target player; or Thunderbolt deals 4 damage to target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Most wizards consider a thunderbolt to be a proper retort."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0083</id>
    <name>Thundering Giant</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)</text>
    <flavorText>The giant was felt a few seconds before he was seen.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0084</id>
    <name>Tolarian Winds</name>
    <text>Discard all the cards in your hand, then draw that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Afterward, Tolaria's winds were like the whispers of lost wizards, calling for life.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0085</id>
    <name>Viashino Warrior</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"When traveling the Great Desert avoid wearing the scales of lizards, for the Viashino rule the sands and look poorly on the skinning of their cousins."
—Zhalfirin Guide to the Desert</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0086</id>
    <name>Vigilant Drake</name>
    <text>Flying

{2}{U}: Untap Vigilant Drake.</text>
    <flavorText>Awake and awing in the blink of an eye.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0087</id>
    <name>Wayward Soul</name>
    <text>Flying

{U}: Put Wayward Soul on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"no home    no heart    no hope"
—Stronghold graffito</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0088</id>
    <name>Wild Growth</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds {G} to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0089</id>
    <name>Woolly Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)
Whenever Woolly Spider blocks a creature with flying, Woolly Spider gets +0/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We need not fear the forces of the air; I've yet to see a spider without an appetite."
—Taaveti of Kelsinko, elvish hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>BTD0090</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Wurm</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>When the gorilla playfully grabbed the wurm's tail, the wurm doubled back and playfully ate the gorilla's head.</flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>