<cards name="The Dark">
  <item>
    <id>DRK0001</id>
    <name>Amnesia</name>
    <text>Target player reveals his or her hand and discards all nonland cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"When one has witnessed the unspeakable, 'tis sometimes better to forget."Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0002</id>
    <name>Angry Mob</name>
    <text>Trample
As long as it's your turn, Angry Mob's power and toughness are each equal to 2 plus the number of Swamps your opponents control. As long as it's not your turn, Angry Mob's power and toughness are each 2.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0003</id>
    <name>Apprentice Wizard</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}: Add {3} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0004</id>
    <name>Ashes to Ashes</name>
    <text>Exile two target nonartifact creatures. Ashes to Ashes deals 5 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"All rivers eventually run to the sea. My job is to sort out who goes first."
—Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0005</id>
    <name>Ball Lightning</name>
    <text>Trample (If this creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)
Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)
At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice Ball Lightning.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0006</id>
    <name>Banshee</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: Banshee deals half X damage, rounded down, to target creature or player, and half X damage, rounded up, to you.</text>
    <flavorText>Some say Banshees are the hounds of Death, baying to herd their prey into the arms of their master.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0007</id>
    <name>Barl's Cage</name>
    <text>{3}: Target creature doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>For a dozen years the Cage had held Lord Ith, but as the Pretender Mairsil's power weakened, so did the bars.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0008</id>
    <name>Blood Moon</name>
    <text>Nonbasic lands are Mountains.</text>
    <flavorText>Heavy light flooded across the landscape, cloaking everything in deep crimson.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0009</id>
    <name>Blood of the Martyr</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, if damage would be dealt to any creature, you may have that damage dealt to you instead.</text>
    <flavorText>The willow knows what the storm does not: that the power to endure harm outlives the power to inflict it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0010</id>
    <name>Bog Imp</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>On guard for larger dangers, we underestimated the power and speed of the Imp's muck-crusted claws.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0011</id>
    <name>Bog Rats</name>
    <text>Bog Rats can't be blocked by Walls.</text>
    <flavorText>Their stench was vile and strong enough, but not nearly as powerful as their hunger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0012</id>
    <name>Bone Flute</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: All creatures get -1/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>After the Battle of Pitdown, Lady Ursnell fashioned the first such instrument out of Lord Ursnell's left leg.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0013</id>
    <name>Book of Rass</name>
    <text>{2}, Pay 2 life: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0014</id>
    <name>Brainwash</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack unless its controller pays {3}.</text>
    <flavorText>"They're not your friends; they despise you. I'm the only one you can count on. Trust me."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0015</id>
    <name>Brothers of Fire</name>
    <text>{1}{R}{R}: Brothers of Fire deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>Fire is never a gentle master.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0016</id>
    <name>Carnivorous Plant</name>
    <text>Defender</text>
    <flavorText>"It had a mouth like that of a great beast, and gnashed its teeth as it strained to reach us. I am thankful it possessed no means of locomotion."Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0017</id>
    <name>Cave People</name>
    <text>Whenever Cave People attacks, it gets +1/-2 until end of turn.
{1}{R}{R}, {T}: Target creature gains mountainwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0018</id>
    <name>City of Shadows</name>
    <text>{T}, Exile a creature you control: Put a storage counter on City of Shadows.
{T}: Add {X} to your mana pool, where X is the number of storage counters on City of Shadows.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0019</id>
    <name>Cleansing</name>
    <text>For each land, destroy that land unless any player pays 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0020</id>
    <name>Coal Golem</name>
    <text>{3}, Sacrifice Coal Golem: Add {R}{R}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Three such creatures stood burning at the crest of the hill. Only seconds later, the Fireball struck our front line."Lydia, Countess Brellis</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0021</id>
    <name>Curse Artifact</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted artifact's controller, Curse Artifact deals 2 damage to that player unless he or she sacrifices that artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>Voska feared the artifact had come too easily.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0022</id>
    <name>Dance of Many</name>
    <text>When Dance of Many enters the battlefield, put a token that's a copy of target nontoken creature onto the battlefield.
When Dance of Many leaves the battlefield, exile the token.
When the token leaves the battlefield, sacrifice Dance of Many.
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Dance of Many unless you pay {U}{U}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0023</id>
    <name>Dark Heart of the Wood</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a Forest: You gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Even the Goblins shun this haunted place, where the tree limbs twist in agony and the ground seems to scuttle under your feet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0024</id>
    <name>Dark Sphere</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Dark Sphere: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, it deals half that damage, rounded up, to you instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"I was struck senseless for a moment, but revived when the strange curiosity I carried fell to the ground, screaming like a dying animal."Barl, Lord Ith</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0025</id>
    <name>Deep Water</name>
    <text>{U}: Until end of turn, if you tap a land you control for mana, it produces {U} instead of any other type.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0026</id>
    <name>Diabolic Machine</name>
    <text>{3}: Regenerate Diabolic Machine.</text>
    <flavorText>"The bolts of our ballistae smashed into the monstrous thing, but our hopes died in our chests as its gears continued turning."Sevti Mukul, The Fall of Alsoor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0027</id>
    <name>Drowned</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Drowned.</text>
    <flavorText>We asked Captain Soll what became of the Serafina, but all he said was, "Ships that go down shouldn't come back up."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0028</id>
    <name>Dust to Dust</name>
    <text>Exile two target artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>Tervish never noticed that the amulet had vanished. It had disappeared not only from his possession, but from his memory as well.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0029</id>
    <name>Eater of the Dead</name>
    <text>{0}: If Eater of the Dead is tapped, exile target creature card from a graveyard and untap Eater of the Dead.</text>
    <flavorText>Even the putrid muscles of the dead can provide strength to those loathsome enough to consume them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0030</id>
    <name>Electric Eel</name>
    <text>When Electric Eel enters the battlefield, it deals 1 damage to you.
{R}{R}: Electric Eel gets +2/+0 until end of turn and deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0031</id>
    <name>Elves of Deep Shadow</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool. Elves of Deep Shadow deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"They are aberrations who have turned on everything we hold sacred. Let them be cast out."Ailheen, Speaker of the Council</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0032</id>
    <name>Erosion</name>
    <text>Enchant land
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted land's controller, destroy that land unless that player pays {1} or 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0033</id>
    <name>Eternal Flame</name>
    <text>Eternal Flame deals X damage to target opponent, where X is the number of Mountains you control. It deals half X damage, rounded up, to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0034</id>
    <name>Exorcist</name>
    <text>{1}{W}, {T}: Destroy target black creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Though they often bore little greater charm than the demons they battled, exorcists were always welcome in Scarwood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0035</id>
    <name>Fasting</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a hunger counter on Fasting. Then destroy Fasting if it has five or more hunger counters on it.
If you would begin your draw step, you may skip that step instead. If you do, you gain 2 life.
When you draw a card, destroy Fasting.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0036</id>
    <name>Fellwar Stone</name>
    <text>{T}: Add to your mana pool one mana of any color that a land an opponent controls could produce.</text>
    <flavorText>"What do you have that I cannot obtain?"
—Mairsil, called the Pretender</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0037</id>
    <name>Festival</name>
    <text>Cast Festival only during an opponent's upkeep.
Creatures can't attack this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Only after the townsfolk had drawn us into their merry celebration did we discover that their holiday rituals held a deeper purpose.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0038</id>
    <name>Fire and Brimstone</name>
    <text>Fire and Brimstone deals 4 damage to target player who declared an attacking creature this turn and 4 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0039</id>
    <name>Fire Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}: Fire Drake gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0040</id>
    <name>Fissure</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature or land. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Must not all things at the last be swallowed up in death?"Plato</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0041</id>
    <name>Flood</name>
    <text>{U}{U}: Tap target creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"A dash of cool water does wonders to clear a cluttered battlefield."
—Vibekke Ragnild, Witches and War</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0042</id>
    <name>Fountain of Youth</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The Fountain had stood in the town square for centuries, but only the pigeons knew its secret.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0043</id>
    <name>Frankenstein's Monster</name>
    <text>As Frankenstein's Monster enters the battlefield, exile X creature cards from your graveyard. If you can't, put Frankenstein's Monster into its owner's graveyard instead of onto the battlefield. For each creature card exiled this way, Frankenstein's Monster enters the battlefield with a +2/+0, +1/+1, or +0/+2 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0044</id>
    <name>Gaea's Touch</name>
    <text>You may play an additional land during your turn if that land is a basic Forest.

Sacrifice Gaea's Touch: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0045</id>
    <name>Ghost Ship</name>
    <text>Flying
{U}{U}{U}: Regenerate Ghost Ship.</text>
    <flavorText>"That phantom prow split the storm as lightning cast its long shadow on the battlefield below."Mireille Gaetane, The Valeriad</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0046</id>
    <name>Giant Shark</name>
    <text>Giant Shark can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.
Whenever Giant Shark blocks or becomes blocked by a creature that has been dealt damage this turn, Giant Shark gets +2/+0 and gains trample until end of turn.
When you control no Islands, sacrifice Giant Shark.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0047</id>
    <name>Goblin Caves</name>
    <text>Enchant land
If enchanted land is a basic Mountain, Goblin creatures get +0/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>The stench of countless generations of unspeakable activities was enough to loosen both our footing and our stomachs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0048</id>
    <name>Goblin Digging Team</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Goblin Digging Team: Destroy target Wall.</text>
    <flavorText>"From down here we can make the whole wall collapse" "Uh, yeah, boss, but how do we get out?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0049</id>
    <name>Goblin Hero</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>They attack in an orgy of rage and madness, but only one seemed as focused on killing us as the sheer joy of battle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0050</id>
    <name>Goblin Rock Sled</name>
    <text>Trample
Goblin Rock Sled doesn't untap during your untap step if it attacked during your last turn.
Goblin Rock Sled can't attack unless defending player controls a Mountain.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0051</id>
    <name>Goblin Shrine</name>
    <text>Enchant land
If enchanted land is a Mountain, Goblin creatures get +1/+0.
When Goblin Shrine leaves the battlefield, it deals 1 damage to each Goblin creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"I knew it weren't no ordinary pile of—you know."Norin the Wary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0052</id>
    <name>Goblin Wizard</name>
    <text>{T}: You may put a Goblin permanent card from your hand onto the battlefield.
{R}: Target Goblin gains protection from white until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0053</id>
    <name>Goblins of the Flarg</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk
When you control a Dwarf, sacrifice Goblins of the Flarg.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0054</id>
    <name>Grave Robbers</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}: Exile target artifact card from a graveyard. You gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you don't have your health, you don't have anything."Proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0055</id>
    <name>Hidden Path</name>
    <text>Green creatures have forestwalk.</text>
    <flavorText>"Where moments before we were lost beyond hope, the strange, floating lights showed us the way and restored our morale."Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0056</id>
    <name>Holy Light</name>
    <text>Nonwhite creatures get -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Bathed in hallowed light, the infidels looked upon the impurities of their souls and despaired."The Book of Tal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0057</id>
    <name>Inferno</name>
    <text>Inferno deals 6 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Any scrap of compassion that still existed in my soul was permanently snuffed out when they cast me out into the flames."Mairsil, called the Pretender</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0058</id>
    <name>Inquisition</name>
    <text>Target player reveals his or her hand. Inquisition deals damage to that player equal to the number of white cards in his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Many of those entrusted to Primata Delphine's care tended to express themselves with screams.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0059</id>
    <name>Knights of Thorn</name>
    <text>Protection from red; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"With a great cry, the Goblin host broke and ran as the first wave of Knights penetrated its ranks."Tivadar of Thorn, History of the Goblin Wars</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0060</id>
    <name>Land Leeches</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>"The standard cure for leeches requires the application of burning embers. Alternative methods must be devised should an ember of sufficient size prove more harmful than the leech."Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0061</id>
    <name>Leviathan</name>
    <text>Trample
Leviathan enters the battlefield tapped and doesn't untap during your untap step.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may sacrifice two Islands. If you do, untap Leviathan.
Leviathan can't attack unless you sacrifice two Islands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0062</id>
    <name>Living Armor</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Living Armor: Put X +0/+1 counters on target creature, where X is that creature's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>Though it affords excellent protection, few don this armor. The process is uncomfortable and not easily reversed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0063</id>
    <name>Lurker</name>
    <text>Lurker can't be the target of spells unless it attacked or blocked this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Each night we felt it watching us from the darkness beyond our fire. We only had one pack horse left."
—Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0064</id>
    <name>Mana Clash</name>
    <text>You and target opponent each flip a coin. Mana Clash deals 1 damage to each player whose coin comes up tails. Repeat this process until both players' coins come up heads on the same flip.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0065</id>
    <name>Mana Vortex</name>
    <text>When you cast Mana Vortex, you may sacrifice a land. If you don't, counter Mana Vortex.
At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player sacrifices a land.
When there are no lands on the battlefield, sacrifice Mana Vortex.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0066</id>
    <name>Marsh Gas</name>
    <text>All creatures get -2/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Comes right outta th' ground. If ya can smell it, it's too late."Keevy Bogsbury</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0067</id>
    <name>Marsh Goblins</name>
    <text>Swampwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Even the other Goblin races shun the Marsh Goblins, thanks to certain unwholesome customs they practice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0068</id>
    <name>Marsh Viper</name>
    <text>Whenever Marsh Viper deals damage to an opponent, that player gets two poison counters. (A player with ten or more poison counters loses the game.)</text>
    <flavorText>"All we had left were their black and bloated bodies."Maeveen
O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0069</id>
    <name>Martyr's Cry</name>
    <text>Exile all white creatures. For each creature exiled this way, its controller draws a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is only fitting that one such as I should die in pursuit of knowledge."Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0070</id>
    <name>Maze of Ith</name>
    <text>{T}: Untap target attacking creature. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by that creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0071</id>
    <name>Merfolk Assassin</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target creature with islandwalk.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0072</id>
    <name>Mind Bomb</name>
    <text>Each player may discard up to three cards. Mind Bomb deals damage to each player equal to 3 minus the number of cards he or she discarded this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0073</id>
    <name>Miracle Worker</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target Aura attached to a creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those blessed hands could bring surcease to even the most tainted soul."Sister Betje, Miracles of the Saints</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0074</id>
    <name>Morale</name>
    <text>Attacking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"After Lacjsi's speech, the Knights grew determined to crush their ancient enemies clan by clan."Tivadar of Thorn, History of the Goblin Wars</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0075</id>
    <name>Murk Dwellers</name>
    <text>Whenever Murk Dwellers attacks and isn't blocked, it gets +2/+0 until end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>When Raganorn unsealed the catacombs, he found more than the dead and their treasures.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0076</id>
    <name>Nameless Race</name>
    <text>Trample
As Nameless Race enters the battlefield, pay any amount of life. The amount you pay can't be more than the total number of white nontoken permanents your opponents control plus the total number of white cards in their graveyards.
Nameless Race's power and toughness are each equal to the life paid as it entered the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0077</id>
    <name>Necropolis</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Exile a creature card from your graveyard: Put X +0/+1 counters on Necropolis, where X is the exiled card's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0078</id>
    <name>Niall Silvain</name>
    <text>{G}{G}{G}{G}, {T}: Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>This is his domain, and while you remain here you must value all life as you value your own.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0079</id>
    <name>Orc General</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice another Orc or Goblin: Other Orc creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your army must fear you more than the enemy. Only then will you triumph."Malga Phlegmtooth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0080</id>
    <name>People of the Woods</name>
    <text>People of the Woods's toughness is equal to the number of Forests you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Their rain of arrows left only myself alive, cowering within a tree hollow. They did not even come out to loot the bodies."Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0081</id>
    <name>Pikemen</name>
    <text>First strike; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"As the cavalry bore down, we faced them with swords drawn and pikes hidden in the grass at our feet. ‘Don't lift your pikes 'til I give the word,' I said."Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0082</id>
    <name>Preacher</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Preacher during your untap step.
{T}: Gain control of target creature of an opponent's choice that he or she controls for as long as Preacher remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0083</id>
    <name>Psychic Allergy</name>
    <text>As Psychic Allergy enters the battlefield, choose a color.
At the beginning of each opponent's upkeep, Psychic Allergy deals X damage to that player, where X is the number of nontoken permanents of the chosen color he or she controls.
At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy Psychic Allergy unless you sacrifice two Islands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0084</id>
    <name>Rag Man</name>
    <text>{B}{B}{B}, {T}: Target opponent reveals his or her hand and discards a creature card at random. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Aw, he's just a silly, dirty little man. What's to be afraid of?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0085</id>
    <name>Reflecting Mirror</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: Change the target of target spell with a single target if that target is you. The new target must be a player. X is twice the converted mana cost of that spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0086</id>
    <name>Riptide</name>
    <text>Tap all blue creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0087</id>
    <name>Runesword</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target attacking creature gets +2/+0 until end of turn. When that creature leaves the battlefield this turn, sacrifice Runesword. If the creature deals damage to a creature this turn, the creature dealt damage can't be regenerated this turn. If a creature dealt damage by the targeted creature would be put into a graveyard this turn, exile that creature instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0088</id>
    <name>Safe Haven</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Exile target creature you control.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may sacrifice Safe Haven. If you do, return each card exiled with Safe Haven to the battlefield under its owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0089</id>
    <name>Savaen Elves</name>
    <text>{G}{G}, {T}: Destroy target Aura attached to a land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Purity of magic can only come from purity of the land. How can a meal nourish if the ingredients are spoiled?Sidaine of Savaen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0090</id>
    <name>Scarecrow</name>
    <text>{6}, {T}: Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you this turn by creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>There was more malice in its button eyes than should have been possible in something that had never known life.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0091</id>
    <name>Scarwood Bandits</name>
    <text>Forestwalk
{2}{G}, {T}: Unless target artifact's controller pays {2}, gain control of that artifact for as long as Scarwood Bandits remains on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0092</id>
    <name>Scarwood Goblins</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Larger and more cunning than most Goblins, Scarwood Goblins are thankfully found only in isolated pockets.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0093</id>
    <name>Scarwood Hag</name>
    <text>{G}{G}{G}{G}, {T}: Target creature gains forestwalk until end of turn.
{T}: Target creature loses forestwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0094</id>
    <name>Scavenger Folk</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}, Sacrifice Scavenger Folk: Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>String, weapons, wax, or jewels—it makes no difference. Leave nothing unguarded in Scarwood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0095</id>
    <name>Season of the Witch</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Season of the Witch unless you pay 2 life.
At the beginning of the end step, destroy all untapped creatures that didn't attack this turn, except for creatures that couldn't attack.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0096</id>
    <name>Sisters of the Flame</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>We are many wicks sharing a common tallow; we feed the skies with the ashes of our prey.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0097</id>
    <name>Skull of Orm</name>
    <text>{5}, {T}: Return target enchantment card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Though lifeless, the Skull still possessed a strange power over the flow of magic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0098</id>
    <name>Sorrow's Path</name>
    <text>{T}: Choose two target blocking creatures an opponent controls. If each of those creatures could block all creatures that the other is blocking, remove both of them from combat. Each one then blocks all creatures the other was blocking.
Whenever Sorrow's Path becomes tapped, it deals 2 damage to you and each creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0099</id>
    <name>Spitting Slug</name>
    <text>Whenever Spitting Slug blocks or becomes blocked, you may pay {1}{G}. If you do, Spitting Slug gains first strike until end of turn. Otherwise, each creature blocking or blocked by Spitting Slug gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0100</id>
    <name>Squire</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Of twenty yeer of age he was, I gesse. Of his stature he was of even lengthe. And wonderly deliver, and greete of strengthe."Geoffrey Chaucer, The Canterbury Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0101</id>
    <name>Standing Stones</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Pay 1 life: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0102</id>
    <name>Stone Calendar</name>
    <text>Spells you cast cost up to {1} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>The Pretender Mairsil ordered a great Calendar drawn up to show when the paths to the Dark Lands were strongest.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0103</id>
    <name>Sunken City</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Sunken City unless you pay {U}{U}.
Blue creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0104</id>
    <name>Tangle Kelp</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Tangle Kelp enters the battlefield, tap enchanted creature.
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step if it attacked during its controller's last turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0105</id>
    <name>The Fallen</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, The Fallen deals 1 damage to each opponent it has dealt damage to this game.</text>
    <flavorText>Magic often masters those who cannot master it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0106</id>
    <name>Tivadar's Crusade</name>
    <text>Destroy all Goblins.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0107</id>
    <name>Tormod's Crypt</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Tormod's Crypt: Exile all cards from target player's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>The dark opening seemed to breathe the cold, damp air of the dead earth in a steady rhythm.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0108</id>
    <name>Tower of Coireall</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature can't be blocked by Walls this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0109</id>
    <name>Tracker</name>
    <text>{G}{G}, {T}: Tracker deals damage equal to its power to target creature. That creature deals damage equal to its power to Tracker.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0110</id>
    <name>Uncle Istvan</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt to Uncle Istvan by creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Solitude drove the old hermit insane. Now he only keeps company with those he can catch.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0111</id>
    <name>Venom</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature blocks or becomes blocked by a non-Wall creature, destroy the other creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"I told him it was just a flesh wound, a wee scratch, but the next time I looked at him, poor Tadhg was dead and gone."Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0112</id>
    <name>Wand of Ith</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target player reveals a card at random from his or her hand. If it's a land card, that player discards it unless he or she pays 1 life. If it isn't a land card, the player discards it unless he or she pays life equal to its converted mana cost. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0113</id>
    <name>War Barge</name>
    <text>{3}: Target creature gains islandwalk until end of turn. When War Barge leaves the battlefield this turn, destroy that creature. A creature destroyed this way can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0114</id>
    <name>Water Wurm</name>
    <text>Water Wurm gets +0/+1 as long as an opponent controls an Island.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0115</id>
    <name>Whippoorwill</name>
    <text>{G}{G}, {T}: Target creature can't be regenerated this turn. Damage that would be dealt to that creature this turn can't be prevented or dealt instead to another creature or player. When the creature is put into a graveyard this turn, exile the creature.</text>
    <flavorText>If the Whippoorwill remains silent, the soul has not reached its reward.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0116</id>
    <name>Witch Hunter</name>
    <text>{T}: Witch Hunter deals 1 damage to target player.
{1}{W}{W}, {T}: Return target creature an opponent controls to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0117</id>
    <name>Word of Binding</name>
    <text>Tap X target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"That was the worst experience of my days, standing there helpless as they killed my whole troop."Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0118</id>
    <name>Worms of the Earth</name>
    <text>Players can't play lands.
If a land would enter the battlefield, instead it doesn't.
At the beginning of each upkeep, any player may sacrifice two lands or pay 5 life. If a player does either, destroy Worms of the Earth.</text>
    <flavorText>The ground collapsed, leaving nothing but the great Worms' mucous residues.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DRK0119</id>
    <name>Wormwood Treefolk</name>
    <text>{G}{G}: Wormwood Treefolk gains forestwalk until end of turn and deals 2 damage to you.
{B}{B}: Wormwood Treefolk gains swampwalk until end of turn and deals 2 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>