<cards name="Ice Age">
  <item>
    <id>ICE0001</id>
    <name>Abyssal Specter</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Abyssal Specter deals damage to a player, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Open the gates, and bid them enter."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0002</id>
    <name>Adarkar Sentinel</name>
    <text>{1}: Adarkar Sentinel gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We encountered the Sentinels in the wastes, near no living thing. Their purpose was inscrutable."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0003</id>
    <name>Adarkar Unicorn</name>
    <text>{T}: Add either {U} or {1}{U} to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to pay cumulative upkeep costs.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is no nobler creature in all of Terisiare."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0004</id>
    <name>Adarkar Wastes</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool. Adarkar Wastes deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0005</id>
    <name>Aegis of the Meek</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Target 1/1 creature gets +1/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"With this marvel, even the weak have a fighting chance"
—Arcum Dagsson,
Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0006</id>
    <name>Aggression</name>
    <text>Enchant non-Wall creature
Enchanted creature has first strike and trample.
At the beginning of the end step of enchanted creature's controller, destroy that creature if it didn't attack this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The star that burns twice as bright burns half as long.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0007</id>
    <name>Altar of Bone</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Altar of Bone, sacrifice a creature.
Search your library for a creature card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0008</id>
    <name>Amulet of Quoz</name>
    <text>Remove Amulet of Quoz from your deck before playing if you're not playing for ante.
{T}, Sacrifice Amulet of Quoz: Target opponent may add the top card of his or her library to the ante. If he or she doesn't, you flip a coin. If you win the flip, that player loses the game. If you lose the flip, you lose the game. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0009</id>
    <name>Anarchy</name>
    <text>Destroy all white permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Shaman waved the staff, and the land itself went mad."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0010</id>
    <name>Arctic Foxes</name>
    <text>Creatures with power 2 or greater can't block Arctic Foxes as long as defending player controls a snow land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those Foxes are wily, swift, and ferocious. They are the warriors of the snows."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0011</id>
    <name>Arcum's Sleigh</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target creature gains vigilance until end of turn. Activate this ability only during combat and only if defending player controls a snow land.</text>
    <flavorText>"With the proper equipment and caution, one can travel anywhere."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0012</id>
    <name>Arcum's Weathervane</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target snow land is no longer snow.
{2}, {T}: Target nonsnow basic land becomes snow.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0013</id>
    <name>Arcum's Whistle</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Choose target non-Wall creature the active player has controlled continuously since the beginning of the turn. That player may pay {X}, where X is that creature's converted mana cost. If he or she doesn't, the creature attacks this turn if able, and at the beginning of the next end step, destroy it if it didn't attack. Activate this ability only before attackers are declared.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0014</id>
    <name>Arenson's Aura</name>
    <text>{W}, Sacrifice an enchantment: Destroy target enchantment.

{3}{U}{U}: Counter target enchantment spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have my faith, and I have my prayers. But if push comes to shove, I've also got a little something extra."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0015</id>
    <name>Armor of Faith</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1.
{W}: Enchanted creature gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Keep your chainmail, warrior. I have my own form of protection."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0016</id>
    <name>Arnjlot's Ascent</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
{1}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The dreams of a child fulfilled:
The wind on my brow,
the air 'neath my feet."
—Arnjlot Olasson, Sky Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0017</id>
    <name>Ashen Ghoul</name>
    <text>Haste
{B}: Return Ashen Ghoul from your graveyard to the battlefield. Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only if three or more creature cards are above Ashen Ghoul.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0018</id>
    <name>Aurochs</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Aurochs attacks, it gets +1/+0 until end of turn for each other attacking Aurochs.</text>
    <flavorText>One Auroch may feed a village, but a herd will flatten it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0019</id>
    <name>Avalanche</name>
    <text>Destroy X target snow lands.</text>
    <flavorText>"The pass was completely blocked by the avalanche; we're forced to turn back. Nevertheless, we've gone farther and seen more than any before us."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0020</id>
    <name>Balduvian Barbarians</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Barbarian raids were a concern to those living in the northwest provinces, but the Skyknights never dealt with the problem in a systematic way. They thought of the Balduvians as an ‘amusing model' of their forebears' culture."
—Kjeldor: Ice Civilization</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0021</id>
    <name>Balduvian Bears</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"They're a hardy bunch, but I'd still bet that they just slept through the worst of the cold times."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0022</id>
    <name>Balduvian Conjurer</name>
    <text>{T}: Target snow land becomes a 2/2 creature until end of turn. It's still a land.</text>
    <flavorText>"The very lands of Balduvia are alive."
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0023</id>
    <name>Balduvian Hydra</name>
    <text>Balduvian Hydra enters the battlefield with X +1/+0 counters on it.
Remove a +1/+0 counter from Balduvian Hydra: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to Balduvian Hydra this turn.
{R}{R}{R}: Put a +1/+0 counter on Balduvian Hydra. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0024</id>
    <name>Balduvian Shaman</name>
    <text>{T}: Change the text of target white enchantment you control that doesn't have cumulative upkeep by replacing all instances of one color word with another. (For example, you may change "counters black spells" to "counters blue spells.") That enchantment gains "Cumulative upkeep {1}." (At the beginning of its controller's upkeep, that player puts an age counter on it, then sacrifices it unless he or she pays its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0025</id>
    <name>Barbarian Guides</name>
    <text>{2}{R}, {T}: Choose a land type. Target creature you control gains snow landwalk of the chosen type until end of turn. Return that creature to its owner's hand at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0026</id>
    <name>Barbed Sextant</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Barbed Sextant: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0027</id>
    <name>Baton of Morale</name>
    <text>{2}: Target creature gains banding until end of turn. (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding a player controls are blocking or being blocked by a creature, that player divides that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The Goblins would kill to get ahold of this one."
—Arcum Dagsson,
Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0028</id>
    <name>Battle Cry</name>
    <text>Untap all white creatures you control.

Whenever a creature blocks this turn, it gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"In the thick of battle, you must keep your wits about you. Yelling a lot helps, too."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0029</id>
    <name>Battle Frenzy</name>
    <text>Green creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn.

Nongreen creatures you control get +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"One day you, too, shall drink the blood of your foes. It is something to look forward to."
—Toothlicker Harj, Orcish Captain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0030</id>
    <name>Binding Grasp</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Binding Grasp unless you pay {1}{U}.
You control enchanted creature.
Enchanted creature gets +0/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>"What I want, I take."
—Gustha Ebbasdotter,
Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0031</id>
    <name>Black Scarab</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't be blocked by black creatures.
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 as long as an opponent controls a black permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0032</id>
    <name>Blessed Wine</name>
    <text>You gain 1 life.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"May the bounty of Kjeld enrich your days."
—Halvor Arenson,
Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0033</id>
    <name>Blinking Spirit</name>
    <text>{0}: Return Blinking Spirit to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Don't look at it Maybe it'll go away"
—Ib Halfheart, Goblin Tactician</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0034</id>
    <name>Blizzard</name>
    <text>Cast Blizzard only if you control a snow land.
Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Creatures with flying don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0035</id>
    <name>Blue Scarab</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't be blocked by blue creatures.
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 as long as an opponent controls a blue permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0036</id>
    <name>Bone Shaman</name>
    <text>{B}: Until end of turn, Bone Shaman gains "Creatures dealt damage by Bone Shaman this turn can't be regenerated this turn."</text>
    <flavorText>Rattle me bones as I cross the floor
And the bones in your grave will rattle no more.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0037</id>
    <name>Brainstorm</name>
    <text>Draw three cards, then put two cards from your hand on top of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"I reeled from the blow, and then suddenly, I knew exactly what to do. Within moments, victory was mine."
—Gustha Ebbasdotter,
Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0038</id>
    <name>Brand of Ill Omen</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Cumulative upkeep {R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Enchanted creature's controller can't cast creature spells.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let those who bear the brand receive no shelter, no kindness, and no comfort from our people."
—Lovisa Coldeyes,
Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0039</id>
    <name>Breath of Dreams</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Green creatures have "Cumulative upkeep {1}."</text>
    <flavorText>"Get up, blast you They're attacking Why are you all so slow?"
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0040</id>
    <name>Brine Shaman</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a creature: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.
{1}{U}{U}, Sacrifice a creature: Counter target creature spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Shamans of Marit Lage do her bidding in secret, but they do it gladly."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0041</id>
    <name>Brown Ouphe</name>
    <text>{1}{G}, {T}: Counter target activated ability from an artifact source. (Mana abilities can't be targeted.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Ouphes love trinkets and love to take them apart. I only wish they wouldn't do so with the magical ones."
—Taaveti of Kelsinko, Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0042</id>
    <name>Brushland</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool. Brushland deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0043</id>
    <name>Burnt Offering</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Burnt Offering, sacrifice a creature.
Add X mana in any combination of {B} and/or {R} to your mana pool, where X is the sacrificed creature's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"My foes serve me twice: in dying, and in death."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0044</id>
    <name>Call to Arms</name>
    <text>As Call to Arms enters the battlefield, choose a color and an opponent.
White creatures get +1/+1 as long as the chosen color is the most common color among nontoken permanents the chosen player controls but isn't tied for most common.
When the chosen color isn't the most common color among nontoken permanents the chosen player controls or is tied for most common, sacrifice Call to Arms.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0045</id>
    <name>Caribou Range</name>
    <text>Enchant land you control
Enchanted land has "{W}{W}, {T}: Put a 0/1 white Caribou creature token onto the battlefield."
Sacrifice a Caribou token: You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0046</id>
    <name>Celestial Sword</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target creature you control gets +3/+3 until end of turn. Destroy it at the beginning of the next end step. A creature destroyed this way can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"So great is its power, only the chosen can wield it and live."
—Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0047</id>
    <name>Centaur Archer</name>
    <text>{T}: Centaur Archer deals 1 damage to target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Centaurs will kill our Aesthir if they can; they've always been enemies. Destroy the horse-people on sight."
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0048</id>
    <name>Chaos Lord</name>
    <text>First strike, haste
At the beginning of each player's upkeep, if the number of permanents is even, that player gains control of Chaos Lord.
When Chaos Lord enters the battlefield, it loses haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0049</id>
    <name>Chaos Moon</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each upkeep, count the number of permanents. If the number is odd, until end of turn, red creatures get +1/+1 and whenever a player taps a Mountain for mana, that player adds {R} to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces). If the number is even, until end of turn, red creatures get -1/-1 and if a player taps a Mountain for mana, that Mountain produces colorless mana instead of any other type.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0050</id>
    <name>Chromatic Armor</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As Chromatic Armor enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Chromatic Armor enters the battlefield with a sleight counter on it.
Prevent all damage that would be dealt to enchanted creature by a source of the last chosen color.
{X}: Put a sleight counter on Chromatic Armor and choose a color. X is the number of sleight counters on Chromatic Armor.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0051</id>
    <name>Chub Toad</name>
    <text>Whenever Chub Toad blocks or becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Chub Toad, Chub Toad
At the door.
Run away quick
Or you'll run no more.
—Traditional children's rhyme</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0052</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Black</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a black source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0053</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Blue</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a blue source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0054</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Green</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a green source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0055</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Red</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a red source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0056</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: White</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a white source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0057</id>
    <name>Clairvoyance</name>
    <text>Look at target player's hand.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"As we followed the ice wall, we had the distinct feeling of being watched. Many of the party wanted to turn back."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0058</id>
    <name>Cloak of Confusion</name>
    <text>Enchant creature you control
Whenever enchanted creature attacks and isn't blocked, you may have it assign no combat damage this turn. If you do, defending player discards a card at random.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0059</id>
    <name>Cold Snap</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Cold Snap deals damage to that player equal to the number of snow lands he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Who knows from whence the winter comes?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0060</id>
    <name>Conquer</name>
    <text>Enchant land
You control enchanted land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why do we trade with those despicable Elves? You don't live in forests, you burn them"
—Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0061</id>
    <name>Cooperation</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has banding. (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding a player controls are blocking or being blocked by a creature, that player divides that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The Elves train our healers, and we keep the Orcs at bay. Most Elvish bargains aren't as fair."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0062</id>
    <name>Counterspell</name>
    <text>Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"The duel was going badly for me, and Zur thought I was finished. He boasted that he would eat my soul—but all he ate were his words."
—Gustha Ebbasdotter,
Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0063</id>
    <name>Crown of the Ages</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Attach target Aura attached to a creature to another creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0064</id>
    <name>Curse of Marit Lage</name>
    <text>When Curse of Marit Lage enters the battlefield, tap all Islands.
Islands don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our world has not felt her thundering steps in lifetimes, but Marit Lage's presence is still with us."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0065</id>
    <name>Dance of the Dead</name>
    <text>Enchant creature card in a graveyard
When Dance of the Dead enters the battlefield, if it's on the battlefield, it loses "enchant creature card in a graveyard" and gains "enchant creature put onto the battlefield with Dance of the Dead." Return enchanted creature card to the battlefield tapped under your control and attach Dance of the Dead to it. When Dance of the Dead leaves the battlefield, that creature's controller sacrifices it.
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, that player may pay {1}{B}. If he or she does, untap that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0066</id>
    <name>Dark Banishing</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Will not the mountains quake and hills melt at the coming of the darkness? Share this vision with your enemies, Lim-Dûl, and they shall wither."
—Leshrac, Walker of Night</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0067</id>
    <name>Dark Ritual</name>
    <text>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Leshrac, my liege, grant me the power I am due."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0068</id>
    <name>Death Ward</name>
    <text>Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Sometimes, a soul is not ready to complete its journey to the next world."
—Halvor Arenson,
Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0069</id>
    <name>Deflection</name>
    <text>Change the target of target spell with a single target.</text>
    <flavorText>Up and down,
over and through,
back around—
the joke's on you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0070</id>
    <name>Demonic Consultation</name>
    <text>Name a card. Exile the top six cards of your library, then reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal the named card. Put that card into your hand and exile all other cards revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0071</id>
    <name>Despotic Scepter</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target permanent you own. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"We were not meant to have such terrible things. They should be left where we found them, if not destroyed"
—Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi Heretic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0072</id>
    <name>Diabolic Vision</name>
    <text>Look at the top five cards of your library. Put one of them into your hand and the rest on top of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have seen the true path. I will not warm myself by the fire—I will become the flame."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0073</id>
    <name>Dire Wolves</name>
    <text>Dire Wolves has banding as long as you control a Plains. (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"It's amazing how scared a city kid can get at a dog. Now, of course, I'd cross Terisiare alone, and keep no watch if I had a pack of greys hanging on my flanks as I went."
—Oddveig Ulfsson, caravan scout</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0074</id>
    <name>Disenchant</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"I implore you not to forget the horrors of the past. You would have us start the Brothers' War anew"
—Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi Heretic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0075</id>
    <name>Dread Wight</name>
    <text>At end of combat, put a paralyzation counter on all creatures blocking or blocked by Dread Wight and tap those creatures. They gain "If this creature has a paralyzation counter on it, it doesn't untap during its controller's untap step" and "{4}: Remove a paralyzation counter from this creature."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0076</id>
    <name>Dreams of the Dead</name>
    <text>{1}{U}: Return target white or black creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield. That creature gains "Cumulative upkeep {2}." If the creature would leave the battlefield, exile it instead of putting it anywhere else. (At the beginning of its controller's upkeep, that player puts an age counter on it, then sacrifices it unless he or she pays its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0077</id>
    <name>Drift of the Dead</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Drift of the Dead's power and toughness are each equal to the number of snow lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Take their dead, and entomb them in the snow. Risen, they shall serve a new purpose."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0078</id>
    <name>Drought</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Drought unless you pay {W}{W}.
Spells cost an additional "Sacrifice a Swamp" to cast for each black mana symbol in their mana costs.
Activated abilities cost an additional "Sacrifice a Swamp" to activate for each black mana symbol in their activation costs.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0079</id>
    <name>Dwarven Armory</name>
    <text>{2}, Sacrifice a land: Put a +2/+2 counter on target creature. Activate this ability only during any upkeep step.</text>
    <flavorText>"Few of us left, now. Confounded Yeti have opened all the vents. We'd best hide here with the weapons."
—Perena Deepcutter,
Dwarven Armorer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0080</id>
    <name>Earthlink</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Earthlink unless you pay {2}.
Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, that creature's controller sacrifices a land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0081</id>
    <name>Earthlore</name>
    <text>Enchant land you control
Enchanted land has "{T}: Target blocking creature gets +1/+2 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>"Even the ground is our friend."
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0082</id>
    <name>Elder Druid</name>
    <text>{3}{G}, {T}: You may tap or untap target artifact, creature, or land.</text>
    <flavorText>"I am older than any Elder Druid before me, and still no child has been born with the Mark to take my place. When will the wheel turn?"
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0083</id>
    <name>Elemental Augury</name>
    <text>{3}: Look at the top three cards of target player's library, then put them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is the changing of perception that is important."
—Gerda Äagesdotter,
Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0084</id>
    <name>Elkin Bottle</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Exile the top card of your library. Until the beginning of your next upkeep, you may play that card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0085</id>
    <name>Elvish Healer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn. If that creature is green, prevent the next 2 damage instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Kjeldorans keep the Orcs at bay and we train their healers. Most human bargains aren't as fair."
—Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0086</id>
    <name>Enduring Renewal</name>
    <text>Play with your hand revealed.
If you would draw a card, reveal the top card of your library instead. If it's a creature card, put it into your graveyard. Otherwise, draw a card.
Whenever a creature is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, return it to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>That which lasts longest serves best.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0087</id>
    <name>Energy Storm</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Prevent all damage that would be dealt by instant and sorcery spells.
Creatures with flying don't untap during their controller's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0088</id>
    <name>Enervate</name>
    <text>Tap target artifact, creature, or land.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"Worlds turn in crucial moments of decision. Make your choice."
—Gustha Ebbasdotter,
Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0089</id>
    <name>Errant Minion</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, that player may pay any amount of mana. Errant Minion deals 2 damage to that player. Prevent X of that damage, where X is the amount of mana that player paid this way.</text>
    <flavorText>Abandon not your faith when others abandon you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0090</id>
    <name>Errantry</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+0 and can only attack alone.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is no shame in solitude. The lone Knight may succeed where a hundred founder."
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0091</id>
    <name>Essence Filter</name>
    <text>Destroy all enchantments or all nonwhite enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>"Freyalise has cleansed our bodies and minds of the plagues of Kjeldor; all she asks in return is that we keep pure our newly given home in Fyndhorn."
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0092</id>
    <name>Essence Flare</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+0.
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, put a -0/-1 counter on that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Never underestimate the power of the soul unleashed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0093</id>
    <name>Essence Vortex</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature unless its controller pays life equal to its toughness. A creature destroyed this way can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>Masters who sacrifice for servants will receive the gift of loyalty.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0094</id>
    <name>Fanatical Fever</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+0 and gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let go your fury, and hone your anger. Become the fist of Freyalise"
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0095</id>
    <name>Fear</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has fear. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Even the bravest of warriors yet knows the dark clutch of fright upon his stalwart heart."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0096</id>
    <name>Fiery Justice</name>
    <text>Fiery Justice deals 5 damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players. Target opponent gains 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The fire of justice burns like nothing else."Lovisa Coldeyes, Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0097</id>
    <name>Fire Covenant</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Fire Covenant, pay X life.
Fire Covenant deals X damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0098</id>
    <name>Flame Spirit</name>
    <text>{R}: Flame Spirit gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The spirit of the flame is the spirit of change."
—Lovisa Coldeyes,
Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0099</id>
    <name>Flare</name>
    <text>Flare deals 1 damage to target creature or player.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"I strive for elegance and speed in my work."
—Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0100</id>
    <name>Flooded Woodlands</name>
    <text>Green creatures can't attack unless their controller sacrifices a land for each green creature he or she controls that's attacking.</text>
    <flavorText>Freyalise's tears bring life and renewal, though they also bring trouble.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0101</id>
    <name>Flow of Maggots</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Flow of Maggots can't be blocked by non-Wall creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"The very earth seemed alive and made a sound like the writhing of the damned."
—Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0102</id>
    <name>Folk of the Pines</name>
    <text>{1}{G}: Folk of the Pines gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our friends of the forest take many forms, yet all serve the will of Freyalise."
—Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0103</id>
    <name>Forbidden Lore</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Enchanted land has "{T}: Target creature gets +2/+1 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0104</id>
    <name>Force Void</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1}.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"My mind and spirit are one—a barrier not readily passed."
—Gustha Ebbasdotter,
Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0105</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0106</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0107</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0108</id>
    <name>Forgotten Lore</name>
    <text>Target opponent chooses a card in your graveyard. You may pay {G}. If you do, repeat this process except that opponent can't choose a card already chosen for Forgotten Lore. Then put the last chosen card into your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>In ashes are the gems of history.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0109</id>
    <name>Formation</name>
    <text>Target creature gains banding until end of turn. (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding a player controls are blocking or being blocked by a creature, that player divides that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have been a warrior for over four hundred years, and yet each generation of Kjeldorans teaches me new tricks. There can be no better allies."
—Taaveti of Kelsinko, Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0110</id>
    <name>Foul Familiar</name>
    <text>Foul Familiar can't block.
{B}, Pay 1 life: Return Foul Familiar to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Serve me, and live forever."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0111</id>
    <name>Foxfire</name>
    <text>Untap target attacking creature. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by that creature this turn.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"Only the foolish fear Foxfire."
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0112</id>
    <name>Freyalise Supplicant</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a red or white creature: Freyalise Supplicant deals damage to target creature or player equal to half the sacrificed creature's power, rounded down.</text>
    <flavorText>"We have joined with the Druids of the Juniper Order. Our faith is one."
—Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0113</id>
    <name>Freyalise's Charm</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a black spell, you may pay {G}{G}. If you do, you draw a card.
{G}{G}: Return Freyalise's Charm to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0114</id>
    <name>Freyalise's Winds</name>
    <text>Whenever a permanent becomes tapped, put a wind counter on it.
If a permanent with a wind counter on it would untap during its controller's untap step, remove all wind counters from it instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0115</id>
    <name>Fumarole</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Fumarole, pay 3 life.
Destroy target creature and target land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Too many of us have died in the explosions that wrack these hills."
—Klazina Jansdotter, Leader of the Order of the Sacred Torch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0116</id>
    <name>Fylgja</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Fylgja enters the battlefield with four healing counters on it.
Remove a healing counter from Fylgja: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to enchanted creature this turn.
{2}{W}: Put a healing counter on Fylgja.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0117</id>
    <name>Fyndhorn Bow</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"With a bow like this, the hunting is always good."
—Taaveti of Kelsinko,
Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0118</id>
    <name>Fyndhorn Brownie</name>
    <text>{2}{G}, {T}: Untap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"I've been insulted by drunks in a hundred inns, but never as skillfully or annoyingly as by those blasted Brownies."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0119</id>
    <name>Fyndhorn Elder</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Do we know what we're doing? Yes—the will of Freyalise."
—Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0120</id>
    <name>Fyndhorn Elves</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Living side by side with the Elves for so long leaves me with no doubt that we serve the same goddess."
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0121</id>
    <name>Fyndhorn Pollen</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
All creatures get -1/-0.
{1}{G}: All creatures get -1/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I breathed deeply, and suddenly I knew not who or where I was."
—Taaveti of Kelsinko, Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0122</id>
    <name>Game of Chaos</name>
    <text>Flip a coin. If you win the flip, you gain 1 life and target opponent loses 1 life, and you decide whether to flip again. If you lose the flip, you lose 1 life and that opponent gains 1 life, and that player decides whether to flip again. Double the life stakes with each flip.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0123</id>
    <name>Gangrenous Zombies</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Gangrenous Zombies: Gangrenous Zombies deals 1 damage to each creature and each player. If you control a snow Swamp, Gangrenous Zombies deals 2 damage to each creature and each player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0124</id>
    <name>Gaze of Pain</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, whenever a creature you control attacks and isn't blocked, you may choose to have it deal damage equal to its power to a target creature. If you do, it assigns no combat damage this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Remove the guardians to ensure your victory.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0125</id>
    <name>General Jarkeld</name>
    <text>{T}: Switch the blocking creatures of two target attacking creatures. Activate this ability only during the declare blockers step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0126</id>
    <name>Ghostly Flame</name>
    <text>Black and/or red permanents and spells are colorless sources of damage.</text>
    <flavorText>"Walk slowly when in the nether world, and seek that which calls."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0127</id>
    <name>Giant Growth</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Here in Fyndhorn, the goddess Freyalise is generous to her children."
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0128</id>
    <name>Giant Trap Door Spider</name>
    <text>{1}{R}{G}, {T}: Exile Giant Trap Door Spider and target creature without flying that's attacking you.</text>
    <flavorText>"So large and so quiet—a combination best avoided."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0129</id>
    <name>Glacial Chasm</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep—Pay 2 life. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
When Glacial Chasm enters the battlefield, sacrifice a land.
Creatures you control can't attack.
Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0130</id>
    <name>Glacial Crevasses</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a snow Mountain: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We were chasing Lim-Dûl when the ridge in front of us suddenly crumbled. I can't believe it was mere coincidence."
—Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0131</id>
    <name>Glacial Wall</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We are farther west than any could have imagined possible, but I still wish to press on. Unfortunately, huge walls of ice block further travel. We can't believe they are natural."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0132</id>
    <name>Glaciers</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Glaciers unless you pay {W}{U}.

All Mountains are Plains.</text>
    <flavorText>"Even the highest mountain can be ground to dust."
—Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0133</id>
    <name>Goblin Lyre</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Goblin Lyre: Flip a coin. If you win the flip, Goblin Lyre deals damage to target opponent equal to the number of creatures you control. If you lose the flip, Goblin Lyre deals damage to you equal to the number of creatures that opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0134</id>
    <name>Goblin Mutant</name>
    <text>Trample
Goblin Mutant can't attack if defending player controls an untapped creature with power 3 or greater.
Goblin Mutant can't block creatures with power 3 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>If only it had three brains, too.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0135</id>
    <name>Goblin Sappers</name>
    <text>{R}{R}, {T}: Target creature you control is unblockable this turn. Destroy it and Goblin Sappers at end of combat.
{R}{R}{R}{R}, {T}: Target creature you control is unblockable this turn. Destroy it at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0136</id>
    <name>Goblin Ski Patrol</name>
    <text>{1}{R}: Goblin Ski Patrol gets +2/+0 and gains flying. Its controller sacrifices it at the beginning of the next end step. Activate this ability only once and only if you control a snow Mountain.</text>
    <flavorText>"AIIIEEEE"
—Ib Halfheart, Goblin Tactician</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0137</id>
    <name>Goblin Snowman</name>
    <text>Whenever Goblin Snowman blocks, prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by it this turn.
{T}: Goblin Snowman deals 1 damage to target creature it's blocking.</text>
    <flavorText>"Strength in numbers? Right."
—Ib Halfheart, Goblin Tactician</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0138</id>
    <name>Gorilla Pack</name>
    <text>Gorilla Pack can't attack unless defending player controls a Forest.

When you control no Forests, sacrifice Gorilla Pack.</text>
    <flavorText>"We learned this at a dear price: once you cross the great river, get through the Yavimaya forest at top speed."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0139</id>
    <name>Gravebind</name>
    <text>Target creature can't be regenerated this turn.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>One foot in the grave,
firmly planted.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0140</id>
    <name>Green Scarab</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't be blocked by green creatures.
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 as long as an opponent controls a green permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0141</id>
    <name>Grizzled Wolverine</name>
    <text>Whenever Grizzled Wolverine becomes blocked, you may pay {R}. If you do, Grizzled Wolverine gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Before you release a Woverine from the trap, make sure it's really dead."
—Lovisa Coldeyes,
Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0142</id>
    <name>Hallowed Ground</name>
    <text>{W}{W}: Return target nonsnow land you control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"On this site where Kjeld's blood was spilled, let none raise a fist or deny a beggar."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0143</id>
    <name>Halls of Mist</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Creatures that attacked during their controller's last turn can't attack.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0144</id>
    <name>Heal</name>
    <text>Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"Sometimes even the smallest boon can save a life."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0145</id>
    <name>Hecatomb</name>
    <text>When Hecatomb enters the battlefield, sacrifice Hecatomb unless you sacrifice four creatures.
Tap an untapped Swamp you control: Hecatomb deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0146</id>
    <name>Hematite Talisman</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a red spell, you may pay {3}. If you do, untap target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0147</id>
    <name>Hipparion</name>
    <text>Hipparion can't block creatures with power 3 or greater unless you pay {1}.</text>
    <flavorText>"Someone once said that Hipparions are to Warriors what Aesthir are to Skyknights. Don't believe it."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0148</id>
    <name>Hoar Shade</name>
    <text>{B}: Hoar Shade gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The creature we fought in the western waste was doubly dangerous: mortally wounded, it rebounded and attacked again."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0149</id>
    <name>Hot Springs</name>
    <text>Enchant land you control
Enchanted land has "{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn."</text>
    <flavorText>Warmth is life; heat is peace.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0150</id>
    <name>Howl from Beyond</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"From the mouths of my servants, my voice shall emerge to shake the souls of my foes."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0151</id>
    <name>Hurricane</name>
    <text>Hurricane deals X damage to each creature with flying and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>"This was quite possibly the least pleasant occurrence on the entire expedition."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0152</id>
    <name>Hyalopterous Lemure</name>
    <text>{0}: Hyalopterous Lemure gets -1/-0 and gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Lemures looked harmless, until they descended on my troops. Within moments, only bones remained."
—Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0153</id>
    <name>Hydroblast</name>
    <text>Choose one — Counter target spell if it's red; or destroy target permanent if it's red.</text>
    <flavorText>"Heed the lessons of our time: the forms of water may move the land itself and hold captive the fires within."
—Gustha Ebbasdotter,
Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0154</id>
    <name>Hymn of Rebirth</name>
    <text>Put target creature card from a graveyard onto the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>"There will come soft rains, and spring shall be amongst us, a welcome friend."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0155</id>
    <name>Ice Cauldron</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Ice Cauldron and exile a nonland card from your hand. You may cast that card for as long as it remains exiled. Note the type and amount of mana spent to pay this activation cost. Activate this ability only if there are no charge counters on Ice Cauldron.
{T}, Remove a charge counter from Ice Cauldron: Add Ice Cauldron's last noted type and amount of mana to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast the last card exiled with Ice Cauldron.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0156</id>
    <name>Ice Floe</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Ice Floe during your untap step.
{T}: Tap target creature without flying that's attacking you. It doesn't untap during its controller's untap step for as long as Ice Floe remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0157</id>
    <name>Iceberg</name>
    <text>Iceberg enters the battlefield with X ice counters on it.
{3}: Put an ice counter on Iceberg.
Remove an ice counter from Iceberg: Add {1} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0158</id>
    <name>Icequake</name>
    <text>Destroy target land. If that land was a snow land, Icequake deals 1 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>"When the earth shakes, and their animals are swallowed up by the ground, perhaps they will think twice before attacking again."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0159</id>
    <name>Icy Manipulator</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Tap target artifact, creature, or land.</text>
    <flavorText>"The scavengers who first found it called it the ‘Bone Crank.' Not a bad name, I'd say."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0160</id>
    <name>Icy Prison</name>
    <text>When Icy Prison enters the battlefield, exile target creature.
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Icy Prison unless any player pays {3}.
When Icy Prison leaves the battlefield, return the exiled creature to the battlefield under its owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0161</id>
    <name>Illusionary Forces</name>
    <text>Flying
Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"This school was founded in secret, operates in secret, and exists for the teaching of secrets. Those who would alter reality must first escape it."
—Gerda Äagesdotter,
Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0162</id>
    <name>Illusionary Presence</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, choose a land type. Illusionary Presence gains landwalk of the chosen type until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We could feel the Shaman's power, as surely as we felt the storm."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0163</id>
    <name>Illusionary Terrain</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
As Illusionary Terrain enters the battlefield, choose two basic land types.
Basic lands of the first chosen type are the second chosen type.</text>
    <flavorText>"The drawing of maps is fruitless in the west near the ice walls; the very earth is formless."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0164</id>
    <name>Illusionary Wall</name>
    <text>Defender, flying, first strike
Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Let them see what is not there and feel what does not touch them. When they no longer trust their senses, that is the time to strike."
—Gerda Äagesdotter,
Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0165</id>
    <name>Illusions of Grandeur</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
When Illusions of Grandeur enters the battlefield, you gain 20 life.
When Illusions of Grandeur leaves the battlefield, you lose 20 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0166</id>
    <name>Imposing Visage</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"I can't believe they expect me to fight with this rabble. A Goblin in a big mask sends ‘em running for cover."
—Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0167</id>
    <name>Incinerate</name>
    <text>Incinerate deals 3 damage to target creature or player. A creature dealt damage this way can't be regenerated this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Yes, I think ‘toast' is an appropriate description."
—Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0168</id>
    <name>Infernal Darkness</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep—Pay {B} and 1 life. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
If a land is tapped for mana, it produces {B} instead of any other type.</text>
    <flavorText>"I thought the day had brought enough horrors for our ragged band, but the night was far worse."
—Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0169</id>
    <name>Infernal Denizen</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice two Swamps. If you can't, tap Infernal Denizen, and an opponent may gain control of a creature you control of his or her choice for as long as Infernal Denizen remains on the battlefield.
{T}: Gain control of target creature for as long as Infernal Denizen remains on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0170</id>
    <name>Infinite Hourglass</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a time counter on Infinite Hourglass.
All creatures get +1/+0 for each time counter on Infinite Hourglass.
{3}: Remove a time counter from Infinite Hourglass. Any player may activate this ability but only during any upkeep step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0171</id>
    <name>Infuse</name>
    <text>Untap target artifact, creature, or land.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"The potential for change lies in all things. Know a thing's nature, know its possibilities, and know it anew."
—Gustha Ebbasdotter,
Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0172</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0173</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0174</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0175</id>
    <name>Jester's Cap</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Jester's Cap: Search target player's library for three cards and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Know your foes' strengths as well as their weaknesses."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0176</id>
    <name>Jester's Mask</name>
    <text>Jester's Mask enters the battlefield tapped.
{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Jester's Mask: Target opponent puts the cards from his or her hand on top of his or her library. Search that player's library for that many cards. That player puts those cards into his or her hand, then shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0177</id>
    <name>Jeweled Amulet</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Jeweled Amulet. Note the type of mana spent to pay this activation cost. Activate this ability only if there are no charge counters on Jeweled Amulet.
{T}, Remove a charge counter from Jeweled Amulet: Add one mana of Jeweled Amulet's last noted type to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0178</id>
    <name>Johtull Wurm</name>
    <text>Whenever Johtull Wurm becomes blocked, it gets -2/-1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.</text>
    <flavorText>"To bring her down we must be on all sides at once—leave one avenue open and we'll all be dead."
—Taaveti of Kelsinko, Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0179</id>
    <name>Jokulhaups</name>
    <text>Destroy all artifacts, creatures, and lands. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"I was shocked when I first saw the aftermath of the Yavimaya Valley disaster. The raging waters had swept away trees, bridges, and even houses. My healers had much work to do."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0180</id>
    <name>Juniper Order Druid</name>
    <text>{T}: Untap target land.</text>
    <flavorText>"The filthy towns of Kjeldor are no place for anyone to live. Fyndhorn is our home now."
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0181</id>
    <name>Justice</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Justice unless you pay {W}{W}.

Whenever a red creature or spell deals damage, Justice deals that much damage to that creature's or spell's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0182</id>
    <name>Karplusan Forest</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool. Karplusan Forest deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0183</id>
    <name>Karplusan Giant</name>
    <text>Tap an untapped snow land you control: Karplusan Giant gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"They aren't the brightest or the quickest of Giants. For that matter, the same holds true if you compare them to rocks."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0184</id>
    <name>Karplusan Yeti</name>
    <text>{T}: Karplusan Yeti deals damage equal to its power to target creature. That creature deals damage equal to its power to Karplusan Yeti.</text>
    <flavorText>"What's that smell?"
—Perena Deepcutter,
Dwarven Armorer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0185</id>
    <name>Kelsinko Ranger</name>
    <text>{1}{W}: Target green creature gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Rangers not trained by the Elves just aren't the same."
—Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0186</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Dead</name>
    <text>When Kjeldoran Dead enters the battlefield, sacrifice a creature.
{B}: Regenerate Kjeldoran Dead.</text>
    <flavorText>"They shall kill those whom once they loved."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0187</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Elite Guard</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn. When that creature leaves the battlefield this turn, sacrifice Kjeldoran Elite Guard. Activate this ability only during combat.</text>
    <flavorText>The winged helms of the Guard are put on for pageants—but taken off for war.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0188</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Frostbeast</name>
    <text>At end of combat, destroy all creatures blocking or blocked by Kjeldoran Frostbeast.</text>
    <flavorText>"Two of my Warriors found that the creature was dangerous not only in combat, but also in simple proximity."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0189</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Guard</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn. When that creature leaves the battlefield this turn, sacrifice Kjeldoran Guard. Activate this ability only during combat and only if defending player controls no snow lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0190</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Knight</name>
    <text>Banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)
{1}{W}: Kjeldoran Knight gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
{W}{W}: Kjeldoran Knight gets +0/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those who do not ride the wind on Aesthir still command loyalty and respect."
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0191</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Phalanx</name>
    <text>First strike; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"There's nothing I like better than watching a street full of soldiers kicking down the doors of the guilty and the impure."
—Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0192</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Royal Guard</name>
    <text>{T}: All combat damage that would be dealt to you by unblocked creatures this turn is dealt to Kjeldoran Royal Guard instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"Honorable in battle,
generous in death."
—Motto of the Kjeldoran Royal Guard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0193</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Skycaptain</name>
    <text>Flying; first strike; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"If we do our duty and uphold our honor, Kjeldor shall stand for a thousand years."
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0194</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Skyknight</name>
    <text>Flying; first strike; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"My Aesthir is my most trusted ally. We fight as one and live as one, and we will die as one."
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0195</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Warrior</name>
    <text>Banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Give me a thousand such Warriors and I could change the world."
—Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0196</id>
    <name>Knight of Stromgald</name>
    <text>Protection from white
{B}: Knight of Stromgald gains first strike until end of turn.
{B}{B}: Knight of Stromgald gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Kjeldorans should rule supreme, and to the rest, death"
—Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0197</id>
    <name>Krovikan Elementalist</name>
    <text>{2}{R}: Target creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
{U}{U}: Target creature you control gains flying until end of turn. Sacrifice it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Elementalists' talents could be useful if turned to other purposes."
—Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0198</id>
    <name>Krovikan Fetish</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Krovikan Fetish enters the battlefield, draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>Some Krovikans find strength in the ears and eyes of their victims and wear such fetishes into battle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0199</id>
    <name>Krovikan Sorcerer</name>
    <text>{T}, Discard a nonblack card: Draw a card.
{T}, Discard a black card: Draw two cards, then discard one of them.</text>
    <flavorText>"These Sorcerers always seem to have another surprise up their sleeves."
—Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0200</id>
    <name>Krovikan Vampire</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each end step, if a creature dealt damage by Krovikan Vampire this turn was put into a graveyard, put that card onto the battlefield under your control. Sacrifice it when you lose control of Krovikan Vampire.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0201</id>
    <name>Land Cap</name>
    <text>Land Cap doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a depletion counter on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Land Cap.
{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Land Cap.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0202</id>
    <name>Lapis Lazuli Talisman</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a blue spell, you may pay {3}. If you do, untap target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0203</id>
    <name>Lava Burst</name>
    <text>Lava Burst deals X damage to target creature or player. If Lava Burst would deal damage to a creature, that damage can't be prevented or dealt instead to another creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Overkill? This isn't a game of Kick-the-Ouphe"
—Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0204</id>
    <name>Lava Tubes</name>
    <text>Lava Tubes doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a depletion counter on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Lava Tubes.
{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Lava Tubes.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0205</id>
    <name>Legions of Lim-Dûl</name>
    <text>Snow swampwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"I have seen the faces of my dead friends among that grim band, and I can bear no more."
—Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0206</id>
    <name>Leshrac's Rite</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has swampwalk.</text>
    <flavorText>"Bind me to thee, my soul to thine. I am your servant and your slave. I shall hunger for your word and thirst for your blessing. Blood for blood, flesh for flesh, Leshrac, my lord."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0207</id>
    <name>Leshrac's Sigil</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a green spell, you may pay {B}{B}. If you do, look at that player's hand and choose a card from it. The player discards that card.
{B}{B}: Return Leshrac's Sigil to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0208</id>
    <name>Lhurgoyf</name>
    <text>Lhurgoyf's power is equal to the number of creature cards in all graveyards and its toughness is equal to that number plus 1.</text>
    <flavorText>"Ach Hans, run It's the Lhurgoyf"
—Saffi Eriksdotter, last words</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0209</id>
    <name>Lightning Blow</name>
    <text>Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you do it right, they'll never know what hit them."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0210</id>
    <name>Lim-Dûl's Cohort</name>
    <text>Whenever Lim-Dûl's Cohort blocks or becomes blocked by a creature, that creature can't be regenerated this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Join me in the place of power, you risen dead. Join me where the waters weep and the trees have no hearts."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0211</id>
    <name>Lim-Dûl's Hex</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, for each player, Lim-Dûl's Hex deals 1 damage to that player unless he or she pays {B} or {3}.</text>
    <flavorText>"The weak shall fall. The strong shall remain."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0212</id>
    <name>Lost Order of Jarkeld</name>
    <text>As Lost Order of Jarkeld enters the battlefield, choose an opponent.
Lost Order of Jarkeld's power and toughness are each equal to 1 plus the number of creatures the chosen player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let us remember brave Jarkeld and his troops, who perished in the Adarkar Wastes so long ago."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0213</id>
    <name>Lure</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
All creatures able to block enchanted creature do so.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0214</id>
    <name>Maddening Wind</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Cumulative upkeep {G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, Maddening Wind deals 2 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is Freyalise, walking on the world."
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0215</id>
    <name>Magus of the Unseen</name>
    <text>{1}{U}, {T}: Untap target artifact an opponent controls and gain control of it until end of turn. It gains haste until end of turn. When you lose control of the artifact, tap it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0216</id>
    <name>Malachite Talisman</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a green spell, you may pay {3}. If you do, untap target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0217</id>
    <name>Márton Stromgald</name>
    <text>Whenever Márton Stromgald attacks, other attacking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn for each attacking creature other than Márton Stromgald.
Whenever Márton Stromgald blocks, other blocking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn for each blocking creature other than Márton Stromgald.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0218</id>
    <name>Melee</name>
    <text>Cast Melee only during your turn and only during combat before blockers are declared.
Instead of defending player, you choose how each creature blocks this turn.
Whenever a creature attacks and isn't blocked this turn, untap it and remove it from combat.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0219</id>
    <name>Melting</name>
    <text>All lands are no longer snow.</text>
    <flavorText>"Who needs the sun when you've got me around?"
—Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0220</id>
    <name>Mercenaries</name>
    <text>{3}: Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you this turn by this creature. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>"Blasted amateurs Doesn't the queen think we can fight well enough on our own?"
—Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0221</id>
    <name>Merieke Ri Berit</name>
    <text>Merieke Ri Berit doesn't untap during your untap step.
{T}: Gain control of target creature for as long as you control Merieke Ri Berit. When Merieke Ri Berit leaves the battlefield or becomes untapped, destroy that creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0222</id>
    <name>Mesmeric Trance</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
{U}, Discard a card: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Magic overused can freeze the mind. Creativity is more important than power."
—Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0223</id>
    <name>Meteor Shower</name>
    <text>Meteor Shower deals X plus 1 damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>"Eenie, meenie, minie, moe . . . oh, why not all of them?"
—Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0224</id>
    <name>Mind Ravel</name>
    <text>Target player discards a card.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>An end to reason, an end to order. Forget all that has been.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0225</id>
    <name>Mind Warp</name>
    <text>Look at target player's hand and choose X cards from it. That player discards those cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0226</id>
    <name>Mind Whip</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, that player may pay {3}. If he or she doesn't, Mind Whip deals 2 damage to that player and you tap that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"A mind in agony is a sparrow without wings."Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0227</id>
    <name>Minion of Leshrac</name>
    <text>Protection from black
At the beginning of your upkeep, Minion of Leshrac deals 5 damage to you unless you sacrifice a creature other than Minion of Leshrac. If Minion of Leshrac deals damage to you this way, tap it.
{T}: Destroy target creature or land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0228</id>
    <name>Minion of Tevesh Szat</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Minion of Tevesh Szat deals 2 damage to you unless you pay {B}{B}.
{T}: Target creature gets +3/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"A minion given over to Tevesh Szat is a stronger minion gained."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0229</id>
    <name>Mistfolk</name>
    <text>{U}: Counter target spell that targets Mistfolk.</text>
    <flavorText>"Although my official log will state there is no evidence pointing to the existence of the Mistfolk, my certainty is lessened by the cursed consistency of the expedition's eyewitness accounts."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0230</id>
    <name>Mole Worms</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Mole Worms during your untap step.
{T}: Tap target land. It doesn't untap during its controller's untap step for as long as Mole Worms remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0231</id>
    <name>Monsoon</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's end step, tap all untapped Islands that player controls and Monsoon deals X damage to the player, where X is the number of Islands tapped this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"No one in her right mind would venture off the coast of Kjeldor during this season."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0232</id>
    <name>Moor Fiend</name>
    <text>Swampwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Let them close the gates of Krov from dusk until dawn if they so choose. It matters not. My fiends shall yet rend their flesh from their bones."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0233</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0234</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0235</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0236</id>
    <name>Mountain Goat</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Folklore has it that to capture a Mountain Goat is a sign of divine blessing. I just know it's a sign that dinner is on the way."
—Klazina Jansdotter, Leader of the Order of the Sacred Torch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0237</id>
    <name>Mountain Titan</name>
    <text>{1}{R}{R}: Until end of turn, whenever you cast a black spell, put a +1/+1 counter on Mountain Titan.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Titans claimed to draw strength from the rocks, but I suspect them of some darker allegiance."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0238</id>
    <name>Mudslide</name>
    <text>Creatures without flying don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.
At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player may choose any number of tapped creatures without flying he or she controls and pay {2} for each creature chosen this way. If the player does, untap those creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0239</id>
    <name>Musician</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
{T}: Put a music counter on target creature. If it doesn't have "At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy this creature unless you pay {1} for each music counter on it," it gains that ability.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0240</id>
    <name>Mystic Might</name>
    <text>Enchant land you control
Cumulative upkeep {1}{U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Enchanted land has "{T}: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0241</id>
    <name>Mystic Remora</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Whenever an opponent casts a noncreature spell, you may draw a card unless that player pays {4}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0242</id>
    <name>Nacre Talisman</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a white spell, you may pay {3}. If you do, untap target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0243</id>
    <name>Naked Singularity</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {3} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
If tapped for mana, Plains produce {R}, Islands produce {G}, Swamps produce {W}, Mountains produce {U}, and Forests produce {B} instead of any other type.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0244</id>
    <name>Nature's Lore</name>
    <text>Search your library for a Forest card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Fyndhorn is our home."
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0245</id>
    <name>Necropotence</name>
    <text>Skip your draw step.
Whenever you discard a card, exile that card from your graveyard.
Pay 1 life: Exile the top card of your library face down. Put that card into your hand at the beginning of your next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0246</id>
    <name>Norritt</name>
    <text>{T}: Untap target blue creature.
{T}: Choose target non-Wall creature the active player has controlled continuously since the beginning of the turn. That creature attacks this turn if able. If it doesn't, destroy it at the beginning of the next end step. Activate this ability only before attackers are declared.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0247</id>
    <name>Oath of Lim-Dûl</name>
    <text>Whenever you lose life, for each 1 life you lost, sacrifice a permanent other than Oath of Lim-Dûl unless you discard a card. (Damage dealt to you causes you to lose life.)
{B}{B}: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0248</id>
    <name>Onyx Talisman</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a black spell, you may pay {3}. If you do, untap target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0249</id>
    <name>Orcish Cannoneers</name>
    <text>{T}: Orcish Cannoneers deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's a thankless job, and you'll probably die in an explosion. But the pay is pretty good."
—Toothlicker Harj, Orcish Captain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0250</id>
    <name>Orcish Conscripts</name>
    <text>Orcish Conscripts can't attack unless at least two other creatures attack.

Orcish Conscripts can't block unless at least two other creatures block.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0251</id>
    <name>Orcish Farmer</name>
    <text>{T}: Target land becomes a Swamp until its controller's next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>"Yes, the Farmers keep our soldiers fed. But why do they have to make every battlefield a pigpen?"
—Toothlicker Harj, Orcish Captain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0252</id>
    <name>Orcish Healer</name>
    <text>{R}{R}, {T}: Target creature can't be regenerated this turn.
{B}{B}{R}, {T}: Regenerate target black or green creature.
{R}{G}{G}, {T}: Regenerate target black or green creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0253</id>
    <name>Orcish Librarian</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}: Look at the top eight cards of your library. Exile four of them at random, then put the rest on top of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>Us hungry, need food . . . .
Lots of books . . . . Hmm . . . .</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0254</id>
    <name>Orcish Lumberjack</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a Forest: Add three mana in any combination of {R} and/or {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"How did I ever let myself get talked into this project?"
—Toothlicker Harj, Orcish Captain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0255</id>
    <name>Orcish Squatters</name>
    <text>Whenever Orcish Squatters attacks and isn't blocked, you may gain control of target land defending player controls for as long as you control Orcish Squatters. If you do, Orcish Squatters assigns no combat damage this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0256</id>
    <name>Order of the Sacred Torch</name>
    <text>{T}, Pay 1 life: Counter target black spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0257</id>
    <name>Order of the White Shield</name>
    <text>Protection from black
{W}: Order of the White Shield gains first strike until end of turn.
{W}{W}: Order of the White Shield gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Shall we turn away a worthy soul because his parents were peasants? I think not."
—Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0258</id>
    <name>Pale Bears</name>
    <text>Islandwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Daughter, on the day you have killed your Pale Bear, then will I give you your true name."
—Lovisa Coldeyes,
Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0259</id>
    <name>Panic</name>
    <text>Cast Panic only during combat before blockers are declared.
Target creature can't block this turn.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you'd been there, you would've run from that deer, too"
—Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0260</id>
    <name>Pentagram of the Ages</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>"Take this item, for instance. How would it destroy us, Relicbane?"
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0261</id>
    <name>Pestilence Rats</name>
    <text>Pestilence Rats's power is equal to the number of other Rats on the battlefield. (For example, as long as there are two other Rats on the battlefield, Pestilence Rats's power and toughness are 2/3.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0262</id>
    <name>Phantasmal Mount</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Target creature you control with toughness 2 or less gets +1/+1 and gains flying until end of turn. When Phantasmal Mount leaves the battlefield this turn, sacrifice that creature. When the creature leaves the battlefield this turn, sacrifice Phantasmal Mount.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0263</id>
    <name>Pit Trap</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Pit Trap: Destroy target attacking creature without flying. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"These traps are truly a symbol of great cruelty and sinister cunning."
—Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi Heretic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0264</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0265</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0266</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0267</id>
    <name>Polar Kraken</name>
    <text>Trample
Polar Kraken enters the battlefield tapped.
Cumulative upkeep—Sacrifice a land. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"It was big. Really, really, big. No, bigger than that. It was big"
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0268</id>
    <name>Portent</name>
    <text>Look at the top three cards of target player's library, then put them back in any order. You may have that player shuffle his or her library.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0269</id>
    <name>Power Sink</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}. If he or she doesn't, that player taps all lands with mana abilities he or she controls and empties his or her mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0270</id>
    <name>Pox</name>
    <text>Each player loses a third of his or her life, then discards a third of the cards in his or her hand, then sacrifices a third of the creatures he or she controls, then sacrifices a third of the lands he or she controls. Round up each time.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0271</id>
    <name>Prismatic Ward</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As Prismatic Ward enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Prevent all damage that would be dealt to enchanted creature by sources of the chosen color.</text>
    <flavorText>"These, of all spells, must have common components I can isolate and use."Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0272</id>
    <name>Pygmy Allosaurus</name>
    <text>Swampwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"I don't understand the appeal of keeping these things as pets, unless you want your children eaten."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0273</id>
    <name>Pyknite</name>
    <text>When Pyknite enters the battlefield, draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"Never cross a Pyknite, if you value your scalp."
—Lovisa Coldeyes,
Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0274</id>
    <name>Pyroblast</name>
    <text>Choose one — Counter target spell if it's blue; or destroy target permanent if it's blue.</text>
    <flavorText>"Just the thing for those pesky water mages."
—Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0275</id>
    <name>Pyroclasm</name>
    <text>Pyroclasm deals 2 damage to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Leaves more room for the big ones to fight in, you know."
—Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0276</id>
    <name>Rally</name>
    <text>Blocking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Stand your ground, troops This shall be our finest hour"
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox, last words</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0277</id>
    <name>Ray of Command</name>
    <text>Untap target creature an opponent controls and gain control of it until end of turn. That creature gains haste until end of turn. When you lose control of the creature, tap it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0278</id>
    <name>Ray of Erasure</name>
    <text>Target player puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"What is real can be unreal."
—Gerda Äagesdotter,
Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0279</id>
    <name>Reality Twist</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1}{U}{U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
If tapped for mana, Plains produce {R}, Swamps produce {G}, Mountains produce {W}, and Forests produce {B} instead of any other type.</text>
    <flavorText>"Nothing is as it seems."
—Gerda Äagesdotter,
Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0280</id>
    <name>Reclamation</name>
    <text>Black creatures can't attack unless their controller sacrifices a land for each black creature he or she controls that's attacking.</text>
    <flavorText>"We shall oppose Lim-Dûl and his forces by any means necessary, even if the very earth be torn asunder."
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0281</id>
    <name>Red Scarab</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't be blocked by red creatures.
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 as long as an opponent controls a red permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0282</id>
    <name>Regeneration</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
{G}: Regenerate enchanted creature. (The next time that creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Faith in Freyalise has given me the gift, not the curse, of unprecedented longevity."
—Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0283</id>
    <name>Rime Dryad</name>
    <text>Snow forestwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"The Dryads told us to stay, as no new horrors would come when it was so cold. Three of us left anyway. The rest believed their lies, and their skeletons weren't found until the thaw."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0284</id>
    <name>Ritual of Subdual</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
If a land is tapped for mana, it produces colorless mana instead of any other type.</text>
    <flavorText>"That which does not bend to the will of Freyalise shall surely break."
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0285</id>
    <name>River Delta</name>
    <text>River Delta doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a depletion counter on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from River Delta.
{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on River Delta.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0286</id>
    <name>Runed Arch</name>
    <text>Runed Arch enters the battlefield tapped.
{X}, {T}, Sacrifice Runed Arch: X target creatures with power 2 or less are unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0287</id>
    <name>Sabretooth Tiger</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>"Daughter, it is now your turn to hunt the Tiger, and make a blanket of its fur."
—Lovisa Coldeyes,
Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0288</id>
    <name>Sacred Boon</name>
    <text>Prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn. At the beginning of the next end step, put a +0/+1 counter on that creature for each 1 damage prevented this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"Divine gifts are granted to those who are worthy."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0289</id>
    <name>Scaled Wurm</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Flourishing during the Ice Age, these Wurms were the bane of all Kjeldorans. Their great size and ferocity made them the subject of countless nightmares—they embodied the worst of the Ice Age."
—Kjeldor: Ice Civilization</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0290</id>
    <name>Sea Spirit</name>
    <text>{U}: Sea Spirit gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"It rose above our heads, above the ship, and still higher yet. No foggy, ice-laden sea in the world could frighten me more."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0291</id>
    <name>Seizures</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature becomes tapped, Seizures deals 3 damage to that creature's controller unless that player pays {3}.</text>
    <flavorText>"Sheathe your sword, warrior, lest ye fall on it when stricken."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0292</id>
    <name>Seraph</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever a creature dealt damage by Seraph this turn is put into a graveyard, put that card onto the battlefield under your control at the beginning of the next end step. Sacrifice the creature when you lose control of Seraph.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0293</id>
    <name>Shambling Strider</name>
    <text>{R}{G}: Shambling Strider gets +1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Freyalise forbid that any stranger should wander into the Striders' territory.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0294</id>
    <name>Shatter</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let the past be the past. Do not call up that which you cannot put down. Destroy that which destroyed us, so long ago."
—Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi Heretic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0295</id>
    <name>Shield Bearer</name>
    <text>Banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"You have almost completed your four years, my son. Soon you shall be a Skyknight."
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0296</id>
    <name>Shield of the Ages</name>
    <text>{2}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to you this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"This shield is a true rarity: an artifact whose purpose is obvious."
—Arcum Dagsson,
Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0297</id>
    <name>Shyft</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may have Shyft become the color or colors of your choice. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Capturing this specimen was not easy. Study it well, that you someday might be as versatile."
—Gerda Äagesdotter,
Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0298</id>
    <name>Sibilant Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Sibilant Spirit attacks, defending player may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Relax. I'm sure it's just a snake hissing."
—Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0299</id>
    <name>Silver Erne</name>
    <text>Flying, trample</text>
    <flavorText>"I've seen a larger Erne knock a Giant to the ground and stay airborne. They move not with the wind, but as the wind."
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0300</id>
    <name>Skeleton Ship</name>
    <text>When you control no Islands, sacrifice Skeleton Ship.
{T}: Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The sea gives up her dead as easily as the soil."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0301</id>
    <name>Skull Catapult</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Skull Catapult deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let any who doubt the evil of using the ancient devices look at this infernal machine. What manner of fiend would design such a sadistic device?"
—Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi Heretic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0302</id>
    <name>Sleight of Mind</name>
    <text>Change the text of target spell or permanent by replacing all instances of one color word with another. (For example, you may change "target black spell" to "target blue spell." This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0303</id>
    <name>Snow Devil</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has flying.
Enchanted creature has first strike as long as it's blocking and you control a snow land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Give me wings to fly and speed to strike. In return, the glory I earn shall be yours."Steinar Icefist, Balduvian Shaman</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0304</id>
    <name>Snow Fortress</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{1}: Snow Fortress gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
{1}: Snow Fortress gets +0/+1 until end of turn.
{3}: Snow Fortress deals 1 damage to target creature without flying that's attacking you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0305</id>
    <name>Snow Hound</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Return Snow Hound and target green or blue creature you control to their owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you're starving, eat your horses, your dead, or yourself—but never eat your dog."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0306</id>
    <name>Snowblind</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets -X/-Y. If that creature is attacking, X is the number of snow lands defending player controls. Otherwise, X is the number of snow lands its controller controls. Y is equal to X or to enchanted creature's toughness minus 1, whichever is smaller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0307</id>
    <name>Snow-Covered Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0308</id>
    <name>Snow-Covered Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0309</id>
    <name>Snow-Covered Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0310</id>
    <name>Snow-Covered Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0311</id>
    <name>Snow-Covered Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0312</id>
    <name>Snowfall</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Whenever an Island is tapped for mana, its controller may add {U} to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces). If that Island is snow, its controller may add {U}{U} to his or her mana pool instead. Spend this mana only to pay cumulative upkeep costs.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0313</id>
    <name>Soldevi Golem</name>
    <text>Soldevi Golem doesn't untap during your untap step.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may untap target tapped creature an opponent controls. If you do, untap Soldevi Golem.</text>
    <flavorText>Slow and steady wins the race.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0314</id>
    <name>Soldevi Machinist</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {2} to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to activate abilities of artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>"Perhaps this time the power of the artificers shall be used wisely."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0315</id>
    <name>Soldevi Simulacrum</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
{1}: Soldevi Simulacrum gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>They look human—
until they bleed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0316</id>
    <name>Songs of the Damned</name>
    <text>Add {B} to your mana pool for each creature card in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Not wind, but the breath of the dead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0317</id>
    <name>Soul Barrier</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a creature spell, Soul Barrier deals 2 damage to that player unless he or she pays {2}.</text>
    <flavorText>"There's more than one way to skin an Ouphe—or thwart a mage."
—Gustha Ebbasdotter,
Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0318</id>
    <name>Soul Burn</name>
    <text>Spend only black and/or red mana on X.
Soul Burn deals X damage to target creature or player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt, but not more than the amount of {B} spent on X, the player's life total before Soul Burn dealt damage, or the creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0319</id>
    <name>Soul Kiss</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{B}, Pay 1 life: Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn. Activate this ability no more than three times each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0320</id>
    <name>Spectral Shield</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +0/+2 and can't be the target of spells.</text>
    <flavorText>"What can be a stronger shield than concealment? Have you ever defeated an enemy you didn't know existed?"
—Gerda Äagesdotter,
Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0321</id>
    <name>Spoils of Evil</name>
    <text>For each artifact or creature card in target opponent's graveyard, add {1} to your mana pool and you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Virtue has its rewards, as does its opposite."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0322</id>
    <name>Spoils of War</name>
    <text>X is the number of artifact and/or creature cards in an opponent's graveyard as you cast Spoils of War.
Distribute X +1/+1 counters among any number of target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"This is the fun part"
—Ib Halfheart, Goblin Tactician</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0323</id>
    <name>Staff of the Ages</name>
    <text>Creatures with landwalk abilities can be blocked as though they didn't have those abilities.</text>
    <flavorText>"We found this staff useful on our visit to this very commission. Would Relicbane prefer we had been slain by Lim-Dûl's horrors?"
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0324</id>
    <name>Stampede</name>
    <text>Attacking creatures get +1/+0 and gain trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We could see the horizon blacken with the great beasts, but it was too late. The icefield offered no immediate safety, but luckily most of us reached a crevasse in which we could take cover."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0325</id>
    <name>Stench of Evil</name>
    <text>Destroy all Plains. For each land put into a graveyard this way, Stench of Evil deals 1 damage to that land's controller unless he or she pays {2}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0326</id>
    <name>Stone Rain</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>"May the forces that took Argoth beneath the waves never come among us again."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0327</id>
    <name>Stone Spirit</name>
    <text>Stone Spirit can't be blocked by creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"The spirit of the stone is the spirit of strength."
—Lovisa Coldeyes,
Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0328</id>
    <name>Stonehands</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +0/+2.
{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Trust in the power of stone. Stone is strong; stone shatters swords; stone breaks bones. Trust in stone."
—Lovisa Coldeyes,
Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0329</id>
    <name>Storm Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Storm Spirit deals 2 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Come to us, with your lightning. Come to us, with your thunder. Serve us with your strength, and smite our foes with your power."
—Steinar Icefist, Balduvian Shaman</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0330</id>
    <name>Stormbind</name>
    <text>{2}, Discard a card at random: Stormbind deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Once, our people could call down the storm itself to do our bidding."
—Lovisa Coldeyes,
Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0331</id>
    <name>Stromgald Cabal</name>
    <text>{T}, Pay 1 life: Counter target white spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"Kjeldor must be supreme at any cost."
—Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0332</id>
    <name>Stunted Growth</name>
    <text>Target player chooses three cards from his or her hand and puts them on top of his or her library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0333</id>
    <name>Sulfurous Springs</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool. Sulfurous Springs deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0334</id>
    <name>Sunstone</name>
    <text>{2}, Sacrifice a snow land: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I dispute Relicbane's hysterical allegations, Commissioner, but it is true that these artifacts can be dangerous."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0335</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0336</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0337</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0338</id>
    <name>Swords to Plowshares</name>
    <text>Exile target creature. Its controller gains life equal to its power.</text>
    <flavorText>"The so-called Barbarians will not respect us for our military might—they will respect us for our honor."
—Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0339</id>
    <name>Tarpan</name>
    <text>When Tarpan is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"A good Tarpan will serve you, faithful and true. A bad one will kick you in the head."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0340</id>
    <name>Thermokarst</name>
    <text>Destroy target land. If that land was a snow land, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Finally we understand the lesson of our home: loss begets renewal."
—Kolbjörn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0341</id>
    <name>Thoughtleech</name>
    <text>Whenever an Island an opponent controls becomes tapped, you may gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"A resourceful mage has many sources of information. The best one is your foe."
—Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0342</id>
    <name>Thunder Wall</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Flying
{U}: Thunder Wall gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Lemures had barely taken wing when the sky roared with thunder. The swarm of little beasts wavered, divided, and fell, crashing to the earth."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0343</id>
    <name>Timberline Ridge</name>
    <text>Timberline Ridge doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a depletion counter on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Timberline Ridge.
{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Timberline Ridge.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0344</id>
    <name>Time Bomb</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a time counter on Time Bomb.

{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Time Bomb: Time Bomb deals damage to each creature and each player equal to the number of time counters on Time Bomb.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0345</id>
    <name>Tinder Wall</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Sacrifice Tinder Wall: Add {R}{R} to your mana pool.
{R}, Sacrifice Tinder Wall: Tinder Wall deals 2 damage to target creature it's blocking.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0346</id>
    <name>Tor Giant</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"What do you do then? Run. Run very fast. Don't stop until you see the camp—or a bigger Giant."
—Toothlicker Harj,
Orcish Captain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0347</id>
    <name>Total War</name>
    <text>Whenever a player attacks with one or more creatures, destroy all untapped non-Wall creatures that player controls that didn't attack, except for creatures the player hasn't controlled continuously since the beginning of the turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0348</id>
    <name>Touch of Death</name>
    <text>Touch of Death deals 1 damage to target player. You gain 1 life.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"What was yours is mine. Your land, your people, and now your life."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0349</id>
    <name>Touch of Vitae</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, target creature gains haste and "{0}: Untap this creature. Activate this ability only once."
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0350</id>
    <name>Trailblazer</name>
    <text>Target creature is unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our Elvish Hunter Taaveti led us swiftly along hidden paths through the dense forest. We caught the Orcs from behind, and completely by surprise."
—Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0351</id>
    <name>Underground River</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool. Underground River deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0352</id>
    <name>Updraft</name>
    <text>Target creature gains flying until end of turn.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"The power of flight has but one equal in battle: surprise. Understanding how to use both is the key to victory."
—Arnjlot Olasson, Sky Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0353</id>
    <name>Urza's Bauble</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Urza's Bauble: Look at a card at random in target player's hand. You draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0354</id>
    <name>Veldt</name>
    <text>Veldt doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a depletion counter on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Veldt.
{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Veldt.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0355</id>
    <name>Venomous Breath</name>
    <text>At end of combat, destroy all creatures that blocked or were blocked by target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0356</id>
    <name>Vertigo</name>
    <text>Vertigo deals 2 damage to target creature with flying. That creature loses flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I saw the wizard gesturing, but I didn't guess his plan until my Aesthir cried out and went into a dive."
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0357</id>
    <name>Vexing Arcanix</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target player names a card, then reveals the top card of his or her library. If it's the named card, the player puts it into his or her hand. Otherwise, the player puts it into his or her graveyard and Vexing Arcanix deals 2 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0358</id>
    <name>Vibrating Sphere</name>
    <text>As long as it's your turn, creatures you control get +2/+0.
As long as it's not your turn, creatures you control get -0/-2.</text>
    <flavorText>"Unearthly and invisible fibers emanate from this sphere, entangling all who draw near."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0359</id>
    <name>Walking Wall</name>
    <text>Defender
{3}: Walking Wall gets +3/-1 until end of turn and can attack this turn as though it didn't have defender. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The fortress is not what it seems."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0360</id>
    <name>Wall of Lava</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{R}: Wall of Lava gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Now there's something you don't see every day."
—Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0361</id>
    <name>Wall of Pine Needles</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{G}: Regenerate Wall of Pine Needles.</text>
    <flavorText>The power of the forest takes a hundred forms. Some are more surprising than others.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0362</id>
    <name>Wall of Shields</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Banding (If any creatures with banding you control are blocking a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by.)</text>
    <flavorText>"It's the pokey bits that hurt the most."
—Ib Halfheart, Goblin Tactician</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0363</id>
    <name>War Chariot</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target creature gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I wouldn't advise using it with a Woolly Mammoth, but it's quite appropriate for many other beasts."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0364</id>
    <name>Warning</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by target attacking creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The folk of the Karplusan Mountains are impossible to ambush."
—Lovisa Coldeyes,
Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0365</id>
    <name>Whalebone Glider</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target creature with power 3 or less gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's no Ornithopter, but then I'm no Urza."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0366</id>
    <name>White Scarab</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't be blocked by white creatures.
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 as long as an opponent controls a white permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0367</id>
    <name>Whiteout</name>
    <text>All creatures lose flying until end of turn.
Sacrifice a snow land: Return Whiteout from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0368</id>
    <name>Wiitigo</name>
    <text>Wiitigo enters the battlefield with six +1/+1 counters on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, put a +1/+1 counter on Wiitigo if it has blocked or been blocked since your last upkeep. Otherwise, remove a +1/+1 counter from it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0369</id>
    <name>Wild Growth</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds {G} to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>"Here in Fyndhorn, where Freyalise's power is strongest, the forest has its own opinion."
—Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0370</id>
    <name>Wind Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying
Wind Spirit can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"To visit the sky requires bravery, and thought, and little else. To master the sky requires the binding of its masters, and little else."
—Arnjlot Olasson, Sky Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0371</id>
    <name>Wings of Aesthir</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 and has flying and first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>"For those of courage, even the sky holds no limit."
—Arnjlot Olasson, Sky Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0372</id>
    <name>Winter's Chill</name>
    <text>Cast Winter's Chill only during combat before blockers are declared.
X can't be greater than the number of snow lands you control.
Destroy X target attacking creatures at end of combat. For each attacking creature, its controller may pay {1} or {2} to prevent this effect. If that player pays only {1} for that creature, prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by that creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0373</id>
    <name>Withering Wisps</name>
    <text>At the beginning of the end step, if no creatures are on the battlefield, sacrifice Withering Wisps.
{B}: Withering Wisps deals 1 damage to each creature and each player. Activate this ability no more times each turn than the number of snow Swamps you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0374</id>
    <name>Woolly Mammoths</name>
    <text>Woolly Mammoths has trample as long as you control a snow land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mammoths may be good to ride on, but they're certainly bad to fall off of"
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0375</id>
    <name>Woolly Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)
Whenever Woolly Spider blocks a creature with flying, Woolly Spider gets +0/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We need not fear the forces of the air; I've yet to see a Spider without an appetite."
—Taaveti of Kelsinko, Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0376</id>
    <name>Word of Blasting</name>
    <text>Destroy target Wall. It can't be regenerated. Word of Blasting deals damage equal to that Wall's converted mana cost to the Wall's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>"Walls? What walls?"
—Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0377</id>
    <name>Word of Undoing</name>
    <text>Return target creature and all white Auras you own attached to it to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>"It was in Urza's journals that I finally found the secret at the core of the summonings."
—Journal, author unknown</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0378</id>
    <name>Wrath of Marit Lage</name>
    <text>When Wrath of Marit Lage enters the battlefield, tap all red creatures.
Red creatures don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>Dread Marit Lage lies dreaming, not dead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0379</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Gnats</name>
    <text>Flying
{G}: Regenerate Yavimaya Gnats.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is our third day of travel on the Yavimaya River, and still these creatures plague us. Davin Lansson, our naturalist, has facetiously labeled them ‘gnats,' and the name has stuck."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0380</id>
    <name>Zuran Enchanter</name>
    <text>{2}{B}, {T}: Target player discards a card. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We are Kjeldorans no more."
—Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0381</id>
    <name>Zuran Orb</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a land: You gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"I will go to any length to achieve my goal. Eternal life is worth any sacrifice."
—Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0382</id>
    <name>Zuran Spellcaster</name>
    <text>{T}: Zuran Spellcaster deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"A mage must be precise as well as potent; cautious, as well as clever."
—Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ICE0383</id>
    <name>Zur's Weirding</name>
    <text>Players play with their hands revealed.
If a player would draw a card, he or she reveals it instead. Then any other player may pay 2 life. If a player does, put that card into its owner's graveyard. Otherwise, that player draws a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>