<cards name="Invasion">
  <item>
    <id>INV0001</id>
    <name>Alabaster Leech</name>
    <text>White spells you cast cost {W} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>"Its stones seem to serve a healing function, but removing them intact is an exhausting process."
—Tolarian research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0002</id>
    <name>Angel of Mercy</name>
    <text>Flying
When Angel of Mercy enters the battlefield, you gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"In times like these, people need to be reminded of compassion."
—Sisay</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0003</id>
    <name>Ardent Soldier</name>
    <text>Kicker {2} (You may pay an additional {2} as you cast this spell.)
Vigilance
If Ardent Soldier was kicked, it enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0004</id>
    <name>Atalya, Samite Master</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: Choose one — Prevent the next X damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn; or you gain X life. Spend only white mana this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"Healing is a gift the divine ones have shared with us. It is a sacred trust."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0005</id>
    <name>Benalish Emissary</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{G} (You may pay an additional {1}{G} as you cast this spell.)
When Benalish Emissary enters the battlefield, if it was kicked, destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0006</id>
    <name>Benalish Heralds</name>
    <text>{3}{U}, {T}: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The detailed dispatch could be summarized in four words: "Time is running out."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0007</id>
    <name>Benalish Lancer</name>
    <text>Kicker {2}{W} (You may pay an additional {2}{W} as you cast this spell.)
If Benalish Lancer was kicked, it enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it and with first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0008</id>
    <name>Benalish Trapper</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'm up here. You're down there. Now who's the lower life form?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0009</id>
    <name>Blinding Light</name>
    <text>Tap all nonwhite creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>An angel's sword impales only the body; her righteousness penetrates the soul.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0010</id>
    <name>Capashen Unicorn</name>
    <text>{1}{W}, {T}, Sacrifice Capashen Unicorn: Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>Capashen riders were stern and humorless even before their ancestral home was reduced to rubble.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0011</id>
    <name>Crimson Acolyte</name>
    <text>Protection from red
{W}: Target creature gains protection from red until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The faithful will walk through streams of fire and emerge unscathed.
—Crimson acolyte creed</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0012</id>
    <name>Crusading Knight</name>
    <text>Protection from black
Crusading Knight gets +1/+1 for each Swamp your opponents control.</text>
    <flavorText>"My only dream is to destroy the nightmares of others."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0013</id>
    <name>Death or Glory</name>
    <text>Separate all creature cards in your graveyard into two piles. Exile the pile of an opponent's choice and return the other to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0014</id>
    <name>Dismantling Blow</name>
    <text>Kicker {2}{U} (You may pay an additional {2}{U} as you cast this spell.)
Destroy target artifact or enchantment.
If Dismantling Blow was kicked, draw two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0015</id>
    <name>Divine Presence</name>
    <text>If a source would deal 4 or more damage to a creature or player, that source deals 3 damage to that creature or player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"Serra's light isn't easily extinguished."
—Reya Dawnbringer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0016</id>
    <name>Fight or Flight</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each opponent's combat, separate all creatures that player controls into two piles. Only creatures in the pile of his or her choice can attack this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0017</id>
    <name>Glimmering Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
{U}: Glimmering Angel gains shroud until end of turn. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We turned to see where the blow came from and saw only a distant light."
—Capashen lord</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0018</id>
    <name>Global Ruin</name>
    <text>Each player chooses from the lands he or she controls a land of each basic land type, then sacrifices the rest.</text>
    <flavorText>"The earth shook, the sky rained fire, and it seemed the world was ending."
—Benalish refugee</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0019</id>
    <name>Harsh Judgment</name>
    <text>As Harsh Judgment enters the battlefield, choose a color.
If an instant or sorcery spell of the chosen color would deal damage to you, it deals that damage to its controller instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"At least they remember me."
—Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0020</id>
    <name>Holy Day</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Will history remember this as the day demons arrived or the day saviors arrived?"
—Barrin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0021</id>
    <name>Liberate</name>
    <text>Exile target creature you control. Return that card to the battlefield under its owner's control at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>"Not everyone gets a second chance."
—Hanna</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0022</id>
    <name>Obsidian Acolyte</name>
    <text>Protection from black
{W}: Target creature gains protection from black until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The truthful will stand in the gaze of death and escape unharmed.
—Obsidian acolyte creed</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0023</id>
    <name>Orim's Touch</name>
    <text>Kicker {1} (You may pay an additional {1} as you cast this spell.)
Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn. If Orim's Touch was kicked, prevent the next 4 damage that would be dealt to that creature or player this turn instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0024</id>
    <name>Pledge of Loyalty</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has protection from the colors of permanents you control. This effect doesn't remove Pledge of Loyalty.</text>
    <flavorText>Urza convinced many Dominarians not only to set aside their differences, but to embrace them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0025</id>
    <name>Prison Barricade</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Kicker {1}{W} (You may pay an additional {1}{W} as you cast this spell.)
If Prison Barricade was kicked, it enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it and with "Prison Barricade can attack as though it didn't have defender."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0026</id>
    <name>Protective Sphere</name>
    <text>{1}, Pay 1 life: Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you this turn by a source of your choice that shares a color with the mana spent on this activation cost. (Colorless mana prevents no damage.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0027</id>
    <name>Pure Reflection</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a creature spell, destroy all Reflections. Then that player puts an X/X white Reflection creature token onto the battlefield, where X is the converted mana cost of that spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0028</id>
    <name>Rampant Elephant</name>
    <text>{G}: Target creature blocks Rampant Elephant this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>No matter how righteous the cause, it helps to bring along some muscle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0029</id>
    <name>Razorfoot Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying
First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Do griffins fight to defend their homes or purely for sport?"
—Sisay</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0030</id>
    <name>Restrain</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by target attacking creature this turn.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Hanna would give up her own life before she'd abandon the Weatherlight."
—Sisay</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0031</id>
    <name>Reviving Dose</name>
    <text>You gain 3 life.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>As healers battled each plague, they learned more about the next.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0032</id>
    <name>Rewards of Diversity</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a multicolored spell, you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Everything is in place. Nothing can happen that isn't part of my plan."
—Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0033</id>
    <name>Reya Dawnbringer</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>A beacon of hope for a battered army.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0034</id>
    <name>Rout</name>
    <text>You may cast Rout any time you could cast an instant if you pay {2} more to cast it.
Destroy all creatures. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0035</id>
    <name>Ruham Djinn</name>
    <text>First strike

Ruham Djinn gets -2/-2 as long as white is the most common color among all permanents or is tied for most common.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0036</id>
    <name>Samite Ministration</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you this turn by a source of your choice. Whenever damage from a black or red source is prevented this way this turn, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0037</id>
    <name>Shackles</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.
{W}: Return Shackles to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"It could be worse," said Gerrard, looking around. "Well, maybe not."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0038</id>
    <name>Spirit of Resistance</name>
    <text>If you control a permanent of each color, prevent all damage that would be dealt to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our victory must come from all of Dominaria, or it will not come."
—Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0039</id>
    <name>Spirit Weaver</name>
    <text>{2}: Target green or blue creature gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let my hope be your shield."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0040</id>
    <name>Strength of Unity</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Domain — Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>All Dominarians agreed on one thing: they would not go down without a fight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0041</id>
    <name>Sunscape Apprentice</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
{U}, {T}: Put target creature you control on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0042</id>
    <name>Sunscape Master</name>
    <text>{G}{G}, {T}: Creatures you control get +2/+2 until end of turn.
{U}{U}, {T}: Return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0043</id>
    <name>Teferi's Care</name>
    <text>{W}, Sacrifice an enchantment: Destroy target enchantment.

{3}{U}{U}: Counter target enchantment spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"If I do nothing else, I will protect my people."
—Teferi</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0044</id>
    <name>Wayfaring Giant</name>
    <text>Domain — Wayfaring Giant gets +1/+1 for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Its stature and stride increase with each step it takes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0045</id>
    <name>Winnow</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonland permanent if another permanent with the same name is on the battlefield.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Strength in numbers? I think not."
—Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0046</id>
    <name>Barrin's Unmaking</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand if that permanent shares a color with the most common color among all permanents or a color tied for most common.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0047</id>
    <name>Blind Seer</name>
    <text>{1}{U}: Target spell or permanent becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I think he sees more than he lets on."
—Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0048</id>
    <name>Breaking Wave</name>
    <text>You may cast Breaking Wave any time you could cast an instant if you pay {2} more to cast it.
Simultaneously untap all tapped creatures and tap all untapped creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0049</id>
    <name>Collective Restraint</name>
    <text>Domain — Creatures can't attack you unless their controller pays {X} for each creature he or she controls that's attacking you, where X is the number of basic land types among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0050</id>
    <name>Crystal Spray</name>
    <text>Change the text of target spell or permanent by replacing all instances of one color word or basic land type with another until end of turn.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0051</id>
    <name>Disrupt</name>
    <text>Counter target instant or sorcery spell unless its controller pays {1}.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Teferi wanted no part of Urza's battle plans, but both agreed the Phyrexian portal must be closed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0052</id>
    <name>Distorting Wake</name>
    <text>Return X target nonland permanents to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard savored a grim smile as the Phyrexian portals disappeared behind the Weatherlight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0053</id>
    <name>Dream Thrush</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Target land becomes the basic land type of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Whether for good or ill, their arrival always means change.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0054</id>
    <name>Empress Galina</name>
    <text>{U}{U}, {T}: Gain control of target legendary permanent. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Above the waves you may be mighty indeed, but down here you belong to me."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0055</id>
    <name>Essence Leak</name>
    <text>Enchant permanent
If enchanted permanent is red or green, it has "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice this permanent unless you pay its mana cost."</text>
    <flavorText>"We define the boundaries of reality; they don't define us."
—Teferi</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0056</id>
    <name>Exclude</name>
    <text>Counter target creature spell.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I don't have time for you right now."
—Teferi</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0057</id>
    <name>Fact or Fiction</name>
    <text>Reveal the top five cards of your library. An opponent separates those cards into two piles. Put one pile into your hand and the other into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0058</id>
    <name>Faerie Squadron</name>
    <text>Kicker {3}{U} (You may pay an additional {3}{U} as you cast this spell.)
If Faerie Squadron was kicked, it enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it and with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0059</id>
    <name>Mana Maze</name>
    <text>Players can't cast spells that share a color with the spell most recently cast this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those who know only one path to victory can never hope to triumph."
—The Blind Seer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0060</id>
    <name>Manipulate Fate</name>
    <text>Search your library for three cards, exile them, then shuffle your library.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0061</id>
    <name>Metathran Aerostat</name>
    <text>Flying
{X}{U}: You may put a creature card with converted mana cost X from your hand onto the battlefield. If you do, return Metathran Aerostat to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0062</id>
    <name>Metathran Transport</name>
    <text>Flying
Metathran Transport can't be blocked by blue creatures.
{U}: Target creature becomes blue until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0063</id>
    <name>Metathran Zombie</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Metathran Zombie.</text>
    <flavorText>"Rise, metathran. You shall serve a nobler cause in death."
—Tsabo Tavoc, Phyrexian general</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0064</id>
    <name>Opt</name>
    <text>Look at the top card of your library. You may put that card on the bottom of your library.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"We need alternatives, Hanna," yelled Gerrard. "Now"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0065</id>
    <name>Phantasmal Terrain</name>
    <text>Enchant land
As Phantasmal Terrain enters the battlefield, choose a basic land type.
Enchanted land is the chosen type.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0066</id>
    <name>Probe</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{B} (You may pay an additional {1}{B} as you cast this spell.)
Draw three cards, then discard two cards.
If Probe was kicked, target player discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0067</id>
    <name>Prohibit</name>
    <text>Kicker {2} (You may pay an additional {2} as you cast this spell.)
Counter target spell if its converted mana cost is 2 or less. If Prohibit was kicked, counter that spell if its converted mana cost is 4 or less instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0068</id>
    <name>Psychic Battle</name>
    <text>Whenever a player chooses one or more targets, each player reveals the top card of his or her library. The player who reveals the card with the highest converted mana cost may change the target or targets. If two or more cards are tied for highest cost, the target or targets remain unchanged. Changing targets this way doesn't trigger this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0069</id>
    <name>Rainbow Crow</name>
    <text>Flying

{1}: Rainbow Crow becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Children claim no two feathers are exactly the same color, then eagerly gather them for proof.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0070</id>
    <name>Repulse</name>
    <text>Return target creature to its owner's hand.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"You aren't invited."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0071</id>
    <name>Sapphire Leech</name>
    <text>Flying
Blue spells you cast cost {U} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>"The subject's wings are clearly vestigial. We suspect the gems somehow keep it aloft."
—Tolarian research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0072</id>
    <name>Shimmering Wings</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has flying. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
{U}: Return Shimmering Wings to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Wings are but fins for swimming the sky."
—Empress Galina</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0073</id>
    <name>Shoreline Raider</name>
    <text>Protection from Kavu</text>
    <flavorText>"This strange new beast makes for an excellent meal. Get me more."
—Empress Galina</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0074</id>
    <name>Sky Weaver</name>
    <text>{2}: Target white or black creature gains flying until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Let my wisdom give you wings."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0075</id>
    <name>Stormscape Apprentice</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Tap target creature.
{B}, {T}: Target player loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0076</id>
    <name>Stormscape Master</name>
    <text>{W}{W}, {T}: Target creature gains protection from the color of your choice until end of turn.
{B}{B}, {T}: Target player loses 2 life and you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0077</id>
    <name>Sway of Illusion</name>
    <text>Any number of target creatures become the color of your choice until end of turn.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I suggest you take a closer look."
—Tidal visionary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0078</id>
    <name>Teferi's Response</name>
    <text>Counter target spell or ability an opponent controls that targets a land you control. If a permanent's ability is countered this way, destroy that permanent.

Draw two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0079</id>
    <name>Temporal Distortion</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature or land becomes tapped, put an hourglass counter on it.
Permanents with hourglass counters on them don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.
At the beginning of each player's upkeep, remove all hourglass counters from permanents that player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0080</id>
    <name>Tidal Visionary</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Beneath the waves, things appear the way merfolk want them to.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0081</id>
    <name>Tolarian Emissary</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{W} (You may pay an additional {1}{W} as you cast this spell.)
Flying
When Tolarian Emissary enters the battlefield, if it was kicked, destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0082</id>
    <name>Tower Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
{W}: Tower Drake gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Young tower drakes quickly learn to maneuver among Benalia's many spires.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0083</id>
    <name>Traveler's Cloak</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As Traveler's Cloak enters the battlefield, choose a land type.
When Traveler's Cloak enters the battlefield, draw a card.
Enchanted creature has landwalk of the chosen type.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0084</id>
    <name>Vodalian Hypnotist</name>
    <text>{2}{B}, {T}: Target player discards a card. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>"Deceit is the heart of war."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0085</id>
    <name>Vodalian Merchant</name>
    <text>When Vodalian Merchant enters the battlefield, draw a card, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Not choosing sides in a war can be dangerous—but lucrative.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0086</id>
    <name>Vodalian Serpent</name>
    <text>Kicker {2} (You may pay an additional {2} as you cast this spell.)
Vodalian Serpent can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.
If Vodalian Serpent was kicked, it enters the battlefield with four +1/+1 counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0087</id>
    <name>Wash Out</name>
    <text>Return all permanents of the color of your choice to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>"Rest now. You've neither won nor lost, but this battle is over for you just the same."
—Teferi</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0088</id>
    <name>Well-Laid Plans</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt to a creature by another creature if they share a color.</text>
    <flavorText>"I knew this day would come," said Urza. Looking at the destruction, Barrin sighed, "You don't have to revel in it."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0089</id>
    <name>Worldly Counsel</name>
    <text>Domain — Look at the top X cards of your library, where X is the number of basic land types among lands you control. Put one of those cards into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0090</id>
    <name>Zanam Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying
Zanam Djinn gets -2/-2 as long as blue is the most common color among all permanents or is tied for most common.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0091</id>
    <name>Addle</name>
    <text>Choose a color. Target player reveals his or her hand and you choose a card of that color from it. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'll wring out your tiny mind like a sponge."
—Urborg witch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0092</id>
    <name>Agonizing Demise</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{R} (You may pay an additional {1}{R} as you cast this spell.)
Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated. If Agonizing Demise was kicked, it deals damage equal to that creature's power to the creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0093</id>
    <name>Andradite Leech</name>
    <text>Black spells you cast cost {B} more to cast.
{B}: Andradite Leech gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Older specimens are completely encrusted with gems, which serve as both armor and weapons."
—Tolarian research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0094</id>
    <name>Annihilate</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Whatever Yawgmoth marks, dies. There is no escape."
—Tsabo Tavoc, Phyrexian general</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0095</id>
    <name>Bog Initiate</name>
    <text>{1}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Urborg's magic is strong. Did Urza send you to protect us or to protect against us?"
—Urborg witch, to Barrin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0096</id>
    <name>Cremate</name>
    <text>Exile target card from a graveyard.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Death's embrace need not be cold.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0097</id>
    <name>Crypt Angel</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from white
When Crypt Angel enters the battlefield, return target blue or red creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Once an angel, now an abomination.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0098</id>
    <name>Cursed Flesh</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets -1/-1 and has fear. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>Misery, filth, disease—all things that bring suffering to the world—only make Phyrexians more dangerous.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0099</id>
    <name>Defiling Tears</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, target creature becomes black, gets +1/-1, and gains "{B}: Regenerate this creature."</text>
    <flavorText>Serra's living warriors looked on in horror. "Where is our Lady now?" they cried.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0100</id>
    <name>Desperate Research</name>
    <text>Name a card other than a basic land card. Then reveal the top seven cards of your library and put all of them with that name into your hand. Exile the rest.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0101</id>
    <name>Devouring Strossus</name>
    <text>Flying, trample
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice a creature.
Sacrifice a creature: Regenerate Devouring Strossus.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0102</id>
    <name>Do or Die</name>
    <text>Separate all creatures target player controls into two piles. Destroy all creatures in the pile of that player's choice. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0103</id>
    <name>Dredge</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature or land.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'd strip away the world to see what's under it, but I'd never just leave it to these Phyrexian parasites and their false god."
—Urborg witch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0104</id>
    <name>Duskwalker</name>
    <text>Kicker {3}{B} (You may pay an additional {3}{B} as you cast this spell.)
If Duskwalker was kicked, it enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it and with fear. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0105</id>
    <name>Exotic Curse</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Domain — Enchanted creature gets -1/-1 for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Fouler than a necromancer's kiss.
—Jamuraan expression</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0106</id>
    <name>Firescreamer</name>
    <text>{R}: Firescreamer gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>In the dark, it's nearly invisible—until it exhales.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0107</id>
    <name>Goham Djinn</name>
    <text>{1}{B}: Regenerate Goham Djinn.
Goham Djinn gets -2/-2 as long as black is the most common color among all permanents or is tied for most common.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0108</id>
    <name>Hate Weaver</name>
    <text>{2}: Target blue or red creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let my hate fuel your fury."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0109</id>
    <name>Hypnotic Cloud</name>
    <text>Kicker {4} (You may pay an additional {4} as you cast this spell.)
Target player discards a card. If Hypnotic Cloud was kicked, that player discards three cards instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0110</id>
    <name>Marauding Knight</name>
    <text>Protection from white
Marauding Knight gets +1/+1 for each Plains your opponents control.</text>
    <flavorText>"They ride our trails as if they were designed to," said the guard.
"They were," replied Gerrard.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0111</id>
    <name>Mourning</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets -2/-0.
{B}: Return Mourning to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Barrin waited for the nausea to pass or for Urza to say something else. He waited in vain.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0112</id>
    <name>Nightscape Apprentice</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}: Put target creature you control on top of its owner's library.
{R}, {T}: Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0113</id>
    <name>Nightscape Master</name>
    <text>{U}{U}, {T}: Return target creature to its owner's hand.
{R}{R}, {T}: Nightscape Master deals 2 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0114</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Battleflies</name>
    <text>Flying
{B}: Phyrexian Battleflies gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Activate this ability no more than twice each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>After encountering them, Squee finally lost his appetite for bugs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0115</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Delver</name>
    <text>When Phyrexian Delver enters the battlefield, return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield. You lose life equal to that card's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0116</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Infiltrator</name>
    <text>{2}{U}{U}: Exchange control of Phyrexian Infiltrator and target creature. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>"It is Yawgmoth's will incarnate: an efficient machine that replaces inefficient flesh."
—Tsabo Tavoc</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0117</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Reaper</name>
    <text>Whenever Phyrexian Reaper becomes blocked by a green creature, destroy that creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>It desires only to help others shed the itchy wet skin of life.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0118</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Slayer</name>
    <text>Flying

Whenever Phyrexian Slayer becomes blocked by a white creature, destroy that creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>Benalia was only the first nation victimized by Tsabo Tavoc's specialized killers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0119</id>
    <name>Plague Spitter</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Plague Spitter deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.
When Plague Spitter is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, Plague Spitter deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0120</id>
    <name>Ravenous Rats</name>
    <text>When Ravenous Rats enters the battlefield, target opponent discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Nothing is sacred to the rats. Everything is simply another meal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0121</id>
    <name>Reckless Spite</name>
    <text>Destroy two target nonblack creatures. You lose 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Death is such an exquisite sensation."
—Tsabo Tavoc, Phyrexian general</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0122</id>
    <name>Recover</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>As Barrin exhumed his daughter's body, he finally realized the full price of his faith in Urza.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0123</id>
    <name>Scavenged Weaponry</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Scavenged Weaponry enters the battlefield, draw a card.
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Phyrexians have progressed," admired Urza. "Their parts are interchangeable."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0124</id>
    <name>Soul Burn</name>
    <text>Spend only black and/or red mana on X.
Soul Burn deals X damage to target creature or player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt, but not more than the amount of {B} spent on X, the player's life total before Soul Burn dealt damage, or the creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0125</id>
    <name>Spreading Plague</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature enters the battlefield, destroy all other creatures that share a color with it. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>The cruelest strain of plague keeps its hosts alive long enough to return home and infect their families.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0126</id>
    <name>Tainted Well</name>
    <text>Enchant land
When Tainted Well enters the battlefield, draw a card.
Enchanted land is a Swamp.</text>
    <flavorText>"No, you get the water. I ain't thirsty."
—Squee</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0127</id>
    <name>Trench Wurm</name>
    <text>{2}{R}, {T}: Destroy target nonbasic land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Their arrival marks the end of Yawgmoth's subtlety."
—Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0128</id>
    <name>Tsabo's Assassin</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target creature if it shares a color with the most common color among all permanents or a color tied for most common. A creature destroyed this way can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0129</id>
    <name>Tsabo's Decree</name>
    <text>Choose a creature type. Target player reveals his or her hand and discards all creature cards of that type. Then destroy all creatures of that type that player controls. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0130</id>
    <name>Twilight's Call</name>
    <text>You may cast Twilight's Call any time you could cast an instant if you pay {2} more to cast it.
Each player returns all creature cards from his or her graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Twilight falls. We rise.
—Necropolis inscription</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0131</id>
    <name>Urborg Emissary</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{U} (You may pay an additional {1}{U} as you cast this spell.)
When Urborg Emissary enters the battlefield, if it was kicked, return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0132</id>
    <name>Urborg Phantom</name>
    <text>Urborg Phantom can't block.
{U}: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by Urborg Phantom this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A chilling fog with teeth of ice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0133</id>
    <name>Urborg Shambler</name>
    <text>Other black creatures get -1/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>A writhing mass of rot, with sharp claws and a vicious spirit.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0134</id>
    <name>Urborg Skeleton</name>
    <text>Kicker {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell.)
{B}: Regenerate Urborg Skeleton.
If Urborg Skeleton was kicked, it enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0135</id>
    <name>Yawgmoth's Agenda</name>
    <text>You can't cast more than one spell each turn.
You may play cards from your graveyard.
If a card would be put into your graveyard from anywhere, exile it instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0136</id>
    <name>Ancient Kavu</name>
    <text>{2}: Ancient Kavu becomes colorless until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Those with the ability to change their nature survived Phyrexia's biological attacks. Everything else died.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0137</id>
    <name>Bend or Break</name>
    <text>Each player separates all nontoken lands he or she controls into two piles. For each player, one of his or her piles is chosen by one of his or her opponents of his or her choice. Destroy all lands in the chosen piles. Tap all lands in the other piles.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0138</id>
    <name>Breath of Darigaaz</name>
    <text>Kicker {2} (You may pay an additional {2} as you cast this spell.)
Breath of Darigaaz deals 1 damage to each creature without flying and each player. If Breath of Darigaaz was kicked, it deals 4 damage to each creature without flying and each player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0139</id>
    <name>Callous Giant</name>
    <text>If a source would deal 3 or less damage to Callous Giant, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>"The invasion has awoken slumbering mountains," noted Urza. "Good. We can use all the help we can get."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0140</id>
    <name>Chaotic Strike</name>
    <text>Cast Chaotic Strike only during combat after blockers are declared.
Flip a coin. If you win the flip, target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0141</id>
    <name>Collapsing Borders</name>
    <text>Domain — At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player gains 1 life for each basic land type among lands he or she controls. Then Collapsing Borders deals 3 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0142</id>
    <name>Crown of Flames</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
{R}: Return Crown of Flames to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"All my life I've fought these monsters. Today I finish that fight."
—Barrin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0143</id>
    <name>Firebrand Ranger</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: You may put a basic land card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>A skilled ranger can glance at the mud on your boots and tell where you last camped.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0144</id>
    <name>Ghitu Fire</name>
    <text>You may cast Ghitu Fire any time you could cast an instant if you pay {2} more to cast it.
Ghitu Fire deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0145</id>
    <name>Goblin Spy</name>
    <text>Play with the top card of your library revealed.</text>
    <flavorText>"Isn't he on our side?"
"Yep."
"Why's he spyin' on us?"
"Don't ask."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0146</id>
    <name>Halam Djinn</name>
    <text>Haste
Halam Djinn gets -2/-2 as long as red is the most common color among all permanents or is tied for most common.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0147</id>
    <name>Hooded Kavu</name>
    <text>{B}: Hooded Kavu gains fear until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>The spread of its hood eclipses all hope.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0148</id>
    <name>Kavu Aggressor</name>
    <text>Kicker {4} (You may pay an additional {4} as you cast this spell.)
Kavu Aggressor can't block.
If Kavu Aggressor was kicked, it enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0149</id>
    <name>Kavu Monarch</name>
    <text>Kavu creatures have trample.
Whenever another Kavu enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on Kavu Monarch.</text>
    <flavorText>Kavu emerged all across Dominaria, but the first and the strongest came from Yavimaya.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0150</id>
    <name>Kavu Runner</name>
    <text>Kavu Runner has haste as long as no opponent controls a white or blue creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0151</id>
    <name>Kavu Scout</name>
    <text>Domain — Kavu Scout gets +1/+0 for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The kavu evolved for centuries deep inside Dominaria, and some can draw from its strength.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0152</id>
    <name>Lightning Dart</name>
    <text>Lightning Dart deals 1 damage to target creature. If that creature is white or blue, Lightning Dart deals 4 damage to it instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Broken and punctured by dozens of Phyrexian portals, the angry sky began to spit lightning back at the world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0153</id>
    <name>Loafing Giant</name>
    <text>Whenever Loafing Giant attacks or blocks, put the top card of your library into your graveyard. If that card is a land card, prevent all combat damage Loafing Giant would deal this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Forget it. I'm not getting up today."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0154</id>
    <name>Mages' Contest</name>
    <text>You and target spell's controller bid life. You start the bidding with a bid of 1. In turn order, each player may top the high bid. The bidding ends if the high bid stands. The high bidder loses life equal to the high bid. If you win the bidding, counter that spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0155</id>
    <name>Maniacal Rage</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>"Remember me?" Tahngarth roared. "Now I'll repay you for my stay on Rath"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0156</id>
    <name>Obliterate</name>
    <text>Obliterate can't be countered.
Destroy all artifacts, creatures, and lands. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>For his family, Barrin made a funeral pyre of Tolaria.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0157</id>
    <name>Overload</name>
    <text>Kicker {2} (You may pay an additional {2} as you cast this spell.)
Destroy target artifact if its converted mana cost is 2 or less. If Overload was kicked, destroy that artifact if its converted mana cost is 5 or less instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0158</id>
    <name>Pouncing Kavu</name>
    <text>Kicker {2}{R} (You may pay an additional {2}{R} as you cast this spell.)
First strike
If Pouncing Kavu was kicked, it enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it and with haste.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0159</id>
    <name>Rage Weaver</name>
    <text>{2}: Target black or green creature gains haste until end of turn. (It can attack and {T} this turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Let my passion spur your victory."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0160</id>
    <name>Rogue Kavu</name>
    <text>Whenever Rogue Kavu attacks alone, it gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I know how this one feels," said Urza. "It's not like others of its kind and has been shunned for its differences."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0161</id>
    <name>Ruby Leech</name>
    <text>First strike
Red spells you cast cost {R} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>"Its gems didn't stop pulsating until they were completely removed."
—Tolarian research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0162</id>
    <name>Savage Offensive</name>
    <text>Kicker {G} (You may pay an additional {G} as you cast this spell.)
Creatures you control gain first strike until end of turn. If Savage Offensive was kicked, they get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0163</id>
    <name>Scarred Puma</name>
    <text>Scarred Puma can't attack unless a black or green creature also attacks.</text>
    <flavorText>It's not eager to lose the other eye.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0164</id>
    <name>Scorching Lava</name>
    <text>Kicker {R} (You may pay an additional {R} as you cast this spell.)
Scorching Lava deals 2 damage to target creature or player. If Scorching Lava was kicked, that creature can't be regenerated this turn and if it would be put into a graveyard this turn, exile it instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0165</id>
    <name>Searing Rays</name>
    <text>Choose a color. Searing Rays deals damage to each player equal to the number of creatures of that color that player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"This is a battle of pawns, for the highest stakes imaginable."
—Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0166</id>
    <name>Shivan Emissary</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{B} (You may pay an additional {1}{B} as you cast this spell.)
When Shivan Emissary enters the battlefield, if it was kicked, destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0167</id>
    <name>Shivan Harvest</name>
    <text>{1}{R}, Sacrifice a creature: Destroy target nonbasic land.</text>
    <flavorText>"The blood of your ancestors ran heavy on this soil. Now it's your turn to sacrifice for the glory of Shiv."
—Viashino heretic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0168</id>
    <name>Skittish Kavu</name>
    <text>Skittish Kavu gets +1/+1 as long as no opponent controls a white or blue creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Fierce when roused, this breed of kavu is easily distracted by a strong voice or melodic tune.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0169</id>
    <name>Skizzik</name>
    <text>Kicker {R} (You may pay an additional {R} as you cast this spell.)
Trample, haste
At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice Skizzik unless it was kicked.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0170</id>
    <name>Slimy Kavu</name>
    <text>{T}: Target land becomes a Swamp until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Its slime liquefies the ground as efficiently as its fangs shred prey.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0171</id>
    <name>Stand or Fall</name>
    <text>At the beginning of combat on your turn, separate all creatures defending player controls into two piles. Only creatures in the pile of that player's choice can block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0172</id>
    <name>Stun</name>
    <text>Target creature can't block this turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"They certainly are well protected. Too bad for them they're not well balanced."
—Sisay</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0173</id>
    <name>Tectonic Instability</name>
    <text>Whenever a land enters the battlefield, tap all lands its controller controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"Think of the problems we'll face if you uproot entire continents," said Urza.
"I have," replied Teferi, "but the alternative is worse."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0174</id>
    <name>Thunderscape Apprentice</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}: Target player loses 1 life.
{G}, {T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0175</id>
    <name>Thunderscape Master</name>
    <text>{B}{B}, {T}: Target player loses 2 life and you gain 2 life.
{G}{G}, {T}: Creatures you control get +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0176</id>
    <name>Tribal Flames</name>
    <text>Domain — Tribal Flames deals X damage to target creature or player, where X is the number of basic land types among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Fire is the universal language."
—Jhoira, master artificer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0177</id>
    <name>Turf Wound</name>
    <text>Target player can't play land cards this turn.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I can't imagine how anyone lives in Shiv, let alone why they choose to stay."
—Sisay</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0178</id>
    <name>Urza's Rage</name>
    <text>Kicker {8}{R} (You may pay an additional {8}{R} as you cast this spell.)
Urza's Rage can't be countered by spells or abilities.
Urza's Rage deals 3 damage to target creature or player. If Urza's Rage was kicked, instead it deals 10 damage to that creature or player and the damage can't be prevented.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0179</id>
    <name>Viashino Grappler</name>
    <text>{G}: Viashino Grappler gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"They've returned for the mana rig, but it no longer belongs to them."
—Viashino bey</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0180</id>
    <name>Zap</name>
    <text>Zap deals 1 damage to target creature or player.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"All this time I thought Squee was useless," chuckled Sisay. "Who knew he'd be such a good shot?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0181</id>
    <name>Aggressive Urge</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The power of the wild, concentrated in a single charge.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0182</id>
    <name>Bind</name>
    <text>Counter target activated ability. (Mana abilities can't be targeted.)
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"The battlefield is cluttered enough. Be still."
—Multani, maro-sorcerer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0183</id>
    <name>Blurred Mongoose</name>
    <text>Blurred Mongoose can't be countered.
Shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The mongoose blew out its candle and was asleep in bed before the room went dark."
—Llanowar fable</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0184</id>
    <name>Canopy Surge</name>
    <text>Kicker {2} (You may pay an additional {2} as you cast this spell.)
Canopy Surge deals 1 damage to each creature with flying and each player. If Canopy Surge was kicked, it deals 4 damage to each creature with flying and each player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0185</id>
    <name>Elfhame Sanctuary</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may search your library for a basic land card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. If you do, you skip your draw step this turn and shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0186</id>
    <name>Elvish Champion</name>
    <text>Other Elf creatures get +1/+1 and have forestwalk. (They're unblockable as long as defending player controls a Forest.)</text>
    <flavorText>"For what are leaves but countless blades
To fight a countless foe on high."
—Skyshroud hymn</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0187</id>
    <name>Explosive Growth</name>
    <text>Kicker {5} (You may pay an additional {5} as you cast this spell.)
Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn. If Explosive Growth was kicked, that creature gets +5/+5 until end of turn instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0188</id>
    <name>Fertile Ground</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds one mana of any color to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>As Phyrexians descended, Multani paused to reflect on the beauty that might never be seen again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0189</id>
    <name>Harrow</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Harrow, sacrifice a land.
Search your library for up to two basic land cards and put them onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>No spot in nature is truly barren.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0190</id>
    <name>Jade Leech</name>
    <text>Green spells you cast cost {G} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>"It took magic to extract one of the stones and five people to carry it."
—Tolarian research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0191</id>
    <name>Kavu Chameleon</name>
    <text>Kavu Chameleon can't be countered.
{G}: Kavu Chameleon becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"They weren't part of my plan, but Gaea insisted."
—Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0192</id>
    <name>Kavu Climber</name>
    <text>When Kavu Climber enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The appearance of the first kavu surprised Multani. As they continued to emerge, he no longer had any doubts about Yavimaya's ability to defend herself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0193</id>
    <name>Kavu Lair</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature with power 4 or greater enters the battlefield, its controller draws a card.</text>
    <flavorText>As a dark rain of Phyrexians fell from the sky, fountains of kavu erupted from the ground.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0194</id>
    <name>Kavu Titan</name>
    <text>Kicker {2}{G} (You may pay an additional {2}{G} as you cast this spell.)
If Kavu Titan was kicked, it enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it and with trample.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0195</id>
    <name>Llanowar Cavalry</name>
    <text>{W}: Llanowar Cavalry gains vigilance until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>For the first time, elves welcomed Benalish soldiers into the forest with something other than arrows.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0196</id>
    <name>Llanowar Elite</name>
    <text>Kicker {8} (You may pay an additional {8} as you cast this spell.)
Trample
If Llanowar Elite was kicked, it enters the battlefield with five +1/+1 counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0197</id>
    <name>Llanowar Vanguard</name>
    <text>{T}: Llanowar Vanguard gets +0/+4 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Llanowar rallied around Eladamri's banner and united in his name.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0198</id>
    <name>Might Weaver</name>
    <text>{2}: Target red or white creature gains trample until end of turn. (If the creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Let my strength harden your resolve."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0199</id>
    <name>Molimo, Maro-Sorcerer</name>
    <text>Trample (If this creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)
Molimo, Maro-Sorcerer's power and toughness are each equal to the number of lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"The world calls and I answer."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0200</id>
    <name>Nomadic Elf</name>
    <text>{1}{G}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"I've journeyed across Dominaria. Phyrexians are everywhere. Plague is everywhere. There's no place left to hide."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0201</id>
    <name>Pincer Spider</name>
    <text>Kicker {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell.)
Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)
If Pincer Spider was kicked, it enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0202</id>
    <name>Pulse of Llanowar</name>
    <text>If a basic land you control is tapped for mana, it produces mana of a color of your choice instead of any other type.</text>
    <flavorText>"Gaea's memory is eternal, and she exists in all things."
—Molimo, maro-sorcerer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0203</id>
    <name>Quirion Elves</name>
    <text>As Quirion Elves enters the battlefield, choose a color.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add one mana of the chosen color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0204</id>
    <name>Quirion Sentinel</name>
    <text>When Quirion Sentinel enters the battlefield, add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>All elvenkind stood against Phyrexia. The Quirion nation deployed its most spiritual adepts, who wielded the power of their native soil.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0205</id>
    <name>Quirion Trailblazer</name>
    <text>When Quirion Trailblazer enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"All that matters is the path ahead."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0206</id>
    <name>Restock</name>
    <text>Return two target cards from your graveyard to your hand. Exile Restock.</text>
    <flavorText>"We hid such stockpiles all over Rath. We should continue that practice here."
—Lin Sivvi</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0207</id>
    <name>Rooting Kavu</name>
    <text>When Rooting Kavu is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may exile it. If you do, shuffle all creature cards from your graveyard into your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0208</id>
    <name>Saproling Infestation</name>
    <text>Whenever a player kicks a spell, you put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"My army took centuries to gather," remarked Urza. "Yavimaya seems to conjure hers out of thin air."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0209</id>
    <name>Saproling Symbiosis</name>
    <text>You may cast Saproling Symbiosis any time you could cast an instant if you pay {2} more to cast it.
Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield for each creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0210</id>
    <name>Scouting Trek</name>
    <text>Search your library for any number of basic land cards. Reveal those cards, then shuffle your library and put them on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have chosen my path. Who will walk it with me?"
—Eladamri</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0211</id>
    <name>Serpentine Kavu</name>
    <text>{R}: Serpentine Kavu gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Under Yavimaya's peaceful facade beat the hearts of many savage beasts.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0212</id>
    <name>Sulam Djinn</name>
    <text>Trample
Sulam Djinn gets -2/-2 as long as green is the most common color among all permanents or is tied for most common.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0213</id>
    <name>Tangle</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.
Each attacking creature doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>Gaea battles rampant death with abundant life.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0214</id>
    <name>Thicket Elemental</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{G} (You may pay an additional {1}{G} as you cast this spell.)
When Thicket Elemental enters the battlefield, if it was kicked, you may reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal a creature card. If you do, put that card onto the battlefield and shuffle all other cards revealed this way into your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0215</id>
    <name>Thornscape Apprentice</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Tap target creature.
{R}, {T}: Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0216</id>
    <name>Thornscape Master</name>
    <text>{R}{R}, {T}: Thornscape Master deals 2 damage to target creature.
{W}{W}, {T}: Target creature gains protection from the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0217</id>
    <name>Tranquility</name>
    <text>Destroy all enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>The plagues robbed Dominaria of all but its dreams. Eladamri hoped dreams were enough.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0218</id>
    <name>Treefolk Healer</name>
    <text>{2}{W}, {T}: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Protected by druids for untold centuries, the forest began to return the favor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0219</id>
    <name>Utopia Tree</name>
    <text>{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The fruit of this fabled tree takes on the flavor of whatever food you love most.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0220</id>
    <name>Verdeloth the Ancient</name>
    <text>Kicker {X} (You may pay an additional {X} as you cast this spell.)
Saproling creatures and other Treefolk creatures get +1/+1.
When Verdeloth the Ancient enters the battlefield, if it was kicked, put X 1/1 green Saproling creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0221</id>
    <name>Verduran Emissary</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{R} (You may pay an additional {1}{R} as you cast this spell.)
When Verduran Emissary enters the battlefield, if it was kicked, destroy target artifact. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0222</id>
    <name>Vigorous Charge</name>
    <text>Kicker {W} (You may pay an additional {W} as you cast this spell.)
Target creature gains trample until end of turn. Whenever that creature deals combat damage this turn, if Vigorous Charge was kicked, you gain life equal to that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0223</id>
    <name>Wallop</name>
    <text>Destroy target blue or black creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>In Yavimaya, flying low to join a battle can be a costly mistake.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0224</id>
    <name>Wandering Stream</name>
    <text>Domain — You gain 2 life for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Dominaria touches us all."
—Molimo, maro-sorcerer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0225</id>
    <name>Whip Silk</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has reach. (It can block creatures with flying.)
{G}: Return Whip Silk to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Llanowar forges weapons of steel. Yavimaya grows her weapons within.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0226</id>
    <name>Absorb</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. You gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your presumption is your downfall."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0227</id>
    <name>Æther Rift</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, discard a card at random. If you discard a creature card this way, return it from your graveyard to the battlefield unless any player pays 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0228</id>
    <name>Angelic Shield</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +0/+1.

Sacrifice Angelic Shield: Return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"If only an angel's wings could shelter us all."
—Barrin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0229</id>
    <name>Armadillo Cloak</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and has trample.
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Don't laugh. It works."
—Yavimaya ranger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0230</id>
    <name>Armored Guardian</name>
    <text>{1}{W}{W}: Target creature you control gains protection from the color of your choice until end of turn.
{1}{U}{U}: Armored Guardian gains shroud until end of turn. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0231</id>
    <name>Artifact Mutation</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact. It can't be regenerated. Put X 1/1 green Saproling creature tokens onto the battlefield, where X is that artifact's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"From shards and splinters I call forth my living horde."
—Molimo, maro-sorcerer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0232</id>
    <name>Aura Mutation</name>
    <text>Destroy target enchantment. Put X 1/1 green Saproling creature tokens onto the battlefield, where X is that enchantment's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"Life can be found in all things, even things unnatural."
—Multani, maro-sorcerer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0233</id>
    <name>Aura Shards</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature enters the battlefield under your control, you may destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>Gaea forged her soldiers into self-wielding weapons that struck down all impurities.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0234</id>
    <name>Backlash</name>
    <text>Tap target untapped creature. That creature deals damage equal to its power to its controller.</text>
    <flavorText>Darigaaz decided his foe would be more useful as a weapon.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0235</id>
    <name>Barrin's Spite</name>
    <text>Choose two target creatures controlled by the same player. Their controller chooses and sacrifices one of them. Return the other to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Only vengeance matters now."
—Barrin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0236</id>
    <name>Blazing Specter</name>
    <text>Flying, haste
Whenever Blazing Specter deals combat damage to a player, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0237</id>
    <name>Captain Sisay</name>
    <text>{T}: Search your library for a legendary card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Her leadership forged the Weatherlight's finest crew.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0238</id>
    <name>Cauldron Dance</name>
    <text>Cast Cauldron Dance only during combat.
Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield. That creature gains haste. Return it to your hand at the beginning of the next end step.
You may put a creature card from your hand onto the battlefield. That creature gains haste. Its controller sacrifices it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0239</id>
    <name>Charging Troll</name>
    <text>Vigilance
{G}: Regenerate Charging Troll.</text>
    <flavorText>They stop for nothing, not even the end of a battle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0240</id>
    <name>Cinder Shade</name>
    <text>{B}: Cinder Shade gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
{R}, Sacrifice Cinder Shade: Cinder Shade deals damage equal to its power to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0241</id>
    <name>Coalition Victory</name>
    <text>You win the game if you control a land of each basic land type and a creature of each color.</text>
    <flavorText>"You can build a perfect machine out of imperfect parts."
—Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0242</id>
    <name>Crosis, the Purger</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Crosis, the Purger deals combat damage to a player, you may pay {2}{B}. If you do, choose a color, then that player reveals his or her hand and discards all cards of that color.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0243</id>
    <name>Darigaaz, the Igniter</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Darigaaz, the Igniter deals combat damage to a player, you may pay {2}{R}. If you do, choose a color, then that player reveals his or her hand and Darigaaz deals damage to the player equal to the number of cards of that color revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0244</id>
    <name>Dromar, the Banisher</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Dromar, the Banisher deals combat damage to a player, you may pay {2}{U}. If you do, choose a color, then return all creatures of that color to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0245</id>
    <name>Dueling Grounds</name>
    <text>No more than one creature can attack each turn.
No more than one creature can block each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"You think you can stop me?" hissed Tsabo.
"I think I can kill you," replied Gerrard.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0246</id>
    <name>Fires of Yavimaya</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have haste.
Sacrifice Fires of Yavimaya: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0247</id>
    <name>Frenzied Tilling</name>
    <text>Destroy target land. Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Beneath her scars, Dominaria's beauty yet shines."
—Multani, maro-sorcerer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0248</id>
    <name>Galina's Knight</name>
    <text>Protection from red</text>
    <flavorText>"Are they on our side?" asked Sisay.
"If they kill Phyrexians they are," replied Gerrard.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0249</id>
    <name>Hanna, Ship's Navigator</name>
    <text>{1}{W}{U}, {T}: Return target artifact or enchantment card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"I never thought I'd spend my life fighting. I'm a maker, not a destroyer."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0250</id>
    <name>Heroes' Reunion</name>
    <text>Target player gains 7 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"You helped save my people from a Phyrexian fate. Did you think I wouldn't return the favor?"
—Eladamri, to Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0251</id>
    <name>Horned Cheetah</name>
    <text>Whenever Horned Cheetah deals damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>"I think she wants us to eat it," said Squee, staring at the oily carcass the cheetah had dragged to their fire.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0252</id>
    <name>Hunting Kavu</name>
    <text>{1}{R}{G}, {T}: Exile Hunting Kavu and target creature without flying that's attacking you.</text>
    <flavorText>Dominarians gladly fought alongside kavu . . . until the kavu figured out some Dominarians were quite tasty.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0253</id>
    <name>Kangee, Aerie Keeper</name>
    <text>Kicker {X}{2} (You may pay an additional {X}{2} as you cast this spell.)
Flying
When Kangee, Aerie Keeper enters the battlefield, if it was kicked, put X feather counters on it.
Other Bird creatures get +1/+1 for each feather counter on Kangee, Aerie Keeper.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0254</id>
    <name>Llanowar Knight</name>
    <text>Protection from black</text>
    <flavorText>Her armor and steed were borrowed, but her courage was hers alone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0255</id>
    <name>Lobotomy</name>
    <text>Target player reveals his or her hand, then you choose a card other than a basic land card from it. Search that player's graveyard, hand, and library for all cards with the same name as the chosen card and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0256</id>
    <name>Meteor Storm</name>
    <text>{2}{R}{G}, Discard two cards at random: Meteor Storm deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>The storm wasn't an omen. It was the fulfillment of one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0257</id>
    <name>Noble Panther</name>
    <text>{1}: Noble Panther gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Unlike many hunters, these panthers have no need for camouflage. They're fast enough to catch any prey.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0258</id>
    <name>Ordered Migration</name>
    <text>Domain — Put a 1/1 blue Bird creature token with flying onto the battlefield for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Birds reach all parts of the world," said Barrin. "They will make excellent scouts."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0259</id>
    <name>Overabundance</name>
    <text>Whenever a player taps a land for mana, that player adds one mana to his or her mana pool of any type that land produced, and Overabundance deals 1 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0260</id>
    <name>Plague Spores</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature and target land. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Breathe deep, Dominaria. Breathe deep and die."
—Tsabo Tavoc, Phyrexian general</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0261</id>
    <name>Pyre Zombie</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if Pyre Zombie is in your graveyard, you may pay {1}{B}{B}. If you do, return Pyre Zombie from your graveyard to your hand.
{1}{R}{R}, Sacrifice Pyre Zombie: Pyre Zombie deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0262</id>
    <name>Raging Kavu</name>
    <text>Flash
Haste</text>
    <flavorText>It took Yavimaya a thousand years to breed them, but it took only seconds for them to prove their worth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0263</id>
    <name>Reckless Assault</name>
    <text>{1}, Pay 2 life: Reckless Assault deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"How will you fight an enemy that cares nothing for itself?"
—The Blind Seer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0264</id>
    <name>Recoil</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand. Then that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Anything sent into a plagued world is bound to come back infected.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0265</id>
    <name>Reviving Vapors</name>
    <text>Reveal the top three cards of your library and put one of them into your hand. You gain life equal to that card's converted mana cost. Put all other cards revealed this way into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0266</id>
    <name>Riptide Crab</name>
    <text>Vigilance
When Riptide Crab is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>It sleeps with its claws open.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0267</id>
    <name>Rith, the Awakener</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Rith, the Awakener deals combat damage to a player, you may pay {2}{G}. If you do, choose a color, then put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield for each permanent of that color.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0268</id>
    <name>Sabertooth Nishoba</name>
    <text>Trample, protection from blue and from red</text>
    <flavorText>They sneer at the terrestrial dangers found on peaks and shores, eager to prove themselves against new and even mightier foes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0269</id>
    <name>Samite Archer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.
{T}: Samite Archer deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"I can preserve ten lives by taking one."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0270</id>
    <name>Seer's Vision</name>
    <text>Your opponents play with their hands revealed.
Sacrifice Seer's Vision: Look at target player's hand and choose a card from it. That player discards that card. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0271</id>
    <name>Shivan Zombie</name>
    <text>Protection from white</text>
    <flavorText>Barbarians long for a glorious death in battle. Phyrexia was eager to grant that wish.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0272</id>
    <name>Simoon</name>
    <text>Simoon deals 1 damage to each creature target opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Hot wind whipped up as if the weather itself wanted to fight Phyrexians.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0273</id>
    <name>Sleeper's Robe</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has fear. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
Whenever enchanted creature deals combat damage to an opponent, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0274</id>
    <name>Slinking Serpent</name>
    <text>Forestwalk</text>
    <flavorText>It winds its way through undergrowth as easily as it swims through shallows.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0275</id>
    <name>Smoldering Tar</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, target player loses 1 life.
Sacrifice Smoldering Tar: Smoldering Tar deals 4 damage to target creature. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0276</id>
    <name>Spinal Embrace</name>
    <text>Cast Spinal Embrace only during combat.
Untap target creature you don't control and gain control of it. It gains haste until end of turn. At the beginning of the next end step, sacrifice it. If you do, you gain life equal to its toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0277</id>
    <name>Stalking Assassin</name>
    <text>{3}{U}, {T}: Tap target creature.
{3}{B}, {T}: Destroy target tapped creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0278</id>
    <name>Sterling Grove</name>
    <text>Other enchantments you control have shroud. (They can't be the targets of spells or abilities.)
{1}, Sacrifice Sterling Grove: Search your library for an enchantment card and reveal that card. Shuffle your library, then put the card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0279</id>
    <name>Teferi's Moat</name>
    <text>As Teferi's Moat enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Creatures of the chosen color without flying can't attack you.</text>
    <flavorText>"Isolation is not the answer."
—Urza, to Teferi.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0280</id>
    <name>Treva, the Renewer</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Treva, the Renewer deals combat damage to a player, you may pay {2}{W}. If you do, choose a color, then you gain 1 life for each permanent of that color.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0281</id>
    <name>Tsabo Tavoc</name>
    <text>First strike, protection from legendary creatures
{B}{B}, {T}: Destroy target legendary creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"I might almost pity my enemies—if it wasn't so amusing to watch them die."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0282</id>
    <name>Undermine</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. Its controller loses 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Which would you like first, the insult or the injury?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0283</id>
    <name>Urborg Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
Urborg Drake attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>Relentless as the sea, remorseless as death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0284</id>
    <name>Vicious Kavu</name>
    <text>Whenever Vicious Kavu attacks, it gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>As battle raged in Shiv, a strange new ally appeared from below the ravaged ground.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0285</id>
    <name>Vile Consumption</name>
    <text>All creatures have "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice this creature unless you pay 1 life."</text>
    <flavorText>The plague moved faster than an army and was far more deadly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0286</id>
    <name>Vodalian Zombie</name>
    <text>Protection from green</text>
    <flavorText>"Every last one of you will become my servant. It's a shame you won't live to see the irony."
—Tsabo Tavoc, Phyrexian general</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0287</id>
    <name>Void</name>
    <text>Choose a number. Destroy all artifacts and creatures with converted mana cost equal to that number. Then target player reveals his or her hand and discards all nonland cards with converted mana cost equal to the number.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0288</id>
    <name>Voracious Cobra</name>
    <text>First strike

Whenever Voracious Cobra deals combat damage to a creature, destroy that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>There's no known antidote for the cobra's venom . . . or its appetite.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0289</id>
    <name>Wings of Hope</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+3 and has flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Urza knew Phyrexians would come through the air and sent his soldiers to greet them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0290</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Barbarian</name>
    <text>Protection from blue</text>
    <flavorText>Not all elves embrace the pastoral life. Some still roam the forest's edge, forever making war against their hated enemies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0291</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Kavu</name>
    <text>Yavimaya Kavu's power is equal to the number of red creatures on the battlefield.
Yavimaya Kavu's toughness is equal to the number of green creatures on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Kavu hunt prey in packs—one kavu hunts a pack of prey.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0292</id>
    <name>Deliver</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0293</id>
    <name>Deliver</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0294</id>
    <name>Stand</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0295</id>
    <name>Stand</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0296</id>
    <name>Malice</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0297</id>
    <name>Malice</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0298</id>
    <name>Spite</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0299</id>
    <name>Spite</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0300</id>
    <name>Pain</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0301</id>
    <name>Pain</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0302</id>
    <name>Suffering</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0303</id>
    <name>Suffering</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0304</id>
    <name>Assault</name>
    <text>Put a 3/3 green Elephant creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0305</id>
    <name>Assault</name>
    <text>Put a 3/3 green Elephant creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0306</id>
    <name>Battery</name>
    <text>Put a 3/3 green Elephant creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0307</id>
    <name>Battery</name>
    <text>Put a 3/3 green Elephant creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0308</id>
    <name>Wane</name>
    <text>Destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0309</id>
    <name>Wane</name>
    <text>Destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0310</id>
    <name>Wax</name>
    <text>Destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0311</id>
    <name>Wax</name>
    <text>Destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0312</id>
    <name>Alloy Golem</name>
    <text>As Alloy Golem enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Alloy Golem is the chosen color. (It's still an artifact.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We turned old weapons into new warriors."
—Jhoira, master artificer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0313</id>
    <name>Bloodstone Cameo</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"The stone whispers to me of dragon's fire and darkness. I wish I'd never pried it from the figurehead of that sunken Keldon longship."
—Isel, master carver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0314</id>
    <name>Chromatic Sphere</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Chromatic Sphere: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let insight and energy be your guides."
—The Blind Seer, to Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0315</id>
    <name>Crosis's Attendant</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice Crosis's Attendant: Add {U}{B}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Crosis is the eye of the ur-dragon, piercing illusion and darkness."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0316</id>
    <name>Darigaaz's Attendant</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice Darigaaz's Attendant: Add {B}{R}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Darigaaz is the breath of the ur-dragon, burning away the burdens of mortality."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0317</id>
    <name>Drake-Skull Cameo</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"A strange skull was turned up by an Ephran farmer's plow. I traded a copper ring for the ‘ox skull.' It resonates of the sea and danger."
—Isel, master carver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0318</id>
    <name>Dromar's Attendant</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice Dromar's Attendant: Add {W}{U}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Dromar is the wings of the ur-dragon, sweeping away all opposition."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0319</id>
    <name>Juntu Stakes</name>
    <text>Creatures with power 1 or less don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those who can't survive are of no consequence."
—Tsabo Tavoc</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0320</id>
    <name>Lotus Guardian</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Lotus fields are too valuable to leave undefended.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0321</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Altar</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your life was meaningless, but your death will glorify Yawgmoth."
—Tsabo Tavoc</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0322</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Lens</name>
    <text>{T}, Pay 1 life: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"There's nothing I wouldn't give to achieve victory. Can you say the same?"
—Tsabo Tavoc, to Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0323</id>
    <name>Planar Portal</name>
    <text>{6}, {T}: Search your library for a card and put that card into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The sky split, and the air crackled and roiled. The Phyrexian invasion of Dominaria had finally begun.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0324</id>
    <name>Power Armor</name>
    <text>Domain — {3}, {T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Great peril demands formidable weaponry."
—Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0325</id>
    <name>Rith's Attendant</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice Rith's Attendant: Add {R}{G}{W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Rith is the claw of the ur-dragon, scattering seeds of devastation."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0326</id>
    <name>Seashell Cameo</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Today a seashell fell from the empty sky here in Kinymu, a hundred leagues from the sea. I'm torn—shall I carve a woman or a bird?"
—Isel, master carver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0327</id>
    <name>Sparring Golem</name>
    <text>Whenever Sparring Golem becomes blocked, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Part drill sergeant, part training dummy," thought Gerrard. "I hope it can stand up to a real war."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0328</id>
    <name>Tek</name>
    <text>Tek gets +0/+2 as long as you control a Plains, has flying as long as you control an Island, gets +2/+0 as long as you control a Swamp, has first strike as long as you control a Mountain, and has trample as long as you control a Forest.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0329</id>
    <name>Tigereye Cameo</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"An elvish adventurer unearthed this stone in Jolrael's jungle. Now it's truly fit for display in one of her palaces."
—Isel, master carver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0330</id>
    <name>Treva's Attendant</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice Treva's Attendant: Add {G}{W}{U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Treva is the voice of the ur-dragon, demanding cries of worship."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0331</id>
    <name>Troll-Horn Cameo</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"I found a troll-horn fragment in the wooded foothills of Hurloon, and it keeps growing larger. I wonder, is the horn recreating itself or the troll?"
—Isel, master carver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0332</id>
    <name>Tsabo's Web</name>
    <text>When Tsabo's Web enters the battlefield, draw a card.
Each land with an activated ability that isn't a mana ability doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0333</id>
    <name>Urza's Filter</name>
    <text>Multicolored spells cost up to {2} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's a tool for aiding my other tools," explained Urza. "Now they'll work in harmony."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0334</id>
    <name>Ancient Spring</name>
    <text>Ancient Spring enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Ancient Spring: Add {W}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0335</id>
    <name>Archaeological Dig</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{T}, Sacrifice Archaeological Dig: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0336</id>
    <name>Coastal Tower</name>
    <text>Coastal Tower enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The Capashen built the highest towers in Benalia to afford themselves the best view.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0337</id>
    <name>Elfhame Palace</name>
    <text>Elfhame Palace enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Llanowar has seven elfhames, or kingdoms, each with its own ruler. Their palaces are objects of awe, wonder, and envy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0338</id>
    <name>Geothermal Crevice</name>
    <text>Geothermal Crevice enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Geothermal Crevice: Add {B}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0339</id>
    <name>Irrigation Ditch</name>
    <text>Irrigation Ditch enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Irrigation Ditch: Add {G}{U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0340</id>
    <name>Keldon Necropolis</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{4}{R}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Keldon Necropolis deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0341</id>
    <name>Salt Marsh</name>
    <text>Salt Marsh enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Only death breeds in stagnant water.
—Urborg saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0342</id>
    <name>Shivan Oasis</name>
    <text>Shivan Oasis enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Only the hardiest explorers survive to eat the fruit.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0343</id>
    <name>Sulfur Vent</name>
    <text>Sulfur Vent enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Sulfur Vent: Add {U}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0344</id>
    <name>Tinder Farm</name>
    <text>Tinder Farm enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Tinder Farm: Add {R}{W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0345</id>
    <name>Urborg Volcano</name>
    <text>Urborg Volcano enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Deep in the heart of Urborg lie massive volcanoes whose thick black smoke covers the land with perpetual darkness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0346</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0347</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0348</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0349</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0350</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0351</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0352</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0353</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0354</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0355</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0356</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0357</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0358</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0359</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0360</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0361</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0362</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0363</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0364</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>INV0365</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>