<cards name="Legions">
  <item>
    <id>LGN0001</id>
    <name>Akroma, Angel of Wrath</name>
    <text>Flying, first strike, vigilance, trample, haste, protection from black and from red</text>
    <flavorText>"No rest. No mercy. No matter what."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0002</id>
    <name>Akroma's Devoted</name>
    <text>Cleric creatures have vigilance.</text>
    <flavorText>Akroma asked for only one thing from her troops: unwavering, unconditional loyalty.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0003</id>
    <name>Aven Redeemer</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Redeemers rise with the sun, and the spirits of the people rise with them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0004</id>
    <name>Aven Warhawk</name>
    <text>Amplify 1 (As this creature enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on it for each Bird and/or Soldier card you reveal in your hand.)
Flying</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0005</id>
    <name>Beacon of Destiny</name>
    <text>{T}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, that damage is dealt to Beacon of Destiny instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"We all borrowed life from the Ancestor to exist in this world. Today, I repay that debt."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0006</id>
    <name>Celestial Gatekeeper</name>
    <text>Flying
When Celestial Gatekeeper is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, exile it, then return up to two target Bird and/or Cleric permanent cards from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0007</id>
    <name>Cloudreach Cavalry</name>
    <text>As long as you control a Bird, Cloudreach Cavalry gets +2/+2 and has flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's easy to lose sight of hope until you gaze out from my vantage point."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0008</id>
    <name>Daru Mender</name>
    <text>Morph {W} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Daru Mender is turned face up, regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0009</id>
    <name>Daru Sanctifier</name>
    <text>Morph {1}{W} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Daru Sanctifier is turned face up, destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0010</id>
    <name>Daru Stinger</name>
    <text>Amplify 1 (As this creature enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on it for each Human and/or Soldier card you reveal in your hand.)
{T}: Daru Stinger deals damage equal to the number of +1/+1 counters on it to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0011</id>
    <name>Defender of the Order</name>
    <text>Morph {W}{W} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Defender of the Order is turned face up, creatures you control get +0/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0012</id>
    <name>Deftblade Elite</name>
    <text>Provoke (When this attacks, you may have target creature defending player controls untap and block it if able.)
{1}{W}: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by Deftblade Elite this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0013</id>
    <name>Essence Sliver</name>
    <text>Whenever a Sliver deals damage, its controller gains that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>The slivers would survive, even at the expense of every other creature on Otaria.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0014</id>
    <name>Gempalm Avenger</name>
    <text>Cycling {2}{W} ({2}{W}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
When you cycle Gempalm Avenger, Soldier creatures get +1/+1 and gain first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0015</id>
    <name>Glowrider</name>
    <text>Noncreature spells cost {1} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is not yet time."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0016</id>
    <name>Liege of the Axe</name>
    <text>Vigilance
Morph {1}{W} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Liege of the Axe is turned face up, untap it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0017</id>
    <name>Lowland Tracker</name>
    <text>First strike
Provoke (When this attacks, you may have target creature defending player controls untap and block it if able.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I feed my hatred to the righteous and they join my crusade."
—Akroma, angelic avenger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0018</id>
    <name>Planar Guide</name>
    <text>{3}{W}, Exile Planar Guide: Exile all creatures. At the beginning of the next end step, return those cards to the battlefield under their owners' control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Every moment has its own savior."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0019</id>
    <name>Plated Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures get +0/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>Overcoming extinction has only made the slivers more determined to live.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0020</id>
    <name>Starlight Invoker</name>
    <text>{7}{W}: You gain 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The Mirari glows in her eyes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0021</id>
    <name>Stoic Champion</name>
    <text>Whenever a player cycles a card, Stoic Champion gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>His outer calm belies his inner fury.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0022</id>
    <name>Sunstrike Legionnaire</name>
    <text>Sunstrike Legionnaire doesn't untap during your untap step.
Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, untap Sunstrike Legionnaire.
{T}: Tap target creature with converted mana cost 3 or less.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0023</id>
    <name>Swooping Talon</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}: Swooping Talon loses flying until end of turn.
Provoke (When this attacks, you may have target creature defending player controls untap and block it if able.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0024</id>
    <name>Wall of Hope</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Whenever Wall of Hope is dealt damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>"What cage would you rather be inside of than out?"
—Daru riddle</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0025</id>
    <name>Ward Sliver</name>
    <text>As Ward Sliver enters the battlefield, choose a color.
All Slivers have protection from the chosen color.</text>
    <flavorText>The first wave of slivers perished from the Riptide wizards' magic. The second wave shrugged off their spells like water.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0026</id>
    <name>Whipgrass Entangler</name>
    <text>{1}{W}: Until end of turn, target creature gains "This creature can't attack or block unless its controller pays {1} for each Cleric on the battlefield."</text>
    <flavorText>"Now that I have your attention, perhaps I can tell you of the Order."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0027</id>
    <name>White Knight</name>
    <text>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)
Protection from black (This creature can't be blocked, targeted, dealt damage, or enchanted by anything black.)</text>
    <flavorText>In the wretched depths of the Grand Coliseum, his soul shines like a single torch blazing in the night.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0028</id>
    <name>Windborn Muse</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Creatures can't attack you unless their controller pays {2} for each creature he or she controls that's attacking you.</text>
    <flavorText>"Her voice is justice, clear and relentless."
—Akroma, angelic avenger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0029</id>
    <name>Wingbeat Warrior</name>
    <text>Flying
Morph {2}{W} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Wingbeat Warrior is turned face up, target creature gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0030</id>
    <name>Aven Envoy</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Their grieving faces tell far more than a list of casualties ever could.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0031</id>
    <name>Cephalid Pathmage</name>
    <text>Cephalid Pathmage is unblockable.
{T}, Sacrifice Cephalid Pathmage: Target creature is unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Pathmages can open doors that aren't even there.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0032</id>
    <name>Chromeshell Crab</name>
    <text>Morph {4}{U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Chromeshell Crab is turned face up, you may exchange control of target creature you control and target creature an opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0033</id>
    <name>Covert Operative</name>
    <text>Covert Operative is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>Some spies seek clarity. Others seek transparency.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0034</id>
    <name>Crookclaw Elder</name>
    <text>Flying
Tap two untapped Birds you control: Draw a card.
Tap two untapped Wizards you control: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0035</id>
    <name>Dermoplasm</name>
    <text>Flying
Morph {2}{U}{U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Dermoplasm is turned face up, you may put a creature card with morph from your hand onto the battlefield face up. If you do, return Dermoplasm to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0036</id>
    <name>Dreamborn Muse</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player puts the top X cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard, where X is the number of cards in his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Her voice is insight, piercing and true."
—Ixidor, reality sculptor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0037</id>
    <name>Echo Tracer</name>
    <text>Morph {2}{U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Echo Tracer is turned face up, return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0038</id>
    <name>Fugitive Wizard</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Many wizards came to the Riptide Project hoping to return home with answers. Most, however, wouldn't return home at all.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0039</id>
    <name>Gempalm Sorcerer</name>
    <text>Cycling {2}{U} ({2}{U}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
When you cycle Gempalm Sorcerer, Wizard creatures gain flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0040</id>
    <name>Glintwing Invoker</name>
    <text>{7}{U}: Glintwing Invoker gets +3/+3 and gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Mirari flares in his mind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0041</id>
    <name>Keeneye Aven</name>
    <text>Flying
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I have no need of a map. The very continent itself guides my way."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0042</id>
    <name>Keeper of the Nine Gales</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}, Tap two untapped Birds you control: Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"You cannot fight the storm."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0043</id>
    <name>Master of the Veil</name>
    <text>Morph {2}{U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Master of the Veil is turned face up, you may turn target creature with morph face down.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0044</id>
    <name>Merchant of Secrets</name>
    <text>When Merchant of Secrets enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>To scrape out a living in Aphetto, wizards are reduced to selling rumors, lies, forgeries, or—if they get desperate enough—the truth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0045</id>
    <name>Mistform Seaswift</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}: Mistform Seaswift becomes the creature type of your choice until end of turn.
Morph {1}{U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0046</id>
    <name>Mistform Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{1}: This permanent becomes the creature type of your choice in addition to its other types until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>Taking the form of a junior researcher, the first sliver slipped out of Riptide.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0047</id>
    <name>Mistform Ultimus</name>
    <text>Mistform Ultimus is every creature type (even if this card isn't on the battlefield).</text>
    <flavorText>It may wear your face, but its mind is its own.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0048</id>
    <name>Mistform Wakecaster</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}: Mistform Wakecaster becomes the creature type of your choice until end of turn.
{2}{U}{U}, {T}: Choose a creature type. Each creature you control becomes that type until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0049</id>
    <name>Primoc Escapee</name>
    <text>Flying
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>Though a completely artificial species, primocs are a natural fit for the skies of Otaria.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0050</id>
    <name>Riptide Director</name>
    <text>{2}{U}{U}, {T}: Draw a card for each Wizard you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Those who lead others to wisdom become the wisest themselves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0051</id>
    <name>Riptide Mangler</name>
    <text>{1}{U}: Change Riptide Mangler's power to target creature's power. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>It wants you to be its chum.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0052</id>
    <name>Shifting Sliver</name>
    <text>Slivers can't be blocked except by Slivers.</text>
    <flavorText>Once the last few slivers the Riptide Project controlled were dead, there was nothing to keep the island from being completely overrun.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0053</id>
    <name>Synapse Sliver</name>
    <text>Whenever a Sliver deals combat damage to a player, its controller may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Species XR17 feeds upon the mental energies of its victims. This explains why the goblins remain unaffected."
—Riptide Project researcher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0054</id>
    <name>Voidmage Apprentice</name>
    <text>Morph {2}{U}{U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Voidmage Apprentice is turned face up, counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0055</id>
    <name>Wall of Deceit</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{3}: Turn Wall of Deceit face down.
Morph {U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0056</id>
    <name>Warped Researcher</name>
    <text>Whenever a player cycles a card, Warped Researcher gains flying and shroud until end of turn. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>New insights yield new senses.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0057</id>
    <name>Weaver of Lies</name>
    <text>Morph {4}{U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Weaver of Lies is turned face up, turn any number of target creatures with morph other than Weaver of Lies face down.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0058</id>
    <name>Willbender</name>
    <text>Morph {1}{U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Willbender is turned face up, change the target of target spell or ability with a single target.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0059</id>
    <name>Aphetto Exterminator</name>
    <text>Morph {3}{B} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Aphetto Exterminator is turned face up, target creature gets -3/-3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0060</id>
    <name>Bane of the Living</name>
    <text>Morph {X}{B}{B} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Bane of the Living is turned face up, all creatures get -X/-X until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0061</id>
    <name>Blood Celebrant</name>
    <text>{B}, Pay 1 life: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Their blood is the nectar that nourishes the Cabal."
—Phage the Untouchable</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0062</id>
    <name>Corpse Harvester</name>
    <text>{1}{B}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Search your library for a Zombie card and a Swamp card, reveal them, and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0063</id>
    <name>Crypt Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{T}: Regenerate target Sliver."</text>
    <flavorText>"Death couldn't contain the slivers. What made us think we could?"
—Riptide Project researcher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0064</id>
    <name>Dark Supplicant</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice three Clerics: Search your graveyard, hand, and/or library for a card named Scion of Darkness and put it onto the battlefield. If you search your library this way, shuffle it.</text>
    <flavorText>Cabal clerics serve two masters: their patriarch and their god.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0065</id>
    <name>Deathmark Prelate</name>
    <text>{2}{B}, {T}, Sacrifice a Zombie: Destroy target non-Zombie creature. It can't be regenerated. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>Death is a secret he is willing to share.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0066</id>
    <name>Drinker of Sorrow</name>
    <text>Drinker of Sorrow can't block.
Whenever Drinker of Sorrow deals combat damage, sacrifice a permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>It strikes at your soul, heedless of your prayers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0067</id>
    <name>Dripping Dead</name>
    <text>Dripping Dead can't block.
Whenever Dripping Dead deals combat damage to a creature, destroy that creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>It oozes death from every pore.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0068</id>
    <name>Earthblighter</name>
    <text>{2}{B}, {T}, Sacrifice a Goblin: Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>"A single dedicated mind can bring about the greatest destruction. That, or goblins—goblins work too."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0069</id>
    <name>Embalmed Brawler</name>
    <text>Amplify 1 (As this creature enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on it for each Zombie card you reveal in your hand.)
Whenever Embalmed Brawler attacks or blocks, you lose 1 life for each +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0070</id>
    <name>Gempalm Polluter</name>
    <text>Cycling {B}{B} ({B}{B}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
When you cycle Gempalm Polluter, you may have target player lose life equal to the number of Zombies on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0071</id>
    <name>Ghastly Remains</name>
    <text>Amplify 1 (As this creature enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on it for each Zombie card you reveal in your hand.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, if Ghastly Remains is in your graveyard, you may pay {B}{B}{B}. If you do, return Ghastly Remains to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0072</id>
    <name>Goblin Turncoat</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a Goblin: Regenerate Goblin Turncoat.</text>
    <flavorText>"Goblins won't betray their own kind for any price. They'll do it for a very specific price."
—Phage the Untouchable</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0073</id>
    <name>Graveborn Muse</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you draw X cards and you lose X life, where X is the number of Zombies you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Her voice is damnation, unyielding and certain."
—Phage the Untouchable</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0074</id>
    <name>Havoc Demon</name>
    <text>Flying
When Havoc Demon is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, all creatures get -5/-5 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A cry of pain as it enters this world. A chorus of screams as it leaves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0075</id>
    <name>Hollow Specter</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Hollow Specter deals combat damage to a player, you may pay {X}. If you do, that player reveals X cards from his or her hand and you choose one of them. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0076</id>
    <name>Infernal Caretaker</name>
    <text>Morph {3}{B} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Infernal Caretaker is turned face up, return all Zombie cards from all graveyards to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0077</id>
    <name>Noxious Ghoul</name>
    <text>Whenever Noxious Ghoul or another Zombie enters the battlefield, all non-Zombie creatures get -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Plague and death wrapped in one convenient package.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0078</id>
    <name>Phage the Untouchable</name>
    <text>When Phage the Untouchable enters the battlefield, if you didn't cast it from your hand, you lose the game.
Whenever Phage deals combat damage to a creature, destroy that creature. It can't be regenerated.
Whenever Phage deals combat damage to a player, that player loses the game.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0079</id>
    <name>Scion of Darkness</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Scion of Darkness deals combat damage to a player, you may put target creature card from that player's graveyard onto the battlefield under your control.
Cycling {3} ({3}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0080</id>
    <name>Skinthinner</name>
    <text>Morph {3}{B}{B} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Skinthinner is turned face up, destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0081</id>
    <name>Smokespew Invoker</name>
    <text>{7}{B}: Target creature gets -3/-3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Mirari festers in its flesh.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0082</id>
    <name>Sootfeather Flock</name>
    <text>Flying
Morph {3}{B} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>They pick at the remains of the city's corpse.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0083</id>
    <name>Spectral Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have "{2}: This creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>"Sure, I've seen agents of the Cabal here and there. Well, not here, and certainly not in any of the sliver labs. Oh dear, I've said too much."
—Apprentice researcher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0084</id>
    <name>Toxin Sliver</name>
    <text>Whenever a Sliver deals combat damage to a creature, destroy that creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>It doesn't need to use its venom—it just needs you to know it can.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0085</id>
    <name>Vile Deacon</name>
    <text>Whenever Vile Deacon attacks, it gets +X/+X until end of turn, where X is the number of Clerics on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Cabal and the Order really aren't that different. After all, we are both empowered by faith."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0086</id>
    <name>Withered Wretch</name>
    <text>{1}: Exile target card from a graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Once it consecrated the dead. Now it desecrates them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0087</id>
    <name>Zombie Brute</name>
    <text>Amplify 1 (As this creature enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on it for each Zombie card you reveal in your hand.)
Trample</text>
    <flavorText>Measure its determination by the screams of its prey.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0088</id>
    <name>Blade Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures get +1/+0.</text>
    <flavorText>After breaking free from the Riptide Project, the slivers quickly adapted to life on Otaria—much to the dismay of life on Otaria.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0089</id>
    <name>Bloodstoke Howler</name>
    <text>Morph {6}{R} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Bloodstoke Howler is turned face up, Beast creatures you control get +3/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0090</id>
    <name>Clickslither</name>
    <text>Haste
Sacrifice a Goblin: Clickslither gets +2/+2 and gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The least popular goblins get the outer caves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0091</id>
    <name>Crested Craghorn</name>
    <text>Haste
Provoke (When this attacks, you may have target creature defending player controls untap and block it if able.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Craghorns experience a wide range of emotions: rage, fury, anger . . ."
—Foothill guide</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0092</id>
    <name>Flamewave Invoker</name>
    <text>{7}{R}: Flamewave Invoker deals 5 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>The Mirari burns in his heart.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0093</id>
    <name>Frenetic Raptor</name>
    <text>Beasts can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>"How do you stop a raptor from charging? No, seriously Help"
—Blarg, goblin jester</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0094</id>
    <name>Gempalm Incinerator</name>
    <text>Cycling {1}{R} ({1}{R}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
When you cycle Gempalm Incinerator, you may have it deal X damage to target creature, where X is the number of Goblins on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0095</id>
    <name>Goblin Assassin</name>
    <text>Whenever Goblin Assassin or another Goblin enters the battlefield, each player flips a coin. Each player whose coin comes up tails sacrifices a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The more victims he kills, the more likely he is to get the right one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0096</id>
    <name>Goblin Clearcutter</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a Forest: Add three mana in any combination of {R} and/or {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Did you know that wood burns even better than rocks?"
—Toggo, goblin weaponsmith</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0097</id>
    <name>Goblin Dynamo</name>
    <text>{T}: Goblin Dynamo deals 1 damage to target creature or player.
{X}{R}, {T}, Sacrifice Goblin Dynamo: Goblin Dynamo deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0098</id>
    <name>Goblin Firebug</name>
    <text>When Goblin Firebug leaves the battlefield, sacrifice a land.</text>
    <flavorText>Most goblins leave behind a wake of destruction. A few goblins take one with them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0099</id>
    <name>Goblin Goon</name>
    <text>Goblin Goon can't attack unless you control more creatures than defending player.
Goblin Goon can't block unless you control more creatures than attacking player.</text>
    <flavorText>Giant-sized body. Goblin-sized brain.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0100</id>
    <name>Goblin Grappler</name>
    <text>Provoke (When this attacks, you may have target creature defending player controls untap and block it if able.)</text>
    <flavorText>Daru soldiers learned it's better to have a clean death from a sharp blade than to tangle with a goblin's rusted chains.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0101</id>
    <name>Goblin Lookout</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a Goblin: Goblin creatures get +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Throw rocks at 'em Throw spears at 'em Throw Furt at 'em"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0102</id>
    <name>Hunter Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have provoke. (When a Sliver attacks, its controller may have target creature defending player controls untap and block it if able.)</text>
    <flavorText>Once they get the scent, there is no escape.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0103</id>
    <name>Imperial Hellkite</name>
    <text>Flying
Morph {6}{R}{R} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Imperial Hellkite is turned face up, you may search your library for a Dragon card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0104</id>
    <name>Kilnmouth Dragon</name>
    <text>Amplify 3 (As this creature enters the battlefield, put three +1/+1 counters on it for each Dragon card you reveal in your hand.)
Flying
{T}: Kilnmouth Dragon deals damage equal to the number of +1/+1 counters on it to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0105</id>
    <name>Lavaborn Muse</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each opponent's upkeep, if that player has two or fewer cards in hand, Lavaborn Muse deals 3 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>"Her voice is disaster, painful and final."
—Matoc, lavamancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0106</id>
    <name>Macetail Hystrodon</name>
    <text>First strike, haste
Cycling {3} ({3}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>The goblins tracked the hystrodon with much stealth and cunning. Then they were eaten with much pain and yelling.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0107</id>
    <name>Magma Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{T}: Target Sliver creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn, where X is the number of Slivers on the battlefield."</text>
    <flavorText>As malleable as molten steel, but as dangerous as the finished blade.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0108</id>
    <name>Ridgetop Raptor</name>
    <text>Double strike (This creature deals both first-strike and regular combat damage.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The Skirk Ridge has many wonderful things to discover—like escape routes."
—Foothill guide</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0109</id>
    <name>Rockshard Elemental</name>
    <text>Double strike (This creature deals both first-strike and regular combat damage.)
Morph {4}{R}{R} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0110</id>
    <name>Shaleskin Plower</name>
    <text>Morph {4}{R} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Shaleskin Plower is turned face up, destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0111</id>
    <name>Skirk Alarmist</name>
    <text>Haste
{T}: Turn target face-down creature you control face up. At the beginning of the next end step, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>"I treat each day as your last."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0112</id>
    <name>Skirk Drill Sergeant</name>
    <text>Whenever Skirk Drill Sergeant or another Goblin is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {2}{R}. If you do, reveal the top card of your library. If it's a Goblin permanent card, put it onto the battlefield. Otherwise, put it into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"I order you to volunteer."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0113</id>
    <name>Skirk Marauder</name>
    <text>Morph {2}{R} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Skirk Marauder is turned face up, it deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0114</id>
    <name>Skirk Outrider</name>
    <text>As long as you control a Beast, Skirk Outrider gets +2/+2 and has trample.</text>
    <flavorText>Once the goblins thought about it, they preferred being atop a slateback to being in front of, behind, or underneath one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0115</id>
    <name>Unstable Hulk</name>
    <text>Morph {3}{R}{R} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Unstable Hulk is turned face up, it gets +6/+6 and gains trample until end of turn. You skip your next turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0116</id>
    <name>Warbreak Trumpeter</name>
    <text>Morph {X}{X}{R} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Warbreak Trumpeter is turned face up, put X 1/1 red Goblin creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0117</id>
    <name>Berserk Murlodont</name>
    <text>Whenever a Beast becomes blocked, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it.</text>
    <flavorText>"The harder we press forward, the harder Krosa pushes us back."
—Aven scout</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0118</id>
    <name>Branchsnap Lorian</name>
    <text>Trample
Morph {G} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>Lorians treat trees and prey the same way: by ripping them limb from limb.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0119</id>
    <name>Brontotherium</name>
    <text>Trample
Provoke (When this attacks, you may have target creature defending player controls untap and block it if able.)</text>
    <flavorText>Lucky victims get run over. Unlucky victims get run through.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0120</id>
    <name>Brood Sliver</name>
    <text>Whenever a Sliver deals combat damage to a player, its controller may put a 1/1 colorless Sliver creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Within weeks, more slivers nested in Otaria than ever existed on Rath.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0121</id>
    <name>Caller of the Claw</name>
    <text>Flash
When Caller of the Claw enters the battlefield, put a 2/2 green Bear creature token onto the battlefield for each nontoken creature put into your graveyard from the battlefield this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0122</id>
    <name>Canopy Crawler</name>
    <text>Amplify 1 (As this creature enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on it for each Beast card you reveal in your hand.)
{T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each +1/+1 counter on Canopy Crawler.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0123</id>
    <name>Defiant Elf</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>"I lost one home when Yavimaya was destroyed. I will not lose another."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0124</id>
    <name>Elvish Soultiller</name>
    <text>When Elvish Soultiller is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, choose a creature type. Shuffle all creature cards of that type from your graveyard into your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Mutated elves wondered if this was their final form, or if it was just another step.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0125</id>
    <name>Enormous Baloth</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Its diet consists of fruits, plants, small woodland animals, large woodland animals, woodlands, fruit groves, fruit farmers, and small cities.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0126</id>
    <name>Feral Throwback</name>
    <text>Amplify 2 (As this creature enters the battlefield, put two +1/+1 counters on it for each Beast card you reveal in your hand.)
Provoke (When this attacks, you may have target creature defending player controls untap and block it if able.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0127</id>
    <name>Gempalm Strider</name>
    <text>Cycling {2}{G}{G} ({2}{G}{G}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
When you cycle Gempalm Strider, Elf creatures get +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0128</id>
    <name>Glowering Rogon</name>
    <text>Amplify 1 (As this creature enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on it for each Beast card you reveal in your hand.)</text>
    <flavorText>A herd of one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0129</id>
    <name>Hundroog</name>
    <text>Cycling {3} ({3}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>"New links are being added to the food chain on a daily basis."
—Riptide Project researcher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0130</id>
    <name>Krosan Cloudscraper</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Krosan Cloudscraper unless you pay {G}{G}.
Morph {7}{G}{G} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0131</id>
    <name>Krosan Vorine</name>
    <text>Provoke (When this attacks, you may have target creature defending player controls untap and block it if able.)
Krosan Vorine can't be blocked by more than one creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0132</id>
    <name>Nantuko Vigilante</name>
    <text>Morph {1}{G} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Nantuko Vigilante is turned face up, destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0133</id>
    <name>Needleshot Gourna</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>The first aven scout squad returned from Krosa with disturbing stories. The second returned with disturbing casualties.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0134</id>
    <name>Patron of the Wild</name>
    <text>Morph {2}{G} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Patron of the Wild is turned face up, target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0135</id>
    <name>Primal Whisperer</name>
    <text>Primal Whisperer gets +2/+2 for each face-down creature on the battlefield.
Morph {3}{G} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0136</id>
    <name>Quick Sliver</name>
    <text>Flash
Any player may play Sliver cards as though they had flash.</text>
    <flavorText>The directors of the Riptide Project wanted instant results on the sliver experiments. They got their wish.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0137</id>
    <name>Root Sliver</name>
    <text>Root Sliver can't be countered.
Sliver spells can't be countered by spells or abilities.</text>
    <flavorText>"It would take another apocalypse to stop the slivers now."
—Riptide Project researcher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0138</id>
    <name>Seedborn Muse</name>
    <text>Untap all permanents you control during each other player's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>"Her voice is wilderness, savage and pure."
—Kamahl, druid acolyte</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0139</id>
    <name>Stonewood Invoker</name>
    <text>{7}{G}: Stonewood Invoker gets +5/+5 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Mirari pulses in his veins.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0140</id>
    <name>Timberwatch Elf</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets +X/+X until end of turn, where X is the number of Elves on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Even through the Mirari's voice, the elves still hear the call of their kinship.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0141</id>
    <name>Totem Speaker</name>
    <text>Whenever a Beast enters the battlefield, you may gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Elves and beasts are tied together, and I am the knot that binds them."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0142</id>
    <name>Tribal Forcemage</name>
    <text>Morph {1}{G} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Tribal Forcemage is turned face up, creatures of the creature type of your choice get +2/+2 and gain trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0143</id>
    <name>Vexing Beetle</name>
    <text>Vexing Beetle can't be countered.
Vexing Beetle gets +3/+3 as long as no opponent controls a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>As the Mirari's mutating effects grew out of control, centaurs and druids fled—but insects swarmed closer.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0144</id>
    <name>Wirewood Channeler</name>
    <text>{T}: Add X mana of any one color to your mana pool, where X is the number of Elves on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your words are meaningless. The rustling of leaves is the only language that makes any sense."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LGN0145</id>
    <name>Wirewood Hivemaster</name>
    <text>Whenever another nontoken Elf enters the battlefield, you may put a 1/1 green Insect creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Most insects have been drawn to the Mirari. But all that remain in Wirewood are under my care."</flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>