<cards name="Lorwyn">
  <item>
    <id>LRW0001</id>
    <name>Ajani Goldmane</name>
    <text>+1: You gain 2 life.
-1: Put a +1/+1 counter on each creature you control. Those creatures gain vigilance until end of turn.
-6: Put a white Avatar creature token onto the battlefield. It has "This creature's power and toughness are each equal to your life total."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0002</id>
    <name>Arbiter of Knollridge</name>
    <text>Vigilance
When Arbiter of Knollridge enters the battlefield, each player's life total becomes the highest life total among all players.</text>
    <flavorText>Though giants are mortal, they live so long and on such a grand scale that many small folk don't believe they ever truly die.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0003</id>
    <name>Austere Command</name>
    <text>Choose two — Destroy all artifacts; or destroy all enchantments; or destroy all creatures with converted mana cost 3 or less; or destroy all creatures with converted mana cost 4 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0004</id>
    <name>Avian Changeling</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Today it flies with the flock. Tomorrow it may wake to find them gone, its body in an unfamiliar form.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0005</id>
    <name>Battle Mastery</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has double strike.</text>
    <flavorText>"Boom Boom Boots the size of oxcarts, then an axe like a falling sun. Elves scattered. Trees scattered. Even the hills ran for the hills"
—Clachan Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0006</id>
    <name>Brigid, Hero of Kinsbaile</name>
    <text>First strike
{T}: Brigid, Hero of Kinsbaile deals 2 damage to each attacking or blocking creature target player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Thanks to one champion archer, the true borders of Kinsbaile extend an arrow's flight beyond the buildings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0007</id>
    <name>Burrenton Forge-Tender</name>
    <text>Protection from red
Sacrifice Burrenton Forge-Tender: Prevent all damage a red source of your choice would deal this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We are a clachan of smiths. The forge is as comfortable to us as a small fire during a cool winter's evening."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0008</id>
    <name>Cenn's Heir</name>
    <text>Whenever Cenn's Heir attacks, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each other attacking Kithkin.</text>
    <flavorText>His home clachan's familial spirit bolsters his own, but he will be ready to preside over the town as cenn only after he learns to project that strength to others.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0009</id>
    <name>Changeling Hero</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
Champion a creature (When this enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you exile another creature you control. When this leaves the battlefield, that card returns to the battlefield.)
Lifelink (Damage dealt by this creature also causes you to gain that much life.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0010</id>
    <name>Cloudgoat Ranger</name>
    <text>When Cloudgoat Ranger enters the battlefield, put three 1/1 white Kithkin Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Tap three untapped Kithkin you control: Cloudgoat Ranger gets +2/+0 and gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0011</id>
    <name>Crib Swap</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
Exile target creature. Its controller puts a 1/1 colorless Shapeshifter creature token with changeling onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0012</id>
    <name>Dawnfluke</name>
    <text>Flash
When Dawnfluke enters the battlefield, prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.
Evoke {W} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0013</id>
    <name>Entangling Trap</name>
    <text>Whenever you clash, tap target creature an opponent controls. If you won, that creature doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step. (This ability triggers after the clash ends.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0014</id>
    <name>Favor of the Mighty</name>
    <text>Each creature with the highest converted mana cost has protection from all colors.</text>
    <flavorText>"What does a mountain fear of a fly? Giants are barely aware of us, let alone afraid."
—Gaddock Teeg</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0015</id>
    <name>Galepowder Mage</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Galepowder Mage attacks, exile another target creature. Return that card to the battlefield under its owner's control at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0016</id>
    <name>Goldmeadow Dodger</name>
    <text>Goldmeadow Dodger can't be blocked by creatures with power 4 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>"I've gotten close enough to a giant to smell his breath, but none has ever so much as spotted me. I wonder how long my record can extend?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0017</id>
    <name>Goldmeadow Harrier</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's a proven fact that sling-stones from the dawn side of the riverbank sail the farthest and truest."
—Deagan, cenn of Burrenton</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0018</id>
    <name>Goldmeadow Stalwart</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Goldmeadow Stalwart, reveal a Kithkin card from your hand or pay {3}.</text>
    <flavorText>The thoughtweft ties a clachan together. Sharing each other's hopes and fears, all the village's citizens spring into action upon the first threat to any one of them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0019</id>
    <name>Harpoon Sniper</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Harpoon Sniper deals X damage to target attacking or blocking creature, where X is the number of Merfolk you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Made from whiskergill bones, merrow spinebows can fire bolts through tree trunks.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0020</id>
    <name>Hillcomber Giant</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk</text>
    <flavorText>The giants believe the fossils they find in Lorwyn's rocky heights are dreams frozen in time, and they treasure them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0021</id>
    <name>Hoofprints of the Stag</name>
    <text>Whenever you draw a card, you may put a hoofprint counter on Hoofprints of the Stag.
{2}{W}, Remove four hoofprint counters from Hoofprints of the Stag: Put a 4/4 white Elemental creature token with flying onto the battlefield. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0022</id>
    <name>Judge of Currents</name>
    <text>Whenever a Merfolk you control becomes tapped, you may gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Though the currents of the Lanes shift every year, the merrow never lose track of where they are or where they are going.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0023</id>
    <name>Kinsbaile Balloonist</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Kinsbaile Balloonist attacks, you may have target creature gain flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Even when a giant's tantrum turns the sky into a chaotic gale, the path of the balloonist never falters.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0024</id>
    <name>Kinsbaile Skirmisher</name>
    <text>When Kinsbaile Skirmisher enters the battlefield, target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"If a boggart even dares breathe near one of my kin, I'll know. And I'll not be happy."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0025</id>
    <name>Kithkin Greatheart</name>
    <text>As long as you control a Giant, Kithkin Greatheart gets +1/+1 and has first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes a curious giant singles out a "little one" to follow for a few days, never realizing the effect it will have on the little one's life.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0026</id>
    <name>Kithkin Harbinger</name>
    <text>When Kithkin Harbinger enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a Kithkin card, reveal it, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>Her ears are open to even the softest voice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0027</id>
    <name>Kithkin Healer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The empathetic nature of the thoughtweft allows kithkin healers to treat the cause of an illness rather than fight its symptoms.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0028</id>
    <name>Knight of Meadowgrain</name>
    <text>First strike
Lifelink (Damage dealt by this creature also causes you to gain that much life.)</text>
    <flavorText>"By tradition, we don't speak for two days after battle. If our deeds won't speak for themselves, what else could be said?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0029</id>
    <name>Lairwatch Giant</name>
    <text>Lairwatch Giant can block an additional creature.
Whenever Lairwatch Giant blocks two or more creatures, it gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A giant can brood over a grudge for decades, and woe to those who interrupt him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0030</id>
    <name>Militia's Pride</name>
    <text>Whenever a nontoken creature you control attacks, you may pay {W}. If you do, put a 1/1 white Kithkin Soldier creature token onto the battlefield tapped and attacking.</text>
    <flavorText>If you pick a fight with one kithkin, be ready to fight them all.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0031</id>
    <name>Mirror Entity</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
{X}: Creatures you control become X/X and gain all creature types until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Unaware of Lorwyn's diversity, it sees only itself, reflected a thousand times over.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0032</id>
    <name>Neck Snap</name>
    <text>Destroy target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"We merrows need not be disadvantaged when fighting on land. We lack the vulnerability of those who breathe only through their throats."
—Minnarin, merrow reejerey</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0033</id>
    <name>Oaken Brawler</name>
    <text>When Oaken Brawler enters the battlefield, clash with an opponent. If you win, put a +1/+1 counter on Oaken Brawler. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0034</id>
    <name>Oblivion Ring</name>
    <text>When Oblivion Ring enters the battlefield, exile another target nonland permanent.
When Oblivion Ring leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to the battlefield under its owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>A circle of sugar and a word of forbiddance.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0035</id>
    <name>Plover Knights</name>
    <text>Flying, first strike</text>
    <flavorText>The knights are a major attraction at every Lammastide festival. Teams of riders perform daring feats of flight to the delight of all below.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0036</id>
    <name>Pollen Lullaby</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn. Clash with an opponent. If you win, creatures that player controls don't untap during the player's next untap step. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0037</id>
    <name>Purity</name>
    <text>Flying
If noncombat damage would be dealt to you, prevent that damage. You gain life equal to the damage prevented this way.
When Purity is put into a graveyard from anywhere, shuffle it into its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0038</id>
    <name>Sentry Oak</name>
    <text>Defender
At the beginning of combat on your turn, you may clash with an opponent. If you win, Sentry Oak gets +2/+0 and loses defender until end of turn. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0039</id>
    <name>Shields of Velis Vel</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
Creatures target player controls get +0/+1 and gain all creature types until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Changelings can alter shape based on what the beings around them desire most.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0040</id>
    <name>Soaring Hope</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Soaring Hope enters the battlefield, you gain 3 life.
Enchanted creature has flying.
{W}: Put Soaring Hope on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0041</id>
    <name>Springjack Knight</name>
    <text>Whenever Springjack Knight attacks, clash with an opponent. If you win, target creature gains double strike until end of turn. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0042</id>
    <name>Summon the School</name>
    <text>Put two 1/1 blue Merfolk Wizard creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Tap four untapped Merfolk you control: Return Summon the School from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"When merrows talk, listeners grow fins."
—Kithkin saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0043</id>
    <name>Surge of Thoughtweft</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn. If you control a Kithkin, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Kithkin weave together their very thoughts, creating a depth of cooperation unknown to other races.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0044</id>
    <name>Thoughtweft Trio</name>
    <text>First strike, vigilance
Champion a Kithkin (When this enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you exile another Kithkin you control. When this leaves the battlefield, that card returns to the battlefield.)
Thoughtweft Trio can block any number of creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0045</id>
    <name>Triclopean Sight</name>
    <text>Flash
Enchant creature
When Triclopean Sight enters the battlefield, untap enchanted creature.
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has vigilance.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0046</id>
    <name>Veteran of the Depths</name>
    <text>Whenever Veteran of the Depths becomes tapped, you may put a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>In the backwaters of the Merrow Lanes lie stones scarred with tallies of countless generations, each representing a victory of merrow soldiers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0047</id>
    <name>Wellgabber Apothecary</name>
    <text>{1}{W}: Prevent all damage that would be dealt to target tapped Merfolk or Kithkin creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"You've discovered that boggarts bite, I see. And will the militia be chasing this lot? . . . Ah, you're staying in town to avoid Nath's hunt. Wise. Now this poultice . . ."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0048</id>
    <name>Wispmare</name>
    <text>Flying
When Wispmare enters the battlefield, destroy target enchantment.
Evoke {W} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0049</id>
    <name>Wizened Cenn</name>
    <text>Other Kithkin creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>"Thoughtweft binds us together as one, part of an intricate pattern that would unravel if even one thread came loose."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0050</id>
    <name>Æthersnipe</name>
    <text>When Æthersnipe enters the battlefield, return target nonland permanent to its owner's hand.
Evoke {1}{U}{U} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0051</id>
    <name>Amoeboid Changeling</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
{T}: Target creature gains all creature types until end of turn.
{T}: Target creature loses all creature types until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0052</id>
    <name>Aquitect's Will</name>
    <text>Put a flood counter on target land. That land is an Island in addition to its other types for as long as it has a flood counter on it. If you control a Merfolk, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>There is nowhere on Lorwyn that the Merrow Lanes cannot go.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0053</id>
    <name>Benthicore</name>
    <text>When Benthicore enters the battlefield, put two 1/1 blue Merfolk Wizard creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Tap two untapped Merfolk you control: Untap Benthicore. It gains shroud until end of turn. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0054</id>
    <name>Broken Ambitions</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}. Clash with an opponent. If you win, that spell's controller puts the top four cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0055</id>
    <name>Captivating Glance</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of your end step, clash with an opponent. If you win, gain control of enchanted creature. Otherwise, that player gains control of enchanted creature. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0056</id>
    <name>Cryptic Command</name>
    <text>Choose two — Counter target spell; or return target permanent to its owner's hand; or tap all creatures your opponents control; or draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0057</id>
    <name>Deeptread Merrow</name>
    <text>{U}: Deeptread Merrow gains islandwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"My success at navigating the Dark Meanders irritates the Inkfathom school. They consider themselves peerless divers, but I try to remind them that they cannot own commodities like bravery and cunning."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0058</id>
    <name>Drowner of Secrets</name>
    <text>Tap an untapped Merfolk you control: Target player puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Merrows consider themselves the keepers of Lorwyn's past—and consider it their duty to edit when necessary.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0059</id>
    <name>Ego Erasure</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
Creatures target player controls get -2/-0 and lose all creature types until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>When all is taken away, all are equal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0060</id>
    <name>Ethereal Whiskergill</name>
    <text>Flying
Ethereal Whiskergill can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.</text>
    <flavorText>Fallowsages debate whether the whiskergill is native to the Dark Meanders or merely dreamstuff made real.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0061</id>
    <name>Faerie Harbinger</name>
    <text>Flash
Flying
When Faerie Harbinger enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a Faerie card, reveal it, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0062</id>
    <name>Faerie Trickery</name>
    <text>Counter target non-Faerie spell. If that spell is countered this way, exile it instead of putting it into its owner's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>The fae are so quick and their life spans so short that it's difficult to get retribution for their pranks.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0063</id>
    <name>Fallowsage</name>
    <text>Whenever Fallowsage becomes tapped, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Memories of ages past are said to swim the minds of lounging fallowsages.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0064</id>
    <name>Familiar's Ruse</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Familiar's Ruse, return a creature you control to its owner's hand.
Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>Because of their capricious nature, faeries can serve as living lenses for disruptive magic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0065</id>
    <name>Fathom Trawl</name>
    <text>Reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal three nonland cards. Put the nonland cards revealed this way into your hand, then put the rest of the revealed cards on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0066</id>
    <name>Forced Fruition</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a spell, that player draws seven cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Petals within petals within petals, tadpole. The truth lurks below an opulence of illusion."
—Neerdiv, fallowsage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0067</id>
    <name>Glen Elendra Pranksters</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever you cast a spell during an opponent's turn, you may return target creature you control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Victims spirited through a faerie ring find themselves stranded miles away.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0068</id>
    <name>Glimmerdust Nap</name>
    <text>Enchant tapped creature
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>The dreams of giants are as long as time and as deep as the earth. Thus they are prized by the dream-harvesting fae.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0069</id>
    <name>Guile</name>
    <text>Guile can't be blocked except by three or more creatures.
If a spell or ability you control would counter a spell, instead exile that spell and you may play that card without paying its mana cost.
When Guile is put into a graveyard from anywhere, shuffle it into its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0070</id>
    <name>Inkfathom Divers</name>
    <text>Islandwalk
When Inkfathom Divers enters the battlefield, look at the top four cards of your library, then put them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"None appreciate sun and shallows like those who have seen the depths."
—Lianda of the Stonybrook school</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0071</id>
    <name>Jace Beleren</name>
    <text>+2: Each player draws a card.
-1: Target player draws a card.
-10: Target player puts the top twenty cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0072</id>
    <name>Merrow Commerce</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your end step, untap all Merfolk you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Schools meet and mingle on Lorwyn's riverways. In the bustling interplay, the merrow renew their sense of community as they sharpen their wits and hone their trading skills.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0073</id>
    <name>Merrow Harbinger</name>
    <text>Islandwalk
When Merrow Harbinger enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a Merfolk card, reveal it, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0074</id>
    <name>Merrow Reejerey</name>
    <text>Other Merfolk creatures you control get +1/+1.
Whenever you cast a Merfolk spell, you may tap or untap target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>Steady and silent as the deep current, the reejerey guides the course of the school.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0075</id>
    <name>Mistbind Clique</name>
    <text>Flash
Flying
Champion a Faerie (When this enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you exile another Faerie you control. When this leaves the battlefield, that card returns to the battlefield.)
When a Faerie is championed with Mistbind Clique, tap all lands target player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0076</id>
    <name>Mulldrifter</name>
    <text>Flying
When Mulldrifter enters the battlefield, draw two cards.
Evoke {2}{U} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0077</id>
    <name>Paperfin Rascal</name>
    <text>When Paperfin Rascal enters the battlefield, clash with an opponent. If you win, put a +1/+1 counter on Paperfin Rascal. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0078</id>
    <name>Pestermite</name>
    <text>Flash
Flying
When Pestermite enters the battlefield, you may tap or untap target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>The fae know when they're not wanted. That's precisely why they show up.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0079</id>
    <name>Ponder</name>
    <text>Look at the top three cards of your library, then put them back in any order. You may shuffle your library.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"We see the same sky as you, just through a different lens."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0080</id>
    <name>Protective Bubble</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature is unblockable and has shroud. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>Skilled merrow rudders ensure their charges arrive on time and without incident.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0081</id>
    <name>Ringskipper</name>
    <text>Flying
When Ringskipper is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, clash with an opponent. If you win, return Ringskipper to its owner's hand. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0082</id>
    <name>Scattering Stroke</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. Clash with an opponent. If you win, at the beginning of your next main phase, you may add {X} to your mana pool, where X is that spell's converted mana cost. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0083</id>
    <name>Scion of Oona</name>
    <text>Flash
Flying
Other Faerie creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other Faeries you control have shroud. (A permanent with shroud can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0084</id>
    <name>Sentinels of Glen Elendra</name>
    <text>Flash
Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Some say the valley of Glen Elendra is mythical, and that rumors of its existence are nothing but a faerie prank. Others say it is the fae's most fiercely guarded secret.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0085</id>
    <name>Shapesharer</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
{2}{U}: Target Shapeshifter becomes a copy of target creature until your next turn.</text>
    <flavorText>One good mimic deserves another.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0086</id>
    <name>Silvergill Adept</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Silvergill Adept, reveal a Merfolk card from your hand or pay {3}.
When Silvergill Adept enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I bring baubles of lore, lost secrets seined from the listening waves."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0087</id>
    <name>Silvergill Douser</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets -X/-0 until end of turn, where X is the number of Merfolk and/or Faeries you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The Silvergill school monitors traffic on the Lanes, ensuring that the riffraff don't interfere with travelers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0088</id>
    <name>Sower of Temptation</name>
    <text>Flying
When Sower of Temptation enters the battlefield, gain control of target creature for as long as Sower of Temptation remains on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>One glamer leads him far from home. The next washes away his memory that home was ever anywhere but at her side.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0089</id>
    <name>Spellstutter Sprite</name>
    <text>Flash
Flying
When Spellstutter Sprite enters the battlefield, counter target spell with converted mana cost X or less, where X is the number of Faeries you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0090</id>
    <name>Stonybrook Angler</name>
    <text>{1}{U}, {T}: You may tap or untap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Water is in the air, the trees, and the earth. Understand its motion, speak its language, and the subtle currents that flow through all living things will fall under your command."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0091</id>
    <name>Streambed Aquitects</name>
    <text>{T}: Target Merfolk creature gets +1/+1 and gains islandwalk until end of turn.
{T}: Target land becomes an Island until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We look in the river and see scattered stones. A merrow looks and sees a map of Lorwyn."
—Illulia, flamekin soulstoke</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0092</id>
    <name>Surgespanner</name>
    <text>Whenever Surgespanner becomes tapped, you may pay {1}{U}. If you do, return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>They ride on waves of Æther, washing out anything that might pollute the Merrow Lanes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0093</id>
    <name>Tideshaper Mystic</name>
    <text>{T}: Target land becomes the basic land type of your choice until end of turn. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>He paints with drop and shimmer a world that exists only in the wistful heart.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0094</id>
    <name>Turtleshell Changeling</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
{1}{U}: Switch Turtleshell Changeling's power and toughness until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A changeling involuntarily mimics the nearest being at hand, sometimes trading a borrowed shell for borrowed claws.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0095</id>
    <name>Wanderwine Prophets</name>
    <text>Champion a Merfolk (When this enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you exile another Merfolk you control. When this leaves the battlefield, that card returns to the battlefield.)
Whenever Wanderwine Prophets deals combat damage to a player, you may sacrifice a Merfolk. If you do, take an extra turn after this one.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0096</id>
    <name>Whirlpool Whelm</name>
    <text>Clash with an opponent, then return target creature to its owner's hand. If you win, you may put that creature on top of its owner's library instead. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0097</id>
    <name>Wings of Velis Vel</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
Target creature becomes 4/4, gains all creature types, and gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Changeling magic grants unusual wishes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0098</id>
    <name>Zephyr Net</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has defender and flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Faeries hang beings that interest them as ornaments in the sky, each clique competing to outshine the prize of the last.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0099</id>
    <name>Black Poplar Shaman</name>
    <text>{2}{B}: Regenerate target Treefolk.</text>
    <flavorText>It absorbs the pain of other treefolk, which leaves it bitter, yet addicted to the sensation of agony.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0100</id>
    <name>Bog Hoodlums</name>
    <text>Bog Hoodlums can't block.
When Bog Hoodlums enters the battlefield, clash with an opponent. If you win, put a +1/+1 counter on Bog Hoodlums. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0101</id>
    <name>Boggart Birth Rite</name>
    <text>Return target Goblin card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Auntie excitedly held up the squalling newborn. "This one looks like Byoog Maybe he'll tell us what he saw and felt in the beyond."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0102</id>
    <name>Boggart Harbinger</name>
    <text>When Boggart Harbinger enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a Goblin card, reveal it, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0103</id>
    <name>Boggart Loggers</name>
    <text>Forestwalk
{2}{B}, Sacrifice Boggart Loggers: Destroy target Treefolk or Forest.</text>
    <flavorText>Auntie Flint lent axes to Nibb and Gyik, thinking they'd share their experiences with her. She's still waiting for them to come back.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0104</id>
    <name>Boggart Mob</name>
    <text>Champion a Goblin (When this enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you exile another Goblin you control. When this leaves the battlefield, that card returns to the battlefield.)
Whenever a Goblin you control deals combat damage to a player, you may put a 1/1 black Goblin Rogue creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0105</id>
    <name>Cairn Wanderer</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
As long as a creature card with flying is in a graveyard, Cairn Wanderer has flying. The same is true for fear, first strike, double strike, deathtouch, haste, landwalk, lifelink, protection, reach, trample, shroud, and vigilance.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0106</id>
    <name>Colfenor's Plans</name>
    <text>When Colfenor's Plans enters the battlefield, exile the top seven cards of your library face down.
You may look at and play cards exiled with Colfenor's Plans.
Skip your draw step.
You can't cast more than one spell each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0107</id>
    <name>Dread</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
Whenever a creature deals damage to you, destroy it.
When Dread is put into a graveyard from anywhere, shuffle it into its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0108</id>
    <name>Dreamspoiler Witches</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever you cast a spell during an opponent's turn, you may have target creature get -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>At night, the faeries steal dreamstuff for their queen. At daybreak, countless creatures wake weak and hollow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0109</id>
    <name>Exiled Boggart</name>
    <text>When Exiled Boggart is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Among the boggarts, there is only one real rule: all new treasures and experiences must be shared. Those who hoard their gifts commit the one truly unforgivable sin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0110</id>
    <name>Eyeblight's Ending</name>
    <text>Destroy target non-Elf creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those without beauty are Lorwyn's greatest tumor. The winnowers have an unpleasant duty, but a necessary one."
—Eidren, perfect of Lys Alana</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0111</id>
    <name>Facevaulter</name>
    <text>{B}, Sacrifice a Goblin: Facevaulter gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Boggarts get so excited when they find something new to smash that they really don't notice who gets underfoot.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0112</id>
    <name>Faerie Tauntings</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a spell during an opponent's turn, you may have each opponent lose 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Beneath the fae's constant pranks runs a subtler undercurrent of mockery: the influence of Oona, their hidden queen.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0113</id>
    <name>Final Revels</name>
    <text>Choose one — All creatures get +2/+0 until end of turn; or all creatures get -0/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>One whiff of the sweet, pungent scent leads to euphoria—or to an early grave.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0114</id>
    <name>Fodder Launch</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Fodder Launch, sacrifice a Goblin.
Target creature gets -5/-5 until end of turn. Fodder Launch deals 5 damage to that creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>Leave it to a boggart to come up with a projectile as disgusting as it is deadly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0115</id>
    <name>Footbottom Feast</name>
    <text>Put any number of target creature cards from your graveyard on top of your library.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The scent of rot and vinegar fills the marsh, inviting boggarts from every warren to reunite and feast.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0116</id>
    <name>Ghostly Changeling</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
{1}{B}: Ghostly Changeling gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>In desolate places, changelings may take the shape of fancies, or memories, or fears.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0117</id>
    <name>Hoarder's Greed</name>
    <text>You lose 2 life and draw two cards, then clash with an opponent. If you win, repeat this process. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0118</id>
    <name>Hornet Harasser</name>
    <text>When Hornet Harasser is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"And though she didn't get her honey, Auntie found something far more interesting."
—A tale of Auntie Grub</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0119</id>
    <name>Hunter of Eyeblights</name>
    <text>When Hunter of Eyeblights enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on target creature you don't control.
{2}{B}, {T}: Destroy target creature with a counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>Snokk ran as fast as he could, but the sound of hooves grew ever louder in his ears.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0120</id>
    <name>Knucklebone Witch</name>
    <text>Whenever a Goblin you control is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Knucklebone Witch.</text>
    <flavorText>Each bone honors its owner's best pranks.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0121</id>
    <name>Liliana Vess</name>
    <text>+1: Target player discards a card.
-2: Search your library for a card, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.
-8: Put all creature cards from all graveyards onto the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0122</id>
    <name>Lys Alana Scarblade</name>
    <text>{T}, Discard an Elf card: Target creature gets -X/-X until end of turn, where X is the number of Elves you control.</text>
    <flavorText>In beauty-obsessed Lys Alana, one cut of her blade means the difference between a high society feast and raking through the dungheap for scraps.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0123</id>
    <name>Mad Auntie</name>
    <text>Other Goblin creatures you control get +1/+1.
{T}: Regenerate another target Goblin.</text>
    <flavorText>One part cunning, one part wise, and many, many parts demented.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0124</id>
    <name>Makeshift Mannequin</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield with a mannequin counter on it. For as long as that creature has a mannequin counter on it, it has "When this creature becomes the target of a spell or ability, sacrifice it."</text>
    <flavorText>"This vulgar mimicry will end now."
—Desmera, perfect of Wren's Run</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0125</id>
    <name>Marsh Flitter</name>
    <text>Flying
When Marsh Flitter enters the battlefield, put two 1/1 black Goblin Rogue creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Sacrifice a Goblin: Marsh Flitter becomes 3/3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0126</id>
    <name>Moonglove Winnower</name>
    <text>Deathtouch (Creatures dealt damage by this creature are destroyed. You can divide this creature's combat damage among any of the creatures blocking or blocked by it.)</text>
    <flavorText>Winnowers live to eliminate eyeblights, creatures the elves deem too ugly to exist.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0127</id>
    <name>Mournwhelk</name>
    <text>When Mournwhelk enters the battlefield, target player discards two cards.
Evoke {3}{B} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>It hoards Lorwyn's rare sorrows.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0128</id>
    <name>Nameless Inversion</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
Target creature gets +3/-3 and loses all creature types until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Just as a changeling's influence can have dramatic effects, so too can its sudden withdrawal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0129</id>
    <name>Nath's Buffoon</name>
    <text>Protection from Elves</text>
    <flavorText>Smik learned the elvish dance quickly enough. The most difficult, yet most important step was to stay out of Nath's sight until called to perform.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0130</id>
    <name>Nectar Faerie</name>
    <text>Flying
{B}, {T}: Target Faerie or Elf gains lifelink until end of turn. (Damage dealt by the creature also causes its controller to gain that much life.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The unpredictable fae are just as likely to provide a blight as a boon."
—Desmera, perfect of Wren's Run</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0131</id>
    <name>Nettlevine Blight</name>
    <text>Enchant creature or land
Enchanted permanent has "At the beginning of your end step, sacrifice this permanent and attach Nettlevine Blight to a creature or land you control."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0132</id>
    <name>Nightshade Stinger</name>
    <text>Flying
Nightshade Stinger can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>"Most faeries are harmless pranksters. Every now and again, though, you get one that crosses over from mischievous to malicious."
—Gaddock Teeg</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0133</id>
    <name>Oona's Prowler</name>
    <text>Flying
Discard a card: Oona's Prowler gets -2/-0 until end of turn. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>Deep in Glen Elendra blossoms Oona, queen of the faeries, nourished by secrets and pollinated by stolen dreams.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0134</id>
    <name>Peppersmoke</name>
    <text>Target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn. If you control a Faerie, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Like being trapped in a perpetual sneeze, faerie-dust poisoning is both exhilarating and agonizing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0135</id>
    <name>Profane Command</name>
    <text>Choose two — Target player loses X life; or return target creature card with converted mana cost X or less from your graveyard to the battlefield; or target creature gets -X/-X until end of turn; or up to X target creatures gain fear until end of turn. (They can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0136</id>
    <name>Prowess of the Fair</name>
    <text>Whenever another nontoken Elf is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, you may put a 1/1 green Elf Warrior creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>An elvish duel is a thing of beauty: the warriors' grace, the crash of steel, then the artful spray of blood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0137</id>
    <name>Quill-Slinger Boggart</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a Kithkin spell, you may have target player lose 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"A good day in Goldmeadow is one in which I don't spend all evening picking quills out of my backside."
—Calydd, kithkin farmer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0138</id>
    <name>Scarred Vinebreeder</name>
    <text>{2}{B}, Exile an Elf card from your graveyard: Scarred Vinebreeder gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>For disfigured elves, there are few choices beyond death or nettlevine.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0139</id>
    <name>Shriekmaw</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
When Shriekmaw enters the battlefield, destroy target nonartifact, nonblack creature.
Evoke {1}{B} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0140</id>
    <name>Skeletal Changeling</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
{1}{B}: Regenerate Skeletal Changeling.</text>
    <flavorText>Though they lack true flesh and bone of their own, changelings imitate either with equal ease.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0141</id>
    <name>Spiderwig Boggart</name>
    <text>When Spiderwig Boggart enters the battlefield, target creature gains fear until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>Auntie Flint was the first to pioneer the spiderwig, a mass of arachnids intended to be worn rather than eaten.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0142</id>
    <name>Squeaking Pie Sneak</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Squeaking Pie Sneak, reveal a Goblin card from your hand or pay {3}.
Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Why do our pies squeak? It's all the faeries, mice, and prickly-hogs we stuff inside."
—Borb of the Squeaking Pie warren</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0143</id>
    <name>Thieving Sprite</name>
    <text>Flying
When Thieving Sprite enters the battlefield, target player reveals X cards from his or her hand, where X is the number of Faeries you control. You choose one of those cards. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0144</id>
    <name>Thorntooth Witch</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a Treefolk spell, you may have target creature get +3/-3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The crone's boughs creaked as she spoke. "You look peaked, little one. Come, sip from my warm brew. It'll have you blooming in no time."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0145</id>
    <name>Thoughtseize</name>
    <text>Target player reveals his or her hand. You choose a nonland card from it. That player discards that card. You lose 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Any dream is a robust harvest. Still, I prefer the timeworn dreams, heavy with import, that haunt the obsessive mind."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0146</id>
    <name>Warren Pilferers</name>
    <text>When Warren Pilferers enters the battlefield, return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand. If that card is a Goblin card, Warren Pilferers gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"What do they need all this stuff for? They're dead. We're alive. Simple enough."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0147</id>
    <name>Weed Strangle</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature. Clash with an opponent. If you win, you gain life equal to that creature's toughness. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0148</id>
    <name>Adder-Staff Boggart</name>
    <text>When Adder-Staff Boggart enters the battlefield, clash with an opponent. If you win, put a +1/+1 counter on Adder-Staff Boggart. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0149</id>
    <name>Ashling the Pilgrim</name>
    <text>{1}{R}: Put a +1/+1 counter on Ashling the Pilgrim. If this is the third time this ability has resolved this turn, remove all +1/+1 counters from Ashling the Pilgrim, and it deals that much damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0150</id>
    <name>Ashling's Prerogative</name>
    <text>As Ashling's Prerogative enters the battlefield, choose odd or even. (Zero is even.)
Each creature with converted mana cost of the chosen value has haste.
Each creature without converted mana cost of the chosen value enters the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0151</id>
    <name>Axegrinder Giant</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The angriest of giants are often the most skillful weaponsmiths. Their grudges fuel endless sessions at the forge, all the while growling ferociously to themselves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0152</id>
    <name>Blades of Velis Vel</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
Up to two target creatures each get +2/+0 and gain all creature types until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The changing kind suffers as we do. We must join as one to quench our tyrants"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0153</id>
    <name>Blind-Spot Giant</name>
    <text>Blind-Spot Giant can't attack or block unless you control another Giant.</text>
    <flavorText>Among the solitude-loving giantkind, teamwork is unusual. But he appreciates hearing the occasional "Swing down and to your left."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0154</id>
    <name>Boggart Forager</name>
    <text>{R}, Sacrifice Boggart Forager: Target player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Reach in this hole, lose a hand. Reach in that hole, find a sparkly."
—Auntie wisdom</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0155</id>
    <name>Boggart Shenanigans</name>
    <text>Whenever another Goblin you control is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may have Boggart Shenanigans deal 1 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Boggarts revel in discovering new sensations, from the texture of an otter pellet to the squeak of a dying warren mate.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0156</id>
    <name>Boggart Sprite-Chaser</name>
    <text>As long as you control a Faerie, Boggart Sprite-Chaser gets +1/+1 and has flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Auntie pointed out to the faerie how much mischief a flying boggart could wreak, and a beautiful new friendship was born."
—A tale of Auntie Grub</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0157</id>
    <name>Caterwauling Boggart</name>
    <text>Each Goblin you control can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.
Each Elemental you control can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"As far as I can tell, that frog dangling from the stick serves absolutely no purpose whatsoever."
—Gaddock Teeg</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0158</id>
    <name>Ceaseless Searblades</name>
    <text>Whenever you activate an ability of an Elemental, Ceaseless Searblades gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Flamekins' fires burn cool until they decide otherwise.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0159</id>
    <name>Chandra Nalaar</name>
    <text>+1: Chandra Nalaar deals 1 damage to target player.
-X: Chandra Nalaar deals X damage to target creature.
-8: Chandra Nalaar deals 10 damage to target player and each creature he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0160</id>
    <name>Changeling Berserker</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
Haste
Champion a creature (When this enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you exile another creature you control. When this leaves the battlefield, that card returns to the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0161</id>
    <name>Consuming Bonfire</name>
    <text>Choose one — Consuming Bonfire deals 4 damage to target non-Elemental creature; or Consuming Bonfire deals 7 damage to target Treefolk creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The elves use treefolk to drive us away. It is time to remove their tools."
—Vessifrus, flamekin demagogue</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0162</id>
    <name>Crush Underfoot</name>
    <text>Choose a Giant creature you control. It deals damage equal to its power to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Five-toed grave
—Kithkin phrase meaning
"a giant's footprint"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0163</id>
    <name>Faultgrinder</name>
    <text>Trample
When Faultgrinder enters the battlefield, destroy target land.
Evoke {4}{R} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0164</id>
    <name>Fire-Belly Changeling</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
{R}: Fire-Belly Changeling gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Activate this ability no more than twice each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"My ears say it hisses. My fingers say it burns."
—Auntie Wort</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0165</id>
    <name>Flamekin Bladewhirl</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Flamekin Bladewhirl, reveal an Elemental card from your hand or pay {3}.</text>
    <flavorText>"The elves may try to confine us, but they will learn that our blazing spirit can never be suppressed."
—Vessifrus, flamekin demagogue</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0166</id>
    <name>Flamekin Brawler</name>
    <text>{R}: Flamekin Brawler gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>When he hits people, they stay hit.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0167</id>
    <name>Flamekin Harbinger</name>
    <text>When Flamekin Harbinger enters the battlefield, you may search your library for an Elemental card, reveal it, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0168</id>
    <name>Flamekin Spitfire</name>
    <text>{3}{R}: Flamekin Spitfire deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Some flamekin warriors explore the art of coherence, an ancient discipline that harnesses the chaos of fire and focuses it with pinpoint precision.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0169</id>
    <name>Giant Harbinger</name>
    <text>When Giant Harbinger enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a Giant card, reveal it, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0170</id>
    <name>Giant's Ire</name>
    <text>Giant's Ire deals 4 damage to target player. If you control a Giant, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The only feeling greater than hurling something a mile is crushing something else with it that was really, really irritating you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0171</id>
    <name>Glarewielder</name>
    <text>Haste
When Glarewielder enters the battlefield, up to two target creatures can't block this turn.
Evoke {1}{R} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0172</id>
    <name>Goatnapper</name>
    <text>When Goatnapper enters the battlefield, untap target Goat and gain control of it until end of turn. It gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Kith goats are just for practice. The real prize, of course, is a giant's cloudgoat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0173</id>
    <name>Hamletback Goliath</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may put X +1/+1 counters on Hamletback Goliath, where X is that creature's power.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you live on a giant's back, there's only one individual you'll ever need to fear."
—Gaddock Teeg</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0174</id>
    <name>Hearthcage Giant</name>
    <text>When Hearthcage Giant enters the battlefield, put two 3/1 red Elemental Shaman creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Sacrifice an Elemental: Target Giant creature gets +3/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The flamekin are mere kindling for his warmth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0175</id>
    <name>Heat Shimmer</name>
    <text>Put a token that's a copy of target creature onto the battlefield. That token has haste and "At the beginning of the end step, exile this permanent."</text>
    <flavorText>"Better to flare out than to gutter."
—Flamekin expression</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0176</id>
    <name>Hostility</name>
    <text>Haste
If a spell you control would deal damage to an opponent, prevent that damage. Put a 3/1 red Elemental Shaman creature token with haste onto the battlefield for each 1 damage prevented this way.
When Hostility is put into a graveyard from anywhere, shuffle it into its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0177</id>
    <name>Hurly-Burly</name>
    <text>Choose one — Hurly-Burly deals 1 damage to each creature without flying; or Hurly-Burly deals 1 damage to each creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Things were popping like corn in a skillet. Olly landed in the pig pen with his prize sow on top of him, both squealin' like boggarts."
—Deagan, cenn of Burrenton</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0178</id>
    <name>Incandescent Soulstoke</name>
    <text>Other Elemental creatures you control get +1/+1.
{1}{R}, {T}: You may put an Elemental creature card from your hand onto the battlefield. That creature gains haste until end of turn. Sacrifice it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0179</id>
    <name>Incendiary Command</name>
    <text>Choose two — Incendiary Command deals 4 damage to target player; or Incendiary Command deals 2 damage to each creature; or destroy target nonbasic land; or each player discards all the cards in his or her hand, then draws that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0180</id>
    <name>Ingot Chewer</name>
    <text>When Ingot Chewer enters the battlefield, destroy target artifact.
Evoke {R} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>Elementals are ideas given form. This one is the idea of "smashitude."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0181</id>
    <name>Inner-Flame Acolyte</name>
    <text>When Inner-Flame Acolyte enters the battlefield, target creature gets +2/+0 and gains haste until end of turn.
Evoke {R} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0182</id>
    <name>Inner-Flame Igniter</name>
    <text>{2}{R}: Creatures you control get +1/+0 until end of turn. If this is the third time this ability has resolved this turn, creatures you control gain first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A light an army can follow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0183</id>
    <name>Lash Out</name>
    <text>Lash Out deals 3 damage to target creature. Clash with an opponent. If you win, Lash Out deals 3 damage to that creature's controller. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0184</id>
    <name>Lowland Oaf</name>
    <text>{T}: Target Goblin creature you control gets +1/+0 and gains flying until end of turn. Sacrifice that creature at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>"I don't know why the little one was so mad. He said to put him down, and I put him down."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0185</id>
    <name>Mudbutton Torchrunner</name>
    <text>When Mudbutton Torchrunner is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, it deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>The oil sloshes against his skull as he nears his destination: the Frogtosser Games and the lighting of the Flaming Boggart.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0186</id>
    <name>Needle Drop</name>
    <text>Needle Drop deals 1 damage to target creature or player that was dealt damage this turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"First it was plovers and mulldrifters. Now it's knitting needles the size of javelins."
—Calydd, kithkin farmer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0187</id>
    <name>Nova Chaser</name>
    <text>Trample
Champion an Elemental (When this enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you exile another Elemental you control. When this leaves the battlefield, that card returns to the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0188</id>
    <name>Rebellion of the Flamekin</name>
    <text>Whenever you clash, you may pay {1}. If you do, put a 3/1 red Elemental Shaman creature token onto the battlefield. If you won, that token gains haste until end of turn. (This ability triggers after the clash ends.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0189</id>
    <name>Smokebraider</name>
    <text>{T}: Add two mana in any combination of colors to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast Elemental spells or activate abilities of Elementals.</text>
    <flavorText>"Be silent and listen to your inner fire. Only then can you walk the Path of Flame."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0190</id>
    <name>Soulbright Flamekin</name>
    <text>{2}: Target creature gains trample until end of turn. If this is the third time this ability has resolved this turn, you may add {R}{R}{R}{R}{R}{R}{R}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>When provoked, a flamekin's inner fire burns far hotter than any giant's forge.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0191</id>
    <name>Stinkdrinker Daredevil</name>
    <text>Giant spells you cast cost {2} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>Boggarts constantly strive to outdo each other with the things they bring back to the warren, each hoping the exploit will become as well-known as those of Auntie Grub.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0192</id>
    <name>Sunrise Sovereign</name>
    <text>Other Giant creatures you control get +2/+2 and have trample.</text>
    <flavorText>A hundred generations has he mentored, a hundred armies has he crushed beneath his feet, yet only a hundred words has he ever spoken, each more revered than a hundred books.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0193</id>
    <name>Tar Pitcher</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a Goblin: Tar Pitcher deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Auntie Grub had caught a goat, a bleating doe that still squirmed in her arms. At the same time, her warren decided to share with her a sensory greeting of hot tar . . . ."
—A tale of Auntie Grub</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0194</id>
    <name>Tarfire</name>
    <text>Tarfire deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"After Auntie brushed the soot from her eyes, she discovered something wonderful: the fire had turned the goat into something that smelled delicious."
—A tale of Auntie Grub</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0195</id>
    <name>Thundercloud Shaman</name>
    <text>When Thundercloud Shaman enters the battlefield, it deals damage equal to the number of Giants you control to each non-Giant creature.</text>
    <flavorText>He cares not for the disasters his storm brings as long as his path ahead is clear.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0196</id>
    <name>Wild Ricochet</name>
    <text>You may choose new targets for target instant or sorcery spell. Then copy that spell. You may choose new targets for the copy.</text>
    <flavorText>"I knew that trick long before your great-grandmother's great-grandmother was born."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0197</id>
    <name>Battlewand Oak</name>
    <text>Whenever a Forest enters the battlefield under your control, Battlewand Oak gets +2/+2 until end of turn.
Whenever you cast a Treefolk spell, Battlewand Oak gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0198</id>
    <name>Bog-Strider Ash</name>
    <text>Swampwalk
Whenever a player casts a Goblin spell, you may pay {G}. If you do, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you want to test wisdom, offer it to fools and watch how they tear it up."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0199</id>
    <name>Briarhorn</name>
    <text>Flash
When Briarhorn enters the battlefield, target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.
Evoke {1}{G} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0200</id>
    <name>Changeling Titan</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
Champion a creature (When this enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you exile another creature you control. When this leaves the battlefield, that card returns to the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0201</id>
    <name>Cloudcrown Oak</name>
    <text>Reach (This can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Clever folk build their homes near cloudcrowns. If a hawk or even just a faerie tries to swoop in, it'll get swatted from here to Cloverdell."
—Calydd, kithkin farmer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0202</id>
    <name>Cloudthresher</name>
    <text>Flash
Reach (This can block creatures with flying.)
When Cloudthresher enters the battlefield, it deals 2 damage to each creature with flying and each player.
Evoke {2}{G}{G} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0203</id>
    <name>Dauntless Dourbark</name>
    <text>Dauntless Dourbark's power and toughness are each equal to the number of Forests you control plus the number of Treefolk you control.
Dauntless Dourbark has trample as long as you control another Treefolk.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0204</id>
    <name>Elvish Branchbender</name>
    <text>{T}: Until end of turn, target Forest becomes an X/X Treefolk creature in addition to its other types, where X is the number of Elves you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"How do the vinebred feel? Fah We do not ask the puppet how it feels when the puppeteer bids it dance."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0205</id>
    <name>Elvish Eulogist</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Elvish Eulogist: You gain 1 life for each Elf card in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"No matter how adept our artistic skill, our effigies can never hope to capture the vibrant beauty of a living elf. Perhaps that is truly why we mourn."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0206</id>
    <name>Elvish Handservant</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a Giant spell, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Elvish Handservant.</text>
    <flavorText>The hardest lesson for any elf to learn is humility. It takes a giant to teach that.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0207</id>
    <name>Elvish Harbinger</name>
    <text>When Elvish Harbinger enters the battlefield, you may search your library for an Elf card, reveal it, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0208</id>
    <name>Elvish Promenade</name>
    <text>Put a 1/1 green Elf Warrior creature token onto the battlefield for each Elf you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The faultless and immaculate castes form the lower tiers of elvish society, with the exquisite caste above them. At the pinnacle is the perfect, a consummate blend of aristocrat and predator.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0209</id>
    <name>Epic Proportions</name>
    <text>Flash
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +5/+5 and has trample.</text>
    <flavorText>From mite to mighty.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0210</id>
    <name>Eyes of the Wisent</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a blue spell during your turn, you may put a 4/4 green Elemental creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Calm as a wisent's watch
—Elvish expression meaning "safe"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0211</id>
    <name>Fertile Ground</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds one mana of any color to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>Pretty, valuable, and delicious—a boggart thief's trifecta.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0212</id>
    <name>Fistful of Force</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn. Clash with an opponent. If you win, that creature gets an additional +2/+2 and gains trample until end of turn. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0213</id>
    <name>Garruk Wildspeaker</name>
    <text>+1: Untap two target lands.
-1: Put a 3/3 green Beast creature token onto the battlefield.
-4: Creatures you control get +3/+3 and gain trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0214</id>
    <name>Gilt-Leaf Ambush</name>
    <text>Put two 1/1 green Elf Warrior creature tokens onto the battlefield. Clash with an opponent. If you win, those creatures gain deathtouch until end of turn. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost. Creatures dealt damage by a creature with deathtouch are destroyed. You can divide combat damage from a creature with deathtouch among any of the creatures blocking or blocked by it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0215</id>
    <name>Gilt-Leaf Seer</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: Look at the top two cards of your library, then put them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>Desmera blinded her seers so that her beauty would be the last image burned in their memories. The act only deepened their insight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0216</id>
    <name>Guardian of Cloverdell</name>
    <text>When Guardian of Cloverdell enters the battlefield, put three 1/1 white Kithkin Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield.
{G}, Sacrifice a Kithkin: You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Although they're protective of all creatures, many treefolk are especially fond of the empathic kithkin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0217</id>
    <name>Heal the Scars</name>
    <text>Regenerate target creature. You gain life equal to that creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>Elvish battle-magic has evolved two specialties: inflicting wounds that scar, and healing wounds without scarring. Politics determines the recipients of each.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0218</id>
    <name>Hunt Down</name>
    <text>Target creature blocks target creature this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>"Springjacks and faeries can be difficult to hunt, but my favorite prey are the flamekin. They never fail to put up a worthy fight when cornered."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0219</id>
    <name>Immaculate Magistrate</name>
    <text>{T}: Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature for each Elf you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Elves of the immaculate class weave flora into living creatures—sometimes to endorse an elite warrior, sometimes to create a breathing work of art.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0220</id>
    <name>Imperious Perfect</name>
    <text>Other Elf creatures you control get +1/+1.
{G}, {T}: Put a 1/1 green Elf Warrior creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>In a culture of beauty, the most beautiful are worshipped as gods.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0221</id>
    <name>Incremental Growth</name>
    <text>Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature, two +1/+1 counters on another target creature, and three +1/+1 counters on a third target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Tie a mouse under a bridge, and your cabbages will triple in size."
—Kithkin superstition</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0222</id>
    <name>Jagged-Scar Archers</name>
    <text>Jagged-Scar Archers's power and toughness are each equal to the number of Elves you control.
{T}: Jagged-Scar Archers deals damage equal to its power to target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0223</id>
    <name>Kithkin Daggerdare</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: Target attacking creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The kith dance their elaborate reels not merely to celebrate the events of their lives but to form an unbreakable bond of loyalty with their kin, a bond stronger than the fear of death itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0224</id>
    <name>Kithkin Mourncaller</name>
    <text>Whenever an attacking Kithkin or Elf is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Eidren's hunts are dangerous affairs. All dread the inevitable recounting of those who died while flushing out his prey.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0225</id>
    <name>Lace with Moonglove</name>
    <text>Target creature gains deathtouch until end of turn. (Creatures dealt damage by that creature are destroyed. You can divide its combat damage among any of the creatures blocking or blocked by it.)
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Which is more filled with poison: the flower of the moonglove or the minds of elves?"
—Vessifrus, flamekin demagogue</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0226</id>
    <name>Lammastide Weave</name>
    <text>Name a card, then target player puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard. If that card is the named card, you gain life equal to its converted mana cost.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"A ribbon torn will ward away dark dreams."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0227</id>
    <name>Leaf Gilder</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Eidren, perfect of Lys Alana, ordered hundreds of trees uprooted and rearranged into a pattern he deemed beautiful. Thus the Gilt-Leaf Wood was born.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0228</id>
    <name>Lignify</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature is a 0/4 Treefolk with no abilities.</text>
    <flavorText>Bulgo paused, puzzled. What was that rustling sound, and why did he feel so stiff? And how could his feet be so thirsty?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0229</id>
    <name>Lys Alana Huntmaster</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an Elf spell, you may put a 1/1 green Elf Warrior creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>From the highest tiers of Dawn's Light Palace to the deepest shade of Wren's Run, the silver notes of the horn shimmer through the air, and all who hear it feel its pull.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0230</id>
    <name>Masked Admirers</name>
    <text>When Masked Admirers enters the battlefield, draw a card.
Whenever you cast a creature spell, you may pay {G}{G}. If you do, return Masked Admirers from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Beauty determines value, and we determine beauty."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0231</id>
    <name>Nath's Elite</name>
    <text>All creatures able to block Nath's Elite do so.
When Nath's Elite enters the battlefield, clash with an opponent. If you win, put a +1/+1 counter on Nath's Elite. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0232</id>
    <name>Oakgnarl Warrior</name>
    <text>Vigilance, trample</text>
    <flavorText>"Roam as you will, your roots remain in the strong earth of your Rising."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0233</id>
    <name>Primal Command</name>
    <text>Choose two — Target player gains 7 life; or put target noncreature permanent on top of its owner's library; or target player shuffles his or her graveyard into his or her library; or search your library for a creature card, reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0234</id>
    <name>Rootgrapple</name>
    <text>Destroy target noncreature permanent. If you control a Treefolk, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"All the sylvan secrets of this world are etched between my rings. The skinfolk's metal aberrations can rot between my roots."
—Colfenor, the Last Yew</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0235</id>
    <name>Seedguide Ash</name>
    <text>When Seedguide Ash is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may search your library for up to three Forest cards and put them onto the battlefield tapped. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"May you shade three generations of seedlings."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0236</id>
    <name>Spring Cleaning</name>
    <text>Destroy target enchantment. Clash with an opponent. If you win, destroy all enchantments your opponents control. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0237</id>
    <name>Sylvan Echoes</name>
    <text>Whenever you clash and win, you may draw a card. (This ability triggers after the clash ends.)</text>
    <flavorText>It takes a huntmaster's eye to discern the contours of mythical prey.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0238</id>
    <name>Timber Protector</name>
    <text>Other Treefolk creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other Treefolk and Forests you control are indestructible.</text>
    <flavorText>In his presence, an ordinary grove becomes a bastion to turn spells and break armies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0239</id>
    <name>Treefolk Harbinger</name>
    <text>When Treefolk Harbinger enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a Treefolk or Forest card, reveal it, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0240</id>
    <name>Vigor</name>
    <text>Trample
If damage would be dealt to a creature you control other than Vigor, prevent that damage. Put a +1/+1 counter on that creature for each 1 damage prevented this way.
When Vigor is put into a graveyard from anywhere, shuffle it into its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0241</id>
    <name>Warren-Scourge Elf</name>
    <text>Protection from Goblins</text>
    <flavorText>"If one can associate any virtue with the eyeblights, it is the talent some achieve in disposing of them. I have seen the slaying of boggarts raised nearly to an art form."
—Fiala, Gilt-Leaf winnower</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0242</id>
    <name>Woodland Changeling</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)</text>
    <flavorText>Changelings cannot resist the draw of a new shape, even if doing so would be in their best interests.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0243</id>
    <name>Woodland Guidance</name>
    <text>Return target card from your graveyard to your hand. Clash with an opponent. If you win, untap all Forests you control. (Each clashing player reveals the top card of his or her library, then puts that card on the top or bottom. A player wins if his or her card had a higher converted mana cost.)
Exile Woodland Guidance.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0244</id>
    <name>Wren's Run Packmaster</name>
    <text>Champion an Elf (When this enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you exile another Elf you control. When this leaves the battlefield, that card returns to the battlefield.)
{2}{G}: Put a 2/2 green Wolf creature token onto the battlefield.
Each Wolf you control has deathtouch. (Creatures dealt damage by those creatures are destroyed. You can divide their combat damage among any of the creatures blocking or blocked by it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0245</id>
    <name>Wren's Run Vanquisher</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Wren's Run Vanquisher, reveal an Elf card from your hand or pay {3}.
Deathtouch (Creatures dealt damage by this creature are destroyed. You can divide this creature's combat damage among any of the creatures blocking or blocked by it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0246</id>
    <name>Brion Stoutarm</name>
    <text>Lifelink (Damage dealt by this creature also causes you to gain that much life.)
{R}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature other than Brion Stoutarm: Brion Stoutarm deals damage equal to the sacrificed creature's power to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0247</id>
    <name>Doran, the Siege Tower</name>
    <text>Each creature assigns combat damage equal to its toughness rather than its power.</text>
    <flavorText>"Each year that passes rings you inwardly with memory and might. Wield your heart, and the world will tremble."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0248</id>
    <name>Gaddock Teeg</name>
    <text>Noncreature spells with converted mana cost 4 or greater can't be cast.
Noncreature spells with {X} in their mana costs can't be cast.</text>
    <flavorText>So great is his wisdom and spirit that many who have met him say that they stood before a giant of a man and talked to the wisest of the four winds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0249</id>
    <name>Horde of Notions</name>
    <text>Vigilance, trample, haste
{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}: You may play target Elemental card from your graveyard without paying its mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>Even the oldest treefolk was but an acorn when Lorwyn's first mysteries were born.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0250</id>
    <name>Nath of the Gilt-Leaf</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may have target opponent discard a card at random.
Whenever an opponent discards a card, you may put a 1/1 green Elf Warrior creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>A savage hunter with a prince's bearing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0251</id>
    <name>Sygg, River Guide</name>
    <text>Islandwalk
{1}{W}: Target Merfolk you control gains protection from the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"If there's a place worth going, the Merrow Lanes already do. And if there's a route worth taking, yours truly already has."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0252</id>
    <name>Wort, Boggart Auntie</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may return target Goblin card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Auntie always knows which berries to lick, which kithkin to trick, and what to do when either goes wrong.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0253</id>
    <name>Wydwen, the Biting Gale</name>
    <text>Flash
Flying
{U}{B}, Pay 1 life: Return Wydwen, the Biting Gale to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>In a world of bright, cloudless skies, she is the dark storm on the horizon.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0254</id>
    <name>Colfenor's Urn</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature with toughness 4 or greater is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, you may exile it.
At the beginning of the end step, if three or more cards have been exiled with Colfenor's Urn, sacrifice it. If you do, return those cards to the battlefield under their owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0255</id>
    <name>Deathrender</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +2/+2.
Whenever equipped creature is put into a graveyard, you may put a creature card from your hand onto the battlefield and attach Deathrender to it.
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0256</id>
    <name>Dolmen Gate</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to attacking creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Lorwyn's stones resonate with the place from which they were hewed. Though taken far, still they call to their home when silence is upon the land.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0257</id>
    <name>Herbal Poultice</name>
    <text>{3}, Sacrifice Herbal Poultice: Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Apply orange leaf to a wound at dawn to clean it, at dusk to prevent the same injury from happening again."
—Kithkin superstition</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0258</id>
    <name>Moonglove Extract</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Moonglove Extract: Moonglove Extract deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Diluted, moonglove can etch living tissue. Concentrated, a drop will kill a giant.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0259</id>
    <name>Rings of Brighthearth</name>
    <text>Whenever you activate an ability, if it isn't a mana ability, you may pay {2}. If you do, copy that ability. You may choose new targets for the copy.</text>
    <flavorText>"Without flame, there would be no iron tools, no cooked meals, no purge of old growth to make room for new."
—Brighthearth creed</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0260</id>
    <name>Runed Stalactite</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +1/+1 and is every creature type.
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>When a changeling adopts a form no other changeling has taken, a rune appears in the caverns of Velis Vel to mark the event.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0261</id>
    <name>Springleaf Drum</name>
    <text>{T}, Tap an untapped creature you control: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>After trying mudskippers for an afternoon, Scratch decided that crickcarp made the best noise.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0262</id>
    <name>Thorn of Amethyst</name>
    <text>Noncreature spells cost {1} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>Mined from a cave in the Dark Meanders, it shines brightest when no one is looking.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0263</id>
    <name>Thousand-Year Elixir</name>
    <text>You may activate abilities of creatures you control as though those creatures had haste.
{1}, {T}: Untap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Paradoxically, to tilt the massive jug for a sip, you'd need the energy of the giant's tonic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0264</id>
    <name>Twinning Glass</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: You may cast a nonland card from your hand without paying its mana cost if it has the same name as a spell that was cast this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It takes two to craft a mirror: a practiced metalsmith to silver one side and her own hazy reflection to polish the other.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0265</id>
    <name>Wanderer's Twig</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice Wanderer's Twig: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>For every tree who falls, there are countless sprouts waiting to rise.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0266</id>
    <name>Ancient Amphitheater</name>
    <text>As Ancient Amphitheater enters the battlefield, you may reveal a Giant card from your hand. If you don't, Ancient Amphitheater enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} or {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The arbiter Galanda Feudkiller judges Lorwyn's squabbles from a lofty perspective.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0267</id>
    <name>Auntie's Hovel</name>
    <text>As Auntie's Hovel enters the battlefield, you may reveal a Goblin card from your hand. If you don't, Auntie's Hovel enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The Stinkdrinker warren's hill of salvaged trinkets is large enough to cut a door in.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0268</id>
    <name>Gilt-Leaf Palace</name>
    <text>As Gilt-Leaf Palace enters the battlefield, you may reveal an Elf card from your hand. If you don't, Gilt-Leaf Palace enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} or {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Dawn's Light, greatest palace of Gilt-Leaf Wood, is built on tiers of wood and power.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0269</id>
    <name>Howltooth Hollow</name>
    <text>Hideaway (This land enters the battlefield tapped. When it does, look at the top four cards of your library, exile one face down, then put the rest on the bottom of your library.)
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.
{B}, {T}: You may play the exiled card without paying its mana cost if each player has no cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0270</id>
    <name>Mosswort Bridge</name>
    <text>Hideaway (This land enters the battlefield tapped. When it does, look at the top four cards of your library, exile one face down, then put the rest on the bottom of your library.)
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{G}, {T}: You may play the exiled card without paying its mana cost if creatures you control have total power 10 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0271</id>
    <name>Secluded Glen</name>
    <text>As Secluded Glen enters the battlefield, you may reveal a Faerie card from your hand. If you don't, Secluded Glen enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Protected by glamers and guile, Glen Elendra harbors the elusive Oona, queen of the fae.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0272</id>
    <name>Shelldock Isle</name>
    <text>Hideaway (This land enters the battlefield tapped. When it does, look at the top four cards of your library, exile one face down, then put the rest on the bottom of your library.)
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.
{U}, {T}: You may play the exiled card without paying its mana cost if a library has twenty or fewer cards in it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0273</id>
    <name>Shimmering Grotto</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Once each year, the sun's rays reach the hidden chamber of Velis Vel, and the changelings congregate from afar to bathe in the ever-shifting light.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0274</id>
    <name>Spinerock Knoll</name>
    <text>Hideaway (This land enters the battlefield tapped. When it does, look at the top four cards of your library, exile one face down, then put the rest on the bottom of your library.)
{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.
{R}, {T}: You may play the exiled card without paying its mana cost if an opponent was dealt 7 or more damage this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0275</id>
    <name>Vivid Crag</name>
    <text>Vivid Crag enters the battlefield tapped with two charge counters on it.
{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.
{T}, Remove a charge counter from Vivid Crag: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0276</id>
    <name>Vivid Creek</name>
    <text>Vivid Creek enters the battlefield tapped with two charge counters on it.
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.
{T}, Remove a charge counter from Vivid Creek: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0277</id>
    <name>Vivid Grove</name>
    <text>Vivid Grove enters the battlefield tapped with two charge counters on it.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{T}, Remove a charge counter from Vivid Grove: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0278</id>
    <name>Vivid Marsh</name>
    <text>Vivid Marsh enters the battlefield tapped with two charge counters on it.
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.
{T}, Remove a charge counter from Vivid Marsh: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0279</id>
    <name>Vivid Meadow</name>
    <text>Vivid Meadow enters the battlefield tapped with two charge counters on it.
{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.
{T}, Remove a charge counter from Vivid Meadow: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0280</id>
    <name>Wanderwine Hub</name>
    <text>As Wanderwine Hub enters the battlefield, you may reveal a Merfolk card from your hand. If you don't, Wanderwine Hub enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Below the great river, a bustling hub channels the flow of merrow trade.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0281</id>
    <name>Windbrisk Heights</name>
    <text>Hideaway (This land enters the battlefield tapped. When it does, look at the top four cards of your library, exile one face down, then put the rest on the bottom of your library.)
{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.
{W}, {T}: You may play the exiled card without paying its mana cost if you attacked with three or more creatures this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0282</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0283</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0284</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0285</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0286</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0287</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0288</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0289</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0290</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0291</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0292</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0293</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0294</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0295</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0296</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0297</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0298</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0299</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0300</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>LRW0301</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>