<cards name="Mirage">
  <item>
    <id>MIR0001</id>
    <name>Abyssal Hunter</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}: Tap target creature. Abyssal Hunter deals damage equal to Abyssal Hunter's power to that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Some smiles show cheer; some merely show teeth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0002</id>
    <name>Acidic Dagger</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Whenever target creature deals combat damage to a non-Wall creature this turn, destroy that non-Wall creature. When the targeted creature leaves the battlefield this turn, sacrifice Acidic Dagger. Activate this ability only during combat before blockers are declared.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0003</id>
    <name>Afiya Grove</name>
    <text>Afiya Grove enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, move a +1/+1 counter from Afiya Grove onto target creature.
When Afiya Grove has no +1/+1 counters on it, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0004</id>
    <name>Afterlife</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature. It can't be regenerated. Its controller puts a 1/1 white Spirit creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Facets of life, reflections of the soul.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0005</id>
    <name>Agility</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has flanking. (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0006</id>
    <name>Alarum</name>
    <text>Untap target nonattacking creature. It gets +1/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"One timely cry of warning can save nine of surprise."
—Sidar Jabari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0007</id>
    <name>Aleatory</name>
    <text>Cast Aleatory only during combat after blockers are declared.
Flip a coin. If you win the flip, target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0008</id>
    <name>Amber Prison</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Amber Prison during your untap step.
{4}, {T}: Tap target artifact, creature, or land. That permanent doesn't untap during its controller's untap step for as long as Amber Prison remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0009</id>
    <name>Amulet of Unmaking</name>
    <text>{5}, {T}, Exile Amulet of Unmaking: Exile target artifact, creature, or land. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>Trade to trade, not to keep.
—Suq'Ata motto</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0010</id>
    <name>Ancestral Memories</name>
    <text>Look at the top seven cards of your library. Put two of them into your hand and the rest into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"Even the ancient storytellers proclaimed Zhalfir to be dominant over all Jamuraa. Kaervek's invasion shocked us all."
—Hakim, Loreweaver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0011</id>
    <name>Armor of Thorns</name>
    <text>You may cast Armor of Thorns as though it had flash. If you cast it any time a sorcery couldn't have been cast, the controller of the permanent it becomes sacrifices it at the beginning of the next cleanup step.
Enchant nonblack creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0012</id>
    <name>Armorer Guildmage</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}: Target creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
{G}, {T}: Target creature gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Zhalfir's destiny rings in tempered steel.
—Armorer Guild maxim</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0013</id>
    <name>Ashen Powder</name>
    <text>Put target creature card from an opponent's graveyard onto the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>"What you call decay, I call ripening. You'll gain no sustenance from this harvest."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0014</id>
    <name>Asmira, Holy Avenger</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of each end step, put a +1/+1 counter on Asmira, Holy Avenger for each creature put into your graveyard from the battlefield this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Omens lie in this early harvest's fruit."
—Asmira, Holy Avenger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0015</id>
    <name>Auspicious Ancestor</name>
    <text>When Auspicious Ancestor is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you gain 3 life.
Whenever a player casts a white spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0016</id>
    <name>Azimaet Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
{U}: Azimaet Drake gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"A vizier's dish, best served drenched in honey and almonds."
—Suq'Ata royal recipe</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0017</id>
    <name>Bad River</name>
    <text>Bad River enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}, Sacrifice Bad River: Search your library for an Island or Swamp card and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0018</id>
    <name>Barbed Foliage</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature attacks you, it loses flanking until end of turn.

Whenever a creature without flying attacks you, Barbed Foliage deals 1 damage to it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0019</id>
    <name>Barbed-Back Wurm</name>
    <text>{B}: Target green creature blocking Barbed-Back Wurm gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Mwonvuli Jungle has given the darkness teeth for tearing the gift of life from the weak."
—Jolrael</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0020</id>
    <name>Barreling Attack</name>
    <text>Target creature gains trample until end of turn. When that creature becomes blocked this turn, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it.</text>
    <flavorText>"The trollish game of push-fall inspired this impressive tactic."
—Sidar Jabari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0021</id>
    <name>Basalt Golem</name>
    <text>Basalt Golem can't be blocked by artifact creatures.
Whenever Basalt Golem becomes blocked by a creature, that creature's controller sacrifices it at end of combat. If the player does, he or she puts a 0/2 colorless Wall artifact creature token with defender onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0022</id>
    <name>Bay Falcon</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>"Wear the falcon's feathers in your hair—
be fast as the falcon, bright as the Sun."
—"Rise on Wings," Zhalfirin song</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0023</id>
    <name>Bazaar of Wonders</name>
    <text>When Bazaar of Wonders enters the battlefield, exile all cards from all graveyards.
Whenever a player casts a spell, counter it if a card with the same name is in a graveyard or a nontoken permanent with the same name is on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0024</id>
    <name>Benevolent Unicorn</name>
    <text>If a spell would deal damage to a creature or player, it deals that much damage minus 1 to that creature or player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>The best use for a unicorn's horn is to adorn a unicorn.
—Femeref adage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0025</id>
    <name>Benthic Djinn</name>
    <text>Islandwalk

At the beginning of your upkeep, you lose 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"In all my years I've only met one mage who successfully trapped a djinn—and none who tried and failed."
—Talibah, embermage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0026</id>
    <name>Binding Agony</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature is dealt damage, Binding Agony deals that much damage to that creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>A crash of rhinos in my head
—Femeref expression meaning
"a severe head pain"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0027</id>
    <name>Blighted Shaman</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a Swamp: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
{T}, Sacrifice a creature: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0028</id>
    <name>Blind Fury</name>
    <text>Cast Blind Fury only before the combat damage step.
All creatures lose trample until end of turn. If a creature would deal combat damage to a creature this turn, it deals double that damage to that creature instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"Tell me . . . have you ever sung the Song of Blood?"
—Purraj of Urborg</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0029</id>
    <name>Blinding Light</name>
    <text>Tap all nonwhite creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"My shield will bear a shining sun so you will always be with me. / Inlaid with gold, it will shine like glowing embers."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0030</id>
    <name>Blistering Barrier</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</text>
    <flavorText>I live without food, stand without leg, wound without force, and am harder to fight than to kill. What am I?
—Femeref riddle</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0031</id>
    <name>Bone Harvest</name>
    <text>Put any number of target creature cards from your graveyard on top of your library.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"Only fools believe they will face my armies but once."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0032</id>
    <name>Bone Mask</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage. For each 1 damage prevented this way, exile the top card of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"The protection offered comes at a price. How numerous are your kin?"
—Purraj of Urborg</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0033</id>
    <name>Boomerang</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>A lie always returns; be careful how you catch it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0034</id>
    <name>Breathstealer</name>
    <text>{B}: Breathstealer gets +1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"As a child, I slept with a cloth over my face, to hide from the spirits that might pull the air from my lungs."
—Mosi, Femeref weaver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0035</id>
    <name>Brushwagg</name>
    <text>Whenever Brushwagg blocks or becomes blocked, it gets -2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Defiantly, the young cyclops popped the brushwagg into his mouth. His cheeks suddenly puffed, his eye bulged, and he was forced to agree with his elder."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0036</id>
    <name>Builder's Bane</name>
    <text>Destroy X target artifacts. Builder's Bane deals damage to each player equal to the number of artifacts he or she controlled destroyed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>There is only so much a person may be buried with.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0037</id>
    <name>Burning Palm Efreet</name>
    <text>{1}{R}{R}: Burning Palm Efreet deals 2 damage to target creature with flying and that creature loses flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Even the lion envies the lark.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0038</id>
    <name>Burning Shield Askari</name>
    <text>Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)
{R}{R}: Burning Shield Askari gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Any day that I ride my horse up to my ankles in the remains of my enemies is a good day."
—Akin, seasoned askari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0039</id>
    <name>Cadaverous Bloom</name>
    <text>Exile a card from your hand: Add {B}{B} or {G}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's filthy work, planting them."
—Kifimbo, Shadow Guildmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0040</id>
    <name>Cadaverous Knight</name>
    <text>Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)
{1}{B}{B}: Regenerate Cadaverous Knight.</text>
    <flavorText>Grieve for the soul in death dishonored.
—Shadow Guild saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0041</id>
    <name>Canopy Dragon</name>
    <text>Trample
{1}{G}: Canopy Dragon gains flying and loses trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"In the Mwonvuli you must divide your attention between what hangs overhead and what lies underfoot."
—Sidar Jabari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0042</id>
    <name>Carrion</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Carrion, sacrifice a creature.
Put X 0/1 black Insect creature tokens onto the battlefield, where X is the sacrificed creature's power.</text>
    <flavorText>King or herder, the maggots care not.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0043</id>
    <name>Catacomb Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Catacomb Dragon becomes blocked by a nonartifact, non-Dragon creature, that creature gets -X/-0 until end of turn, where X is half the creature's power, rounded down.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0044</id>
    <name>Celestial Dawn</name>
    <text>Lands you control are Plains.
Nonland cards you own that aren't on the battlefield, spells you control, and nonland permanents you control are white.
You may spend white mana as though it were mana of any color. You may spend other mana only as though it were colorless mana.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0045</id>
    <name>Cerulean Wyvern</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from green</text>
    <flavorText>"Once, a Quirion asked why I was so cautious when the day was clear. I told him of the sky-blue hide of the cerluean wyvern, and he offered me double if I could conjure a strong tailwind"
—Sisay, Captain of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0046</id>
    <name>Chaos Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Destroy target Wall; or Chaos Charm deals 1 damage to target creature; or target creature gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0047</id>
    <name>Chaosphere</name>
    <text>Creatures with flying can block only creatures with flying.
Creatures without flying have reach. (They can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I dance the nothing dance, / Feet in the air, knives in the ground."
—Femeref chant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0048</id>
    <name>Charcoal Diamond</name>
    <text>Charcoal Diamond enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0049</id>
    <name>Chariot of the Sun</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Until end of turn, target creature you control gains flying and its toughness becomes 1.</text>
    <flavorText>"Sun follows Moon until she tires, then carries her until she's strong / and runs ahead of him again."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0050</id>
    <name>Choking Sands</name>
    <text>Destroy target non-Swamp land. If that land was nonbasic, Choking Sands deals 2 damage to the land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>"The people wiped the sand from their eyes and cursed—and left the barren land to the hyenas and vipers."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0051</id>
    <name>Cinder Cloud</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature. If a white creature is put into a graveyard this way, Cinder Cloud deals damage to that creature's controller equal to the creature's power.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0052</id>
    <name>Circle of Despair</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice a creature: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to target creature or player this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>"Life is a resource that should belong only to the strong."
—Shauku, Endbringer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0053</id>
    <name>Civic Guildmage</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: Target creature gets +0/+1 until end of turn.
{U}, {T}: Put target creature you control on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>To condemn the innocent you must first condemn yourself.
—Civic Guild maxim</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0054</id>
    <name>Cloak of Invisibility</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has phasing and can't be blocked except by Walls. (It phases in or out before its controller untaps during each of his or her untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Useful . . . if you can find it."
—Pashad ibn Asim, Suq'Ata trader</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0055</id>
    <name>Consuming Ferocity</name>
    <text>Enchant non-Wall creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+0.
At the beginning of your upkeep, put a +1/+0 counter on enchanted creature. If that creature has three or more +1/+0 counters on it, it deals damage equal to its power to its controller, then destroy that creature and it can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0056</id>
    <name>Coral Fighters</name>
    <text>Whenever Coral Fighters attacks and isn't blocked, look at the top card of defending player's library. You may put that card on the bottom of that player's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0057</id>
    <name>Crash of Rhinos</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>Love is like a rhino, short-sighted and hasty; if it cannot find a way, it will make a way.
—Femeref adage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0058</id>
    <name>Crimson Hellkite</name>
    <text>Flying

{X}, {T}: Crimson Hellkite deals X damage to target creature. Spend only red mana this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"Dragonfire forged me a warrior."
—Rashida Scalebane</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0059</id>
    <name>Crimson Roc</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Crimson Roc blocks a creature without flying, Crimson Roc gets +1/+0 and gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0060</id>
    <name>Crypt Cobra</name>
    <text>Whenever Crypt Cobra attacks and isn't blocked, defending player gets a poison counter. (A player with ten or more poison counters loses the game.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0061</id>
    <name>Crystal Golem</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your end step, Crystal Golem phases out. (While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist. It phases in before you untap during your next untap step.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Once, a wealthy king commissioned an artificial creature to be crafted from the royal treasury, thinking it a clever ploy to have the jewels guard themselves."
—Azeworai, "The Golem's Wish"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0062</id>
    <name>Crystal Vein</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{T}, Sacrifice Crystal Vein: Add {2} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0063</id>
    <name>Cursed Totem</name>
    <text>Activated abilities of creatures can't be activated.</text>
    <flavorText>Pass me from soul to soul / soldier to herder, herder to beast, beast to soil / until I am everywhere. / Then pass me those souls.
—Totem inscription (translated)</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0064</id>
    <name>Cycle of Life</name>
    <text>Return Cycle of Life to its owner's hand: Target creature you cast this turn becomes 0/1 until your next upkeep. At the beginning of your next upkeep, put a +1/+1 counter on that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Thus does nature assert herself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0065</id>
    <name>Daring Apprentice</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Daring Apprentice: Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>In front of every great wizard is a doomed apprentice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0066</id>
    <name>Dark Banishing</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Femeref was guided by the wisdom of the Council of Voices. But in one terrible instant, they were slain, leaving Asmira as the sole voice of leadership."
—Hakim, Loreweaver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0067</id>
    <name>Dark Ritual</name>
    <text>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"The ceremony ended with a voice from the shadows, a voice with vast, ominous power."
—Kifimbo, Shadow Guildmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0068</id>
    <name>Dazzling Beauty</name>
    <text>Cast Dazzling Beauty only during the declare blockers step.
Target attacking unblocked creature becomes blocked.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0069</id>
    <name>Decomposition</name>
    <text>Enchant black creature
Enchanted creature has "Cumulative upkeep—Pay 1 life." (At the beginning of its controller's upkeep, that player puts an age counter on it, then sacrifices it unless he or she pays its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, its controller loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0070</id>
    <name>Delirium</name>
    <text>Cast Delirium only during an opponent's turn.
Tap target creature that player controls. That creature deals damage equal to its power to the player. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by the creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0071</id>
    <name>Dirtwater Wraith</name>
    <text>Swampwalk

{B}: Dirtwater Wraith gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The foul entities of the Uuserk swamp had never before dared to spread their influence to the very heart of Zhalfir."
—Hakim, Loreweaver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0072</id>
    <name>Discordant Spirit</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each end step, if it's an opponent's turn, put a +1/+1 counter on Discordant Spirit for each 1 damage dealt to you this turn.
At the beginning of your end step, remove all +1/+1 counters on Discordant Spirit.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0073</id>
    <name>Disempower</name>
    <text>Put target artifact or enchantment on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mangara is gone. Who among you doubts that I have taken his power?"
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0074</id>
    <name>Disenchant</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"There are harsher ways to learn the meaning of the word ‘no.'"
—Rashida Scalebane</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0075</id>
    <name>Dissipate</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. If that spell is countered this way, exile it instead of putting it into its owner's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you weren't born with it, you don't need it."
—Grahilah, former trader of Amiqat</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0076</id>
    <name>Divine Offering</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact. You gain life equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"Suq'Ata believe in trade; Femeref, alms; Zhalfirins, steel. Be warned, Kaervek—now we are joined."
—Sidar Jabari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0077</id>
    <name>Divine Retribution</name>
    <text>Divine Retribution deals damage to target attacking creature equal to the number of attacking creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"To the undiscerning eye, justice and vengeance can look the same."
—Rashida Scalebane</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0078</id>
    <name>Drain Life</name>
    <text>Spend only black mana on X.
Drain Life deals X damage to target creature or player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt, but not more life than the player's life total before Drain Life dealt damage or the creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0079</id>
    <name>Dread Specter</name>
    <text>Whenever Dread Specter blocks or becomes blocked by a nonblack creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>Whatever follows life is incurable.
—Zhalfirin aphorism</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0080</id>
    <name>Dream Cache</name>
    <text>Draw three cards, then put two cards from your hand both on top of your library or both on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Dreams' riches are easily spent.
—Suq'Ata adage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0081</id>
    <name>Dream Fighter</name>
    <text>Whenever Dream Fighter blocks or becomes blocked by a creature, Dream Fighter and that creature phase out. (While they're phased out, they're treated as though they don't exist. Each one phases in before its controller untaps during his or her next untap step.)</text>
    <flavorText>Not only the sleeping should fear dreams.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0082</id>
    <name>Dwarven Miner</name>
    <text>{2}{R}, {T}: Destroy target nonbasic land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Fetch the pestridder, Paka—we've got dwarves in the rutabagas"
—Jamul, Femeref farmer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0083</id>
    <name>Dwarven Nomad</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature with power 2 or less is unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A dwarf's life belongs as much to the land as to the dwarf.
—Creed of the Stonethrow Clan</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0084</id>
    <name>Early Harvest</name>
    <text>Target player untaps all basic lands he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"Tonight we'll eat a farewell feast. Cold corn porridge is not enough. / Let's peel papayas, pineapples, and mangoes, drink coconut milk, / and bake bananas."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0085</id>
    <name>Ebony Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target opponent loses 1 life and you gain 1 life; or exile up to three target cards from a single graveyard; or target creature gains fear until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0086</id>
    <name>Ekundu Cyclops</name>
    <text>If a creature you control attacks, Ekundu Cyclops also attacks if able.</text>
    <flavorText>"Big one I,
One big eye.
One-eye see
Two-eye die"
—Traditional cyclops chant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0087</id>
    <name>Ekundu Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying, first strike</text>
    <flavorText>"My goat was a small price to pay for the chance to see the hunting griffin dive and seize it."
—Pashad ibn Asim, Suq'Ata trader</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0088</id>
    <name>Elixir of Vitality</name>
    <text>Elixir of Vitality enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}, Sacrifice Elixir of Vitality: You gain 4 life.
{8}, {T}, Sacrifice Elixir of Vitality: You gain 8 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Eternal life or your money back."
—Unnamed Suq'Ata merchant, deceased</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0089</id>
    <name>Emberwilde Caliph</name>
    <text>Flying, trample

Emberwilde Caliph attacks each turn if able.

Whenever Emberwilde Caliph deals damage, you lose that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>The fire breathes while the air burns.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0090</id>
    <name>Emberwilde Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying

At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player may pay {R}{R} or 2 life. If he or she does, the player gains control of Emberwilde Djinn.</text>
    <flavorText>A hefty price is no guarantee of quality merchandise.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0091</id>
    <name>Energy Bolt</name>
    <text>Choose one — Energy Bolt deals X damage to target player; or target player gains X life.</text>
    <flavorText>Life and death are two faces of the same coin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0092</id>
    <name>Energy Vortex</name>
    <text>As Energy Vortex enters the battlefield, choose an opponent.
At the beginning of your upkeep, remove all energy counters from Energy Vortex.
At the beginning of the chosen player's upkeep, Energy Vortex deals 3 damage to that player unless he or she pays {1} for each energy counter on Energy Vortex.
{X}: Put X energy counters on Energy Vortex. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0093</id>
    <name>Enfeeblement</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature gets -2/-2.</text>
    <flavorText>"If it is weak, either kill it or ignore it. Anything else honors it."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0094</id>
    <name>Enlightened Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for an artifact or enchantment card and reveal that card. Shuffle your library, then put the card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>"I do not teach. I simply reveal."
—Daudi, Femeref tutor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0095</id>
    <name>Ersatz Gnomes</name>
    <text>{T}: Target spell is colorless.

{T}: Target permanent becomes colorless until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>From jungle to sea, from sea to stone, from stone to field, from field to bone. What am I?    Zhalfirin riddle</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0096</id>
    <name>Ether Well</name>
    <text>Put target creature on top of its owner's library. If that creature is red, you may put it on the bottom of its owner's library instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"Whoa—my tail will never fit through that hole"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0097</id>
    <name>Ethereal Champion</name>
    <text>Pay 1 life: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to Ethereal Champion this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"If I have learned anything as a wizard it is this: never fight your own battles."
—Waffa, sorcerer of Nyomba</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0098</id>
    <name>Fallow Earth</name>
    <text>Put target land on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>". . . and when the farmer awoke the next morning, all the seeds from his field were once again in their sacks."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0099</id>
    <name>Favorable Destiny</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+2 as long as it's white.
Enchanted creature has shroud as long as its controller controls another creature. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0100</id>
    <name>Femeref Archers</name>
    <text>{T}: Femeref Archers deals 4 damage to target attacking creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"They say a Zhalfirin archer can split the eye of a griffin. Nonsense, of course: they have no faith to guide their darts."
—Nuru, Femeref archer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0101</id>
    <name>Femeref Healer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Faith is my shield, and hope is my armor; I am vulnerable only to myself."
—Asmira, Holy Avenger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0102</id>
    <name>Femeref Knight</name>
    <text>Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)
{W}: Femeref Knight gains vigilance until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I will return / with lizard skins for your sandals. Paint your eyes black and wait for me."    "Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0103</id>
    <name>Femeref Scouts</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"The days before the war were filled with strange portents: scouts and herders spoke of villages reduced to ash, of farmers taken from their fields, and of foul beasts roaming the plains in packs. I know, for I spoke to them all."
—Hakim, Loreweaver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0104</id>
    <name>Feral Shadow</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"The night stalkers are such a minor power in Urborg. Their sad eagerness to elevate themselves makes them willing tools in the plundering of little Femeref."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0105</id>
    <name>Fetid Horror</name>
    <text>{B}: Fetid Horror gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Of the six who went down the Uuserek Trail to scout ahead, one returned. She clawed at her eyes and nostrils and sobbed with horror. I was curious about what she saw, but we chose another path."
—Scout Ekemet, final journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0106</id>
    <name>Final Fortune</name>
    <text>Take an extra turn after this one. At the beginning of that turn's end step, you lose the game.</text>
    <flavorText>Want all, lose all.
—Zhalfirin aphorism</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0107</id>
    <name>Fire Diamond</name>
    <text>Fire Diamond enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0108</id>
    <name>Firebreathing</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Magic's only part of it, my friend. Diet does the rest."
—Pashad ibn Asim, Suq'Ata trader</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0109</id>
    <name>Flame Elemental</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}, Sacrifice Flame Elemental: Flame Elemental deals damage equal to its power to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Storyteller: By my hand in the fire, this story is a tale of power.
Listeners: May it give you strength.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0110</id>
    <name>Flare</name>
    <text>Flare deals 1 damage to target creature or player.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"In the forest, fires light the sky as black clouds unfold their weight."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0111</id>
    <name>Flash</name>
    <text>You may put a creature card from your hand onto the battlefield. If you do, sacrifice it unless you pay its mana cost reduced by up to {2}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0112</id>
    <name>Flood Plain</name>
    <text>Flood Plain enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}, Sacrifice Flood Plain: Search your library for a Plains or Island card and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0113</id>
    <name>Floodgate</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
When Floodgate has flying, sacrifice it.
When Floodgate leaves the battlefield, it deals damage equal to half the number of Islands you control, rounded down, to each nonblue creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Quick, Rhirhok—teach me to swim"
—Makht, goblin casualty</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0114</id>
    <name>Fog</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"More armies have been lost in the confusion of the jungle mists than to any battle."
—Jolrael</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0115</id>
    <name>Foratog</name>
    <text>{G}, Sacrifice a Forest: Foratog gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Five hundred years to grow—barely a minute to eat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0116</id>
    <name>Forbidden Crypt</name>
    <text>If you would draw a card, return a card from your graveyard to your hand instead. If you can't, you lose the game.
If a card would be put into your graveyard from anywhere, exile that card instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0117</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0118</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0119</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0120</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0121</id>
    <name>Forsaken Wastes</name>
    <text>Players can't gain life.
At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player loses 1 life.
Whenever Forsaken Wastes becomes the target of a spell, that spell's controller loses 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0122</id>
    <name>Frenetic Efreet</name>
    <text>Flying
{0}: Flip a coin. If you win the flip, Frenetic Efreet phases out. If you lose the flip, sacrifice Frenetic Efreet. (While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist. It phases in before you untap during your next untap step.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0123</id>
    <name>Giant Mantis</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I hate insects of every sort. The only mercy is that they are generally small."
—Mwani, Mtenda goatherd</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0124</id>
    <name>Gibbering Hyenas</name>
    <text>Gibbering Hyenas can't block black creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Hyenas laughing—what's the joke?
—Femeref phrase meaning
"that's not funny"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0125</id>
    <name>Goblin Elite Infantry</name>
    <text>Whenever Goblin Elite Infantry blocks or becomes blocked, it gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>They talk a good fight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0126</id>
    <name>Goblin Scouts</name>
    <text>Put three 1/1 red Goblin Scout creature tokens with mountainwalk onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Pathetic—like I wouldn't know a goblin painted up to look like a dwarf"
—Pashad ibn Asim, Suq'Ata trader</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0127</id>
    <name>Goblin Soothsayer</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}, Sacrifice a Goblin: Red creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I see a great victory and rivers of blood. And . . . hmm, looks like a spleen."
—Grishnak, goblin soothsayer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0128</id>
    <name>Goblin Tinkerer</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}: Destroy target artifact. That artifact deals damage equal to its converted mana cost to Goblin Tinkerer.</text>
    <flavorText>"Can they do that?"
—Imwita, Zhalfirin artificer, last words</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0129</id>
    <name>Granger Guildmage</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.
{R}, {T}: Granger Guildmage deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>Leave no mouth agape, no stomach unfilled.
—Granger Guild maxim</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0130</id>
    <name>Grasslands</name>
    <text>Grasslands enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}, Sacrifice Grasslands: Search your library for a Forest or Plains card and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0131</id>
    <name>Grave Servitude</name>
    <text>You may cast Grave Servitude as though it had flash. If you cast it any time a sorcery couldn't have been cast, the controller of the permanent it becomes sacrifices it at the beginning of the next cleanup step.
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/-1 and is black.</text>
    <flavorText>"I no longer believe in a final resting place."
—Shauku, Endbringer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0132</id>
    <name>Gravebane Zombie</name>
    <text>If Gravebane Zombie would be put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put Gravebane Zombie on top of its owner's library instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"A zombie's bed must be a lumpy one or he wouldn't leave it so often."
—Rana, Suq'Ata market fool</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0133</id>
    <name>Grim Feast</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Grim Feast deals 1 damage to you.
Whenever a creature is put into an opponent's graveyard from the battlefield, you gain life equal to its toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>"Hmmm—midnight snack."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0134</id>
    <name>Grinning Totem</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Grinning Totem: Search target opponent's library for a card and exile it. Then that player shuffles his or her library. Until the beginning of your next upkeep, you may play that card. At the beginning of your next upkeep, if you haven't played it, put it into its owner's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0135</id>
    <name>Hakim, Loreweaver</name>
    <text>Flying
{U}{U}: Return target Aura card from your graveyard to the battlefield attached to Hakim, Loreweaver. Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only if Hakim isn't enchanted.
{U}{U}, {T}: Destroy all Auras attached to Hakim.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0136</id>
    <name>Hall of Gemstone</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player chooses a color. Until end of turn, lands tapped for mana produce mana of the chosen color instead of any other color.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0137</id>
    <name>Hammer of Bogardan</name>
    <text>Hammer of Bogardan deals 3 damage to target creature or player.
{2}{R}{R}{R}: Return Hammer of Bogardan from your graveyard to your hand. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0138</id>
    <name>Harbinger of Night</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a -1/-1 counter on each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Embrace the Harbinger
—Suq'Ata expression meaning
"abandon hope"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0139</id>
    <name>Harbor Guardian</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)
Whenever Harbor Guardian attacks, defending player may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our guardian levies a tax on all traders. Wise travelers pay with a minimum of fuss."
—Qhattib, Vizier of Amiqat</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0140</id>
    <name>Harmattan Efreet</name>
    <text>Flying

{1}{U}{U}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"One moment I was walking along the beach, and the next I was high in the air, staring into a hideous smiling face."
—Tarub, Suq'Ata sailor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0141</id>
    <name>Haunting Apparition</name>
    <text>Flying
As Haunting Apparition enters the battlefield, choose an opponent.
Haunting Apparition's power is equal to 1 plus the number of green creature cards in the chosen player's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Like some foul herdbeast, it grazes on the dead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0142</id>
    <name>Hazerider Drake</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from red</text>
    <flavorText>"The hazerider danced in the thunderstorm and sang to its music."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0143</id>
    <name>Healing Salve</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target player gains 3 life; or prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Femeref look only to the Sun for healing; they have never truly understood life's cycle."
—Kifimbo, Shadow Guildmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0144</id>
    <name>Hivis of the Scale</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Hivis of the Scale during your untap step.
{T}: Gain control of target Dragon for as long as you control Hivis and Hivis remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0145</id>
    <name>Horrible Hordes</name>
    <text>Rampage 1 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</text>
    <flavorText>Few are able to underestimate the hordes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0146</id>
    <name>Igneous Golem</name>
    <text>{2}: Igneous Golem gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The creature rose from the mountain, its body weeping fire."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0147</id>
    <name>Illicit Auction</name>
    <text>Each player may bid life for control of target creature. You start the bidding with a bid of 0. In turn order, each player may top the high bid. The bidding ends if the high bid stands. The high bidder loses life equal to the high bid and gains control of the creature. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0148</id>
    <name>Illumination</name>
    <text>Counter target artifact or enchantment spell. Its controller gains life equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"A brilliant light can either illuminate or blind. How will you know which until you open your eyes?"
—Asmira, Holy Avenger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0149</id>
    <name>Incinerate</name>
    <text>Incinerate deals 3 damage to target creature or player. A creature dealt damage this way can't be regenerated this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Never taunt an embermage, ‘What are you going to do about it?'"
—Akin, seasoned askari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0150</id>
    <name>Infernal Contract</name>
    <text>Draw four cards. You lose half your life, rounded up.</text>
    <flavorText>"But I signed nothing"
—Taraneh, Suq'Ata mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0151</id>
    <name>Iron Tusk Elephant</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>"The fury in the lion's eye;
the patience in the hippo's yawn;
the pride within the griffin's cry
are one within the iron tusk's stride."
—"Iron Tusk," Femeref song</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0152</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0153</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0154</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0155</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0156</id>
    <name>Ivory Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — All creatures get -2/-0 until end of turn; or tap target creature; or prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0157</id>
    <name>Jabari's Influence</name>
    <text>Cast Jabari's Influence only after combat.
Gain control of target nonartifact, nonblack creature that attacked you this turn and put a -1/-0 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Common soldiers can't understand what a sidar knows: the enemy can be a resource."
—Sidar Jabari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0158</id>
    <name>Jolrael's Centaur</name>
    <text>Shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)
Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>"What need have I for cavalry when I can have horse and rider both in one?"
—Jolrael</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0159</id>
    <name>Jolt</name>
    <text>You may tap or untap target artifact, creature, or land.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"There's nothing like a sudden shock to clarify one's thoughts."
—Pashad ibn Asim, Suq'Ata trader</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0160</id>
    <name>Jungle Patrol</name>
    <text>{1}{G}, {T}:  Put a 0/1 green Wall creature token with defender named Wood onto the battlefield.
Sacrifice a token named Wood: Add {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0161</id>
    <name>Jungle Troll</name>
    <text>{R}: Regenerate Jungle Troll.

{G}: Regenerate Jungle Troll.</text>
    <flavorText>"You eat plants; I eat plants. You eat beasts; I eat you."
—Drulvurg, troll king</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0162</id>
    <name>Jungle Wurm</name>
    <text>Whenever Jungle Wurm becomes blocked, it gets -1/-1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.</text>
    <flavorText>Broad as a baobab—and about as smart.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0163</id>
    <name>Kaervek's Hex</name>
    <text>Kaervek's Hex deals 1 damage to each nonblack creature and an additional 1 damage to each green creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"If the curse does not strike you dead, question your soul."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0164</id>
    <name>Kaervek's Purge</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature with converted mana cost X. If that creature is put into a graveyard this way, Kaervek's Purge deals damage equal to the creature's power to the creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0165</id>
    <name>Kaervek's Torch</name>
    <text>As long as Kaervek's Torch is on the stack, spells that target it cost {2} more to cast.
Kaervek's Torch deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>The pulsing heat of the midday Sun burns in the Lion's eye.
—Stone inscription, source unkown</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0166</id>
    <name>Karoo Meerkat</name>
    <text>Protection from blue</text>
    <flavorText>"Be like the meerkat, my daughters: ever vigilant, true to your own, and wary of strangers."
—Nabil Alamat, Suq'Ata merchant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0167</id>
    <name>Kukemssa Pirates</name>
    <text>Whenever Kukemssa Pirates attacks and isn't blocked, you may gain control of target artifact defending player controls. If you do, Kukemssa Pirates assigns no combat damage this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>". . . pirates gambled with a djinn and lost the thing more dear than gold."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0168</id>
    <name>Kukemssa Serpent</name>
    <text>Kukemssa Serpent can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.

{U}, Sacrifice an Island: Target land an opponent controls becomes an Island until end of turn.

When you control no Islands, sacrifice Kukemssa Serpent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0169</id>
    <name>Lead Golem</name>
    <text>Whenever Lead Golem attacks, it doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>Slow and heavy swings the club.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0170</id>
    <name>Leering Gargoyle</name>
    <text>Flying

{T}: Leering Gargoyle gets -2/+2 and loses flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Only a gargoyle would take such delight in a thunderstorm."
—Qhattib, Vizier of Amiqat</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0171</id>
    <name>Lightning Reflexes</name>
    <text>You may cast Lightning Reflexes as though it had flash. If you cast it any time a sorcery couldn't have been cast, the controller of the permanent it becomes sacrifices it at the beginning of the next cleanup step.
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 and has first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>"Inhale. Kill. Exhale."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0172</id>
    <name>Lion's Eye Diamond</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Lion's Eye Diamond, Discard your hand: Add three mana of any one color to your mana pool. Activate this ability only any time you could cast an instant.</text>
    <flavorText>Held in the lion's eye
—Zhalfirin saying meaning "caught in the moment of crisis"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0173</id>
    <name>Locust Swarm</name>
    <text>Flying
{G}: Regenerate Locust Swarm.
{G}: Untap Locust Swarm. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Better a fierce thunderhead than a sky filled with locusts.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0174</id>
    <name>Lure of Prey</name>
    <text>Cast Lure of Prey only if an opponent cast a creature spell this turn.
You may put a green creature card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0175</id>
    <name>Malignant Growth</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, put a growth counter on Malignant Growth.
At the beginning of each opponent's draw step, that player draws an additional card for each growth counter on Malignant Growth, then Malignant Growth deals damage to the player equal to the number of cards he or she drew this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0176</id>
    <name>Mana Prism</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{1}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0177</id>
    <name>Mangara's Blessing</name>
    <text>You gain 5 life.
When a spell or ability an opponent controls causes you to discard Mangara's Blessing, you gain 2 life, and you return Mangara's Blessing from your graveyard to your hand at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0178</id>
    <name>Mangara's Equity</name>
    <text>As Mangara's Equity enters the battlefield, choose black or red.
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Mangara's Equity unless you pay {1}{W}.
Whenever a creature of the chosen color deals damage to you or a white creature you control, Mangara's Equity deals that much damage to that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0179</id>
    <name>Mangara's Tome</name>
    <text>When Mangara's Tome enters the battlefield, search your library for five cards, exile them in a face-down pile, and shuffle that pile. Then shuffle your library.
{2}: The next time you would draw a card this turn, instead put the top card of the exiled pile into its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0180</id>
    <name>Marble Diamond</name>
    <text>Marble Diamond enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0181</id>
    <name>Maro</name>
    <text>Maro's power and toughness are each equal to the number of cards in your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>No two see the same Maro.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0182</id>
    <name>Meddle</name>
    <text>If target spell has only one target and that target is a creature, change that spell's target to another creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Shadimir was as surprised as he was relieved when the blow turned aside."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0183</id>
    <name>Melesse Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from black</text>
    <flavorText>Like a laughing knife, immaculate and sharp, is the Melesse.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0184</id>
    <name>Memory Lapse</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. If that spell is countered this way, put it on top of its owner's library instead of into that player's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"The caliph was so intelligent he could not remember what he knew."
—Azeworai, "Three Riddles"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0185</id>
    <name>Merfolk Raiders</name>
    <text>Islandwalk
Phasing (This phases in or out before you untap during each of your untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Turn your back for a second and they just vanish As if they weren't shifty enough before."
—Rhirhok, goblin archer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0186</id>
    <name>Merfolk Seer</name>
    <text>When Merfolk Seer is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {1}{U}. If you do, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The sea leaves no room for tears.
—Zhalfirin adage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0187</id>
    <name>Mind Bend</name>
    <text>Change the text of target permanent by replacing all instances of one color word with another or one basic land type with another. (For example, you may change "nonblack creature" to "nongreen creature" or "forestwalk" to "islandwalk." This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0188</id>
    <name>Mind Harness</name>
    <text>Enchant red or green creature
Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
You control enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Centuries ago, Mangara won the loyalty of the Quirion not by ruling their minds but by supporting their independence.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0189</id>
    <name>Mindbender Spores</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Flying
Whenever Mindbender Spores blocks a creature, put four fungus counters on that creature. The creature gains "This creature doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a fungus counter on it" and "At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a fungus counter from this creature."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0190</id>
    <name>Mire Shade</name>
    <text>{B}, Sacrifice a Swamp: Put a +1/+1 counter on Mire Shade. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>"We realized the bog had not given up a soul but had come to claim a new one."
—Scout Ekemet, final journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0191</id>
    <name>Misers' Cage</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each opponent's upkeep, if that player has five or more cards in hand, Misers' Cage deals 2 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let him be imprisoned while his possessions wander free."
—Suq'Ata legal decree</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0192</id>
    <name>Mist Dragon</name>
    <text>{0}: Mist Dragon gains flying. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)
{0}: Mist Dragon loses flying. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)
{3}{U}{U}: Mist Dragon phases out. (While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist. It phases in before you untap during your next untap step.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Across the plains, farmers who braved the mists began to vanish. Most blamed the goblins; none guessed the truth."
—Hakim, Loreweaver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0193</id>
    <name>Moss Diamond</name>
    <text>Moss Diamond enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0194</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0195</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0196</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0197</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0198</id>
    <name>Mountain Valley</name>
    <text>Mountain Valley enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}, Sacrifice Mountain Valley: Search your library for a Mountain or Forest card and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0199</id>
    <name>Mtenda Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying
{W}, {T}: Return Mtenda Griffin to its owner's hand and return target Griffin card from your graveyard to your hand. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"Unlike Zhalfir, the griffin needs no council to keep harmony among its parts."Asmira, Holy Avenger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0200</id>
    <name>Mtenda Herder</name>
    <text>Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>"All animals—even humans—can be herded. The trick is to make them think they choose their own destination."
—Mangara</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0201</id>
    <name>Mtenda Lion</name>
    <text>Whenever Mtenda Lion attacks, defending player may pay {U}. If that player does, prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by Mtenda Lion this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The lion drank that lake right up In thanks, he gave Siti the power to speak with lions and make them leave the goats alone."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0202</id>
    <name>Mystical Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for an instant or sorcery card and reveal that card. Shuffle your library, then put the card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>"To the tutors, a ‘poem of sand' was of little account, a ‘poem of ivory,' priceless."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0203</id>
    <name>Natural Balance</name>
    <text>Each player who controls six or more lands chooses five lands he or she controls and sacrifices the rest. Each player who controls four or fewer lands may search his or her library for X basic land cards and put them onto the battlefield, where X is five minus the number of lands he or she controls. Then each player who searched his or her library this way shuffles it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0204</id>
    <name>Nettletooth Djinn</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Nettletooth Djinn deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"The few of us who survived were denied entry to our camp for two days—so like the pox were the marks we bore."
—Travelogue of Najat</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0205</id>
    <name>Noble Elephant</name>
    <text>Trample; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Proud am I, / strong am I, / courageous in defending my children / and fierce in punishing what stands in my way."
—"So the Elephant Speaks,"
Zhalfirin song</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0206</id>
    <name>Nocturnal Raid</name>
    <text>Black creatures get +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The finest offering of night is not stealth but daring."
—Tetlok, Breathstealer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0207</id>
    <name>Null Chamber</name>
    <text>As Null Chamber enters the battlefield, you and an opponent each name a card other than a basic land card.
The named cards can't be played.</text>
    <flavorText>Discovered by Femeref mages, the Null Chamber is the ultimate testing ground for the uncreative.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0208</id>
    <name>Pacifism</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block.</text>
    <flavorText>For the first time in his life, Grakk felt a little warm and fuzzy inside.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0209</id>
    <name>Painful Memories</name>
    <text>Look at target opponent's hand and choose a card from it. Put that card on top of that player's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is terrible how one brief action can live forever in memory."
—Jolrael</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0210</id>
    <name>Patagia Golem</name>
    <text>{3}: Patagia Golem gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It scattered falcons like a lion hunting among jackals.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0211</id>
    <name>Paupers' Cage</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each opponent's upkeep, if that player has two or fewer cards in hand, Paupers' Cage deals 2 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>A cage may keep you in, but it does not keep the stones out.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0212</id>
    <name>Pearl Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{W}: Pearl Dragon gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"They knew Bantau was lost when, to hide the pearl he had found on the beach, he swallowed it—and soon grew wings."
—Hakim, Loreweaver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0213</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Dreadnought</name>
    <text>Trample
When Phyrexian Dreadnought enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you sacrifice any number of creatures with total power 12 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0214</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Purge</name>
    <text>Destroy any number of target creatures.
Phyrexian Purge costs 3 life more to cast for each target.</text>
    <flavorText>Only those who have nothing have nothing to fear.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0215</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Tribute</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Phyrexian Tribute, sacrifice two creatures.
Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>"In your final breath you still have something to offer Phyrexia."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0216</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Vault</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"The secrets of Phyrexia are expensive. You will pay in brass and bone, steel and sinew."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0217</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0218</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0219</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0220</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0221</id>
    <name>Political Trickery</name>
    <text>Exchange control of target land you control and target land an opponent controls. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Politics is a game—move a stone here, move a stone there—except sometimes the stones bleed."
—Shauku, Endbringer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0222</id>
    <name>Polymorph</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature. It can't be regenerated. Its controller reveals cards from the top of his or her library until he or she reveals a creature card. The player puts that card onto the battlefield, then shuffles all other cards revealed this way into his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Ahh Opposable digits"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0223</id>
    <name>Power Sink</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}. If he or she doesn't, that player taps all lands with mana abilities he or she controls and empties his or her mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0224</id>
    <name>Preferred Selection</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, look at the top two cards of your library. You may sacrifice Preferred Selection and pay {2}{G}{G}. If you do, put one of those cards into your hand. If you don't, put one of those cards on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0225</id>
    <name>Prismatic Boon</name>
    <text>X target creatures gain protection from the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"How ironic that the greatest forge of civilization is battle."
—Mangara</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0226</id>
    <name>Prismatic Circle</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
As Prismatic Circle enters the battlefield, choose a color.
{1}: The next time a source of your choice of the chosen color would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0227</id>
    <name>Prismatic Lace</name>
    <text>Target permanent becomes the color or colors of your choice. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0228</id>
    <name>Psychic Transfer</name>
    <text>If the difference between your life total and target player's life total is 5 or less, exchange life totals with that player.</text>
    <flavorText>"The memory of your existence will fade like the final stars of morning."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0229</id>
    <name>Purgatory</name>
    <text>Whenever a nontoken creature is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, exile that card.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {4} and 2 life. If you do, return a card exiled with Purgatory to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0230</id>
    <name>Purraj of Urborg</name>
    <text>Purraj of Urborg has first strike as long as it's attacking.
Whenever a player casts a black spell, you may pay {B}. If you do, put a +1/+1 counter on Purraj of Urborg.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0231</id>
    <name>Pyric Salamander</name>
    <text>{R}: Pyric Salamander gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Sacrifice Pyric Salamander at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>When you've been chased by a dragon, you run from every lizard.
—Suq'Ata saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0232</id>
    <name>Quirion Elves</name>
    <text>As Quirion Elves enters the battlefield, choose a color.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add one mana of the chosen color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0233</id>
    <name>Radiant Essence</name>
    <text>Radiant Essence gets +1/+2 as long as an opponent controls a black permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"Her beauty was the beauty of the Sun at midday, deadly to those who underestimated her strength."
—Azeworai, "Kenechi's Dream"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0234</id>
    <name>Raging Spirit</name>
    <text>{2}: Raging Spirit becomes colorless until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Its burning power is more elusive than shade on the Unyaro Plains, more perilous than the horn of a rhino."
—Akin, seasoned askari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0235</id>
    <name>Rampant Growth</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"I've never heard growth before."
—Gowon, Femeref herder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0236</id>
    <name>Rashida Scalebane</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target attacking or blocking Dragon. It can't be regenerated. You gain life equal to its power.</text>
    <flavorText>It is not by the blood of dragons that Rashida measures victories, but by the sum of children who no longer wake from nightmares of scales and fire.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0237</id>
    <name>Ravenous Vampire</name>
    <text>Flying

At the beginning of your upkeep, you may sacrifice a nonartifact creature. If you do, put a +1/+1 counter on Ravenous Vampire. If you don't, tap Ravenous Vampire.</text>
    <flavorText>Eternal life brings eternal hunger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0238</id>
    <name>Ray of Command</name>
    <text>Untap target creature an opponent controls and gain control of it until end of turn. That creature gains haste until end of turn. When you lose control of the creature, tap it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Heel."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0239</id>
    <name>Razor Pendulum</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's end step, if that player has 5 or less life, Razor Pendulum deals 2 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>"Amazing thing, gravity. It seems to work every time."
—Telim'Tor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0240</id>
    <name>Reality Ripple</name>
    <text>Target artifact, creature, or land phases out. (While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist. It phases in before its controller untaps during his or her next untap step.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Can you prepare for the unexpected? No, you cannot. You can prepare only to be surprised."
—Teferi</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0241</id>
    <name>Reckless Embermage</name>
    <text>{1}{R}: Reckless Embermage deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to itself.</text>
    <flavorText>Many mages have been consumed by their work.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0242</id>
    <name>Reflect Damage</name>
    <text>The next time a source of your choice would deal damage this turn, that damage is dealt to that source's controller instead.</text>
    <flavorText>From you to me, so me to you.
—Femeref children's taunt</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0243</id>
    <name>Regeneration</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
{G}: Regenerate enchanted creature. (The next time that creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Death is not a debt I am yet willing to pay."
—Purraj of Urborg</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0244</id>
    <name>Reign of Chaos</name>
    <text>Choose one — Destroy target Plains and target white creature; or destroy target Island and target blue creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Burning Isles are the home to a dozen lords who claim dominion. Jamuraa will look to only one leader: me."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0245</id>
    <name>Reign of Terror</name>
    <text>Destroy all green creatures or all white creatures. They can't be regenerated. You lose 2 life for each creature put into a graveyard this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"I don't know what takes them; they die around me without time to scream."
—Scout Ekemet, final journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0246</id>
    <name>Reparations</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a spell that targets you or a creature you control, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Sorry I burned down your village. Here's some gold."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0247</id>
    <name>Restless Dead</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Restless Dead.</text>
    <flavorText>The rich's heirs often thank them after death . . . but preferably not in person.
—Suq'Ata epigram</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0248</id>
    <name>Ritual of Steel</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Ritual of Steel enters the battlefield, draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.
Enchanted creature gets +0/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our soldiers are blessed with lizard scales as hard and cold as steel."
—Sidar Jabari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0249</id>
    <name>Rock Basilisk</name>
    <text>Whenever Rock Basilisk blocks or becomes blocked by a non-Wall creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>In the eastern reaches of Jamuraa are arrangements of massive stones. No one knows their origins—for certain.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0250</id>
    <name>Rocky Tar Pit</name>
    <text>Rocky Tar Pit enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}, Sacrifice Rocky Tar Pit: Search your library for a Swamp or Mountain card and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0251</id>
    <name>Roots of Life</name>
    <text>As Roots of Life enters the battlefield, choose Islands or Swamps.
Whenever a land of the chosen type an opponent controls becomes tapped, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0252</id>
    <name>Sabertooth Cobra</name>
    <text>Whenever Sabertooth Cobra deals damage to a player, he or she gets a poison counter. That player gets another poison counter at the beginning of his or her next upkeep unless he or she pays {2} before that turn. (A player with ten or more poison counters loses the game.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0253</id>
    <name>Sacred Mesa</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Sacred Mesa unless you sacrifice a Pegasus.
{1}{W}: Put a 1/1 white Pegasus creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Do not go there, do not go / unless you rise on wings, unless you walk on hooves."
—"Song to the Sun," Femeref song</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0254</id>
    <name>Sand Golem</name>
    <text>When a spell or ability an opponent controls causes you to discard Sand Golem, return Sand Golem from your graveyard to the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0255</id>
    <name>Sandbar Crocodile</name>
    <text>Phasing (This phases in or out before you untap during each of your untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We've run aground sandbars before, but today, a sandbar ran aground us."
—Kipkemboi, Kukemssa pirate</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0256</id>
    <name>Sandstorm</name>
    <text>Sandstorm deals 1 damage to each attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Better to fight the sand for a few hours than to sleep beneath it forever.
—Suq'Ata truism</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0257</id>
    <name>Sapphire Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target player draws a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep; or target creature gains flying until end of turn; or target creature an opponent controls phases out. (While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist. It phases in before its controller untaps during his or her next untap step.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0258</id>
    <name>Savage Twister</name>
    <text>Savage Twister deals X damage to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Frozen, we watched the funnel pluck up three of the goats—pook pook pook—before we ran for the wadi."
—Travelogue of Najat</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0259</id>
    <name>Sawback Manticore</name>
    <text>{4}: Sawback Manticore gains flying until end of turn.
{1}: Sawback Manticore deals 2 damage to target attacking or blocking creature. Activate this ability only if Sawback Manticore is attacking or blocking and only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0260</id>
    <name>Sea Scryer</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}, {T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0261</id>
    <name>Sealed Fate</name>
    <text>Look at the top X cards of target opponent's library. Exile one of those cards and put the rest back on top of that player's library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>It's good to know more about your enemy's fate than your enemy does.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0262</id>
    <name>Searing Spear Askari</name>
    <text>Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)
{1}{R}: Searing Spear Askari can't be blocked except by two or more creatures this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>When the other soldiers of Zhalfir fall, the askaris will yet stand.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0263</id>
    <name>Seedling Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Return target Aura attached to a creature to its owner's hand; or regenerate target green creature; or target creature gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0264</id>
    <name>Seeds of Innocence</name>
    <text>Destroy all artifacts. They can't be regenerated. The controller of each artifact destroyed this way gains life equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have hidden from the machinations of Zhalfir for centuries. Why should I join your campaign?"
—Jolrael</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0265</id>
    <name>Serene Heart</name>
    <text>Destroy all Auras.</text>
    <flavorText>"If magic is your crutch, cast it aside and learn to walk without it."
—Teferi</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0266</id>
    <name>Sewer Rats</name>
    <text>{B}, Pay 1 life: Sewer Rats gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Activate this ability no more than three times each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>You lie down with rats, and the rats run away.
—Suq'Ata insult</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0267</id>
    <name>Shadow Guildmage</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}: Put target creature you control on top of its owner's library.
{R}, {T}: Shadow Guildmage deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>To keep the dead so others may live.
—Shadow Guild maxim</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0268</id>
    <name>Shadowbane</name>
    <text>The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you and/or creatures you control this turn, prevent that damage. If damage from a black source is prevented this way, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>Light creates shadow; light destroys shadow. Such is the transience of darkness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0269</id>
    <name>Shallow Grave</name>
    <text>Return the top creature card of your graveyard to the battlefield. That creature gains haste until end of turn. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>Good help is hard to dig up.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0270</id>
    <name>Shaper Guildmage</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.
{B}, {T}: Target creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Shape this world in Zhalfir's image.
—Shaper Guild maxim</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0271</id>
    <name>Shauku, Endbringer</name>
    <text>Flying
Shauku, Endbringer can't attack if there's another creature on the battlefield.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you lose 3 life.
{T}: Exile target creature and put a +1/+1 counter on Shauku.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0272</id>
    <name>Shauku's Minion</name>
    <text>{B}{R}, {T}: Shauku's Minion deals 2 damage to target white creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"My minions serve me in the light; I serve no one."
—Shauku, Endbringer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0273</id>
    <name>Shimmer</name>
    <text>As Shimmer enters the battlefield, choose a land type.
Each land of the chosen type has phasing. (It phases in or out before its controller untaps during each of his or her untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)</text>
    <flavorText>To buy unseen land, pay in unseen coin.
—Suq'Ata maxim</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0274</id>
    <name>Sidar Jabari</name>
    <text>Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)
Whenever Sidar Jabari attacks, tap target creature defending player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"Prophecy is whatever one makes of it, but destiny cannot be changed."
—Sidar Jabari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0275</id>
    <name>Sirocco</name>
    <text>Target player reveals his or her hand. For each blue instant card revealed this way, that player discards that card unless he or she pays 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Blow, fiery wind, / strip illusion from the eye. / Blow, fiery wind of truth."
—Femeref chant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0276</id>
    <name>Skulking Ghost</name>
    <text>Flying
When Skulking Ghost becomes the target of a spell or ability, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>"They exist only so long as the living take no notice."
—Kifimbo, Shadow Guildmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0277</id>
    <name>Sky Diamond</name>
    <text>Sky Diamond enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0278</id>
    <name>Soar</name>
    <text>You may cast Soar as though it had flash. If you cast it any time a sorcery couldn't have been cast, the controller of the permanent it becomes sacrifices it at the beginning of the next cleanup step.
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +0/+1 and has flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Would you give up your hands to fly? That is what the birds have done."
—The One Thousand Questions</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0279</id>
    <name>Soul Echo</name>
    <text>Soul Echo enters the battlefield with X echo counters on it.
You don't lose the game for having 0 or less life.
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Soul Echo if there are no echo counters on it. Otherwise, target opponent may choose that for each 1 damage that would be dealt to you until your next upkeep, you remove an echo counter from Soul Echo instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0280</id>
    <name>Soul Rend</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature if it's white. A creature destroyed this way can't be regenerated.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"Since I cannot stop death, I choose to stop life."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0281</id>
    <name>Soulshriek</name>
    <text>Target creature you control gets +X/+0 until end of turn, where X is the number of creature cards in your graveyard. Sacrifice that creature at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>"The flesh is a casket for the soul."
—Shauku, Endbringer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0282</id>
    <name>Spatial Binding</name>
    <text>Pay 1 life: Until your next upkeep, target permanent can't phase out.</text>
    <flavorText>Time is the one shackle you can't break.
—Zhalfirin aphorism</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0283</id>
    <name>Spectral Guardian</name>
    <text>Noncreature artifacts have shroud as long as Spectral Guardian is untapped. (They can't be the targets of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>"A treasure to guard other treasures is worth the highest price."
—Mtai, Civic Guildmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0284</id>
    <name>Spirit of the Night</name>
    <text>Flying, trample, haste, protection from black
Spirit of the Night has first strike as long as it's attacking.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0285</id>
    <name>Spitting Earth</name>
    <text>Spitting Earth deals damage equal to the number of Mountains you control to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"There are times solid ground gives precious little comfort."
—Talibah, embermage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0286</id>
    <name>Stalking Tiger</name>
    <text>Stalking Tiger can't be blocked by more than one creature.</text>
    <flavorText>In the Jamuraan jungles, there is often no separating beauty from danger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0287</id>
    <name>Stone Rain</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>"What rainbow could possibly come of this rain?"
—Asmira, Holy Avenger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0288</id>
    <name>Stupor</name>
    <text>Target opponent discards a card at random, then discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>There are medicines for all afflictions but idleness.
—Suq'Ata saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0289</id>
    <name>Subterranean Spirit</name>
    <text>Protection from red
{T}: Subterranean Spirit deals 1 damage to each creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Air hot with sulfur. / Earth heaves beneath me. / Could it be the mountain / ate something bad?"
—Dwarven mining song</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0290</id>
    <name>Sunweb</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Flying
Sunweb can't block creatures with power 2 or less.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is no sweeter music than the wails of a dying dragon."
—Rashida Scalebane</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0291</id>
    <name>Superior Numbers</name>
    <text>Superior Numbers deals damage to target creature equal to the number of creatures you control in excess of the number of creatures target opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0292</id>
    <name>Suq'Ata Firewalker</name>
    <text>Suq'Ata Firewalker can't be the target of red spells or abilities from red sources.
{T}: Suq'Ata Firewalker deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Comfortable even in a furnace? I've never met one who'd accept my wager."
—Talibah, embermage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0293</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0294</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0295</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0296</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0297</id>
    <name>Tainted Specter</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{B}{B}, {T}: Target player discards a card unless he or she puts a card from his or her hand on top of his or her library. If that player discards a card this way, Tainted Specter deals 1 damage to each creature and each player. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0298</id>
    <name>Talruum Minotaur</name>
    <text>Haste</text>
    <flavorText>Don't insult a Talruum unless your mount is swift.
—Suq'Ata saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0299</id>
    <name>Taniwha</name>
    <text>Trample
Phasing (This phases in or out before you untap during each of your untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, all lands you control phase out. (They phase in before you untap during your next untap step.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Taniwha rolls in its sleep, and the land is awash with the waves."
—Poetics of Hanan</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0300</id>
    <name>Teeka's Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying; trample; rampage 4 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +4/+4 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0301</id>
    <name>Teferi's Curse</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact or creature
Enchanted permanent has phasing. (It phases in or out before its controller untaps during each of his or her untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Stepping through time is like riding a camel. It may get you where you want to go, but the ride is rarely pleasant."
—Teferi</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0302</id>
    <name>Teferi's Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
Phasing (This phases in or out before you untap during each of your untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We threw dried fruit to the drakes that rode the air, streaming along the Weatherlight's side as we sailed amidst the clouds."
—Sisay, Captain of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0303</id>
    <name>Teferi's Imp</name>
    <text>Flying
Phasing (This phases in or out before you untap during each of your untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)
Whenever Teferi's Imp phases out, discard a card.
Whenever Teferi's Imp phases in, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Made you look.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0304</id>
    <name>Teferi's Isle</name>
    <text>Phasing (This phases in or out before you untap during each of your untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)
Teferi's Isle enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U}{U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The three wizards knew only that this isle held a great mystery—and that patience alone would solve it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0305</id>
    <name>Telim'Tor</name>
    <text>Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)
Whenever Telim'Tor attacks, all attacking creatures with flanking get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The curious merely amass knowledge. The ambitious use it."
—Telim'Tor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0306</id>
    <name>Telim'Tor's Darts</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Telim'Tor's Darts deals 1 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>"People laughed at my darts—once."
—Telim'Tor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0307</id>
    <name>Telim'Tor's Edict</name>
    <text>Exile target permanent you own or control.
Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"Execution awaits the dissenter."
—Kasib ibn Naji, Letters</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0308</id>
    <name>Teremko Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"When we're aloft, I love to lean over the Weatherlight's railing and watch the patterns the griffins' shadows make on the clouds below."
—Sisay, Captain of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0309</id>
    <name>Thirst</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Thirst enters the battlefield, tap enchanted creature.
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Thirst unless you pay {U}.</text>
    <flavorText>The first of the Thousand Deaths.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0310</id>
    <name>Tidal Wave</name>
    <text>Put a 5/5 blue Wall creature token with defender onto the battlefield. Sacrifice it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>When mountains ride the sea, waves live upon the fields.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0311</id>
    <name>Tombstone Stairwell</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1}{B} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
At the beginning of each upkeep, if Tombstone Stairwell is on the battlefield, each player puts a 2/2 black Zombie creature token with haste named Tombspawn onto the battlefield for each creature card in his or her graveyard.
At the beginning of each end step or when Tombstone Stairwell leaves the battlefield, destroy all tokens put onto the battlefield with Tombstone Stairwell. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0312</id>
    <name>Torrent of Lava</name>
    <text>Torrent of Lava deals X damage to each creature without flying.
As long as Torrent of Lava is on the stack, each creature has "{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to this creature by Torrent of Lava this turn."</text>
    <flavorText>The mountain's voice shouts us all down.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0313</id>
    <name>Tranquil Domain</name>
    <text>Destroy all non-Aura enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>"An ancient court mage unified the houses into guilds to serve Zhalfir above their own interests. Even during the civil war, the guilds stood together, a testament to the wisdom of Teferi."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0314</id>
    <name>Tropical Storm</name>
    <text>Tropical Storm deals X damage to each creature with flying and 1 additional damage to each blue creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"After the storm, I found a sea turtle dying on the sands, a blade of grass driven through its shell."
—Travelogue of Najat</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0315</id>
    <name>Uktabi Faerie</name>
    <text>Flying
{3}{G}, Sacrifice Uktabi Faerie: Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>Victim of the two-toed faerie
—Suq'Ata expression meaning "broken"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0316</id>
    <name>Uktabi Wildcats</name>
    <text>Uktabi Wildcats's power and toughness are each equal to the number of Forests you control.
{G}, Sacrifice a Forest: Regenerate Uktabi Wildcats.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0317</id>
    <name>Unerring Sling</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}, Tap an untapped creature you control: Unerring Sling deals damage equal to the tapped creature's power to target attacking or blocking creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0318</id>
    <name>Unfulfilled Desires</name>
    <text>{1}, Pay 1 life: Draw a card, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Like Day from Night, / I'll live my life apart from you, just glimpsing you across the sky, / because you cannot change, my dear, and nor can I."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0319</id>
    <name>Unseen Walker</name>
    <text>Forestwalk

{1}{G}{G}: Target creature gains forestwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"To pass through the jungle: silence, courtesy, ferocity, as the occasion demands."
—Kamau, "Proper Passage"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0320</id>
    <name>Unyaro Bee Sting</name>
    <text>Unyaro Bee Sting deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Much can be learned from the bees about dying for a cause."
—Asmira, Holy Avenger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0321</id>
    <name>Unyaro Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying

Sacrifice Unyaro Griffin: Counter target red instant or sorcery spell.</text>
    <flavorText>The griffin's shadow gives courage to the righteous and dread to the idle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0322</id>
    <name>Urborg Panther</name>
    <text>{B}, Sacrifice Urborg Panther: Destroy target creature blocking Urborg Panther.
Sacrifice a creature named Feral Shadow, a creature named Breathstealer, and Urborg Panther: Search your library for a card named Spirit of the Night and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0323</id>
    <name>Vaporous Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, Vaporous Djinn phases out unless you pay {U}{U}. (While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist. It phases in before you untap during your next untap step.)</text>
    <flavorText>"What is taking them so long to fill the waterskins?"
—Mwani, Mtenda goatherd</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0324</id>
    <name>Ventifact Bottle</name>
    <text>{X}{1}, {T}: Put X charge counters on Ventifact Bottle. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.
At the beginning of your precombat main phase, if Ventifact Bottle has a charge counter on it, tap it and remove all charge counters from it. Add {1} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0325</id>
    <name>Viashino Warrior</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"When traveling the Great Desert avoid wearing the scales of lizards, for the Viashino rule the sands and look poorly on the skinning of their cousins."
—Zhalfirin Guide to the Desert</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0326</id>
    <name>Vigilant Martyr</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Vigilant Martyr: Regenerate target creature.
{W}{W}, {T}, Sacrifice Vigilant Martyr: Counter target spell that targets an enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0327</id>
    <name>Village Elder</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}, Sacrifice a Forest: Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Enchant me with your tale-telling. Tell about Tree, Grass, River, and Wind. / Tell why Truth must fight with Falsehood, and why Truth will always win."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0328</id>
    <name>Vitalizing Cascade</name>
    <text>You gain X plus 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Water is like breathing—necessary for life."
—Asmira, Holy Avenger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0329</id>
    <name>Volcanic Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying, haste</text>
    <flavorText>Speed and fire are always a deadly combination.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0330</id>
    <name>Volcanic Geyser</name>
    <text>Volcanic Geyser deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>My thunder comes before the lightning; my lightning comes before the clouds; my rain dries all the land it touches. What am I?
—Femeref riddle</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0331</id>
    <name>Waiting in the Weeds</name>
    <text>Each player puts a 1/1 green Cat creature token onto the battlefield for each untapped Forest he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>The trees have ears, eyes, and teeth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0332</id>
    <name>Wall of Corpses</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{B}, Sacrifice Wall of Corpses: Destroy target creature Wall of Corpses is blocking.</text>
    <flavorText>"I shall make walls of their flesh, and their blood will by my mortar."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0333</id>
    <name>Wall of Resistance</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Flying
At the beginning of each end step, if Wall of Resistance was dealt damage this turn, put a +0/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>Telim'Tor could no longer recall the exact number of assaults—but his troops could.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0334</id>
    <name>Wall of Roots</name>
    <text>Defender
Put a -0/-1 counter on Wall of Roots: Add {G} to your mana pool. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes the wise ones wove their magic into living plants; as the plant grew, so grew the magic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0335</id>
    <name>Ward of Lights</name>
    <text>You may cast Ward of Lights as though it had flash. If you cast it any time a sorcery couldn't have been cast, the controller of the permanent it becomes sacrifices it at the beginning of the next cleanup step.
Enchant creature
As Ward of Lights enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Enchanted creature has protection from the chosen color. This effect doesn't remove Ward of Lights.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0336</id>
    <name>Warping Wurm</name>
    <text>Phasing (This phases in or out before you untap during each of your untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {2}{G}{U}. If you don't, Warping Wurm phases out.
When Warping Wurm phases in, put a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>Even wurms start out small.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0337</id>
    <name>Wave Elemental</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}, Sacrifice Wave Elemental: Tap up to three target creatures without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Consider the wave: how weak the mother yet how strong the child."
—Tywanna, Shaper Guildmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0338</id>
    <name>Wellspring</name>
    <text>Enchant land
When Wellspring enters the battlefield, gain control of enchanted land until end of turn.
At the beginning of your upkeep, untap enchanted land. You gain control of that land until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0339</id>
    <name>Wild Elephant</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>"I will tell my father's stories . . . . How the elephants trampled the leopard cub, and its father, though he knew, killed nine goats instead."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0340</id>
    <name>Wildfire Emissary</name>
    <text>Protection from white
{1}{R}: Wildfire Emissary gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The efreet is a striding storm with a voice that crackles like fire."
—Qhattib, Vizier of Amiqat</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0341</id>
    <name>Windreaper Falcon</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from blue</text>
    <flavorText>Watching the windreaper
—Zhalfirin phrase meaning
"daydreaming"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0342</id>
    <name>Withering Boon</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Withering Boon, pay 3 life.
Counter target creature spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"Life for life: this is the immutable law."
—Panya, Granger Guildmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0343</id>
    <name>Worldly Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for a creature card and reveal that card. Shuffle your library, then put the revealed card back on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Aselbo soon had the rhino eating from his palm and the snake waiting at his heels."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0344</id>
    <name>Yare</name>
    <text>Target creature defending player controls gets +3/+0 until end of turn. That creature can block up to two additional creatures this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0345</id>
    <name>Zebra Unicorn</name>
    <text>Whenever Zebra Unicorn deals damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'll capture gentle zebras / for your steeds and fill the stable with every kind of unicorn."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0346</id>
    <name>Zhalfirin Commander</name>
    <text>Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)
{1}{W}{W}: Target Knight creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Command is the act of balancing on a vine and convincing others that it is firm ground."
—Sidar Jabari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0347</id>
    <name>Zhalfirin Knight</name>
    <text>Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)
{W}{W}: Zhalfirin Knight gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"You returned a warrior. . . . Your hair was cut, your eye tattooed with the red triangle of war."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0348</id>
    <name>Zirilan of the Claw</name>
    <text>{1}{R}{R}, {T}: Search your library for a Dragon permanent card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library. That Dragon gains haste until end of turn. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0349</id>
    <name>Zombie Mob</name>
    <text>Zombie Mob enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it for each creature card in your graveyard.
When Zombie Mob enters the battlefield, exile all creature cards from your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MIR0350</id>
    <name>Zuberi, Golden Feather</name>
    <text>Flying
Other Griffin creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>"If the griffins tell of their gods, perhaps they speak of feathers bright as the Sun."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>