<cards name="New Phyrexia">
  <item>
    <id>NPH0001</id>
    <name>Karn Liberated</name>
    <text>+4: Target player exiles a card from his or her hand.
-3: Exile target permanent.
-14: Restart the game, leaving in exile all non-Aura permanent cards exiled with Karn Liberated. Then put those cards onto the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0002</id>
    <name>Apostle's Blessing</name>
    <text>({WP} can be paid with either {W} or 2 life.)
Target artifact or creature you control gains protection from artifacts or from the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0003</id>
    <name>Auriok Survivors</name>
    <text>When Auriok Survivors enters the battlefield, you may return target Equipment card from your graveyard to the battlefield. If you do, you may attach it to Auriok Survivors.</text>
    <flavorText>"We are Mirrodin's children. We will reclaim her—one scrap at a time, if we have to."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0004</id>
    <name>Blade Splicer</name>
    <text>When Blade Splicer enters the battlefield, put a 3/3 colorless Golem artifact creature token onto the battlefield.
Golem creatures you control have first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0005</id>
    <name>Cathedral Membrane</name>
    <text>({WP} can be paid with either {W} or 2 life.)
Defender
When Cathedral Membrane dies during combat, it deals 6 damage to each creature it blocked this combat.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0006</id>
    <name>Chancellor of the Annex</name>
    <text>You may reveal this card from your opening hand. If you do, when each opponent casts his or her first spell of the game, counter that spell unless that player pays {1}.
Flying
Whenever an opponent casts a spell, counter it unless that player pays {1}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0007</id>
    <name>Dispatch</name>
    <text>Tap target creature.
Metalcraft — If you control three or more artifacts, exile that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Venser wondered if it could still be called a teleportation spell if the destination is oblivion.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0008</id>
    <name>Due Respect</name>
    <text>Permanents enter the battlefield tapped this turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"A display of humility is required of those who still possess such frailties."
—Elesh Norn, Grand Cenobite</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0009</id>
    <name>Elesh Norn, Grand Cenobite</name>
    <text>Vigilance
Other creatures you control get +2/+2.
Creatures your opponents control get -2/-2.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Gitaxians whisper among themselves of other worlds. If they exist, we must bring Phyrexia's magnificence to them."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0010</id>
    <name>Exclusion Ritual</name>
    <text>Imprint — When Exclusion Ritual enters the battlefield, exile target nonland permanent.
Players can't cast spells with the same name as the exiled card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your desires have become our discretion."
—Izathel, priest of the Annex</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0011</id>
    <name>Forced Worship</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack.
{2}{W}: Return Forced Worship to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Imprisonment teaches revenge. Hobbling teaches resignation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0012</id>
    <name>Inquisitor Exarch</name>
    <text>When Inquisitor Exarch enters the battlefield, choose one — You gain 2 life; or target opponent loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Skin is the prison of the blessed and the stronghold of the heretic."
—Argent Etchings, plate 64, passage 17</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0013</id>
    <name>Lost Leonin</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>Mirrans were broken down and rebuilt, made to be loyal servants of the force they had fought.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0014</id>
    <name>Loxodon Convert</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Just one drop of the glistening oil can eventually stain even a soul as stalwart as a loxodon's beyond redemption.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0015</id>
    <name>Marrow Shards</name>
    <text>({WP} can be paid with either {W} or 2 life.)
Marrow Shards deals 1 damage to each attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"We are a single entity. Dissenters must be sutured into the Orthodoxy."
—Elesh Norn, Grand Cenobite</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0016</id>
    <name>Master Splicer</name>
    <text>When Master Splicer enters the battlefield, put a 3/3 colorless Golem artifact creature token onto the battlefield.
Golem creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>With Phyrexia's victory at hand, each sect began perfecting its vision.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0017</id>
    <name>Norn's Annex</name>
    <text>({WP} can be paid with either {W} or 2 life.)
Creatures can't attack you or a planeswalker you control unless their controller pays {WP} for each of those creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0018</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Unlife</name>
    <text>You don't lose the game for having 0 or less life.
As long as you have 0 or less life, all damage is dealt to you as though its source had infect. (Damage is dealt to you in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0019</id>
    <name>Porcelain Legionnaire</name>
    <text>({WP} can be paid with either {W} or 2 life.)
First strike</text>
    <flavorText>"My new design has lightweight plating specially cultivated from heretics' spare tissues."
—Izathel, priest of the Annex</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0020</id>
    <name>Puresteel Paladin</name>
    <text>Whenever an Equipment enters the battlefield under your control, you may draw a card.
Metalcraft — Equipment you control have equip {0} as long as you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0021</id>
    <name>Remember the Fallen</name>
    <text>Choose one or both — Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand; and/or return target artifact card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>When the Mirrans had fallen, Planeswalkers carried the burden of remembrance.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0022</id>
    <name>Sensor Splicer</name>
    <text>When Sensor Splicer enters the battlefield, put a 3/3 colorless Golem artifact creature token onto the battlefield.
Golem creatures you control have vigilance.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0023</id>
    <name>Shattered Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever a land enters the battlefield under an opponent's control, you may gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>She preaches the blessings of the Machine Orthodoxy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0024</id>
    <name>Shriek Raptor</name>
    <text>Flying
Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>"That's no glint hawk. The skies have changed for the worse."
—Ria Ivor, White Sun partisan</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0025</id>
    <name>Suture Priest</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature enters the battlefield under your control, you may gain 1 life.
Whenever a creature enters the battlefield under an opponent's control, you may have that player lose 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0026</id>
    <name>War Report</name>
    <text>You gain life equal to the number of creatures on the battlefield plus the number of artifacts on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Underling Ethu's 263rd report read simply "Yes, my lord. Overwhelmingly, my lord." This marked the end of the Mirran-Phyrexian War.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0027</id>
    <name>Argent Mutation</name>
    <text>Target permanent becomes an artifact in addition to its other types until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"My world is corrupted beyond cleansing. I must prevent this from happening to other worlds."
—Karn</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0028</id>
    <name>Arm with Æther</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, creatures you control gain "Whenever this creature deals damage to an opponent, you may return target creature that player controls to its owner's hand."</text>
    <flavorText>"Anything we can do to hurt the Phyrexian invaders is worth dying for."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0029</id>
    <name>Blighted Agent</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
Blighted Agent is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>"Urabrask may suspect our surveillance, but he cannot stop it."
—Avaricta, Gitaxian sective</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0030</id>
    <name>Chained Throatseeker</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
Chained Throatseeker can't attack unless defending player is poisoned.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0031</id>
    <name>Chancellor of the Spires</name>
    <text>You may reveal this card from your opening hand. If you do, at the beginning of the first upkeep, each opponent puts the top seven cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.
Flying
When Chancellor of the Spires enters the battlefield, you may cast target instant or sorcery card from an opponent's graveyard without paying its mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0032</id>
    <name>Corrupted Resolve</name>
    <text>Counter target spell if its controller is poisoned.</text>
    <flavorText>"Flesh is a sickness that infects Phyrexia."
—Avaricta, Gitaxian sective</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0033</id>
    <name>Deceiver Exarch</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
When Deceiver Exarch enters the battlefield, choose one — Untap target permanent you control; or tap target permanent an opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0034</id>
    <name>Defensive Stance</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets -1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>"It isn't for fighting. It's for when the fighting's gone bad."
—Kara Vrist, Mirran resistance</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0035</id>
    <name>Gitaxian Probe</name>
    <text>({UP} can be paid with either {U} or 2 life.)
Look at target player's hand.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"My flesh holds no secrets, monster. The spirit of Mirrodin will fight on."
—Vy Covalt, Mirran resistance</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0036</id>
    <name>Impaler Shrike</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Impaler Shrike deals combat damage to a player, you may sacrifice it. If you do, draw three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Interrogation is an unnecessary step for acquiring information."
—Politus, Gitaxian morphologist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0037</id>
    <name>Jin-Gitaxias, Core Augur</name>
    <text>Flash
At the beginning of your end step, draw seven cards.
Each opponent's maximum hand size is reduced by seven.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is not a goal, but a process—the process of creating the perfect Phyrexia."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0038</id>
    <name>Mental Misstep</name>
    <text>({UP} can be paid with either {U} or 2 life.)
Counter target spell with converted mana cost 1.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your first mistake was thinking I would let you live long enough to make a second."
—Sarnvax, Gitaxian sective</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0039</id>
    <name>Mindculling</name>
    <text>You draw two cards and target opponent discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why infiltrate their strongholds when what we seek resides in such a poorly guarded safe?"
—Malcator, Executor of Synthesis</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0040</id>
    <name>Numbing Dose</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact or creature
Enchanted permanent doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted permanent's controller, that player loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0041</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Ingester</name>
    <text>Imprint — When Phyrexian Ingester enters the battlefield, you may exile target nontoken creature.
Phyrexian Ingester gets +X/+Y, where X is the exiled creature card's power and Y is its toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0042</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Metamorph</name>
    <text>({UP} can be paid with either {U} or 2 life.)
You may have Phyrexian Metamorph enter the battlefield as a copy of any artifact or creature on the battlefield, except it's an artifact in addition to its other types.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0043</id>
    <name>Psychic Barrier</name>
    <text>Counter target creature spell. Its controller loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"I tolerate Phyrexians because the dragon requires it. But I have no patience for uninvited guests."
—Tezzeret</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0044</id>
    <name>Psychic Surgery</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent shuffles his or her library, you may look at the top two cards of that library. You may exile one of those cards. Then put the rest on top of that library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0045</id>
    <name>Spined Thopter</name>
    <text>({UP} can be paid with either {U} or 2 life.)
Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"I appreciate the depravity of noble designs turned to devious ends."
—Tezzeret</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0046</id>
    <name>Spire Monitor</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Each monitor is given an eye for each spire it is to guard.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0047</id>
    <name>Tezzeret's Gambit</name>
    <text>({UP} can be paid with either {U} or 2 life.)
Draw two cards, then proliferate. (You choose any number of permanents and/or players with counters on them, then give each another counter of a kind already there.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0048</id>
    <name>Vapor Snag</name>
    <text>Return target creature to its owner's hand. Its controller loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"This creature is inadequate. Send it to the splicers for innovation."
—Malcator, Executor of Synthesis</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0049</id>
    <name>Viral Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
{3}{U}: Proliferate. (You choose any number of permanents and/or players with counters on them, then give each another counter of a kind already there.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0050</id>
    <name>Wing Splicer</name>
    <text>When Wing Splicer enters the battlefield, put a 3/3 colorless Golem artifact creature token onto the battlefield.
Golem creatures you control have flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0051</id>
    <name>Xenograft</name>
    <text>As Xenograft enters the battlefield, choose a creature type.
Each creature you control is the chosen type in addition to its other types.</text>
    <flavorText>"I despise Vorinclex and his slobberings about ‘evolution.' Only I know true progress."
—Jin-Gitaxias, Core Augur</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0052</id>
    <name>Blind Zealot</name>
    <text>Intimidate (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or creatures that share a color with it.)
Whenever Blind Zealot deals combat damage to a player, you may sacrifice it. If you do, destroy target creature that player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0053</id>
    <name>Caress of Phyrexia</name>
    <text>Target player draws three cards, loses 3 life, and gets three poison counters.</text>
    <flavorText>"I am weak. Make . . . me . . . ideal."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0054</id>
    <name>Chancellor of the Dross</name>
    <text>You may reveal this card from your opening hand. If you do, at the beginning of the first upkeep, each opponent loses 3 life, then you gain life equal to the life lost this way.
Flying, lifelink</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0055</id>
    <name>Dementia Bat</name>
    <text>Flying
{4}{B}, Sacrifice Dementia Bat: Target player discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"When terror outweighs all other thoughts, they will understand that I am the true Father of Machines."
—Azax-Azog, the Demon Thane</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0056</id>
    <name>Despise</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You choose a creature or planeswalker card from it. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Truth is always a weapon in your enemies' hands."
—Geth, Lord of the Vault</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0057</id>
    <name>Dismember</name>
    <text>({BP} can be paid with either {B} or 2 life.)
Target creature gets -5/-5 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"You serve Phyrexia. Your pieces would better serve Phyrexia elsewhere."
—Azax-Azog, the Demon Thane</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0058</id>
    <name>Enslave</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
You control enchanted creature.
At the beginning of your upkeep, enchanted creature deals 1 damage to its owner.</text>
    <flavorText>Phyrexia extended its command until there was nothing left to take.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0059</id>
    <name>Entomber Exarch</name>
    <text>When Entomber Exarch enters the battlefield, choose one — Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand; or target opponent reveals his or her hand, you choose a noncreature card from it, then that player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0060</id>
    <name>Evil Presence</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Enchanted land is a Swamp.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Accorders would lament the transformation of their cherished lands, had they lived to see it."
—Sheoldred, Whispering One</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0061</id>
    <name>Geth's Verdict</name>
    <text>Target player sacrifices a creature and loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Everyone should owe you something."
—Geth, Lord of the Vault</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0062</id>
    <name>Glistening Oil</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has infect.
At the beginning of your upkeep, put a -1/-1 counter on enchanted creature.
When Glistening Oil is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Glistening Oil to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0063</id>
    <name>Grim Affliction</name>
    <text>Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature, then proliferate. (You choose any number of permanents and/or players with counters on them, then give each another counter of a kind already there.)</text>
    <flavorText>Even the small wounds let hope bleed out.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0064</id>
    <name>Ichor Explosion</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Ichor Explosion, sacrifice a creature.
All creatures get -X/-X until end of turn, where X is the sacrificed creature's power.</text>
    <flavorText>The first explosion that didn't excite goblins.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0065</id>
    <name>Life's Finale</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures, then search target opponent's library for up to three creature cards and put them into his or her graveyard. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>The feeble resistance of the flesh is over. Phyrexia spreads its shadow over all.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0066</id>
    <name>Mortis Dogs</name>
    <text>Whenever Mortis Dogs attacks, it gets +2/+0 until end of turn.
When Mortis Dogs dies, target player loses life equal to its power.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0067</id>
    <name>Parasitic Implant</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of your upkeep, enchanted creature's controller sacrifices it and you put a 1/1 colorless Myr artifact creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0068</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Obliterator</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever a source deals damage to Phyrexian Obliterator, that source's controller sacrifices that many permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>"Behold blessed perfection."
—Sheoldred, Whispering One</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0069</id>
    <name>Pith Driller</name>
    <text>({BP} can be paid with either {B} or 2 life.)
When Pith Driller enters the battlefield, put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>After boring up through the crust of Mirrodin, it turned its expertise upon the surface dwellers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0070</id>
    <name>Postmortem Lunge</name>
    <text>({BP} can be paid with either {B} or 2 life.)
Return target creature card with converted mana cost X from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0071</id>
    <name>Praetor's Grasp</name>
    <text>Search target opponent's library for a card and exile it face down. Then that player shuffles his or her library. You may look at and play that card for as long as it remains exiled.</text>
    <flavorText>Sheoldred weaves every thread of information into a noose to hang her enemies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0072</id>
    <name>Reaper of Sheoldred</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
Whenever a source deals damage to Reaper of Sheoldred, that source's controller gets a poison counter.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0073</id>
    <name>Sheoldred, Whispering One</name>
    <text>Swampwalk
At the beginning of your upkeep, return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.
At the beginning of each opponent's upkeep, that player sacrifices a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0074</id>
    <name>Surgical Extraction</name>
    <text>({BP} can be paid with either {B} or 2 life.)
Choose target card in a graveyard other than a basic land card. Search its owner's graveyard, hand, and library for any number of cards with the same name as that card and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0075</id>
    <name>Toxic Nim</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
{B}: Regenerate Toxic Nim.</text>
    <flavorText>The nim have become roving killers marshaled by whichever thane holds tenuous leadership.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0076</id>
    <name>Vault Skirge</name>
    <text>({BP} can be paid with either {B} or 2 life.)
Flying
Lifelink (Damage dealt by this creature also causes you to gain that much life.)</text>
    <flavorText>From the remnants of the dead, Geth forged a swarm to safeguard his throne.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0077</id>
    <name>Whispering Specter</name>
    <text>Flying
Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
Whenever Whispering Specter deals combat damage to a player, you may sacrifice it. If you do, that player discards a card for each poison counter he or she has.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0078</id>
    <name>Act of Aggression</name>
    <text>({RP} can be paid with either {R} or 2 life.)
Gain control of target creature an opponent controls until end of turn. Untap that creature. It gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0079</id>
    <name>Artillerize</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Artillerize, sacrifice an artifact or creature.
Artillerize deals 5 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Phyrexian or Mirran, most goblins stick to the job they know best.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0080</id>
    <name>Bludgeon Brawl</name>
    <text>Each noncreature, non-Equipment artifact is an Equipment with equip {X} and "Equipped creature gets +X/+0," where X is that artifact's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0081</id>
    <name>Chancellor of the Forge</name>
    <text>You may reveal this card from your opening hand. If you do, at the beginning of the first upkeep, put a 1/1 red Goblin creature token with haste onto the battlefield.
When Chancellor of the Forge enters the battlefield, put X 1/1 red Goblin creature tokens with haste onto the battlefield, where X is the number of creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0082</id>
    <name>Fallen Ferromancer</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
{1}{R}, {T}: Fallen Ferromancer deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0083</id>
    <name>Flameborn Viron</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Large or small, all will toil for the Great Work."
—Decree of Urabrask</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0084</id>
    <name>Furnace Scamp</name>
    <text>Whenever Furnace Scamp deals combat damage to a player, you may sacrifice it. If you do, Furnace Scamp deals 3 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>Born of the core, and dying to stoke it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0085</id>
    <name>Geosurge</name>
    <text>Add {R}{R}{R}{R}{R}{R}{R} to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast artifact or creature spells.</text>
    <flavorText>"The mountains have been corrupted. Otherwise, they would not lend me their fire so easily."
—Koth of the Hammer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0086</id>
    <name>Gut Shot</name>
    <text>({RP} can be paid with either {R} or 2 life.)
Gut Shot deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Down here, we have a more pointed version of the scriptures."
—Urabrask's enforcer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0087</id>
    <name>Invader Parasite</name>
    <text>Imprint — When Invader Parasite enters the battlefield, exile target land.
Whenever a land with the same name as the exiled card enters the battlefield under an opponent's control, Invader Parasite deals 2 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0088</id>
    <name>Moltensteel Dragon</name>
    <text>({RP} can be paid with either {R} or 2 life.)
Flying
{RP}: Moltensteel Dragon gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>An apocalypse in dragon form.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0089</id>
    <name>Ogre Menial</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
{R}: Ogre Menial gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0090</id>
    <name>Priest of Urabrask</name>
    <text>When Priest of Urabrask enters the battlefield, add {R}{R}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Even in New Phyrexia, red mana sparks glimmers of individualism, passion, and freedom.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0091</id>
    <name>Rage Extractor</name>
    <text>({RP} can be paid with either {R} or 2 life.)
Whenever you cast a spell with p in its mana cost, Rage Extractor deals damage equal to that spell's converted mana cost to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>New Phyrexia is an engine that both consumes and creates malice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0092</id>
    <name>Razor Swine</name>
    <text>First strike
Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>"They aren't helping the forges. Send them to the surface."
—Furnace boss, sector 12</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0093</id>
    <name>Ruthless Invasion</name>
    <text>({RP} can be paid with either {R} or 2 life.)
Nonartifact creatures can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"For the survival of our people, every conflict must now end in retreat."
—Pythor, Mirran resistance</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0094</id>
    <name>Scrapyard Salvo</name>
    <text>Scrapyard Salvo deals damage to target player equal to the number of artifact cards in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"Squealstokers! Build me a glorious pile of Mirran metal. Then add yourselves to the pile."
—Furnace boss, sector 11</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0095</id>
    <name>Slag Fiend</name>
    <text>Slag Fiend's power and toughness are each equal to the number of artifact cards in all graveyards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Seal the furnace vents. Admit no others. We'll tend our forges without their tainted ways."
—Decree of Urabrask</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0096</id>
    <name>Slash Panther</name>
    <text>({RP} can be paid with either {R} or 2 life.)
Haste</text>
    <flavorText>It runs an endless circuit along the ruined roads of the soon-to-be-forgotten Mirran civilization.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0097</id>
    <name>Tormentor Exarch</name>
    <text>When Tormentor Exarch enters the battlefield, choose one — Target creature gets +2/+0 until end of turn; or target creature gets -0/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Tend the molten slag, or be the molten slag."
—Urabrask's enforcer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0098</id>
    <name>Urabrask the Hidden</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have haste.
Creatures your opponents control enter the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>When the Mirran resistance arrived, the furnace dwellers looked to Urabrask for guidance. His decree stunned the others: "Let them be."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0099</id>
    <name>Victorious Destruction</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or land. Its controller loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The refugees look at these structures with hope. We must relieve them of this burden."
—Juex, tormentor exarch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0100</id>
    <name>Volt Charge</name>
    <text>Volt Charge deals 3 damage to target creature or player. Proliferate. (You choose any number of permanents and/or players with counters on them, then give each another counter of a kind already there.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0101</id>
    <name>Vulshok Refugee</name>
    <text>Protection from red</text>
    <flavorText>"I will carve my people's vengeance on the face of Phyrexia."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0102</id>
    <name>Whipflare</name>
    <text>Whipflare deals 2 damage to each nonartifact creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The slag-workers wasted no time in creating their own flare pulses to cleanse the area of the incompleat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0103</id>
    <name>Beast Within</name>
    <text>Destroy target permanent. Its controller puts a 3/3 green Beast creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Kill the weak so they can't drag the strong down to their level. This is true compassion."
—Benzir, archdruid of Temple Might</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0104</id>
    <name>Birthing Pod</name>
    <text>({GP} can be paid with either {G} or 2 life.)
{1}{GP}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Search your library for a creature card with converted mana cost equal to 1 plus the sacrificed creature's converted mana cost, put that card onto the battlefield, then shuffle your library. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0105</id>
    <name>Brutalizer Exarch</name>
    <text>When Brutalizer Exarch enters the battlefield, choose one — Search your library for a creature card, reveal it, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it; or put target noncreature permanent on the bottom of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0106</id>
    <name>Chancellor of the Tangle</name>
    <text>You may reveal this card from your opening hand. If you do, at the beginning of your first main phase, add {G} to your mana pool.
Vigilance, reach</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0107</id>
    <name>Corrosive Gale</name>
    <text>({GP} can be paid with either {G} or 2 life.)
Corrosive Gale deals X damage to each creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Wipe Sheoldred's spies from the sky. She'll see the result of our vision soon enough."
—Glissa</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0108</id>
    <name>Death-Hood Cobra</name>
    <text>{1}{G}: Death-Hood Cobra gains reach until end of turn. (It can block creatures with flying.)
{1}{G}: Death-Hood Cobra gains deathtouch until end of turn. (Any amount of damage it deals to a creature is enough to destroy it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0109</id>
    <name>Fresh Meat</name>
    <text>Put a 3/3 green Beast creature token onto the battlefield for each creature put into your graveyard from the battlefield this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A scavenger's favorite appetizer is death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0110</id>
    <name>Glissa's Scorn</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact. Its controller loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"If it were fit to survive, it wouldn't have been so easily put down."
—Glissa</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0111</id>
    <name>Glistener Elf</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Beg me for life, and I will fill you with the glory of Phyrexian perfection."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0112</id>
    <name>Greenhilt Trainee</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn. Activate this ability only if Greenhilt Trainee's power is 4 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our ancestors adapted to this world of metal. Just as they did, we will adapt to this world of evil."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0113</id>
    <name>Leeching Bite</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn. Another target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A substantial portion of Vorinclex's forces became fuel for the rest.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0114</id>
    <name>Maul Splicer</name>
    <text>When Maul Splicer enters the battlefield, put two 3/3 colorless Golem artifact creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Golem creatures you control have trample.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0115</id>
    <name>Melira, Sylvok Outcast</name>
    <text>You can't get poison counters.
Creatures you control can't have -1/-1 counters placed on them.
Creatures your opponents control lose infect.</text>
    <flavorText>Once a pariah, now Mirrodin's greatest hope.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0116</id>
    <name>Mutagenic Growth</name>
    <text>({GP} can be paid with either {G} or 2 life.)
Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Sympathy is for weaklings. Whoever survives, wins."
—Benzir, archdruid of Temple Might</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0117</id>
    <name>Mycosynth Fiend</name>
    <text>Mycosynth Fiend gets +1/+1 for each poison counter your opponents have.</text>
    <flavorText>"I wish I could take credit for it, but nature progresses on its own, just the way it should."
—Vorinclex, Voice of Hunger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0118</id>
    <name>Noxious Revival</name>
    <text>({GP} can be paid with either {G} or 2 life.)
Put target card from a graveyard on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Dead or alive, my creations are stronger than Jin-Gitaxias's septic minions."
—Vorinclex, Voice of Hunger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0119</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Swarmlord</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, put a 1/1 green Insect creature token with infect onto the battlefield for each poison counter your opponents have.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0120</id>
    <name>Rotted Hystrix</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Vorinclex had no grand plan. The oil did its own work, evolving creatures into worthy predators.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0121</id>
    <name>Spinebiter</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
You may have Spinebiter assign its combat damage as though it weren't blocked.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0122</id>
    <name>Thundering Tanadon</name>
    <text>({GP} can be paid with either {G} or 2 life.)
Trample</text>
    <flavorText>"We do not need beakers and vials to test our predators."
—Vorinclex, Voice of Hunger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0123</id>
    <name>Triumph of the Hordes</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, creatures you control get +1/+1 and gain trample and infect. (Creatures with infect deal damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0124</id>
    <name>Viridian Betrayers</name>
    <text>Viridian Betrayers has infect as long as an opponent is poisoned. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>To secure a place in Phyrexia's ranks, they hunted their surviving kin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0125</id>
    <name>Viridian Harvest</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact
When enchanted artifact is put into a graveyard, you gain 6 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"In the midst of horror beyond imagining, I still see things that lift my heart."
—Ezuri</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0126</id>
    <name>Vital Splicer</name>
    <text>When Vital Splicer enters the battlefield, put a 3/3 colorless Golem artifact creature token onto the battlefield.
{1}: Regenerate target Golem you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"For every one that falls, ten shall rise. The revelation of New Phyrexia is at hand."
—Vorinclex, Voice of Hunger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0127</id>
    <name>Vorinclex, Voice of Hunger</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever you tap a land for mana, add one mana to your mana pool of any type that land produced.
Whenever an opponent taps a land for mana, that land doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0128</id>
    <name>Jor Kadeen, the Prevailer</name>
    <text>First strike
Metalcraft — Creatures you control get +3/+0 as long as you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>"As long as my hand holds a blade, there's hope for a pure Mirrodin once again."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0129</id>
    <name>Alloy Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>With or without witnesses, the suns continued their prismatic dance.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0130</id>
    <name>Batterskull</name>
    <text>Living weapon (When this Equipment enters the battlefield, put a 0/0 black Germ creature token onto the battlefield, then attach this to it.)
Equipped creature gets +4/+4 and has vigilance and lifelink.
{3}: Return Batterskull to its owner's hand.
Equip {5}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0131</id>
    <name>Blinding Souleater</name>
    <text>{WP}, {T}: Tap target creature. ({WP} can be paid with either {W} or 2 life.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We thank the souleaters for inscribing our souls with subservience, to reinforce the sacred order."
—Drones' hymn of gratitude</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0132</id>
    <name>Caged Sun</name>
    <text>As Caged Sun enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Creatures you control of the chosen color get +1/+1.
Whenever a land's ability adds one or more mana of the chosen color to your mana pool, add one additional mana of that color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0133</id>
    <name>Conversion Chamber</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Exile target artifact card from a graveyard. Put a charge counter on Conversion Chamber.
{2}, {T}, Remove a charge counter from Conversion Chamber: Put a 3/3 colorless Golem artifact creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0134</id>
    <name>Darksteel Relic</name>
    <text>Darksteel Relic is indestructible. (Effects that say "destroy" don't destroy it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"It's the last thing we can call our own."
—Minhu, Mirran resistance</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0135</id>
    <name>Etched Monstrosity</name>
    <text>Etched Monstrosity enters the battlefield with five -1/-1 counters on it.
{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}, Remove five -1/-1 counters from Etched Monstrosity: Target player draws three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Now etched only with the scars of phyresis.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0136</id>
    <name>Gremlin Mine</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Gremlin Mine: Gremlin Mine deals 4 damage to target artifact creature.
{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Gremlin Mine: Remove up to four charge counters from target noncreature artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0137</id>
    <name>Hex Parasite</name>
    <text>{X}{BP}: Remove up to X counters from target permanent. For each counter removed this way, Hex Parasite gets +1/+0 until end of turn. ({BP} can be paid with either {B} or 2 life.)</text>
    <flavorText>Drawn by power, fueled by conquest.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0138</id>
    <name>Hovermyr</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>Originally created to harvest blinkmoths, the hovermyr are now the silent observers of a dying world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0139</id>
    <name>Immolating Souleater</name>
    <text>{RP}: Immolating Souleater gets +1/+0 until end of turn. ({RP} can be paid with either {R} or 2 life.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We thank the souleaters for melting the sinful that we may be reminded of our own insignificance."
—Drones' hymn of gratitude</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0140</id>
    <name>Insatiable Souleater</name>
    <text>{GP}: Insatiable Souleater gains trample until end of turn. ({GP} can be paid with either {G} or 2 life.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We thank the souleaters for culling our sick so that the strong may earn their triumphs."
—Drones' hymn of gratitude</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0141</id>
    <name>Isolation Cell</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a creature spell, that player loses 2 life unless he or she pays {2}.</text>
    <flavorText>"Attrition is the answer. Starve them, and let their despair be their undoing."
—Sheoldred, Whispering One</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0142</id>
    <name>Kiln Walker</name>
    <text>Whenever Kiln Walker attacks, it gets +3/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>If it possesses an ability to understand and appreciate life, it has never shown it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0143</id>
    <name>Lashwrithe</name>
    <text>Living weapon (When this Equipment enters the battlefield, put a 0/0 black Germ creature token onto the battlefield, then attach this to it.)
Equipped creature gets +1/+1 for each Swamp you control.
Equip {BP}{BP} ({BP} can be paid with either {B} or 2 life.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0144</id>
    <name>Mindcrank</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent loses life, that player puts that many cards from the top of his or her library into his or her graveyard. (Damage dealt by sources without infect causes loss of life.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Let go of your memories and be reborn."
—Argent Etchings, plate 106, passage 27</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0145</id>
    <name>Mycosynth Wellspring</name>
    <text>When Mycosynth Wellspring enters the battlefield or is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The oil created the mycosynth. The mycosynth created New Phyrexia.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0146</id>
    <name>Myr Superion</name>
    <text>Spend only mana produced by creatures to cast Myr Superion.</text>
    <flavorText>Two kinds of myr survive: the powerful and those that stay close by them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0147</id>
    <name>Necropouncer</name>
    <text>Living weapon (When this Equipment enters the battlefield, put a 0/0 black Germ creature token onto the battlefield, then attach this to it.)
Equipped creature gets +3/+1 and has haste.
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0148</id>
    <name>Omen Machine</name>
    <text>Players can't draw cards.
At the beginning of each player's draw step, that player exiles the top card of his or her library. If it's a land card, the player puts it onto the battlefield. Otherwise, the player casts it without paying its mana cost if able.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0149</id>
    <name>Pestilent Souleater</name>
    <text>{BP}: Pestilent Souleater gains infect until end of turn. ({BP} can be paid with either {B} or 2 life. A creature with infect deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0150</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Hulk</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>An invasion weapon of ages past, the glistening oil contained the blueprints of countless atrocities.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0151</id>
    <name>Pristine Talisman</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool. You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Tools and artisans can be destroyed, but the act of creation is inviolate."
—Elspeth Tirel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0152</id>
    <name>Shrine of Boundless Growth</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep or whenever you cast a green spell, put a charge counter on Shrine of Boundless Growth.
{T}, Sacrifice Shrine of Boundless Growth: Add {1} to your mana pool for each charge counter on Shrine of Boundless Growth.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0153</id>
    <name>Shrine of Burning Rage</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep or whenever you cast a red spell, put a charge counter on Shrine of Burning Rage.
{3}, {T}, Sacrifice Shrine of Burning Rage: Shrine of Burning Rage deals damage equal to the number of charge counters on it to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0154</id>
    <name>Shrine of Limitless Power</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep or whenever you cast a black spell, put a charge counter on Shrine of Limitless Power.
{4}, {T}, Sacrifice Shrine of Limitless Power: Target player discards a card for each charge counter on Shrine of Limitless Power.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0155</id>
    <name>Shrine of Loyal Legions</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep or whenever you cast a white spell, put a charge counter on Shrine of Loyal Legions.
{3}, {T}, Sacrifice Shrine of Loyal Legions: Put a 1/1 colorless Myr artifact creature token onto the battlefield for each charge counter on Shrine of Loyal Legions.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0156</id>
    <name>Shrine of Piercing Vision</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep or whenever you cast a blue spell, put a charge counter on Shrine of Piercing Vision.
{T}, Sacrifice Shrine of Piercing Vision: Look at the top X cards of your library, where X is the number of charge counters on Shrine of Piercing Vision. Put one of those cards into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0157</id>
    <name>Sickleslicer</name>
    <text>Living weapon (When this Equipment enters the battlefield, put a 0/0 black Germ creature token onto the battlefield, then attach this to it.)
Equipped creature gets +2/+2.
Equip {4}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0158</id>
    <name>Soul Conduit</name>
    <text>{6}, {T}: Two target players exchange life totals.</text>
    <flavorText>"You have an unhealthy attachment to your selfhood. I can help you with that."
—Malcator, Executor of Synthesis</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0159</id>
    <name>Spellskite</name>
    <text>{UP}: Change a target of target spell or ability to Spellskite. ({UP} can be paid with either {U} or 2 life.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Let's show Vorinclex that progress doesn't always need teeth or claws."
—Malcator, Executor of Synthesis</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0160</id>
    <name>Surge Node</name>
    <text>Surge Node enters the battlefield with six charge counters on it.
{1}, {T}, Remove a charge counter from Surge Node: Put a charge counter on target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>Without a foe to focus on, the machine priests had time to indulge in new sciences.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0161</id>
    <name>Sword of War and Peace</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +2/+2 and has protection from red and from white.
Whenever equipped creature deals combat damage to a player, Sword of War and Peace deals damage to that player equal to the number of cards in his or her hand and you gain 1 life for each card in your hand.
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0162</id>
    <name>Torpor Orb</name>
    <text>Creatures entering the battlefield don't cause abilities to trigger.</text>
    <flavorText>"Phyrexia is certainly dangerous, but I have to admire some of its innovations."
—Tezzeret</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0163</id>
    <name>Trespassing Souleater</name>
    <text>{UP}: Trespassing Souleater is unblockable this turn. ({UP} can be paid with either {U} or 2 life.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We thank the souleaters for surveilling our lives that we may be preserved from our own ignorance."
—Drones' hymn of gratitude</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0164</id>
    <name>Unwinding Clock</name>
    <text>Untap all artifacts you control during each other player's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>"The partisans have unearthed a strange artifact. None know its origin, but it gives them hope of a life beyond."
—Elspeth's journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0165</id>
    <name>Phyrexia's Core</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}, {T}, Sacrifice an artifact: You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"So even the heart of our world has succumbed."
—Koth of the Hammer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0166</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0167</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0168</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0169</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0170</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0171</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0172</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0173</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0174</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>NPH0175</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>