<cards name="Planar Chaos">
  <item>
    <id>PLC0001</id>
    <name>Aven Riftwatcher</name>
    <text>Flying
Vanishing 3 (This permanent enters the battlefield with three time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter from it. When the last is removed, sacrifice it.)
When Aven Riftwatcher enters the battlefield or leaves the battlefield, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0002</id>
    <name>Benalish Commander</name>
    <text>Benalish Commander's power and toughness are each equal to the number of Soldiers you control.
Suspend X—{X}{W}{W}. X can't be 0. (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {X}{W}{W} and exile it with X time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost. It has haste.)
Whenever a time counter is removed from Benalish Commander while it's exiled, put a 1/1 white Soldier creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0003</id>
    <name>Crovax, Ascendant Hero</name>
    <text>Other white creatures get +1/+1.
Nonwhite creatures get -1/-1.
Pay 2 life: Return Crovax, Ascendant Hero to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Crovax was destined for an angel's curse, but one warped timeline saw the noble redeemed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0004</id>
    <name>Dawn Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn; or regenerate target creature; or counter target spell that targets you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0005</id>
    <name>Dust Elemental</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
Flying; fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
When Dust Elemental enters the battlefield, return three creatures you control to their owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0006</id>
    <name>Ghost Tactician</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}, Discard a card: Creatures you control get +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Its ethereal hand confers a lifetime of experience with combat and steel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0007</id>
    <name>Heroes Remembered</name>
    <text>You gain 20 life.
Suspend 10—{W} (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {W} and exile it with ten time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0008</id>
    <name>Magus of the Tabernacle</name>
    <text>All creatures have "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice this creature unless you pay {1}."</text>
    <flavorText>The Tabernacle's disciples channel the emanations from Pendrell Vale, spreading its paradoxical demand to be both worshipped and left alone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0009</id>
    <name>Mantle of Leadership</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
Enchant creature
Whenever a creature enters the battlefield, enchanted creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0010</id>
    <name>Pallid Mycoderm</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a spore counter on Pallid Mycoderm.
Remove three spore counters from Pallid Mycoderm: Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.
Sacrifice a Saproling: Fungus and/or Saproling creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0011</id>
    <name>Poultice Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{2}, {T}: Regenerate target Sliver."</text>
    <flavorText>"Its broad claw suggests a chitinous shield, but in fact it conceals glands that secrete a remarkably swift healing agent."
—Rukarumel, field journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0012</id>
    <name>Rebuff the Wicked</name>
    <text>Counter target spell that targets a permanent you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"I cannot teach you their brand of magic, but I can teach you how to defend against it."
—Tavalus, priest of Korlis</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0013</id>
    <name>Retether</name>
    <text>Return each Aura card from your graveyard to the battlefield. Only creatures can be enchanted this way. (Aura cards that can't enchant a creature on the battlefield remain in your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>The rifts reach into infinite time streams, bringing the divergent products of alternate pasts into the present.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0014</id>
    <name>Riftmarked Knight</name>
    <text>Protection from black; flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)
Suspend 3—{1}{W}{W} (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {1}{W}{W} and exile it with three time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost. It has haste.)
When the last time counter is removed from Riftmarked Knight while it's exiled, put a 2/2 black Knight creature token with flanking, protection from white, and haste onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0015</id>
    <name>Saltblast</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonwhite permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>Dominaria erodes with each passing gust.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0016</id>
    <name>Saltfield Recluse</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>He remembers a past of light and healing. But he lives the bitter present—parching salt, scouring wind, and the withering heat of the desert.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0017</id>
    <name>Serra's Boon</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+2 as long as it's white. Otherwise, it gets -2/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>"The light of an angel's glance is warm, but her fixed stare blinds and burns."
—Calexis, deacon of the New Order of Serra</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0018</id>
    <name>Shade of Trokair</name>
    <text>{W}: Shade of Trokair gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
Suspend 3—{W} (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {W} and exile it with three time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost. It has haste.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0019</id>
    <name>Stonecloaker</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
Flying
When Stonecloaker enters the battlefield, return a creature you control to its owner's hand.
When Stonecloaker enters the battlefield, exile target card from a graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0020</id>
    <name>Stormfront Riders</name>
    <text>Flying
When Stormfront Riders enters the battlefield, return two creatures you control to their owner's hand.
Whenever Stormfront Riders or another creature is returned to your hand from the battlefield, put a 1/1 white Soldier creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0021</id>
    <name>Voidstone Gargoyle</name>
    <text>Flying
As Voidstone Gargoyle enters the battlefield, name a nonland card.
The named card can't be cast.
Activated abilities of sources with the chosen name can't be activated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0022</id>
    <name>Whitemane Lion</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
When Whitemane Lion enters the battlefield, return a creature you control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Saltfield nomads call a sudden storm a "whitemane."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0023</id>
    <name>Calciderm</name>
    <text>Shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)
Vanishing 4 (This permanent enters the battlefield with four time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter from it. When the last is removed, sacrifice it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0024</id>
    <name>Malach of the Dawn</name>
    <text>Flying
{W}{W}{W}: Regenerate Malach of the Dawn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The sun rises, but the world still feels dark. Pray for the arrival of the malachim—they'll bring Dawn to the world and to our hearts."
—Sister Betje, Miracles of the Saints</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0025</id>
    <name>Mana Tithe</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1}.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those who seek to upset the balance must be taxed for such ambitions."
—Verithain, mesa high priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0026</id>
    <name>Mesa Enchantress</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an enchantment spell, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>She shepherds mysteries and dust as others would a flock of sheep.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0027</id>
    <name>Mycologist</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a spore counter on Mycologist.
Remove three spore counters from Mycologist: Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.
Sacrifice a Saproling: You gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0028</id>
    <name>Porphyry Nodes</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy the creature with the least power. It can't be regenerated. If two or more creatures are tied for least power, you choose one of them.
When there are no creatures on the battlefield, sacrifice Porphyry Nodes.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0029</id>
    <name>Revered Dead</name>
    <text>{W}: Regenerate Revered Dead.</text>
    <flavorText>"The mists coalesced into silent warriors. We charged them and broke through their lines, only to see them swirl and re-form behind us."
—Golas Mahr, black knight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0030</id>
    <name>Sinew Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>As the muscle cords of the creature twitched, Hanna saw an unsettling unanimity in the others' rippling flesh. She didn't know what it meant, but she urged Sisay to keep the ship at a safe distance.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0031</id>
    <name>Sunlance</name>
    <text>Sunlance deals 3 damage to target nonwhite creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's easy for the innocent to speak of justice. They seldom feel its terrible power."
—Orim, Samite inquisitor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0032</id>
    <name>Aeon Chronicler</name>
    <text>Aeon Chronicler's power and toughness are each equal to the number of cards in your hand.
Suspend X—{X}{3}{U}. X can't be 0.  (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {X}{3}{U} and exile it with X time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost. It has haste.)
Whenever a time counter is removed from Aeon Chronicler while it's exiled, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0033</id>
    <name>Aquamorph Entity</name>
    <text>As Aquamorph Entity enters the battlefield or is turned face up, it becomes your choice of 5/1 or 1/5.
Morph {2}{U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0034</id>
    <name>Auramancer's Guise</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 for each Aura attached to it and has vigilance.</text>
    <flavorText>"Consider not what the mask hides, but what it can reveal."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0035</id>
    <name>Body Double</name>
    <text>You may have Body Double enter the battlefield as a copy of any creature card in a graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Where the dead outnumbered the living, mimics scavenged faces from the fallen.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0036</id>
    <name>Braids, Conjurer Adept</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player may put an artifact, creature, or land card from his or her hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The rifted multiverse became a sea of conflicting realities, each peopled by possible versions of every living being.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0037</id>
    <name>Chronozoa</name>
    <text>Flying
Vanishing 3 (This permanent enters the battlefield with three time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter from it. When the last is removed, sacrifice it.)
When Chronozoa is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no time counters on it, put two tokens that are copies of it onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0038</id>
    <name>Dichotomancy</name>
    <text>For each tapped nonland permanent target opponent controls, search that player's library for a card with the same name as that permanent and put it onto the battlefield under your control. Then that player shuffles his or her library.
Suspend 3—{1}{U}{U} (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {1}{U}{U} and exile it with three time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0039</id>
    <name>Dismal Failure</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. Its controller discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Two magi could trade spells all day and never crown a victor. The real battle is not one of power but of will. If your confidence breaks, so too shall you."
—Venser</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0040</id>
    <name>Dreamscape Artist</name>
    <text>{2}{U}, {T}, Discard a card, Sacrifice a land: Search your library for up to two basic land cards and put them onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>He's mastered the art of sleight of land.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0041</id>
    <name>Erratic Mutation</name>
    <text>Choose target creature. Reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal a nonland card. That creature gets +X/-X until end of turn, where X is that card's converted mana cost. Put all cards revealed this way on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0042</id>
    <name>Jodah's Avenger</name>
    <text>{0}: Until end of turn, Jodah's Avenger gets -1/-1 and gains your choice of double strike, protection from red, vigilance, or shadow. (A creature with shadow can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0043</id>
    <name>Magus of the Bazaar</name>
    <text>{T}: Draw two cards, then discard three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Some trade in goods, some in secrets. My soul has walked the futures, and I offer the rare coin of possibility."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0044</id>
    <name>Pongify</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature. It can't be regenerated. That creature's controller puts a 3/3 green Ape creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Some spellcrafting mistakes go on to become spells of their own.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0045</id>
    <name>Reality Acid</name>
    <text>Enchant permanent
Vanishing 3 (This permanent enters the battlefield with three time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter from it. When the last is removed, sacrifice it.)
When Reality Acid leaves the battlefield, enchanted permanent's controller sacrifices it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0046</id>
    <name>Shaper Parasite</name>
    <text>Morph {2}{U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Shaper Parasite is turned face up, target creature gets +2/-2 or -2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0047</id>
    <name>Spellshift</name>
    <text>Counter target instant or sorcery spell. Its controller reveals cards from the top of his or her library until he or she reveals an instant or sorcery card. That player may cast that card without paying its mana cost. Then he or she shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0048</id>
    <name>Synchronous Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have vigilance.</text>
    <flavorText>"With a twitch of its muscles, its timeline forks. Then, just as quickly, its two selves reintegrate. Causality, strangely, seems not to mind."
—Rukarumel, field journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0049</id>
    <name>Tidewalker</name>
    <text>Tidewalker enters the battlefield with a time counter on it for each Island you control.
Vanishing (At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter from this permanent. When the last is removed, sacrifice it.)
Tidewalker's power and toughness are each equal to the number of time counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0050</id>
    <name>Timebender</name>
    <text>Morph {U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)
When Timebender is turned face up, choose one — Remove two time counters from target permanent or suspended card; or put two time counters on target permanent with a time counter on it or suspended card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0051</id>
    <name>Veiling Oddity</name>
    <text>Suspend 4—{1}{U} (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {1}{U} and exile it with four time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost. It has haste.)
When the last time counter is removed from Veiling Oddity while it's exiled, creatures are unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0052</id>
    <name>Venarian Glimmer</name>
    <text>Target player reveals his or her hand. You choose a nonland card with converted mana cost X or less from it. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>Dream of nothing, and wake to a dream come true.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0053</id>
    <name>Wistful Thinking</name>
    <text>Target player draws two cards, then discards four cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"To probe the wonders of the multiverse, to gaze upon worlds unspoiled by blade or spell . . . it's enough to make one weep for the possibilities denied."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0054</id>
    <name>Frozen Æther</name>
    <text>Artifacts, creatures, and lands your opponents control enter the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>Gjornersen entertained his followers by taking bets on which would move first—the drowsing land wurm or the frozen goblins.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0055</id>
    <name>Gossamer Phantasm</name>
    <text>Flying
When Gossamer Phantasm becomes the target of a spell or ability, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Belief matters more than truth. Every moment, belief in imaginary things alters lives while truth sits unnoticed and waits."
—Hakim, Loreweaver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0056</id>
    <name>Merfolk Thaumaturgist</name>
    <text>{T}: Switch target creature's power and toughness until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Blasted fishtails It's not enough that they meddle with my head, but they twist my body as well."
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0057</id>
    <name>Ovinize</name>
    <text>Target creature loses all abilities and becomes 0/1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"You wish for me to cow your enemies? I can do better than that . . . ."
—Teferi, second-level student</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0058</id>
    <name>Piracy Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target creature gains islandwalk until end of turn; or target creature gets +2/-1 until end of turn; or target player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0059</id>
    <name>Primal Plasma</name>
    <text>As Primal Plasma enters the battlefield, it becomes your choice of a 3/3 creature, a 2/2 creature with flying, or a 1/6 creature with defender.</text>
    <flavorText>Tocasia brushed the gears and cogs from the table. There, before two wide-eyed brothers, she began a lesson on raw elemental magic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0060</id>
    <name>Riptide Pilferer</name>
    <text>Whenever Riptide Pilferer deals combat damage to a player, that player discards a card.
Morph {U} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0061</id>
    <name>Serendib Sorcerer</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature other than Serendib Sorcerer becomes 0/2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Even a dragon is humble as a kitten if it thinks itself a slave."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0062</id>
    <name>Serra Sphinx</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>Sphinxes drink from the mystic meres of Serra's realm, where their keen eyes watch reflections of what is and what is yet to come.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0063</id>
    <name>Big Game Hunter</name>
    <text>When Big Game Hunter enters the battlefield, destroy target creature with power 4 or greater. It can't be regenerated.
Madness {B} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0064</id>
    <name>Blightspeaker</name>
    <text>{T}: Target player loses 1 life.
{4}, {T}: Search your library for a Rebel permanent card with converted mana cost 3 or less and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>One croaked sermon spreads propaganda and plague.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0065</id>
    <name>Brain Gorgers</name>
    <text>When you cast Brain Gorgers, any player may sacrifice a creature. If a player does, counter Brain Gorgers.
Madness {1}{B} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>In spite of their hunger, they're slow eaters.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0066</id>
    <name>Circle of Affliction</name>
    <text>As Circle of Affliction enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Whenever a source of the chosen color deals damage to you, you may pay {1}. If you do, target player loses 1 life and you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0067</id>
    <name>Cradle to Grave</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature that entered the battlefield this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"As the fell soil's appetite grows, it gulps down passersby upon their first footfall."
—Ezrith, druid of the Dark Hours</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0068</id>
    <name>Dash Hopes</name>
    <text>When you cast Dash Hopes, any player may pay 5 life. If a player does, counter Dash Hopes.
Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"Focus an enemy's mind on what's already gone, and it's easier to take away more."
—Holux, stronghold racketeer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0069</id>
    <name>Deadly Grub</name>
    <text>Vanishing 3 (This permanent enters the battlefield with three time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter from it. When the last is removed, sacrifice it.)
When Deadly Grub is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no time counters on it, put a 6/1 green Insect creature token with shroud onto the battlefield. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0070</id>
    <name>Enslave</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
You control enchanted creature.
At the beginning of your upkeep, enchanted creature deals 1 damage to its owner.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0071</id>
    <name>Extirpate</name>
    <text>Split second (As long as this spell is on the stack, players can't cast spells or activate abilities that aren't mana abilities.)
Choose target card in a graveyard other than a basic land card. Search its owner's graveyard, hand, and library for all cards with the same name as that card and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0072</id>
    <name>Imp's Mischief</name>
    <text>Change the target of target spell with a single target. You lose life equal to that spell's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"Do the innocent pay for the crimes of the guilty? Of course they do. That's the fate of the weak."
—Nicol Bolas</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0073</id>
    <name>Magus of the Coffers</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Add {B} to your mana pool for each Swamp you control.</text>
    <flavorText>All that remains of the Cabal are the echoes in its deepest vault. Yet those who hear the echoes feel a power undiminished by the dust of ages.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0074</id>
    <name>Midnight Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Midnight Charm deals 1 damage to target creature and you gain 1 life; or target creature gains first strike until end of turn; or tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0075</id>
    <name>Mirri the Cursed</name>
    <text>Flying, first strike, haste
Whenever Mirri the Cursed deals combat damage to a creature, put a +1/+1 counter on Mirri the Cursed.</text>
    <flavorText>A hero fails, a martyr falls. Time twists and destinies interchange.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0076</id>
    <name>Muck Drubb</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
When Muck Drubb enters the battlefield, change the target of target spell that targets only a single creature to Muck Drubb.
Madness {2}{B} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0077</id>
    <name>Phantasmagorian</name>
    <text>When you cast Phantasmagorian, any player may discard three cards. If a player does, counter Phantasmagorian.
Discard three cards: Return Phantasmagorian from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0078</id>
    <name>Ridged Kusite</name>
    <text>{1}{B}, {T}, Discard a card: Target creature gets +1/+0 and gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"It offers but a taste of the power that the shadows have to offer. But even that is a heady wine indeed."
—Ratadrabik of Urborg</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0079</id>
    <name>Roiling Horror</name>
    <text>Roiling Horror's power and toughness are each equal to your life total minus the life total of an opponent with the most life.
Suspend X—{X}{B}{B}{B}. X can't be 0. (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {X}{B}{B}{B} and exile it with X time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost. It has haste.)
Whenever a time counter is removed from Roiling Horror while it's exiled, target player loses 1 life and you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0080</id>
    <name>Spitting Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our lances' reach had been our saving grace in our fight against the hive. Now even that advantage is taken from us."
—Adom Capashen, Benalish knight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0081</id>
    <name>Temporal Extortion</name>
    <text>When you cast Temporal Extortion, any player may pay half his or her life, rounded up. If a player does, counter Temporal Extortion.
Take an extra turn after this one.</text>
    <flavorText>"The scythe of time or my blade at your throat—the choice is yours."
—Holux, stronghold racketeer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0082</id>
    <name>Treacherous Urge</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You may put a creature card from it onto the battlefield under your control. That creature has haste. Sacrifice it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0083</id>
    <name>Waning Wurm</name>
    <text>Vanishing 2 (This permanent enters the battlefield with two time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter from it. When the last is removed, sacrifice it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0084</id>
    <name>Bog Serpent</name>
    <text>Bog Serpent can't attack unless defending player controls a Swamp.
When you control no Swamps, sacrifice Bog Serpent.</text>
    <flavorText>"We thought it was a fallen tree trunk. Then it ate Snod."
—Sneed, goblin barkwright</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0085</id>
    <name>Damnation</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0086</id>
    <name>Dunerider Outlaw</name>
    <text>Protection from green
At the beginning of each end step, if Dunerider Outlaw dealt damage to an opponent this turn, put a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>Tales of the outlaw's cruelty and might grew more embellished with each crime.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0087</id>
    <name>Kor Dirge</name>
    <text>All damage that would be dealt this turn to target creature you control by a source of your choice is dealt to another target creature instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Rath's new evincar eliminated the brutish moggs and took a new slave race, one more reminiscent of her own feline grace.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0088</id>
    <name>Melancholy</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Melancholy enters the battlefield, tap enchanted creature.
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Melancholy unless you pay {B}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0089</id>
    <name>Null Profusion</name>
    <text>Skip your draw step.
Whenever you play a card, draw a card.
Your maximum hand size is two.</text>
    <flavorText>"Some say that time is cyclical and that history inevitably repeats. My will is my own. I won't bow to fate."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0090</id>
    <name>Rathi Trapper</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}: Tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Tangling vines, fetid murk, paralyzing poisons, and crawling dead. The swamp is nature's trap waiting to be exploited by unnatural minds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0091</id>
    <name>Shrouded Lore</name>
    <text>Target opponent chooses a card in your graveyard. You may pay {B}. If you do, repeat this process except that opponent can't choose a card already chosen for Shrouded Lore. Then put the last chosen card into your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0092</id>
    <name>Vampiric Link</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>The familiar's fangs deliver the master's bite.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0093</id>
    <name>Æther Membrane</name>
    <text>Defender; reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)
Whenever Æther Membrane blocks a creature, return that creature to its owner's hand at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0094</id>
    <name>Akroma, Angel of Fury</name>
    <text>Akroma, Angel of Fury can't be countered.
Flying, trample, protection from white and from blue
{R}: Akroma, Angel of Fury gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
Morph {3}{R}{R}{R} (You may cast this face down as a 2/2 creature for {3}. Turn it face up any time for its morph cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0095</id>
    <name>Battering Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have trample.</text>
    <flavorText>Covered with hard shell-like plates, these slivers burrow through solid rock to carve out new nests for their hives.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0096</id>
    <name>Detritivore</name>
    <text>Detritivore's power and toughness are each equal to the number of nonbasic land cards in your opponents' graveyards.
Suspend X—{X}{3}{R}. X can't be 0. (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {X}{3}{R} and exile it with X time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost. It has haste.)
Whenever a time counter is removed from Detritivore while it's exiled, destroy target nonbasic land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0097</id>
    <name>Dust Corona</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+0 and can't be blocked by creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"They infiltrated deep into the enemy camp under cover of darkness . . . and dirt."
—Corus, viashino warrior</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0098</id>
    <name>Fatal Frenzy</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, target creature you control gains trample and gets +X/+0, where X is its power. Sacrifice it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>"I hope to have such a death—lying in triumph upon the broken bodies of those who slew me."
—Radha, Keldon warlord</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0099</id>
    <name>Firefright Mage</name>
    <text>{1}{R}, {T}, Discard a card: Target creature can't be blocked this turn except by artifact creatures and/or red creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>After millennia of advancement in goblin military theory, Toggo VI realized that almost everyone is afraid of fire.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0100</id>
    <name>Fury Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Destroy target artifact; or target creature gets +1/+1 and gains trample until end of turn; or remove two time counters from target permanent or suspended card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0101</id>
    <name>Hammerheim Deadeye</name>
    <text>Echo {5}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Hammerheim Deadeye enters the battlefield, destroy target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0102</id>
    <name>Keldon Marauders</name>
    <text>Vanishing 2 (This permanent enters the battlefield with two time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter from it. When the last is removed, sacrifice it.)
When Keldon Marauders enters the battlefield or leaves the battlefield, it deals 1 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0103</id>
    <name>Lavacore Elemental</name>
    <text>Vanishing 1 (This permanent enters the battlefield with a time counter on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter from it. When the last is removed, sacrifice it.)
Whenever a creature you control deals combat damage to a player, put a time counter on Lavacore Elemental.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0104</id>
    <name>Magus of the Arena</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Tap target creature you control and target creature of an opponent's choice he or she controls. Each of those creatures deals damage equal to its power to the other.</text>
    <flavorText>The magus still hears the roar of the crowds. They're gone, but the will to compete remains.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0105</id>
    <name>Needlepeak Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>"It's a testament to the forests' devastation that giant spiders now make their homes amid Dominaria's barren spires."
—Aznaph, greenseeker</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0106</id>
    <name>Shivan Meteor</name>
    <text>Shivan Meteor deals 13 damage to target creature.
Suspend 2—{1}{R}{R} (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {1}{R}{R} and exile it with two time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0107</id>
    <name>Stingscourger</name>
    <text>Echo {3}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Stingscourger enters the battlefield, return target creature an opponent controls to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0108</id>
    <name>Sulfur Elemental</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
Split second (As long as this spell is on the stack, players can't cast spells or activate abilities that aren't mana abilities.)
White creatures get +1/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0109</id>
    <name>Timecrafting</name>
    <text>Choose one — Remove X time counters from target permanent or suspended card; or put X time counters on target permanent with a time counter on it or suspended card.</text>
    <flavorText>Oddly, an unstable time stream makes wizards want to tinker with it even more.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0110</id>
    <name>Torchling</name>
    <text>{R}: Untap Torchling.
{R}: Target creature blocks Torchling this turn if able.
{R}: Change the target of target spell that targets only Torchling.
{1}: Torchling gets +1/-1 until end of turn.
{1}: Torchling gets -1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0111</id>
    <name>Volcano Hellion</name>
    <text>Volcano Hellion has echo {X}, where X is your life total. (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Volcano Hellion enters the battlefield, it deals an amount of damage of your choice to you and target creature. The damage can't be prevented.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0112</id>
    <name>Boom</name>
    <text>Destroy all lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0113</id>
    <name>Bust</name>
    <text>Destroy all lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0114</id>
    <name>Dead</name>
    <text>Return target creature you don't control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0115</id>
    <name>Gone</name>
    <text>Return target creature you don't control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0116</id>
    <name>Rough</name>
    <text>Tumble deals 6 damage to each creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0117</id>
    <name>Tumble</name>
    <text>Tumble deals 6 damage to each creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0118</id>
    <name>Blood Knight</name>
    <text>First strike, protection from white</text>
    <flavorText>His is the fury of the wildfire, the boiling blood of the volcano. He fights you not because you've wronged him, but because you're there.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0119</id>
    <name>Brute Force</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Blood, bone, and sinew are magnified, as is the rage that drives them. The brain, however, remains unchanged—a little bean, swinging by a strand in a cavernous, raving head.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0120</id>
    <name>Molten Firebird</name>
    <text>Flying
When Molten Firebird is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control at the beginning of the next end step and you skip your next draw step.
{4}{R}: Exile Molten Firebird.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0121</id>
    <name>Prodigal Pyromancer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prodigal Pyromancer deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Learn to burn"
—Institute of Arcane Studies motto</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0122</id>
    <name>Pyrohemia</name>
    <text>At the beginning of the end step, if no creatures are on the battlefield, sacrifice Pyrohemia.
{R}: Pyrohemia deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0123</id>
    <name>Reckless Wurm</name>
    <text>Trample
Madness {2}{R} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>Bred for battle in the Grand Coliseum, these wurms annihilated whole ecosystems when released into the wild.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0124</id>
    <name>Shivan Wumpus</name>
    <text>Trample
When Shivan Wumpus enters the battlefield, any player may sacrifice a land. If a player does, put Shivan Wumpus on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>It's easier to move the village than to divert the wumpus.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0125</id>
    <name>Simian Spirit Guide</name>
    <text>Exile Simian Spirit Guide from your hand: Add {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"All my spells smell like burnt hair lately."
—Jaya Ballard, task mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0126</id>
    <name>Skirk Shaman</name>
    <text>Skirk Shaman can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or red creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>In a shaman's grimy hands, a concoction of dried Skirk Ridge herbs can become the face of panic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0127</id>
    <name>Ana Battlemage</name>
    <text>Kicker {2}{U} and/or {1}{B} (You may pay an additional {2}{U} and/or {1}{B} as you cast this spell.)
When Ana Battlemage enters the battlefield, if it was kicked with its {2}{U} kicker, target player discards three cards.
When Ana Battlemage enters the battlefield, if it was kicked with its {1}{B} kicker, tap target untapped creature and that creature deals damage equal to its power to its controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0128</id>
    <name>Citanul Woodreaders</name>
    <text>Kicker {2}{G} (You may pay an additional {2}{G} as you cast this spell.)
When Citanul Woodreaders enters the battlefield, if it was kicked, draw two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>They seek out living trees to glean age-old secrets from sap and wood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0129</id>
    <name>Deadwood Treefolk</name>
    <text>Vanishing 3 (This permanent enters the battlefield with three time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter from it. When the last is removed, sacrifice it.)
When Deadwood Treefolk enters the battlefield or leaves the battlefield, return another target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0130</id>
    <name>Evolution Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library; or return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand; or target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0131</id>
    <name>Fungal Behemoth</name>
    <text>Fungal Behemoth's power and toughness are each equal to the number of +1/+1 counters on creatures you control.
Suspend X—{X}{G}{G}. X can't be 0. (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {X}{G}{G} and exile it with X time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost. It has haste.)
Whenever a time counter is removed from Fungal Behemoth while it's exiled, you may put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0132</id>
    <name>Giant Dustwasp</name>
    <text>Flying
Suspend 4—{1}{G} (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {1}{G} and exile it with four time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost. It has haste.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0133</id>
    <name>Hunting Wilds</name>
    <text>Kicker {3}{G} (You may pay an additional {3}{G} as you cast this spell.)
Search your library for up to two Forest cards and put them onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.
If Hunting Wilds was kicked, untap all Forests put onto the battlefield this way. They become 3/3 green creatures with haste that are still lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0134</id>
    <name>Jedit Ojanen of Efrava</name>
    <text>Forestwalk
Whenever Jedit Ojanen of Efrava attacks or blocks, put a 2/2 green Cat Warrior creature token with forestwalk onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The cat warriors recognized this Jedit's face, but not his fierce loyalty to Efrava.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0135</id>
    <name>Kavu Predator</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever an opponent gains life, put that many +1/+1 counters on Kavu Predator.</text>
    <flavorText>In a withered world, the scent of healthy prey is enough to drive a predator to frenzy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0136</id>
    <name>Life and Limb</name>
    <text>All Forests and all Saprolings are 1/1 green Saproling creatures and Forest lands in addition to their other types.</text>
    <flavorText>"It was a sight of pain and awe—a twisted forest, migrating across the salt plain in search of richer soil."
—Edahlis, greenseeker</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0137</id>
    <name>Magus of the Library</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Draw a card. Activate this ability only if you have exactly seven cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The ancient books slowly crumbled, their secrets turning to dust. But their every word sings within the magus's head.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0138</id>
    <name>Mire Boa</name>
    <text>Swampwalk
{G}: Regenerate Mire Boa.</text>
    <flavorText>Mire slime courses through its veins in place of blood. No sooner does it bleed than it opens its mouth to replace the loss.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0139</id>
    <name>Pouncing Wurm</name>
    <text>Kicker {2}{G} (You may pay an additional {2}{G} as you cast this spell.)
If Pouncing Wurm was kicked, it enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it and with haste.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0140</id>
    <name>Psychotrope Thallid</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a spore counter on Psychotrope Thallid.
Remove three spore counters from Psychotrope Thallid: Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.
{1}, Sacrifice a Saproling: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0141</id>
    <name>Reflex Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have haste.</text>
    <flavorText>"This sliver comes into the world a perfect predator. It's ready to hunt and devour its first meal within seconds of hatching."
—Rukarumel, field journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0142</id>
    <name>Sophic Centaur</name>
    <text>{2}{G}{G}, {T}, Discard a card: You gain 2 life for each card in your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>He endures the pain of remembering Krosa as it once was and hopes that a future generation will have need of his memories.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0143</id>
    <name>Timbermare</name>
    <text>Haste
Echo {5}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Timbermare enters the battlefield, tap all other creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Only nature wreaks such lovely havoc.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0144</id>
    <name>Uktabi Drake</name>
    <text>Flying, haste
Echo {1}{G}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0145</id>
    <name>Utopia Vow</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block.
Enchanted creature has "{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>"I'll guard this fruit and its seedling until the land is healed. My life now belongs to Dominaria."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0146</id>
    <name>Vitaspore Thallid</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a spore counter on Vitaspore Thallid.
Remove three spore counters from Vitaspore Thallid: Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.
Sacrifice a Saproling: Target creature gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0147</id>
    <name>Wild Pair</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature enters the battlefield, if you cast it from your hand, you may search your library for a creature card with the same total power and toughness and put it onto the battlefield. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0148</id>
    <name>Essence Warden</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The more our numbers grow, the more I gain hope that Volrath and his cursed stronghold will one day fall."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0149</id>
    <name>Fa'adiyah Seer</name>
    <text>{T}: Draw a card and reveal it. If it isn't a land card, discard it.</text>
    <flavorText>"My visions don't show me home. They show me where home is yet to be found."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0150</id>
    <name>Gaea's Anthem</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>"To those who can hear it, Gaea's battle song brings power as swift as sunlight and as enduring as the deep roots of the forest."
—Gamelen, Citanul elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0151</id>
    <name>Groundbreaker</name>
    <text>Trample, haste
At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice Groundbreaker.</text>
    <flavorText>The earth's memory is long, its retribution brief.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0152</id>
    <name>Harmonize</name>
    <text>Draw three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Life's greatest lessons don't come from focus or concentration. They come from breathing and simply noticing."
—Seton, centaur druid</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0153</id>
    <name>Healing Leaves</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target player gains 3 life; or prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The elves of Llanowar don't trust in alchemy. They rely instead on pure herbs harvested from the forest's sacred heart.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0154</id>
    <name>Hedge Troll</name>
    <text>Hedge Troll gets +1/+1 as long as you control a Plains.
{W}: Regenerate Hedge Troll.</text>
    <flavorText>His abode was clean and bare, not a morsel in sight. I asked him what he ate, fearing the answer. He smiled and said his faith alone sustained him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0155</id>
    <name>Keen Sense</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage to an opponent, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Crovax sensed that Mirri wasn't ready for the curse taking hold of her. Weeping in his heart, he fled.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0156</id>
    <name>Seal of Primordium</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Seal of Primordium: Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"I am the simplifier, the root that drags all artifice to earth."
—Seal inscription</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0157</id>
    <name>Cautery Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{1}, Sacrifice this permanent: This permanent deals 1 damage to target creature or player."
All Slivers have "{1}, Sacrifice this permanent: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target Sliver creature or player this turn."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0158</id>
    <name>Darkheart Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "Sacrifice this permanent: You gain 3 life."</text>
    <flavorText>"At first we thought we were in some haunted wood. Then the branches twisted and scuttled toward us."
—Merrik Aidar, Benalish patrol</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0159</id>
    <name>Dormant Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have defender.
All Slivers have "When this permanent enters the battlefield, draw a card."</text>
    <flavorText>"It triggers the hive's period of Ætheric fertility—a time when even feeding is a lower priority than reproduction."
—Rukarumel, field journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0160</id>
    <name>Frenetic Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{0}: If this permanent is on the battlefield, flip a coin. If you win the flip, exile this permanent and return it to the battlefield under its owner's control at the beginning of the next end step. If you lose the flip, sacrifice it."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0161</id>
    <name>Intet, the Dreamer</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Intet, the Dreamer deals combat damage to a player, you may pay {2}{U}. If you do, exile the top card of your library face down. You may look at that card for as long as it remains exiled. You may play that card without paying its mana cost for as long as Intet remains on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0162</id>
    <name>Necrotic Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{3}, Sacrifice this permanent: Destroy target permanent."</text>
    <flavorText>Though Volrath is long dead, the slivers have become everything he wanted them to be: mindless instruments of destruction and despair.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0163</id>
    <name>Numot, the Devastator</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Numot, the Devastator deals combat damage to a player, you may pay {2}{R}. If you do, destroy up to two target lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0164</id>
    <name>Oros, the Avenger</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Oros, the Avenger deals combat damage to a player, you may pay {2}{W}. If you do, Oros deals 3 damage to each nonwhite creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0165</id>
    <name>Radha, Heir to Keld</name>
    <text>Whenever Radha, Heir to Keld attacks, you may add {R}{R} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Run home, cur. I've already taken your master's head. Don't make me thrash you with it."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0166</id>
    <name>Teneb, the Harvester</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Teneb, the Harvester deals combat damage to a player, you may pay {2}{B}. If you do, put target creature card from a graveyard onto the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0167</id>
    <name>Vorosh, the Hunter</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Vorosh, the Hunter deals combat damage to a player, you may pay {2}{G}. If you do, put six +1/+1 counters on Vorosh.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PLC0168</id>
    <name>Urborg, Tomb of Yawgmoth</name>
    <text>Each land is a Swamp in addition to its other land types.</text>
    <flavorText>"Yawgmoth's corpse is a wound in the universe. His foul blood seeps out, infecting the land with his final curse."
—Lord Windgrace</flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>