<cards name="Cicatrici di Mirrodin">
  <item>
    <id>SOM0001</id>
    <name>Abuna Acolyte</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.
{T}: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to target artifact creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"You can break nothing I cannot mend."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0002</id>
    <name>Arrest</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block, and its activated abilities can't be activated.</text>
    <flavorText>Bladehold houses a rogues' gallery filled with the living "statues" of the worst enemies of the Auriok.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0003</id>
    <name>Auriok Edgewright</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — Auriok Edgewright has double strike as long as you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>Auriok soldiers craft their own weapons, forging a connection to the steel with each blow of the hammer.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0004</id>
    <name>Auriok Sunchaser</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — As long as you control three or more artifacts, Auriok Sunchaser gets +2/+2 and has flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Grant me loft. Grant me light. Grant me the accuracy I need to kill all who threaten Bladehold."
—Prayer to the Whitesun</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0005</id>
    <name>Dispense Justice</name>
    <text>Target player sacrifices an attacking creature.
Metalcraft — That player sacrifices two attacking creatures instead if you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>The Accorders never strike first, but they always strike back.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0006</id>
    <name>Elspeth Tirel</name>
    <text>+2: You gain 1 life for each creature you control.
-2: Put three 1/1 white Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield.
-5: Destroy all other permanents except
for lands and tokens.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0007</id>
    <name>Fulgent Distraction</name>
    <text>Choose two target creatures. Tap those creatures, then unattach all Equipment from them.</text>
    <flavorText>"Channeling the white-hot power of all five suns creates a pretty good diversion."
—Yavash of the Accorders</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0008</id>
    <name>Ghalma's Warden</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — Ghalma's Warden gets +2/+2 as long as you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>A special unit guards the loxodon artificer known as Ghalma the Shaper. They are armed and armored in her finest works of silver and steel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0009</id>
    <name>Glimmerpoint Stag</name>
    <text>Vigilance
When Glimmerpoint Stag enters the battlefield, exile another target permanent. Return that card to the battlefield under its owner's control at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0010</id>
    <name>Glint Hawk</name>
    <text>Flying
When Glint Hawk enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you return an artifact you control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Its eyes burned nearly blind by the Whitesun, it hunts by metallic gleam.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0011</id>
    <name>Indomitable Archangel</name>
    <text>Flying
Metalcraft — Artifacts you control have shroud as long as you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>"Every sword drawn to defend is an angelic blade, guided to justice by an angelic hand."
—Auriok proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0012</id>
    <name>Kemba, Kha Regent</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a 2/2 white Cat creature token onto the battlefield for each Equipment attached to Kemba, Kha Regent.</text>
    <flavorText>"I am not Raksha. I never will be. But I refuse to be the kha who watched her pride be torn asunder."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0013</id>
    <name>Kemba's Skyguard</name>
    <text>Flying
When Kemba's Skyguard enters the battlefield, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"We're now to dispense aid to any Mirran we see battling anything . . . ‘strange.' Regent's orders."
—Ranya, skyhunter captain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0014</id>
    <name>Leonin Arbiter</name>
    <text>Players can't search libraries. Any player may pay {2} for that player to ignore this effect until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our people are torn by infighting. Until the two sides reconcile, our laws can carry no meaning."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0015</id>
    <name>Loxodon Wayfarer</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The Mirran elders vanished with Memnarch, leaving behind a generation of wayward orphans.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0016</id>
    <name>Myrsmith</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an artifact spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, put a 1/1 colorless Myr artifact creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The Auriok see the artificer as a conduit, beckoning new creations into the world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0017</id>
    <name>Razor Hippogriff</name>
    <text>Flying
When Razor Hippogriff enters the battlefield, return target artifact card from your graveyard to your hand. You gain life equal to that card's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>She incubates her eggs in gold and mana.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0018</id>
    <name>Revoke Existence</name>
    <text>Exile target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"No half measures, no regrets. We'll tell no stories of this day. It will be as if it never existed at all."
—Ganedor, loxodon mystic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0019</id>
    <name>Salvage Scout</name>
    <text>{W}, Sacrifice Salvage Scout: Return target artifact card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'm not saying it's dangerous work. I'm just saying don't sign up if you have plans for your seventieth birthday."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0020</id>
    <name>Seize the Initiative</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +1/+1 and gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The time between spotting a leonin shikari and feeling its claws is just time enough to draw your last breath.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0021</id>
    <name>Soul Parry</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage one or two target creatures would deal this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I was called to this world of steel, and it will be my steel that answers."
—Elspeth Tirel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0022</id>
    <name>Sunblast Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
When Sunblast Angel enters the battlefield, destroy all tapped creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>There may exist powers even greater than Phyrexia.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0023</id>
    <name>Sunspear Shikari</name>
    <text>As long as Sunspear Shikari is equipped, it has first strike and lifelink.</text>
    <flavorText>Left without their leader Raksha, the leonin split into two prides: one side supported the regent kha, while the other rebelled in fury.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0024</id>
    <name>Tempered Steel</name>
    <text>Artifact creatures you control get +2/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>"Death shall prevail as long as our will falls to rust. May necessity anneal our resolve."
—Ghalma the Shaper</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0025</id>
    <name>True Conviction</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have double strike and lifelink.</text>
    <flavorText>Dozens of spells known only to the Auriok elders were lost, but the next generation, galvanized by war, devised even more potent magic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0026</id>
    <name>Vigil for the Lost</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {X}. If you do, you gain X life.</text>
    <flavorText>"As she grew cold in my arms, I swore an oath that her funeral pyre would be dwarfed by a bonfire of our enemies."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0027</id>
    <name>Whitesun's Passage</name>
    <text>You gain 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>All over the Razor Fields, Whitesun is celebrated. Even the followers of the rebel Juryan, far from the Cave of Light, bow their heads in reverence.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0028</id>
    <name>Argent Sphinx</name>
    <text>Flying
Metalcraft — {U}: Exile Argent Sphinx. Return it to the battlefield under your control at the beginning of the next end step. Activate this ability only if you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>A great mirage, a dream of wings and silver.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0029</id>
    <name>Bonds of Quicksilver</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>The sea's reach extends beyond its shores.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0030</id>
    <name>Darkslick Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
When Darkslick Drake is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>At the edge of the Mephidross, Phyrexia's influence seeps into life and land.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0031</id>
    <name>Disperse</name>
    <text>Return target nonland permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Most casualties of the power struggle between vedalken and Neurok didn't die on the field of battle; they merely disappeared.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0032</id>
    <name>Dissipation Field</name>
    <text>Whenever a permanent deals damage to you, return it to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Strike me once, shame on you. Strike me twice . . . Well, let's just see if you can."
—Kara Vrist, Neurok agent</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0033</id>
    <name>Grand Architect</name>
    <text>Other blue creatures you control get +1/+1.
{U}: Target artifact creature becomes blue until end of turn.
Tap an untapped blue creature you control: Add {2} to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast artifact spells or activate abilities of artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0034</id>
    <name>Halt Order</name>
    <text>Counter target artifact spell.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>An artificer's least favorite mind-missive may be "I regret to inform you that the funding for your project has been cut."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0035</id>
    <name>Inexorable Tide</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a spell, proliferate. (You choose any number of permanents and/or players with counters on them, then give each another counter of a kind already there.)</text>
    <flavorText>"See how gratefully this world accepts our blessings."
—Jin-Gitaxias, Core Augur</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0036</id>
    <name>Lumengrid Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
Metalcraft — When Lumengrid Drake enters the battlefield, if you control three or more artifacts, return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Properly outfitted, drakes made perfect sentries for vedalken strongholds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0037</id>
    <name>Neurok Invisimancer</name>
    <text>Neurok Invisimancer is unblockable.
When Neurok Invisimancer enters the battlefield, target creature is unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"They won't see your shadow or hear your breath, but they will feel your blade."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0038</id>
    <name>Plated Seastrider</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The Neurok buried entangling cables just under the Quicksilver Sea. One seastrider harvest can provide an army's worth of armor and shields.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0039</id>
    <name>Quicksilver Gargantuan</name>
    <text>You may have Quicksilver Gargantuan enter the battlefield as a copy of any creature on the battlefield, except it's still 7/7.</text>
    <flavorText>"You know you have achieved true power if the sea itself seeks to emulate your greatness."
—Vy Covalt, Neurok agent</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0040</id>
    <name>Riddlesmith</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an artifact spell, you may draw a card. If you do, discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The Neurok see the artificer as an archaeologist, clearing away falsehoods to see the truth hidden beneath.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0041</id>
    <name>Scrapdiver Serpent</name>
    <text>Scrapdiver Serpent is unblockable as long as defending player controls an artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>Smart artificers clean up after themselves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0042</id>
    <name>Screeching Silcaw</name>
    <text>Flying
Metalcraft — Whenever Screeching Silcaw deals combat damage to a player, if you control three or more artifacts, that player puts the top four cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>It's adaptively deaf to its own cries.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0043</id>
    <name>Shape Anew</name>
    <text>The controller of target artifact sacrifices it, then reveals cards from the top of his or her library until he or she reveals an artifact card. That player puts that card onto the battlefield, then shuffles all other cards revealed this way into his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0044</id>
    <name>Sky-Eel School</name>
    <text>Flying
When Sky-Eel School enters the battlefield, draw a card, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>They swim on tides few can see, away from a threat few yet understand.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0045</id>
    <name>Steady Progress</name>
    <text>Proliferate. (You choose any number of permanents and/or players with counters on them, then give each another counter of a kind already there.)
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"More of that strange oil . . . It's probably nothing."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0046</id>
    <name>Stoic Rebuttal</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — Stoic Rebuttal costs {1} less to cast if you control three or more artifacts.
Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>Obsessed with the pursuit of knowledge above all else, vedalken can appear to be cold and emotionless.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0047</id>
    <name>Thrummingbird</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Thrummingbird deals combat damage to a player, proliferate. (You choose any number of permanents and/or players with counters on them, then give each another counter of a kind already there.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0048</id>
    <name>Trinket Mage</name>
    <text>When Trinket Mage enters the battlefield, you may search your library for an artifact card with converted mana cost 1 or less, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0049</id>
    <name>Turn Aside</name>
    <text>Counter target spell that targets a permanent you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's not my job to ask our leaders about their experiments at the Knowledge Pool. It's my job to make sure they can continue performing them."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0050</id>
    <name>Twisted Image</name>
    <text>Switch target creature's power and toughness until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"True strength is in the mind, for the body is too malleable a form."
—Politus, vedalken emisar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0051</id>
    <name>Vault Skyward</name>
    <text>Target creature gains flying until end of turn. Untap it.</text>
    <flavorText>"The edges of the Quicksilver Sea run dark with the spread of the Mephidross. Two more aerial passes before I can be sure what I'm seeing . . ."
—Lafarius, Neurok sky agent</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0052</id>
    <name>Vedalken Certarch</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — {T}: Tap target artifact, creature, or land. Activate this ability only if you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>"An appropriately detailed model is indistinguishable from reality, and much easier to control."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0053</id>
    <name>Volition Reins</name>
    <text>Enchant permanent
When Volition Reins enters the battlefield, if enchanted permanent is tapped, untap it.
You control enchanted permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"Glorifying the will is a mistake. It is simply one more force to be mastered."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0054</id>
    <name>Blackcleave Goblin</name>
    <text>Haste
Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Bitten? Save time, amputate now."
—Lephar, loxodon surgeon</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0055</id>
    <name>Bleak Coven Vampires</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — When Bleak Coven Vampires enters the battlefield, if you control three or more artifacts, target player loses 4 life and you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>As the shadow of the Mephidross spread over the Tangle, the vampires' territory expanded.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0056</id>
    <name>Blistergrub</name>
    <text>Swampwalk
When Blistergrub is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, each opponent loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The sooner you join Phyrexia, the sooner you'll forget your painful rebirth."
—Sheoldred, Whispering One</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0057</id>
    <name>Carnifex Demon</name>
    <text>Flying
Carnifex Demon enters the battlefield with two -1/-1 counters on it.
{B}, Remove a -1/-1 counter from Carnifex Demon: Put a -1/-1 counter on each other creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Every contagion has a host.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0058</id>
    <name>Contagious Nim</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>"This species has grown to be my preferred receptacle for our divine message."
—Sheoldred, Whispering One</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0059</id>
    <name>Corrupted Harvester</name>
    <text>{B}, Sacrifice a creature: Regenerate Corrupted Harvester.</text>
    <flavorText>"Before the blessed assault begins, we must seek specimens that are well-adapted to our way of . . . life."
—Sheoldred, Whispering One</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0060</id>
    <name>Dross Hopper</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: Dross Hopper gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Bred in the vicious Mephidross, dross hoppers learned to eat quickly and escape faster.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0061</id>
    <name>Exsanguinate</name>
    <text>Each opponent loses X life. You gain life equal to the life lost this way.</text>
    <flavorText>Vampires don't consider patience a virtue nor gluttony a sin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0062</id>
    <name>Flesh Allergy</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Flesh Allergy, sacrifice a creature.
Destroy target creature. Its controller loses life equal to the number of creatures put into all graveyards from the battlefield this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0063</id>
    <name>Fume Spitter</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Fume Spitter: Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our archers made sport of it as it fumbled its way up the slag ridge. As it collapsed we thought ourselves safe, but the foul thing carried more than necrogen."
—Adaran, Tangle hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0064</id>
    <name>Geth, Lord of the Vault</name>
    <text>Intimidate
{X}{B}: Put target artifact or creature card with converted mana cost X from an opponent's graveyard onto the battlefield under your control tapped. Then that player puts the top X cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0065</id>
    <name>Grasp of Darkness</name>
    <text>Target creature gets -4/-4 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>On a world with five suns, night is compelled to become an aggressive force.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0066</id>
    <name>Hand of the Praetors</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
Other creatures you control with infect get +1/+1.
Whenever you cast a creature spell with infect, target player gets a poison counter.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0067</id>
    <name>Ichor Rats</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
When Ichor Rats enters the battlefield, each player gets a poison counter.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0068</id>
    <name>Instill Infection</name>
    <text>Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"The results of our ninth inoculation were the same. The specimen was, of course, euthanized before the contagion could spread."
—Vedalken research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0069</id>
    <name>Memoricide</name>
    <text>Name a nonland card. Search target player's graveyard, hand, and library for any number of cards with that name and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>"You claim wisdom, yet I see nothing in here but tawdry wishes."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0070</id>
    <name>Moriok Reaver</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"The Moriok are fools. They try so hard to gain my favor. All I want is for them to die quickly, to join the ranks of the nim."
—Geth, Lord of the Vault</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0071</id>
    <name>Necrogen Scudder</name>
    <text>Flying
When Necrogen Scudder enters the battlefield, you lose 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Contrary to popular belief, it's kept aloft by necrogen gas, not the screaming agony of a thousand murdered souls.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0072</id>
    <name>Necrotic Ooze</name>
    <text>As long as Necrotic Ooze is on the battlefield, it has all activated abilities of all creature cards in all graveyards.</text>
    <flavorText>"To death all must go, and so in death lies ultimate power."
—Geth, Lord of the Vault</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0073</id>
    <name>Painful Quandary</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a spell, that player loses 5 life unless he or she discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"For each word spoken, one forgotten. For each thought, a memory rotten."
—Moriok incantation</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0074</id>
    <name>Painsmith</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an artifact spell, you may have target creature get +2/+0 and gain deathtouch until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Moriok see the artificer as a taskmaster, forcing lazy metal into more potent shapes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0075</id>
    <name>Plague Stinger</name>
    <text>Flying
Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>It leaves its victims one sting closer to phyresis.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0076</id>
    <name>Psychic Miasma</name>
    <text>Target player discards a card. If a land card is discarded this way, return Psychic Miasma to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"A mind may be steeled against madness, but all battlements fall in time."
—Jin-Gitaxias, Core Augur</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0077</id>
    <name>Relic Putrescence</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact
Whenever enchanted artifact becomes tapped, its controller gets a poison counter.</text>
    <flavorText>"Until we shed the curse of sentience, we must endure its grotesque handiwork."
—Vorinclex, Voice of Hunger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0078</id>
    <name>Skinrender</name>
    <text>When Skinrender enters the battlefield, put three -1/-1 counters on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your creations are effective, Sheoldred, but we must unite the flesh, not merely flay it."
—Elesh Norn, Grand Cenobite</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0079</id>
    <name>Skithiryx, the Blight Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
{B}: Skithiryx, the Blight Dragon gains haste until end of turn.
{B}{B}: Regenerate Skithiryx.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0080</id>
    <name>Tainted Strike</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +1/+0 and gains infect until end of turn. (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Welcome to perfection."
—Sheoldred, Whispering One</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0081</id>
    <name>Arc Trail</name>
    <text>Arc Trail deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to another target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Don't try to hit your enemies. Concentrate on the space between them, and fill the air with doom."
—Spear-Tribe teaching</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0082</id>
    <name>Assault Strobe</name>
    <text>Target creature gains double strike until end of turn. (It deals both first-strike and regular combat damage.)</text>
    <flavorText>When breaking someone's face once just isn't enough.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0083</id>
    <name>Barrage Ogre</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice an artifact: Barrage Ogre deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>The elves had devised countless strategies to combat Memnarch's war machines, but they had no idea what to do when one was thrown at them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0084</id>
    <name>Blade-Tribe Berserkers</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — When Blade-Tribe Berserkers enters the battlefield, if you control three or more artifacts, Blade-Tribe Berserkers gets +3/+3 and gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0085</id>
    <name>Bloodshot Trainee</name>
    <text>{T}: Bloodshot Trainee deals 4 damage to target creature. Activate this ability only if Bloodshot Trainee's power is 4 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>"Just think how strong I'll be if my arms don't tear off!"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0086</id>
    <name>Cerebral Eruption</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals the top card of his or her library. Cerebral Eruption deals damage equal to the revealed card's converted mana cost to that player and each creature he or she controls. If a land card is revealed this way, return Cerebral Eruption to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0087</id>
    <name>Embersmith</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an artifact spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, Embersmith deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>The Vulshok see the artificer as a catalyst, bringing the spark of creation that ignites change.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0088</id>
    <name>Ferrovore</name>
    <text>{R}, Sacrifice an artifact: Ferrovore gets +3/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Vulshok use its digestion to break down the most obstinate metals, from darksteel myr to seastrider plates.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0089</id>
    <name>Flameborn Hellion</name>
    <text>Haste
Flameborn Hellion attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>"The most reliable omen of a future hellion attack is a past hellion attack."
—Spear-Tribe teaching</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0090</id>
    <name>Furnace Celebration</name>
    <text>Whenever you sacrifice another permanent, you may pay {2}. If you do, Furnace Celebration deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Reduce. Reuse. Wreak havoc.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0091</id>
    <name>Galvanic Blast</name>
    <text>Galvanic Blast deals 2 damage to target creature or player.
Metalcraft — Galvanic Blast deals 4 damage to that creature or player instead if you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>Mirrodin has little weather, but it certainly has lightning.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0092</id>
    <name>Goblin Gaveleer</name>
    <text>Trample
Goblin Gaveleer gets +2/+0 for each Equipment attached to it.</text>
    <flavorText>"When everything looks like a nail, you really need to get yourself a hammer."
—Krol, goblin furnace-priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0093</id>
    <name>Hoard-Smelter Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
{3}{R}: Destroy target artifact. Hoard-Smelter Dragon gets +X/+0 until end of turn, where X is that artifact's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>He collects the precious metals, and then converts the rest to propellant.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0094</id>
    <name>Koth of the Hammer</name>
    <text>+1: Untap target Mountain. It becomes a 4/4 red Elemental creature until end of turn. It's still a land.
-2: Add {R} to your mana pool for each Mountain you control.
-5: You get an emblem with "Mountains you control have ‘{T}: This land deals 1 damage to target creature or player.'"</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0095</id>
    <name>Kuldotha Phoenix</name>
    <text>Flying, haste
Metalcraft — {4}: Return Kuldotha Phoenix from your graveyard to the battlefield. Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only if you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0096</id>
    <name>Kuldotha Rebirth</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Kuldotha Rebirth, sacrifice an artifact.
Put three 1/1 red Goblin creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>All goblin rituals serve a dual purpose as fertility rites, even the destructive ones. Especially the destructive ones.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0097</id>
    <name>Melt Terrain</name>
    <text>Destroy target land. Melt Terrain deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>Just as the most finely wrought metal can warp and rust, so too does Mirrodin buckle under pressures from without and within.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0098</id>
    <name>Molten Psyche</name>
    <text>Each player shuffles the cards from his or her hand into his or her library, then draws that many cards.
Metalcraft — If you control three or more artifacts, Molten Psyche deals damage to each opponent equal to the number of cards that player has drawn this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0099</id>
    <name>Ogre Geargrabber</name>
    <text>Whenever Ogre Geargrabber attacks, gain control of target Equipment an opponent controls until end of turn. Attach it to Ogre Geargrabber. When you lose control of that Equipment, unattach it.</text>
    <flavorText>Long reach, short attention span.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0100</id>
    <name>Oxidda Daredevil</name>
    <text>Sacrifice an artifact: Oxidda Daredevil gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>His goggles spattered with grime and his mouth full of bugs, he tossed the engines another priceless relic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0101</id>
    <name>Oxidda Scrapmelter</name>
    <text>When Oxidda Scrapmelter enters the battlefield, destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>It subsists on a diet rich in screaming metal and molten blood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0102</id>
    <name>Scoria Elemental</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>A single molten cord links it to the subterranean furnaces, drawing heat and metal from beneath Kuldotha. Until that bond is cut, it carves a swath of raw destruction.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0103</id>
    <name>Shatter</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>"I am an artist, a builder, a creator . . . I create the biggest explosions around."
—Krol, goblin furnace-priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0104</id>
    <name>Spikeshot Elder</name>
    <text>{1}{R}{R}: Spikeshot Elder deals damage equal to its power to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Now that he knows a thousand ways of hurting people, his next shamanic quest is to discover a thousand more.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0105</id>
    <name>Tunnel Ignus</name>
    <text>Whenever a land enters the battlefield under an opponent's control, if that player had another land enter the battlefield under his or her control this turn, Tunnel Ignus deals 3 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>Fight mischief with mischief.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0106</id>
    <name>Turn to Slag</name>
    <text>Turn to Slag deals 5 damage to target creature. Destroy all Equipment attached to that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"If it wasn't a blackened, stinking, melted abomination before, it certainly is now."
—Koth of the Hammer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0107</id>
    <name>Vulshok Heartstoker</name>
    <text>When Vulshok Heartstoker enters the battlefield, target creature gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>He fashions stirring words with as much passion as a smith fashioning a warhammer.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0108</id>
    <name>Acid Web Spider</name>
    <text>Reach
When Acid Web Spider enters the battlefield, you may destroy target Equipment.</text>
    <flavorText>Its web is an excellent source of found copper for the daring or the stupid.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0109</id>
    <name>Alpha Tyrranax</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Hunger seized the tyrranax, and the Sylvok's vision quest ended in disaster.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0110</id>
    <name>Asceticism</name>
    <text>Creatures you control can't be the targets of spells or abilities your opponents control.
{1}{G}: Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let my ignominy build walls thicker than iron and stronger than darksteel."
—Thrun, the last troll</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0111</id>
    <name>Bellowing Tanglewurm</name>
    <text>Intimidate (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or creatures that share a color with it.)
Other green creatures you control have intimidate.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0112</id>
    <name>Blight Mamba</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
{1}{G}: Regenerate Blight Mamba.</text>
    <flavorText>Its venom drips with Phyrexia's hate.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0113</id>
    <name>Blunt the Assault</name>
    <text>You gain 1 life for each creature on the battlefield. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Much can be gained from the appearance of vulnerability."
—Ezuri, renegade leader</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0114</id>
    <name>Carapace Forger</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — Carapace Forger gets +2/+2 as long as you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>"Bows and whips cannot save us from these new horrors of the Mephidross."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0115</id>
    <name>Carrion Call</name>
    <text>Put two 1/1 green Insect creature tokens with infect onto the battlefield. (They deal damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>The natural order is out of order.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0116</id>
    <name>Copperhorn Scout</name>
    <text>Whenever Copperhorn Scout attacks, untap each other creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Fangren spur may sound louder, but Viridian resurgents claim that the horn of the vorrac creates a truer, more inspiring note.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0117</id>
    <name>Cystbearer</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>Phyrexia strives to simulate natural life, but it can't resist improving on the design.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0118</id>
    <name>Engulfing Slagwurm</name>
    <text>Whenever Engulfing Slagwurm blocks or becomes blocked by a creature, destroy that creature. You gain life equal to that creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>Its teeth exist only for decoration.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0119</id>
    <name>Ezuri, Renegade Leader</name>
    <text>{G}: Regenerate another target Elf.
{2}{G}{G}{G}: Elf creatures you control get +3/+3 and gain trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The infamous Ezuri commands the highest bounty the vedalken have ever placed upon an outlaw.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0120</id>
    <name>Ezuri's Archers</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)
Whenever Ezuri's Archers blocks a creature with flying, Ezuri's Archers gets +3/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0121</id>
    <name>Ezuri's Brigade</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — As long as you control three or more artifacts, Ezuri's Brigade gets +4/+4 and has trample.</text>
    <flavorText>Riding ravenous, ever-growing vorracs is almost as dangerous as fitting them with saddles.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0122</id>
    <name>Genesis Wave</name>
    <text>Reveal the top X cards of your library. You may put any number of permanent cards with converted mana cost X or less from among them onto the battlefield. Then put all cards revealed this way that weren't put onto the battlefield into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0123</id>
    <name>Liege of the Tangle</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Liege of the Tangle deals combat damage to a player, you may choose any number of target lands you control and put an awakening counter on each of them. Each of those lands is an 8/8 green Elemental creature for as long as it has an awakening counter on it. They're still lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0124</id>
    <name>Lifesmith</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an artifact spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The Sylvok see the artificer as a gardener, preparing the world for hardy growth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0125</id>
    <name>Molder Beast</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever an artifact is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, Molder Beast gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"A trail of scrap metal can lead it into an ambush. But take care not to overfeed it."
—Adaran, Tangle hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0126</id>
    <name>Putrefax</name>
    <text>Trample, haste
Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice Putrefax.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0127</id>
    <name>Slice in Twain</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"The hypocrisy of these elves is thicker than steel—destroying ‘unnatural metal' with their own enchanted swords."
—Kara Vrist, Neurok agent</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0128</id>
    <name>Tangle Angler</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
{G}: Target creature blocks Tangle Angler this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>A plague on the curious.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0129</id>
    <name>Tel-Jilad Defiance</name>
    <text>Target creature gains protection from artifacts until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The Viridian elves had purged their culture of the trolls' traitorous influence. In times of strife, however, the ancestral memories returned.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0130</id>
    <name>Tel-Jilad Fallen</name>
    <text>Protection from artifacts
Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>"No longer am I shackled to antiquity. My new masters will etch a glorious future."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0131</id>
    <name>Untamed Might</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +X/+X until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Beasts kill for their very survival. If you would have their strength, you must know their desperation."
—Konnos, Sylvok sage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0132</id>
    <name>Viridian Revel</name>
    <text>Whenever an artifact is put into an opponent's graveyard from the battlefield, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let them have their revel. Soon those who won't submit will be turned. Those who won't be turned will die."
—Vorinclex, Voice of Hunger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0133</id>
    <name>Wing Puncture</name>
    <text>Target creature you control deals damage equal to its power to target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"If I were the air, I wouldn't taunt the ground. It has the weight advantage."
—Konnos, Sylvok sage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0134</id>
    <name>Withstand Death</name>
    <text>Target creature is indestructible this turn. (Lethal damage and effects that say "destroy" don't destroy it. If its toughness is 0 or less, it's still put into its owner's graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>On Mirrodin, every conflict ends in either death or darksteel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0135</id>
    <name>Venser, the Sojourner</name>
    <text>+2: Exile target permanent you own. Return it to the battlefield under your control at the beginning of the next end step.
-1: Creatures are unblockable this turn.
-8: You get an emblem with "Whenever you cast a spell, exile target permanent."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0136</id>
    <name>Accorder's Shield</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +0/+3 and has vigilance.
Equip {3}</text>
    <flavorText>An Auriok shield is polished to a mirror finish even on the inside, enabling its bearer to watch foes ahead and behind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0137</id>
    <name>Argentum Armor</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +6/+6.
Whenever equipped creature attacks, destroy target permanent.
Equip {6}</text>
    <flavorText>Mirrodin's creator still lives, still shapes metal, and still commands world-shaking power.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0138</id>
    <name>Auriok Replica</name>
    <text>{W}, Sacrifice Auriok Replica: Prevent all damage a source of your choice would deal to you this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>All the loyalty of the Auriok with only a trace of their self-righteousness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0139</id>
    <name>Barbed Battlegear</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +4/-1.
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>"One need only look at the inhabitants of this world to see that they are forged halfway to perfection. All they need is a whisper of the Glorious Word."
—Urabrask the Hidden</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0140</id>
    <name>Bladed Pinions</name>
    <text>Equipped creature has flying and first strike.
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>Lacking trained pterons, the Auriok had to rely on other measures to gain the upper hand in the skies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0141</id>
    <name>Chimeric Mass</name>
    <text>Chimeric Mass enters the battlefield with X charge counters on it.
{1}: Until end of turn, Chimeric Mass becomes a Construct artifact creature with "This creature's power and toughness are each equal to the number of charge counters on it."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0142</id>
    <name>Chrome Steed</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — Chrome Steed gets +2/+2 as long as you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>According to Auriok myth, it collects scrap in order to reassemble its lost rider.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0143</id>
    <name>Clone Shell</name>
    <text>Imprint — When Clone Shell enters the battlefield, look at the top four cards of your library, exile one face down, then put the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.
When Clone Shell is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, turn the exiled card face up. If it's a creature card, put it onto the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0144</id>
    <name>Contagion Clasp</name>
    <text>When Contagion Clasp enters the battlefield, put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.
{4}, {T}: Proliferate. (You choose any number of permanents and/or players with counters on them, then give each another counter of a kind already there.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0145</id>
    <name>Contagion Engine</name>
    <text>When Contagion Engine enters the battlefield, put a -1/-1 counter on each creature target player controls.
{4}, {T}: Proliferate, then proliferate again. (You choose any number of permanents and/or players with counters on them, then give each another counter of a kind already there. Then do it again.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0146</id>
    <name>Copper Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The myr are like verdigris: an ever-present patina on the surface of a metal world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0147</id>
    <name>Corpse Cur</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
When Corpse Cur enters the battlefield, you may return target creature card with infect from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0148</id>
    <name>Culling Dais</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a creature: Put a charge counter on Culling Dais.
{1}, Sacrifice Culling Dais: Draw a card for each charge counter on Culling Dais.</text>
    <flavorText>"Forswear the flesh and you will truly see."
—Jin-Gitaxias, Core Augur</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0149</id>
    <name>Darksteel Axe</name>
    <text>Darksteel Axe is indestructible. (Effects that say "destroy" don't destroy it.)
Equipped creature gets +2/+0.
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>Heavier than it looks, tricky to wield, guaranteed to last.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0150</id>
    <name>Darksteel Juggernaut</name>
    <text>Darksteel Juggernaut's power and toughness are each equal to the number of artifacts you control.
Darksteel Juggernaut is indestructible and attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>One part unstoppable force, one part immovable object.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0151</id>
    <name>Darksteel Myr</name>
    <text>Darksteel Myr is indestructible. (Lethal damage and effects that say "destroy" don't destroy it. If its toughness is 0 or less, it's still put into its owner's graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0152</id>
    <name>Darksteel Sentinel</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
Vigilance
Darksteel Sentinel is indestructible. (Lethal damage and effects that say "destroy" don't destroy it. If its toughness is 0 or less, it's still put into its owner's graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0153</id>
    <name>Echo Circlet</name>
    <text>Equipped creature can block an additional creature.
Equip {1}</text>
    <flavorText>After the vanishing of the elder generations, the Anvil Tribe developed creative solutions to their personnel shortages.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0154</id>
    <name>Etched Champion</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — Etched Champion has protection from all colors as long as you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>Its predecessors were etched with the wisdom of ancients; its own etchings bear warnings of a future fraught with war.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0155</id>
    <name>Flight Spellbomb</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Flight Spellbomb: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.
When Flight Spellbomb is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {U}. If you do, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0156</id>
    <name>Glint Hawk Idol</name>
    <text>Whenever another artifact enters the battlefield under your control, you may have Glint Hawk Idol become a 2/2 Bird artifact creature with flying until end of turn.
{W}: Glint Hawk Idol becomes a 2/2 Bird artifact creature with flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0157</id>
    <name>Gold Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The myr are like razorgrass: numberless metal figures, reflecting each other's light.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0158</id>
    <name>Golden Urn</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a charge counter on Golden Urn.
{T}, Sacrifice Golden Urn: You gain life equal to the number of charge counters on Golden Urn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0159</id>
    <name>Golem Artisan</name>
    <text>{2}: Target artifact creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
{2}: Target artifact creature gains your choice of flying, trample, or haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Better living through metallurgy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0160</id>
    <name>Golem Foundry</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an artifact spell, you may put a charge counter on Golem Foundry.
Remove three charge counters from Golem Foundry: Put a 3/3 colorless Golem artifact creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0161</id>
    <name>Golem's Heart</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts an artifact spell, you may gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The heart of a golem gives life to more than just the iron husk around it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0162</id>
    <name>Grafted Exoskeleton</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +2/+2 and has infect. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
Whenever Grafted Exoskeleton becomes unattached from a permanent, sacrifice that permanent.
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0163</id>
    <name>Grindclock</name>
    <text>{T}: Put a charge counter on Grindclock.
{T}: Target player puts the top X cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard, where X is the number of charge counters on Grindclock.</text>
    <flavorText>Pray you never hear it chime.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0164</id>
    <name>Heavy Arbalest</name>
    <text>Equipped creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.
Equipped creature has "{T}: This creature deals 2 damage to target creature or player."
Equip {4}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0165</id>
    <name>Horizon Spellbomb</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Horizon Spellbomb: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.
When Horizon Spellbomb is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {G}. If you do, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0166</id>
    <name>Ichorclaw Myr</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
Whenever Ichorclaw Myr becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0167</id>
    <name>Infiltration Lens</name>
    <text>Whenever equipped creature becomes blocked by a creature, you may draw two cards.
Equip {1}</text>
    <flavorText>Neurok spies carry devices that let them look a few moments into the future, giving them an almost insurmountable edge.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0168</id>
    <name>Iron Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The myr are like rusted metal: gleaming purpose hidden by a thin disguise of debris.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0169</id>
    <name>Kuldotha Forgemaster</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice three artifacts: Search your library for an artifact card and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The goblins say it used to be larger, before it began to stoke the Great Furnace with pieces of itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0170</id>
    <name>Leaden Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The myr are like necrogen: a transformative force unconcerned with the changes they wreak.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0171</id>
    <name>Liquimetal Coating</name>
    <text>{T}: Target permanent becomes an artifact in addition to its other types until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"They'll soon become accustomed to wearing skin that is not their own."
—Elesh Norn, Grand Cenobite</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0172</id>
    <name>Livewire Lash</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +2/+0 and has "Whenever this creature becomes the target of a spell, this creature deals 2 damage to target creature or player."
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0173</id>
    <name>Lux Cannon</name>
    <text>{T}: Put a charge counter on Lux Cannon.
{T}, Remove three charge counters from Lux Cannon: Destroy target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>There are few problems that can't be solved by putting a hole in the world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0174</id>
    <name>Memnite</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Reminders of Memnarch's reign still skirr across Mirrodin, reminiscent of his form if not his power.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0175</id>
    <name>Mimic Vat</name>
    <text>Imprint — Whenever a nontoken creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may exile that card. If you do, return each other card exiled with Mimic Vat to its owner's graveyard.
{3}, {T}: Put a token onto the battlefield that's a copy of the exiled card. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0176</id>
    <name>Mindslaver</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}, Sacrifice Mindslaver: You control target player during that player's next turn. (You see all cards that player could see and make all decisions for the player.)</text>
    <flavorText>It's a helm that leaves the head at its most vulnerable.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0177</id>
    <name>Molten-Tail Masticore</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Molten-Tail Masticore unless you discard a card.
{4}, Exile a creature card from your graveyard: Molten-Tail Masticore deals 4 damage to target creature or player.
{2}: Regenerate Molten-Tail Masticore.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0178</id>
    <name>Moriok Replica</name>
    <text>{1}{B}, Sacrifice Moriok Replica: You draw two cards and lose 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>All the secrets of the Moriok with only a trace of their corruption.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0179</id>
    <name>Mox Opal</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. Activate this ability only if you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>The suns of Mirrodin have shone upon perfection only once.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0180</id>
    <name>Myr Battlesphere</name>
    <text>When Myr Battlesphere enters the battlefield, put four 1/1 colorless Myr artifact creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Whenever Myr Battlesphere attacks, you may tap X untapped Myr you control. If you do, Myr Battlesphere gets +X/+0 until end of turn and deals X damage to defending player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0181</id>
    <name>Myr Galvanizer</name>
    <text>Other Myr creatures you control get +1/+1.
{1}, {T}: Untap each other Myr you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"We can't quite determine what they're doing, but they seem to be doing it quite well."
—Vedalken research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0182</id>
    <name>Myr Propagator</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Put a token that's a copy of Myr Propagator onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"We will ingest and remake this world in our image, not unlike some admirable designs I have seen here."
—Vorinclex, Voice of Hunger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0183</id>
    <name>Myr Reservoir</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {2} to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast Myr spells or activate abilities of Myr.
{3}, {T}: Return target Myr card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>A mana well as bottomless as the myr are tireless.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0184</id>
    <name>Necrogen Censer</name>
    <text>Necrogen Censer enters the battlefield with two charge counters on it.
{T}, Remove a charge counter from Necrogen Censer: Target player loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Moriok necromancers actively spread necrogen, encouraging the transformation from Mirran to nim.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0185</id>
    <name>Necropede</name>
    <text>Infect (This creature deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)
When Necropede is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0186</id>
    <name>Neurok Replica</name>
    <text>{1}{U}, Sacrifice Neurok Replica: Return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>All the curiosity of the Neurok with only a trace of their duplicity.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0187</id>
    <name>Nihil Spellbomb</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Nihil Spellbomb: Exile all cards from target player's graveyard.
When Nihil Spellbomb is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {B}. If you do, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0188</id>
    <name>Nim Deathmantle</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +2/+2, has intimidate, and is a black Zombie.
Whenever a nontoken creature is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {4}. If you do, return that card to the battlefield and attach Nim Deathmantle to it.
Equip {4}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0189</id>
    <name>Origin Spellbomb</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Origin Spellbomb: Put a 1/1 colorless Myr artifact creature token onto the battlefield.
When Origin Spellbomb is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {W}. If you do, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0190</id>
    <name>Palladium Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {2} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The myr are like the Glimmervoid: blank canvases on which to build grand creations.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0191</id>
    <name>Panic Spellbomb</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Panic Spellbomb: Target creature can't block this turn.
When Panic Spellbomb is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {R}. If you do, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0192</id>
    <name>Perilous Myr</name>
    <text>When Perilous Myr is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, it deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>To Mirrodin, an explosive. To Phyrexia, a missionary.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0193</id>
    <name>Platinum Emperion</name>
    <text>Your life total can't change. (You can't gain or lose life. You can't pay any amount of life except 0.)</text>
    <flavorText>It ignores such insignificant forces as time, entropy, and death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0194</id>
    <name>Precursor Golem</name>
    <text>When Precursor Golem enters the battlefield, put two 3/3 colorless Golem artifact creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Whenever a player casts an instant or sorcery spell that targets only a single Golem, that player copies that spell for each other Golem that spell could target. Each copy targets a different one of those Golems.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0195</id>
    <name>Prototype Portal</name>
    <text>Imprint — When Prototype Portal enters the battlefield, you may exile an artifact card from your hand.
{X}, {T}: Put a token that's a copy of the exiled card onto the battlefield. X is the converted mana cost of that card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0196</id>
    <name>Ratchet Bomb</name>
    <text>{T}: Put a charge counter on Ratchet Bomb.
{T}, Sacrifice Ratchet Bomb: Destroy each nonland permanent with converted mana cost equal to the number of charge counters on Ratchet Bomb.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0197</id>
    <name>Razorfield Thresher</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>DANGER! Keep appendages clear of front of machine. And rear of machine. And side of machine. And top of machine.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0198</id>
    <name>Rust Tick</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Rust Tick during your untap step.
{1}, {T}: Tap target artifact. It doesn't untap during its controller's untap step for as long as Rust Tick remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0199</id>
    <name>Rusted Relic</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — Rusted Relic is a 5/5 Golem artifact creature as long as you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>"We consider rust a curable disease."
—Tarrin, Hammer-Tribe shaman</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0200</id>
    <name>Saberclaw Golem</name>
    <text>{R}: Saberclaw Golem gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The warriors of the Blade Tribe charged the golem, twenty strong. They returned numbering ten . . . and a half.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0201</id>
    <name>Semblance Anvil</name>
    <text>Imprint — When Semblance Anvil enters the battlefield, you may exile a nonland card from your hand.
Spells you cast that share a card type with the exiled card cost {2} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>Forged from what it forges.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0202</id>
    <name>Silver Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The myr are like quicksilver: malleable in function and adaptable in form.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0203</id>
    <name>Snapsail Glider</name>
    <text>Metalcraft — Snapsail Glider has flying as long as you control three or more artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>Built from a reconfigured thresher, it charges with light reflected off the golden plain, ready to take to the air in case of danger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0204</id>
    <name>Soliton</name>
    <text>{U}: Untap Soliton.</text>
    <flavorText>The gemini engines had lost connection with each other and wandered apart, developing an independent awareness of their surroundings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0205</id>
    <name>Steel Hellkite</name>
    <text>Flying
{2}: Steel Hellkite gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
{X}: Destroy each nonland permanent with converted mana cost X whose controller was dealt combat damage by Steel Hellkite this turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0206</id>
    <name>Strata Scythe</name>
    <text>Imprint — When Strata Scythe enters the battlefield, search your library for a land card, exile it, then shuffle your library.
Equipped creature gets +1/+1 for each land on the battlefield with the same name as the exiled card.
Equip {3}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0207</id>
    <name>Strider Harness</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +1/+1 and has haste.
Equip {1}</text>
    <flavorText>Each journey begins with a single step—and sometimes ends with that single step as well.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0208</id>
    <name>Sword of Body and Mind</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +2/+2 and has protection from green and from blue.
Whenever equipped creature deals combat damage to a player, you put a 2/2 green Wolf creature token onto the battlefield and that player puts the top ten cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0209</id>
    <name>Sylvok Lifestaff</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +1/+0.
Whenever equipped creature is put into a graveyard, you gain 3 life.
Equip {1}</text>
    <flavorText>The druid's lifestaff connects her to generations of bygone Sylvok.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0210</id>
    <name>Sylvok Replica</name>
    <text>{G}, Sacrifice Sylvok Replica: Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>All the zeal of the Sylvok with only a trace of their conservancy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0211</id>
    <name>Throne of Geth</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice an artifact: Proliferate. (You choose any number of permanents and/or players with counters on them, then give each another counter of a kind already there.)</text>
    <flavorText>At the heart of Ish Sah, Geth stokes the dark fires of Phyrexia.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0212</id>
    <name>Tower of Calamities</name>
    <text>{8}, {T}: Tower of Calamities deals 12 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The ur-golems concealed one of their towers out of fear that its power would be abused, and in anticipation of a time when its power would be sorely needed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0213</id>
    <name>Trigon of Corruption</name>
    <text>Trigon of Corruption enters the battlefield with three charge counters on it.
{B}{B}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Trigon of Corruption.
{2}, {T}, Remove a charge counter from Trigon of Corruption: Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0214</id>
    <name>Trigon of Infestation</name>
    <text>Trigon of Infestation enters the battlefield with three charge counters on it.
{G}{G}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Trigon of Infestation.
{2}, {T}, Remove a charge counter from Trigon of Infestation: Put a 1/1 green Insect creature token with infect onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0215</id>
    <name>Trigon of Mending</name>
    <text>Trigon of Mending enters the battlefield with three charge counters on it.
{W}{W}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Trigon of Mending.
{2}, {T}, Remove a charge counter from Trigon of Mending: Target player gains 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0216</id>
    <name>Trigon of Rage</name>
    <text>Trigon of Rage enters the battlefield with three charge counters on it.
{R}{R}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Trigon of Rage.
{2}, {T}, Remove a charge counter from Trigon of Rage: Target creature gets +3/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0217</id>
    <name>Trigon of Thought</name>
    <text>Trigon of Thought enters the battlefield with three charge counters on it.
{U}{U}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Trigon of Thought.
{2}, {T}, Remove a charge counter from Trigon of Thought: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0218</id>
    <name>Tumble Magnet</name>
    <text>Tumble Magnet enters the battlefield with three charge counters on it.
{T}, Remove a charge counter from Tumble Magnet: Tap target artifact or creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Magnetic devices that keep massive golems and structures standing can also be used for the opposite purpose.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0219</id>
    <name>Vector Asp</name>
    <text>{B}: Vector Asp gains infect until end of turn. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters and to players in the form of poison counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>Phyrexia's machines take inspiration from nature. Twisted, disturbing inspiration.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0220</id>
    <name>Venser's Journal</name>
    <text>You have no maximum hand size.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you gain 1 life for each card in your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>A Planeswalker's chronicle spans worlds and civilizations, each page a lifetime.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0221</id>
    <name>Vulshok Replica</name>
    <text>{1}{R}, Sacrifice Vulshok Replica: Vulshok Replica deals 3 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>All the fury of the Vulshok with only a trace of their recklessness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0222</id>
    <name>Wall of Tanglecord</name>
    <text>Defender
{G}: Wall of Tanglecord gains reach until end of turn. (It can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>Rootlike fibers travel far from Mirrodin's metallic forests, emerging from the crust to drink in the mana-infused sunlight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0223</id>
    <name>Wurmcoil Engine</name>
    <text>Deathtouch, lifelink
When Wurmcoil Engine is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a 3/3 colorless Wurm artifact creature token with deathtouch and a 3/3 colorless Wurm artifact creature token with lifelink onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0224</id>
    <name>Blackcleave Cliffs</name>
    <text>Blackcleave Cliffs enters the battlefield tapped unless you control two or fewer other lands.
{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Where the Oxidda Chain mingles with the Mephidross, oil-suffused metal crumbles away, leaving walls of blackened bones.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0225</id>
    <name>Copperline Gorge</name>
    <text>Copperline Gorge enters the battlefield tapped unless you control two or fewer other lands.
{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Where the Tangle overruns the Oxidda mountains, metallic beasts scratch their territories in the verdigris.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0226</id>
    <name>Darkslick Shores</name>
    <text>Darkslick Shores enters the battlefield tapped unless you control two or fewer other lands.
{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Where the Mephidross leaches into the Quicksilver Sea, the waves writhe with necrogen.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0227</id>
    <name>Glimmerpost</name>
    <text>When Glimmerpost enters the battlefield, you gain 1 life for each Locus on the battlefield.
{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>What once spied upon Mirrodin from above now waits below for another to assume control.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0228</id>
    <name>Razorverge Thicket</name>
    <text>Razorverge Thicket enters the battlefield tapped unless you control two or fewer other lands.
{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Where the Razor Fields beat back the Tangle, the crowded thicket yields to bright scimitars of grass.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0229</id>
    <name>Seachrome Coast</name>
    <text>Seachrome Coast enters the battlefield tapped unless you control two or fewer other lands.
{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Where the Quicksilver Sea laps over the Razor Fields, the landscape reflects the suns' fading hope.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0230</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0231</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0232</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0233</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0234</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0235</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0236</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0237</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0238</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0239</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0240</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0241</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0242</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0243</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0244</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0245</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0246</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0247</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0248</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SOM0249</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>