<cards name="Tempest">
  <item>
    <id>TMP0001</id>
    <name>Abandon Hope</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Abandon Hope, discard X cards.
Look at target opponent's hand and choose X cards from it. That player discards those cards.</text>
    <flavorText>As Gerrard's form vanished into the maw of trees, Hanna mouthed a silent plea, mourning a crushed dream.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0002</id>
    <name>Advance Scout</name>
    <text>First strike
{W}: Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The soldier's path is worn smooth by the tread of many feet—all in one direction, none returning."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0003</id>
    <name>Aftershock</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact, creature, or land. Aftershock deals 3 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"Every act of destruction has a repercussion."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0004</id>
    <name>Altar of Dementia</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: Target player puts a number of cards equal to the sacrificed creature's power from the top of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is not that you will go mad. It is that you will beg for madness."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0005</id>
    <name>Aluren</name>
    <text>Any player may play creature cards with converted mana cost 3 or less without paying their mana cost and as though they had flash.</text>
    <flavorText>Squee bounced up and down. "I sees a horsey, an' a piggy, an' a—"
"If you don't shut up," hissed Mirri, "you'll see a kidney and a spleeny."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0006</id>
    <name>Ancient Runes</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Ancient Runes deals damage to that player equal to the number of artifacts he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Ertai volunteered to open the portal. He figured he owed it one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0007</id>
    <name>Ancient Tomb</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {2} to your mana pool. Ancient Tomb deals 2 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>There is no glory to be gained in the kingdom of the dead.
—Vec tomb inscription</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0008</id>
    <name>Angelic Protector</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Angelic Protector becomes the target of a spell or ability, Angelic Protector gets +0/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"My family sheltered in her light, the dark was content to wait."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0009</id>
    <name>Anoint</name>
    <text>Buyback {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0010</id>
    <name>Apes of Rath</name>
    <text>Whenever Apes of Rath attacks, it doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>Monkeys three, monkeys through.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0011</id>
    <name>Apocalypse</name>
    <text>Exile all permanents. You discard your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is a future in which I can see only mist and a single shadow."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0012</id>
    <name>Armor Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have "{2}: This creature gets +0/+1 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>Hanna: "We must learn how they protect each other."
Mirri: "After they've done trying to kill us, all right?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0013</id>
    <name>Armored Pegasus</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"I always charge a little extra to take on a pegasus. They fly like eagles, kick like mules, and hide like hermits."
—Tahli en-Dal, bounty hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0014</id>
    <name>Auratog</name>
    <text>Sacrifice an enchantment: Auratog gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The auratog enjoys eating its wards.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0015</id>
    <name>Avenging Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
When Avenging Angel is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may put Avenging Angel on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0016</id>
    <name>Barbed Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have "{2}: This creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>Spans of spines leapt from one sliver to the next, forming a deadly hedge around the Weatherlight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0017</id>
    <name>Bayou Dragonfly</name>
    <text>Flying, swampwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Like a sugar stick with wings"
—Squee, goblin cabin hand</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0018</id>
    <name>Bellowing Fiend</name>
    <text>Flying

Whenever Bellowing Fiend deals damage to a creature, Bellowing Fiend deals 3 damage to that creature's controller and 3 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0019</id>
    <name>Benthic Behemoth</name>
    <text>Islandwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Deep devourer   concealed in darkhome
Shrouded it seeks   all becomes fodder
Once we swam   alone and asea
But no more."
—Rootwater Saga</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0020</id>
    <name>Blood Frenzy</name>
    <text>Cast Blood Frenzy only before the combat damage step.
Target attacking or blocking creature gets +4/+0 until end of turn. Destroy that creature at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>"When Torahn bellows, none survive—not even the warrior whose horns he rides."
—Talruum adage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0021</id>
    <name>Blood Pet</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Blood Pet: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"You are wrong," Volrath said. "I do not hate the living. They often prove quite useful to me." And then he laughed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0022</id>
    <name>Boil</name>
    <text>Destroy all Islands.</text>
    <flavorText>"The fishers will throw out their nets and draw them back filled with dust."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0023</id>
    <name>Booby Trap</name>
    <text>As Booby Trap enters the battlefield, name a card other than a basic land card and choose an opponent.
The chosen player reveals each card he or she draws.
When the chosen player draws the named card, sacrifice Booby Trap. If you do, Booby Trap deals 10 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0024</id>
    <name>Bottle Gnomes</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Bottle Gnomes: You gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"I am reminded of the fable of the silver egg. Its owner cracks it open to see what jewels it holds, only to discover a simple yellow yolk."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0025</id>
    <name>Bounty Hunter</name>
    <text>{T}: Put a bounty counter on target nonblack creature.
{T}: Destroy target creature with a bounty counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Once they've marked you," Starke said, "the world is made of glass."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0026</id>
    <name>Broken Fall</name>
    <text>Return Broken Fall to its owner's hand: Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"I think I used up all my good luck and all my bad luck in the same fall."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0027</id>
    <name>Caldera Lake</name>
    <text>Caldera Lake enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {U} or {R} to your mana pool. Caldera Lake deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0028</id>
    <name>Canopy Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We know our place in the cycle of life—and it is not as flies."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0029</id>
    <name>Canyon Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}, Discard a card at random: Canyon Drake gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"These runes are tough enough without the distraction," Ertai muttered, one eye on the drake.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0030</id>
    <name>Canyon Wildcat</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Relative of yours?" Ertai teased. Mirri simply sneered.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0031</id>
    <name>Capsize</name>
    <text>Buyback {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0032</id>
    <name>Carrionette</name>
    <text>{2}{B}{B}: Exile Carrionette and target creature unless that creature's controller pays {2}. Activate this ability only if Carrionette is in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0033</id>
    <name>Chaotic Goo</name>
    <text>Chaotic Goo enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may flip a coin. If you win the flip, put a +1/+1 counter on Chaotic Goo. If you lose the flip, remove a +1/+1 counter from Chaotic Goo.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0034</id>
    <name>Charging Rhino</name>
    <text>Charging Rhino can't be blocked by more than one creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Is it wrong to go straight for what you want? Sneaking is for cats and goblins."
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0035</id>
    <name>Chill</name>
    <text>Red spells cost {2} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>"Temper, temper."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0036</id>
    <name>Choke</name>
    <text>Islands don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>"One day we shall walk where once was water."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0037</id>
    <name>Cinder Marsh</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool. Cinder Marsh doesn't untap during your next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0038</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Black</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a black source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0039</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Blue</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a blue source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0040</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Green</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a green source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0041</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Red</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a red source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0042</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Shadow</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a creature of your choice with shadow would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0043</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: White</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a white source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0044</id>
    <name>Clergy en-Vec</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Faith's shield is hammered out by the blows of unbelievers."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0045</id>
    <name>Clot Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{2}: Regenerate this permanent."</text>
    <flavorText>"One would think I would be accustomed to unexpected returns."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0046</id>
    <name>Cloudchaser Eagle</name>
    <text>Flying
When Cloudchaser Eagle enters the battlefield, destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>When the eagle catches a cloud, it tears it into strips that fall to earth.
—Vec myth of the rains</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0047</id>
    <name>Coercion</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You choose a card from it. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>"There's very little that escapes me, Greven. And you will escape very little if you fail."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0048</id>
    <name>Coffin Queen</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Coffin Queen during your untap step.
{2}{B}, {T}: Put target creature card from a graveyard onto the battlefield under your control. When Coffin Queen becomes untapped or you lose control of Coffin Queen, exile that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0049</id>
    <name>Coiled Tinviper</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>The bite of the tinviper feels most like a razor drawn across the tongue.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0050</id>
    <name>Cold Storage</name>
    <text>{3}: Exile target creature you control.
Sacrifice Cold Storage: Return each creature card exiled with Cold Storage to the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0051</id>
    <name>Commander Greven il-Vec</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
When Commander Greven il-Vec enters the battlefield, sacrifice a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Rage is the only freedom left me."
—Greven il-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0052</id>
    <name>Corpse Dance</name>
    <text>Buyback {2} (You may pay an additional {2} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Return the top creature card of your graveyard to the battlefield. That creature gains haste until end of turn. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0053</id>
    <name>Counterspell</name>
    <text>Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"It was probably a lousy spell in the first place."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0054</id>
    <name>Crazed Armodon</name>
    <text>{G}: Crazed Armodon gets +3/+0 and gains trample until end of turn. Destroy Crazed Armodon at the beginning of the next end step. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>These are its last days. Mourning is over. Rage remains.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0055</id>
    <name>Crown of Flames</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
{R}: Return Crown of Flames to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>It is the forge of kings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0056</id>
    <name>Cursed Scroll</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Name a card. Reveal a card at random from your hand. If it's the named card, Cursed Scroll deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0057</id>
    <name>Dark Banishing</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is the way of most wizards to begin by exiling themselves and to end by exiling everyone else."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0058</id>
    <name>Dark Ritual</name>
    <text>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"If there is such a thing as too much power, I have not discovered it."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0059</id>
    <name>Darkling Stalker</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Darkling Stalker.
{B}: Darkling Stalker gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"In this dark place, yes, I am afraid of my own shadow."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0060</id>
    <name>Dauthi Embrace</name>
    <text>{B}{B}: Target creature gains shadow until end of turn. (It can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The Dauthi army grows by screams and bounds."
—Lyna, Soltari emissary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0061</id>
    <name>Dauthi Ghoul</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
Whenever a creature with shadow is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on Dauthi Ghoul.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0062</id>
    <name>Dauthi Horror</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
Dauthi Horror can't be blocked by white creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0063</id>
    <name>Dauthi Marauder</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The Dauthi came from beneath the Ruins one night, and the darkness cast them in the best possible light."
—Soltari Tales of Life</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0064</id>
    <name>Dauthi Mercenary</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
{1}{B}: Dauthi Mercenary gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Dauthi believe they dignify murder by paying for it."
—Lyna, Soltari emissary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0065</id>
    <name>Dauthi Mindripper</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
Whenever Dauthi Mindripper attacks and isn't blocked, you may sacrifice it. If you do, defending player discards three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0066</id>
    <name>Dauthi Slayer</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
Dauthi Slayer attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>"They have knives for every soul."
—Lyna, Soltari emissary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0067</id>
    <name>Deadshot</name>
    <text>Tap target creature. It deals damage equal to its power to another target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Carrion Keep your distance. My blade will come to you"
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0068</id>
    <name>Death Pits of Rath</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is dealt damage, destroy it. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>As the sludge below began to shift and take shapes, Gerrard turned from the railing to Orim. "I suppose," he said, "it's a little too late for prayer, isn't it?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0069</id>
    <name>Diabolic Edict</name>
    <text>Target player sacrifices a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Greven il-Vec lifted Vhati off his feet. "The fall will give you time to think on your failure."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0070</id>
    <name>Dirtcowl Wurm</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent plays a land, put a +1/+1 counter on Dirtcowl Wurm.</text>
    <flavorText>Few of Rath's rivers follow a steady course, so many new channels are carved for them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0071</id>
    <name>Disenchant</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>The swarm seemed unmoved by the artificial slivers' destruction. "They clearly were not the leaders," Hanna cursed. "I guess we'll have to do this the hard way."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0072</id>
    <name>Dismiss</name>
    <text>Counter target spell.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is nothing you can do that I cannot simply deny."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0073</id>
    <name>Disturbed Burial</name>
    <text>Buyback {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0074</id>
    <name>Dracoplasm</name>
    <text>Flying

As Dracoplasm enters the battlefield, sacrifice any number of creatures. Dracoplasm's power becomes the total power of those creatures and its toughness becomes their total toughness.

{R}: Dracoplasm gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0075</id>
    <name>Dread of Night</name>
    <text>White creatures get -1/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>"These moonless, foreign skies keep me in thrall. Dark whispers echo in the night, and I cannot resist."
—Selenia, dark angel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0076</id>
    <name>Dream Cache</name>
    <text>Draw three cards, then put two cards from your hand both on top of your library or both on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"The sanctity of poverty is an invention of the rich."
—Starke</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0077</id>
    <name>Dregs of Sorrow</name>
    <text>Destroy X target nonblack creatures. Draw X cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Crovax gazed on the dead, and for one dark moment he saw a banquet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0078</id>
    <name>Duplicity</name>
    <text>When Duplicity enters the battlefield, exile the top five cards of your library face down.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may exile all cards from your hand face down. If you do, put all other cards you own exiled with Duplicity into your hand.
At the beginning of your end step, discard a card.
When you lose control of Duplicity, put all cards exiled with Duplicity into their owners' graveyards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0079</id>
    <name>Earthcraft</name>
    <text>Tap an untapped creature you control: Untap target basic land.</text>
    <flavorText>"The land gives up little, but we are masters of persuasion."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0080</id>
    <name>Echo Chamber</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: An opponent chooses target creature he or she controls. Put a token that's a copy of that creature onto the battlefield. That token gains haste until end of turn. Exile the token at the beginning of the next end step. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0081</id>
    <name>Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</name>
    <text>Other Elf creatures have forestwalk.
Other Elves have shroud. (They can't be the targets of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We have been patient. We have planned our attack. We are ready . . . now."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0082</id>
    <name>Eladamri's Vineyard</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's precombat main phase, add {G}{G} to that player's mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The mushroom wine made Gerrard's head spin, and his stomach soon followed suit.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0083</id>
    <name>Elite Javelineer</name>
    <text>Whenever Elite Javelineer blocks, it deals 1 damage to target attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Precision is frequently more valuable than force."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0084</id>
    <name>Elven Warhounds</name>
    <text>Whenever Elven Warhounds becomes blocked by a creature, put that creature on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"If a creature is dumb enough to love you for leashing it, why would you want to follow its lead?"
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0085</id>
    <name>Elvish Fury</name>
    <text>Buyback {4} (You may pay an additional {4} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0086</id>
    <name>Emerald Medallion</name>
    <text>Green spells you cast cost {1} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0087</id>
    <name>Emmessi Tome</name>
    <text>{5}, {T}: Draw two cards, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>It is like life and destiny: we think we know the story, but we have read only half the tale.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0088</id>
    <name>Endless Scream</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Endless Scream enters the battlefield with X scream counters on it.
Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 for each scream counter on Endless Scream.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have made Crovax weep; now I will make him scream. The pain will not end, but will bind him to me."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0089</id>
    <name>Energizer</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Put a +1/+1 counter on Energizer.</text>
    <flavorText>Like a kettle set to boil, it must eventually go off—on someone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0090</id>
    <name>Enfeeblement</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature gets -2/-2.</text>
    <flavorText>Crovax had witnessed Selenia lead the Predator to the Weatherlight. As the battle raged on deck, he felt his strength melt in the heat of her betrayal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0091</id>
    <name>Enraging Licid</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}: Enraging Licid loses this ability and becomes an Aura enchantment with enchant creature. Attach it to target creature. You may pay {R} to end this effect.
Enchanted creature has haste.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0092</id>
    <name>Ertai's Meddling</name>
    <text>X can't be 0.
Target spell's controller exiles it with X delay counters on it.
At the beginning of each of that player's upkeeps, if that card is exiled, remove a delay counter from it. If the card has no delay counters on it, he or she puts it onto the stack as a copy of the original spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0093</id>
    <name>Escaped Shapeshifter</name>
    <text>As long as an opponent controls a creature with flying not named Escaped Shapeshifter, Escaped Shapeshifter has flying. The same is true for first strike, trample, and protection from any color.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0094</id>
    <name>Essence Bottle</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Put an elixir counter on Essence Bottle.
{T}, Remove all elixir counters from Essence Bottle: You gain 2 life for each elixir counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0095</id>
    <name>Evincar's Justice</name>
    <text>Buyback {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Evincar's Justice deals 2 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0096</id>
    <name>Excavator</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a basic land: Target creature gains landwalk of each of the land types of the sacrificed land until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0097</id>
    <name>Extinction</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures of the creature type of your choice.</text>
    <flavorText>"I once had an entire race killed just to listen to the rattling of their dried bones as I waded through them."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0098</id>
    <name>Fevered Convulsions</name>
    <text>{2}{B}{B}: Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Tell me again why you failed to capture Gerrard, you worthless pile of spine."
—Volrath, to Greven</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0099</id>
    <name>Field of Souls</name>
    <text>Whenever a nontoken creature is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, put a 1/1 white Spirit creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0100</id>
    <name>Fighting Drake</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Two things are needed to survive the harsh skies of Rath: a thick hide and a thicker skull.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0101</id>
    <name>Firefly</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}: Firefly gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"If they don't pinch, they burn. Can't ya eat any of da bugs here?"
—Squee, goblin cabin hand</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0102</id>
    <name>Fireslinger</name>
    <text>{T}: Fireslinger deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"Remember the moral of the fireslinger fable: with power comes isolation."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0103</id>
    <name>Flailing Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Flailing Drake blocks or becomes blocked by a creature, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Too many choices will always distract a greedy beast.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0104</id>
    <name>Flickering Ward</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As Flickering Ward enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Enchanted creature has protection from the chosen color. This effect doesn't remove Flickering Ward.
{W}: Return Flickering Ward to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0105</id>
    <name>Flowstone Giant</name>
    <text>{R}: Flowstone Giant gets +2/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>When the first of these giants woke from the bedrock, he was still sleepy. He yawned and stretched until his legs grew so thin that they snapped like icicles in the sun.
—Vec lore</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0106</id>
    <name>Flowstone Salamander</name>
    <text>{R}: Flowstone Salamander deals 1 damage to target creature blocking it.</text>
    <flavorText>The Furnace of Rath is periodically illuminated by their sparkling yawns.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0107</id>
    <name>Flowstone Sculpture</name>
    <text>{2}, Discard a card: Put a +1/+1 counter on Flowstone Sculpture or Flowstone Sculpture gains flying, first strike, or trample. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>The sculptor, weary of his work, created art that would finish itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0108</id>
    <name>Flowstone Wyvern</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}: Flowstone Wyvern gets +2/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Where I come from, stone stays on the ground."
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0109</id>
    <name>Fool's Tome</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Draw a card. Activate this ability only if you have no cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Squee: "What's that?"
Ertai: "It's a magical book."
Squee: "Am I smart enough ta use it?"
Ertai: "You could say that."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0110</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0111</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0112</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0113</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0114</id>
    <name>Frog Tongue</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Frog Tongue enters the battlefield, draw a card.
Enchanted creature has reach. (It can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>"But why can't I get one?" sniveled Squee. "All da bugs here got wings."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0115</id>
    <name>Fugitive Druid</name>
    <text>Whenever Fugitive Druid becomes the target of an Aura spell, you draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"If the druids are so devoted to their trees, I will carve them coffins from their precious heartwood."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0116</id>
    <name>Furnace of Rath</name>
    <text>If a source would deal damage to a creature or player, it deals double that damage to that creature or player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0117</id>
    <name>Fylamarid</name>
    <text>Flying
Fylamarid can't be blocked by blue creatures.
{U}: Target creature becomes blue until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0118</id>
    <name>Gallantry</name>
    <text>Target blocking creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Forgive me," Mirri whispered. "I thought you a burden, and you saved my life." Hanna quietly accepted the apology.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0119</id>
    <name>Gaseous Form</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's hard to hurt anyone when you're as transparent as your motives."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0120</id>
    <name>Gerrard's Battle Cry</name>
    <text>{2}{W}: Creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard grinned and drew his sword. "This won't be a fair fight," he called to his crew. "They should have brought a second ship"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0121</id>
    <name>Ghost Town</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{0}: Return Ghost Town to its owner's hand. Activate this ability only if it's not your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The air here smells like a grave."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0122</id>
    <name>Giant Crab</name>
    <text>{U}: Giant Crab gains shroud until end of turn. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>During the giant crabs' mating season, Skyshroud nights are filled with the clatter of their skirmishes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0123</id>
    <name>Giant Strength</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>"Crovax seems filled only with shadows," thought Orim. "Where does his strength come from?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0124</id>
    <name>Goblin Bombardment</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: Goblin Bombardment deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>One mogg to aim the catapult, one mogg to steer the rock.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0125</id>
    <name>Gravedigger</name>
    <text>When Gravedigger enters the battlefield, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>A full coffin is like a full coffer—both are attractive to thieves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0126</id>
    <name>Grindstone</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Put the top two cards of target player's library into that player's graveyard. If both cards share a color, repeat this process.</text>
    <flavorText>"Memory is a burden that wears at the soul as weather wears at stone."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0127</id>
    <name>Hand to Hand</name>
    <text>During combat, players can't cast instant spells or activate abilities that aren't mana abilities.</text>
    <flavorText>The match between Tahngarth and Greven was close only in the mind of the minotaur.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0128</id>
    <name>Hanna's Custody</name>
    <text>All artifacts have shroud. (They can't be the targets of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I protect the Legacy with my life if necessary, for its purpose is far more important than my own."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0129</id>
    <name>Harrow</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Harrow, sacrifice a land.
Search your library for up to two basic land cards and put them onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Changing Rath's landscape is like tearing the scab from a wound.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0130</id>
    <name>Havoc</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a white spell, he or she loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>As Orim put the lightning rod into place on the bow, she cast a spell of protection to shield herself from the heat. That's when the Furnace got personal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0131</id>
    <name>Heart Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have haste.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard looked all around for the source of the mysterious pulse, and at that moment the slivers boiled forth from the crevasses.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0132</id>
    <name>Heartwood Dryad</name>
    <text>Heartwood Dryad can block creatures with shadow as though they didn't have shadow.</text>
    <flavorText>To snare what lies between worlds takes the patient reach of trees.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0133</id>
    <name>Heartwood Giant</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a Forest: Heartwood Giant deals 2 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Wind in the trees is soothing, but the same can't be said for trees on the wind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0134</id>
    <name>Heartwood Treefolk</name>
    <text>Forestwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"In all my years in Llanowar I never understood where trees fit in. They are revered by elves and watered on by dogs."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0135</id>
    <name>Helm of Possession</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Helm of Possession during your untap step.
{2}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Gain control of target creature for as long as you control Helm of Possession and Helm of Possession remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0136</id>
    <name>Hero's Resolve</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+5.</text>
    <flavorText>"Destiny, chance, fate, fortune—they're all just ways of claiming your successes without claiming your failures."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0137</id>
    <name>Horned Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have trample.</text>
    <flavorText>A bristling wave of slivers broke against the Weatherlight's timbers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0138</id>
    <name>Horned Turtle</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"So like men are they: a hardened shell with fragile flesh beneath."
—Selenia, dark angel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0139</id>
    <name>Humility</name>
    <text>All creatures lose all abilities and are 1/1.</text>
    <flavorText>"One cannot cleanse the wounds of failure."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0140</id>
    <name>Imps' Taunt</name>
    <text>Buyback {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Target creature attacks this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0141</id>
    <name>Insight</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a green spell, you draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"We can fight with you or against you. After my day, I'd prefer the former."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0142</id>
    <name>Interdict</name>
    <text>Counter target activated ability from an artifact, creature, enchantment, or land. That permanent's activated abilities can't be activated this turn. (Mana abilities can't be targeted.)
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0143</id>
    <name>Intuition</name>
    <text>Search your library for any three cards and reveal them. Target opponent chooses one. Put that card into your hand and the rest into your graveyard. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0144</id>
    <name>Invulnerability</name>
    <text>Buyback {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0145</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0146</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0147</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0148</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0149</id>
    <name>Jackal Pup</name>
    <text>Whenever Jackal Pup is dealt damage, it deals that much damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>The first morning after acquiring her familiar, the wizard awoke with fleabites and mange.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0150</id>
    <name>Jet Medallion</name>
    <text>Black spells you cast cost {1} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0151</id>
    <name>Jinxed Idol</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Jinxed Idol deals 2 damage to you.
Sacrifice a creature: Target opponent gains control of Jinxed Idol. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Here."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0152</id>
    <name>Kezzerdrix</name>
    <text>First strike
At the beginning of your upkeep, if your opponents control no creatures, Kezzerdrix deals 4 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0153</id>
    <name>Kindle</name>
    <text>Kindle deals X damage to target creature or player, where X is 2 plus the number of cards named Kindle in all graveyards.</text>
    <flavorText>Hope of deliverance is scorched by the fire of futility.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0154</id>
    <name>Knight of Dawn</name>
    <text>First strike
{W}{W}: Knight of Dawn gains protection from the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Flash like daybreak to the fray.
—Motto of the Knights of Dawn</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0155</id>
    <name>Knight of Dusk</name>
    <text>{B}{B}: Destroy target creature blocking Knight of Dusk.</text>
    <flavorText>Fall like night upon the foe.
—Motto of the Knights of Dusk</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0156</id>
    <name>Krakilin</name>
    <text>Krakilin enters the battlefield with X +1/+1 counters on it.
{1}{G}: Regenerate Krakilin.</text>
    <flavorText>"A perfect reflection of its world: brutal, fetal, and lacking truth."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0157</id>
    <name>Leeching Licid</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}: Leeching Licid loses this ability and becomes an Aura enchantment with enchant creature. Attach it to target creature. You may pay {B} to end this effect.
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, Leeching Licid deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0158</id>
    <name>Legacy's Allure</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a treasure counter on Legacy's Allure.
Sacrifice Legacy's Allure: Gain control of target creature with power less than or equal to the number of treasure counters on Legacy's Allure. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0159</id>
    <name>Legerdemain</name>
    <text>Exchange control of target artifact or creature and another target permanent that shares one of those types with it. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>Squee tucked the warm ball in his pocket and slipped a pebble in its place. ‘Glok,' he mumbled, and hid.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0160</id>
    <name>Light of Day</name>
    <text>Black creatures can't attack or block.</text>
    <flavorText>"I do not miss sunlight. The very memory of it burns my eyes."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0161</id>
    <name>Lightning Blast</name>
    <text>Lightning Blast deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those who fear the darkness have never seen what the light can do."
—Selenia, dark angel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0162</id>
    <name>Lightning Elemental</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)</text>
    <flavorText>A lightning elemental once killed an entire tribe of merfolk—simply by going for a swim.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0163</id>
    <name>Living Death</name>
    <text>Each player exiles all creature cards from his or her graveyard, then sacrifices all creatures he or she controls, then puts all cards he or she exiled this way onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0164</id>
    <name>Lobotomy</name>
    <text>Target player reveals his or her hand, then you choose a card other than a basic land card from it. Search that player's graveyard, hand, and library for all cards with the same name as the chosen card and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0165</id>
    <name>Lotus Petal</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Lotus Petal: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Hard to imagine," mused Hanna, stroking the petal, "such a lovely flower inspiring such greed."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0166</id>
    <name>Lowland Giant</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Faugh" snorted Tahngarth. "Why would it make a meal of something like you?" Squee looked relieved. "No," he continued, "you'd make a much better toothpick."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0167</id>
    <name>Maddening Imp</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Non-Wall creatures the active player controls attack this turn if able. At the beginning of the next end step, destroy each of those creatures that didn't attack this turn. Activate this ability only during an opponent's turn and only before combat.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0168</id>
    <name>Magmasaur</name>
    <text>Magmasaur enters the battlefield with five +1/+1 counters on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Magmasaur unless you remove a +1/+1 counter from it. If you sacrifice Magmasaur this way, it deals damage equal to the number of +1/+1 counters on it to each creature without flying and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0169</id>
    <name>Magnetic Web</name>
    <text>If a creature with a magnet counter on it attacks, all creatures with magnet counters on them attack if able.
Whenever a creature with a magnet counter on it attacks, all creatures with magnet counters on them block that creature this turn if able.
{1}, {T}: Put a magnet counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0170</id>
    <name>Mana Severance</name>
    <text>Search your library for any number of land cards and exile them. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"And when this land is wasted, where will we go?"
—Thalakos lament</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0171</id>
    <name>Manakin</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Hanna regarded Squee sternly. "Because it's not a toy, no matter how much it may look like one," she said, taking the manakin from him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0172</id>
    <name>Manta Riders</name>
    <text>{U}: Manta Riders gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Water is firmament to the finned."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0173</id>
    <name>Marble Titan</name>
    <text>Creatures with power 3 or greater don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>"Strapping on nine hundred pounds of armor every morning would make any warrior cross."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0174</id>
    <name>Marsh Lurker</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a Swamp: Marsh Lurker gains fear until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>From the mists it rises, into the mists it retreats; through the mists it walks, fearless and unseen.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0175</id>
    <name>Master Decoy</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"A skilled decoy can throw your enemies off your trail. A master decoy can survive to do it again."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0176</id>
    <name>Mawcor</name>
    <text>Flying

{T}: Mawcor deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>From its maw comes neither word nor whisper—only wind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0177</id>
    <name>Maze of Shadows</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{T}: Untap target attacking creature with shadow. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by that creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0178</id>
    <name>Meditate</name>
    <text>Draw four cards. You skip your next turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Part of me believes that Barrin taught me meditation simply to shut me up."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0179</id>
    <name>Metallic Sliver</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>When the clever counterfeit was accepted by the hive, Volrath's influence upon the slivers grew even stronger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0180</id>
    <name>Mindwhip Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{2}, Sacrifice this permanent: Target player discards a card at random. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery."</text>
    <flavorText>"They share more than their thoughts. We must shatter their link quickly"
—Hanna, to Orim</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0181</id>
    <name>Minion of the Wastes</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Minion of the Wastes, pay any amount of life.
Trample
Minion of the Wastes's power and toughness are each equal to the life paid as it was cast.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0182</id>
    <name>Mirri's Guile</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may look at the top three cards of your library, then put them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>Hanna was astounded. Mirri read every leaf and wisp of breeze like a book of ancient lore.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0183</id>
    <name>Mnemonic Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{2}, Sacrifice this permanent: Draw a card."</text>
    <flavorText>"A jigsaw puzzle that lives, breeds, and thinks."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0184</id>
    <name>Mogg Cannon</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature you control gets +1/+0 and gains flying until end of turn. Destroy that creature at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>Moggs never volunteer for anything twice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0185</id>
    <name>Mogg Conscripts</name>
    <text>Mogg Conscripts can't attack unless you've cast a creature spell this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Torahn's horns They've seen us. Now, statue, you must fight to save yourself"
—Tahngarth, aboard the Predator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0186</id>
    <name>Mogg Fanatic</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Mogg Fanatic: Mogg Fanatic deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"I got it I got it I—"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0187</id>
    <name>Mogg Hollows</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool. Mogg Hollows doesn't untap during your next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0188</id>
    <name>Mogg Raider</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a Goblin: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The evisceration of one mogg always cheers up the rest.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0189</id>
    <name>Mogg Squad</name>
    <text>Mogg Squad gets -1/-1 for each other creature on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>As they crept into the Weatherlight's hold, the squad leader held up his hand and whispered, "Stop, goblins—what's that sound?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0190</id>
    <name>Mongrel Pack</name>
    <text>When Mongrel Pack is put into a graveyard from the battlefield during combat, put four 1/1 green Hound creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0191</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0192</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0193</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0194</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0195</id>
    <name>Mounted Archers</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)
{W}: Mounted Archers can block an additional creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0196</id>
    <name>Muscle Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>The air was filled with the cracks and snaps of flesh hardening as the new sliver joined the battle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0197</id>
    <name>Natural Spring</name>
    <text>Target player gains 8 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Mirri listened intently, even as Hanna held the healing water to her lips. Would the sound of the spring drown out the elves' approach?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0198</id>
    <name>Nature's Revolt</name>
    <text>All lands are 2/2 creatures that are still lands.</text>
    <flavorText>"One day the land will don the semblance of flesh and challenge even the plowshare's blade."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0199</id>
    <name>Needle Storm</name>
    <text>Needle Storm deals 4 damage to each creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>The rain is driven like nails.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0200</id>
    <name>No Quarter</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature becomes blocked by a creature with lesser power, destroy the blocking creature.

Whenever a creature blocks a creature with lesser power, destroy the attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>As Gerrard and Greven neared each other, the moggs caught between them realized they should flee.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0201</id>
    <name>Nurturing Licid</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: Nurturing Licid loses this ability and becomes an Aura enchantment with enchant creature. Attach it to target creature. You may pay {G} to end this effect.
{G}: Regenerate enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0202</id>
    <name>Opportunist</name>
    <text>{T}: Opportunist deals 1 damage to target creature that was dealt damage this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The third time the Oracle glanced suspiciously at him, Starke decided she had glanced twice too often.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0203</id>
    <name>Oracle en-Vec</name>
    <text>{T}: Target opponent chooses any number of creatures he or she controls. During that player's next turn, the chosen creatures attack if able, and other creatures can't attack. At the beginning of that turn's end step, destroy each of the chosen creatures that didn't attack. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0204</id>
    <name>Orim, Samite Healer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The silkworm spins itself a new existence. So the healer weaves the threads of life."
—Orim, Samite healer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0205</id>
    <name>Orim's Prayer</name>
    <text>Whenever one or more creatures attack you, you gain 1 life for each attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"As usual, there will be time for prayer only after the worst happens."
—Orim, Samite healer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0206</id>
    <name>Overrun</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +3/+3 and gain trample until end of turn. (If a creature you control would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)</text>
    <flavorText>"You want to know your enemy? Look at your feet while you trample him."
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0207</id>
    <name>Pacifism</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block.</text>
    <flavorText>Frozen by conscience, Karn did not resist as the moggs carried him to the Predator.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0208</id>
    <name>Pallimud</name>
    <text>As Pallimud enters the battlefield, choose an opponent.
Pallimud's power is equal to the number of tapped lands the chosen player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>The old Vec tell tales of a beast that fed on scraps but turned its nose up at the lavish banquet they set in its honor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0209</id>
    <name>Patchwork Gnomes</name>
    <text>Discard a card: Regenerate Patchwork Gnomes.</text>
    <flavorText>"Just when I get them working, they always start fighting and tearing at each other for spare parts."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0210</id>
    <name>Pearl Medallion</name>
    <text>White spells you cast cost {1} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0211</id>
    <name>Pegasus Refuge</name>
    <text>{2}, Discard a card: Put a 1/1 white Pegasus creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The first Rath-born pegasus was so offended by the sky that it hid its eyes in the earth.
—Vec lore</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0212</id>
    <name>Perish</name>
    <text>Destroy all green creatures. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"There will come a time when the voices of soil and seedling will sing only laments."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0213</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Grimoire</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Target opponent chooses one of the top two cards of your graveyard. Exile that card and put the other one into your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Every page cost a life; every secret cost a thousand more.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0214</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Hulk</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"They are convenient in having no souls, but less so in having no spirit."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0215</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Splicer</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Choose one — flying; first strike; shadow; or trample. Target creature with that ability loses it until end of turn and another target creature gains it until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0216</id>
    <name>Pincher Beetles</name>
    <text>Shroud (This creature can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>"No fair Since when does a bug get ta munch on me?"
—Squee, goblin cabin hand</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0217</id>
    <name>Pine Barrens</name>
    <text>Pine Barrens enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {B} or {G} to your mana pool. Pine Barrens deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0218</id>
    <name>Pit Imp</name>
    <text>Flying
{B}: Pit Imp gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Activate this ability no more than twice each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The moans of the Death Pits were underscored by the chattering of imps, for whom the ship was cause for much discussion.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0219</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0220</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0221</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0222</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0223</id>
    <name>Power Sink</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}. If he or she doesn't, that player taps all lands with mana abilities he or she controls and empties his or her mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0224</id>
    <name>Precognition</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may look at the top card of target opponent's library. If you do, you may put that card on the bottom of that player's library.</text>
    <flavorText>A gleam like struggling sunlight penetrated Selenia's dark thoughts.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0225</id>
    <name>Propaganda</name>
    <text>Creatures can't attack you unless their controller pays {2} for each creature he or she controls that's attacking you.</text>
    <flavorText>"You've failed Gerrard. You've failed the Legacy. You've failed yourself. I can do no more."
—Volrath, to Karn</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0226</id>
    <name>Puppet Strings</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: You may tap or untap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Have no illusions," Volrath warned Greven, "about free will."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0227</id>
    <name>Quickening Licid</name>
    <text>{1}{W}, {T}: Quickening Licid loses this ability and becomes an Aura enchantment with enchant creature. Attach it to target creature. You may pay {W} to end this effect.
Enchanted creature has first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0228</id>
    <name>Rain of Tears</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>"These rains cannot quench; they carve the land's face like a scalpel on flesh."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0229</id>
    <name>Rampant Growth</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Rath forces plants from its surface as one presses whey from cheese.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0230</id>
    <name>Ranger en-Vec</name>
    <text>First strike
{G}: Regenerate Ranger en-Vec.</text>
    <flavorText>"The path of least resistance will seldom lead you beyond your doorstep."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0231</id>
    <name>Rathi Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
When Rathi Dragon enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you sacrifice two Mountains.</text>
    <flavorText>Wrap the flame as twine
Kingdoms will be thine.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0232</id>
    <name>Rats of Rath</name>
    <text>{B}: Destroy target artifact, creature, or land you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"These creatures offer new challenges in the scrutiny of entrails."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0233</id>
    <name>Reality Anchor</name>
    <text>Target creature loses shadow until end of turn.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"See how you like it."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0234</id>
    <name>Reanimate</name>
    <text>Put target creature card from a graveyard onto the battlefield under your control. You lose life equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"You will learn to earn death."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0235</id>
    <name>Reap</name>
    <text>Return up to X target cards from your graveyard to your hand, where X is the number of black permanents target opponent controls as you cast Reap.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let Volrath choke on his crop of hatred."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0236</id>
    <name>Reckless Spite</name>
    <text>Destroy two target nonblack creatures. You lose 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"My plan's elegance leads my enemies to believe it is spite that fuels me."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0237</id>
    <name>Recycle</name>
    <text>Skip your draw step.
Whenever you play a card, draw a card.
Your maximum hand size is two.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0238</id>
    <name>Reflecting Pool</name>
    <text>{T}: Add to your mana pool one mana of any type that a land you control could produce.</text>
    <flavorText>"The reflection of land interests me far more than its reality."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0239</id>
    <name>Renegade Warlord</name>
    <text>First strike
Whenever Renegade Warlord attacks, each other attacking creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"His tongue must be honey, the way he gathers ants to fight with him."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0240</id>
    <name>Repentance</name>
    <text>Target creature deals damage to itself equal to its power.</text>
    <flavorText>"The cannon wasn't aimed at you" pleaded Vhati.
"I'm not sure which is more pathetic," replied Greven, "your judgment or your aim."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0241</id>
    <name>Respite</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn. You gain 1 life for each attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"If they board us we're finished," warned Orim. Crovax nodded. "And if they don't . . . what then?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0242</id>
    <name>Rolling Thunder</name>
    <text>Rolling Thunder deals X damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>"Such rage," thought Vhati, gazing up at the thunderhead from the Predator. "It is Greven's mind manifest."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0243</id>
    <name>Root Maze</name>
    <text>Artifacts and lands enter the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>"We should step up repairs. I think the forest has plans for us."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0244</id>
    <name>Rootbreaker Wurm</name>
    <text>Trample (If this creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)</text>
    <flavorText>As Gerrard made his escape, the wurm covered his flight by helping itself to three great mouthfuls of merfolk.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0245</id>
    <name>Rootwalla</name>
    <text>{1}{G}: Rootwalla gets +2/+2 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>If you try to sneak up on a rootwalla, you'll suddenly find yourself dealing with twice the lizard.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0246</id>
    <name>Rootwater Depths</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool. Rootwater Depths doesn't untap during your next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0247</id>
    <name>Rootwater Diver</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Rootwater Diver: Return target artifact card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Drop a dagger into the murky deep and the merfolk will cut your throat with it."
—Skyshroud saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0248</id>
    <name>Rootwater Hunter</name>
    <text>{T}: Rootwater Hunter deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Bitter water   vicious wave
Shadow-cold shallows   root-made maze
Home's angry embrace."
—Rootwater Saga</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0249</id>
    <name>Rootwater Matriarch</name>
    <text>{T}: Gain control of target creature for as long as that creature is enchanted.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0250</id>
    <name>Rootwater Shaman</name>
    <text>You may cast Aura cards with enchant creature as though they had flash.</text>
    <flavorText>"Ugh When did orcs and fish start having kids?"
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0251</id>
    <name>Ruby Medallion</name>
    <text>Red spells you cast cost {1} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0252</id>
    <name>Sacred Guide</name>
    <text>{1}{W}, Sacrifice Sacred Guide: Reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal a white card. Put that card into your hand and exile all other cards revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0253</id>
    <name>Sadistic Glee</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"First blood isn't as important as last blood."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0254</id>
    <name>Safeguard</name>
    <text>{2}{W}: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'm amused by wasted effort when it's not my own."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0255</id>
    <name>Salt Flats</name>
    <text>Salt Flats enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {W} or {B} to your mana pool. Salt Flats deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0256</id>
    <name>Sandstone Warrior</name>
    <text>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)
{R}: Sandstone Warrior gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I used to describe something stable as ‘rock solid.' So much for that expression."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0257</id>
    <name>Sapphire Medallion</name>
    <text>Blue spells you cast cost {1} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0258</id>
    <name>Sarcomancy</name>
    <text>When Sarcomancy enters the battlefield, put a 2/2 black Zombie creature token onto the battlefield.
At the beginning of your upkeep, if there are no Zombies on the battlefield, Sarcomancy deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0259</id>
    <name>Scabland</name>
    <text>Scabland enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {R} or {W} to your mana pool. Scabland deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0260</id>
    <name>Scalding Tongs</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you have three or fewer cards in hand, Scalding Tongs deals 1 damage to target opponent.</text>
    <flavorText>"This has nothing to do with what you know and everything to do with what I wish."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0261</id>
    <name>Scorched Earth</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Scorched Earth, discard X land cards.
Destroy X target lands.</text>
    <flavorText>"Fire cleanses as well as destroys; that is the nature of change."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0262</id>
    <name>Scragnoth</name>
    <text>Scragnoth can't be countered.
Protection from blue</text>
    <flavorText>It possesses no intelligence, only counter-intelligence.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0263</id>
    <name>Screeching Harpy</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{B}: Regenerate Screeching Harpy.</text>
    <flavorText>"They are called ‘fowl' for a reason."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0264</id>
    <name>Scroll Rack</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Exile any number of cards from your hand face down. Put that many cards from the top of your library into your hand. Then look at the exiled cards and put them on top of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0265</id>
    <name>Sea Monster</name>
    <text>Sea Monster can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.</text>
    <flavorText>Water is life. Or perhaps it is just something to wash it down with.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0266</id>
    <name>Searing Touch</name>
    <text>Buyback {4} (You may pay an additional {4} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Searing Touch deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0267</id>
    <name>Seeker of Skybreak</name>
    <text>{T}: Untap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"We shun them not for their dream but for their refusal to let such a noble dream die a noble death."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0268</id>
    <name>Segmented Wurm</name>
    <text>Whenever Segmented Wurm becomes the target of a spell or ability, put a -1/-1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"If only we could so easily leave behind those parts of ourselves that pain us."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0269</id>
    <name>Selenia, Dark Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
Pay 2 life: Return Selenia, Dark Angel to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"I am light. I am dark. I must give my life to serve; not even death can release me."
—Selenia, dark angel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0270</id>
    <name>Serene Offering</name>
    <text>Destroy target enchantment. You gain life equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"A sacrifice made in peace is worth a dozen made in panic."
—Orim, Samite healer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0271</id>
    <name>Servant of Volrath</name>
    <text>When Servant of Volrath leaves the battlefield, sacrifice a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Volrath is a harsh master. My reflection is a constant reminder of that."
—Greven il-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0272</id>
    <name>Shadow Rift</name>
    <text>Target creature gains shadow until end of turn. (It can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0273</id>
    <name>Shadowstorm</name>
    <text>Shadowstorm deals 2 damage to each creature with shadow.</text>
    <flavorText>"You've not seen a storm until you've seen the kind that roars between worlds."
—Lyna, Soltari emissary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0274</id>
    <name>Shatter</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>"Such fuss over machines, Gerrard. Remember that you are the prize of the Legacy. Throw away your toys"
—Orim, Samite healer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0275</id>
    <name>Shimmering Wings</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has flying. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
{U}: Return Shimmering Wings to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The brighter the wings, the deeper the impact crater.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0276</id>
    <name>Shocker</name>
    <text>Whenever Shocker deals damage to a player, that player discards all the cards in his or her hand, then draws that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0277</id>
    <name>Sky Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying, first strike</text>
    <flavorText>"Like a strain of music: easy to remember but impossible to catch."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0278</id>
    <name>Skyshroud Condor</name>
    <text>Flying
Cast Skyshroud Condor only if you've cast another spell this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Condor's flight augurs sleepless night.
—Skyshroud proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0279</id>
    <name>Skyshroud Elf</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{1}: Add {W} or {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is our duty to endure."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0280</id>
    <name>Skyshroud Forest</name>
    <text>Skyshroud Forest enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {U} or {G} to your mana pool. Skyshroud Forest deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0281</id>
    <name>Skyshroud Ranger</name>
    <text>{T}: You may put a land card from your hand onto the battlefield. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>"Just as you see the grave and remember the friend, I see this forest and remember Llanowar."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0282</id>
    <name>Skyshroud Troll</name>
    <text>{1}{G}: Regenerate Skyshroud Troll.</text>
    <flavorText>The elves and merfolk have nothing but bitterness for each other. The trolls, however, find them both rather tasty.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0283</id>
    <name>Skyshroud Vampire</name>
    <text>Flying
Discard a creature card: Skyshroud Vampire gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"If it tastes one drop of elvish blood I will cast it from the shroud to see it burn."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0284</id>
    <name>Soltari Crusader</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
{1}{W}: Soltari Crusader gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Carry war to the Dauthi, no matter the way, no matter the world."
—Soltari battle chant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0285</id>
    <name>Soltari Emissary</name>
    <text>{W}: Soltari Emissary gains shadow until end of turn. (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)</text>
    <flavorText>Alone at the portal, Ertai began his meditation. He realized immediately that he was not alone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0286</id>
    <name>Soltari Foot Soldier</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Children of the Ruins, raised to be warriors, know that life begins when another speaks their names."
—Soltari Tales of Life</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0287</id>
    <name>Soltari Guerrillas</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
{0}: The next time Soltari Guerrillas would deal combat damage to an opponent this turn, it deals that damage to target creature instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0288</id>
    <name>Soltari Lancer</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
Soltari Lancer has first strike as long as it's attacking.</text>
    <flavorText>"In times of war the victors rarely save their best for last."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0289</id>
    <name>Soltari Monk</name>
    <text>Protection from black
Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Prayer rarely explains."
—Orim, Samite healer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0290</id>
    <name>Soltari Priest</name>
    <text>Protection from red
Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)</text>
    <flavorText>"In Rath," the priest said, "there is even greater need for prayer."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0291</id>
    <name>Soltari Trooper</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
Whenever Soltari Trooper attacks, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Dauthi blood is Soltari wine."
—Soltari Tales of Life</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0292</id>
    <name>Souldrinker</name>
    <text>Pay 3 life: Put a +1/+1 counter on Souldrinker.</text>
    <flavorText>Don't drink and thrive.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0293</id>
    <name>Spell Blast</name>
    <text>Counter target spell with converted mana cost X.</text>
    <flavorText>Call it the thinking mage's version of brute force.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0294</id>
    <name>Spike Drone</name>
    <text>Spike Drone enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.
{2}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Spike Drone: Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0295</id>
    <name>Spinal Graft</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.
When enchanted creature becomes the target of a spell or ability, destroy that creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"This one has not screamed enough to show effective implantation. Kill it."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0296</id>
    <name>Spirit Mirror</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if there are no Reflection tokens on the battlefield, put a 2/2 white Reflection creature token onto the battlefield.
{0}: Destroy target Reflection.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0297</id>
    <name>Spontaneous Combustion</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Spontaneous Combustion, sacrifice a creature.
Spontaneous Combustion deals 3 damage to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Heat of battle" is usually a metaphor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0298</id>
    <name>Squee's Toy</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>As the horrors closed in on Gerrard, Squee trembled and clutched his toy for comfort. He didn't know where it came from or why it was so warm, but he was glad he'd kept it near.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0299</id>
    <name>Stalking Stones</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{6}: Stalking Stones becomes a 3/3 Elemental artifact creature that's still a land. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0300</id>
    <name>Starke of Rath</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target artifact or creature. That permanent's controller gains control of Starke of Rath. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I know to whom I owe the most loyalty, and I see him in the mirror every day."
—Starke</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0301</id>
    <name>Static Orb</name>
    <text>If Static Orb is untapped, players can't untap more than two permanents during their untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>Time passes, time crawls;
Time doesn't move at all.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0302</id>
    <name>Staunch Defenders</name>
    <text>When Staunch Defenders enters the battlefield, you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Hold your position Leave doubt for the dying"
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0303</id>
    <name>Steal Enchantment</name>
    <text>Enchant enchantment
You control enchanted enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why should I flatter another with imitation when I can satisfy myself through possession?"
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0304</id>
    <name>Stinging Licid</name>
    <text>{1}{U}, {T}: Stinging Licid loses this ability and becomes an Aura enchantment with enchant creature. Attach it to target creature. You may pay {U} to end this effect.
Whenever enchanted creature becomes tapped, Stinging Licid deals 2 damage to that creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0305</id>
    <name>Stone Rain</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>"The land shall beg for drink and curse the rain that follows."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0306</id>
    <name>Storm Front</name>
    <text>{G}{G}: Tap target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>The calmest day on Rath would be thought a storm anywhere else.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0307</id>
    <name>Stun</name>
    <text>Target creature can't block this turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I concede it was a cheap shot, but it was the only one I could afford."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0308</id>
    <name>Sudden Impact</name>
    <text>Sudden Impact deals damage equal to the number of cards in target player's hand to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>The Predator roared like an unruly beast, and the Weatherlight suddenly listed. "No" screamed Hanna.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0309</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0310</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0311</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0312</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0313</id>
    <name>Tahngarth's Rage</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+0 as long as it's attacking. Otherwise, it gets -2/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>"Taste my horns"
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0314</id>
    <name>Talon Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>"Keep them at sword's length" Gerrard's order fell flat as each sliver's talon suddenly grew longer. "Hold on—break out the polearms"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0315</id>
    <name>Telethopter</name>
    <text>Tap an untapped creature you control: Telethopter gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>After losing several of the devices to midair collisions, Greven forbade moggs from operating telethopters.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0316</id>
    <name>Thalakos Dreamsower</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
You may choose not to untap Thalakos Dreamsower during your untap step.
Whenever Thalakos Dreamsower deals damage to an opponent, tap target creature. That creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step for as long as Thalakos Dreamsower remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0317</id>
    <name>Thalakos Lowlands</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool. Thalakos Lowlands doesn't untap during your next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0318</id>
    <name>Thalakos Mistfolk</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
{U}: Put Thalakos Mistfolk on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"They are ‘between' in every way."
—Lyna, Soltari emissary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0319</id>
    <name>Thalakos Seer</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
When Thalakos Seer leaves the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"You see our world when you shut your eyes so tightly that tiny shapes float before them."
—Lyna, to Ertai</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0320</id>
    <name>Thalakos Sentry</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow)</text>
    <flavorText>"Ill luck and poor geography caught the Thalakos between us and the Dauthi."
—Lyna, Soltari emissary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0321</id>
    <name>Thumbscrews</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you have five or more cards in hand, Thumbscrews deals 1 damage to target opponent.</text>
    <flavorText>"We will start small, I think."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0322</id>
    <name>Time Ebb</name>
    <text>Put target creature on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Gone today, here tomorrow."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0323</id>
    <name>Time Warp</name>
    <text>Target player takes an extra turn after this one.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let's do it again"
—Squee, goblin cabin hand</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0324</id>
    <name>Tooth and Claw</name>
    <text>Sacrifice two creatures: Put a 3/1 red Beast creature token named Carnivore onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"You deify nature as female—kind and gentle—yet you cringe at what is natural."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0325</id>
    <name>Torture Chamber</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a pain counter on Torture Chamber.
At the beginning of your end step, Torture Chamber deals damage to you equal to the number of pain counters on it.
{1}, {T}, Remove all pain counters from Torture Chamber: Torture Chamber deals damage to target creature equal to the number of pain counters removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0326</id>
    <name>Tradewind Rider</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}, Tap two untapped creatures you control: Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>It is said that the wind will blow the world past if you wait long enough.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0327</id>
    <name>Trained Armodon</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>These are its last days. Better to grow broad and heavy. Better that the enemy is crushed beneath its carcass.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0328</id>
    <name>Tranquility</name>
    <text>Destroy all enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>"Peace will come, but whether born of harmony or entropy I cannot say."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0329</id>
    <name>Trumpeting Armodon</name>
    <text>{1}{G}: Target creature blocks Trumpeting Armodon this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>These are its last days. But it will not go quietly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0330</id>
    <name>Twitch</name>
    <text>You may tap or untap target artifact, creature, or land.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Battles are won in nuance.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0331</id>
    <name>Unstable Shapeshifter</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, Unstable Shapeshifter becomes a copy of that creature and gains this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>"In a world of untruths, the living lie rules."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0332</id>
    <name>Vec Townships</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool. Vec Townships doesn't untap during your next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0333</id>
    <name>Verdant Force</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each upkeep, put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Burl, scurf, and bower
Birth fern and flower.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0334</id>
    <name>Verdigris</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>"Only the most sophisticated inventions can survive nature's unsophisticated motivations."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0335</id>
    <name>Vhati il-Dal</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature's power or toughness becomes 1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Sir, I just thought . . . ," explained Vhati.
"Don't think," interrupted Greven. "It doesn't suit you."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0336</id>
    <name>Volrath's Curse</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block and its activated abilities can't be activated. That creature's controller may sacrifice a permanent for that player to ignore this effect until end of turn.
{1}{U}: Return Volrath's Curse to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0337</id>
    <name>Wall of Diffusion</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Wall of Diffusion can block creatures with shadow as though they didn't have shadow.</text>
    <flavorText>"The injury was being caught between this world and our own; the insult was to find walls within."
—Lyna, Soltari emissary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0338</id>
    <name>Warmth</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a red spell, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Flame grows gentle with but a little distance."
—Orim, Samite healer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0339</id>
    <name>Wasteland</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{T}, Sacrifice Wasteland: Destroy target nonbasic land.</text>
    <flavorText>"The land promises nothing and keeps its promise."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0340</id>
    <name>Watchdog</name>
    <text>Watchdog blocks each turn if able.
As long as Watchdog is untapped, all creatures attacking you get -1/-0.</text>
    <flavorText>Its growl is a long, rumbling grind of gears and clockwork, its bark a blast of hissing steam.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0341</id>
    <name>Whim of Volrath</name>
    <text>Buyback {2} (You may pay an additional {2} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Change the text of target permanent by replacing all instances of one color word or basic land type with another until end of turn. (For example, you may change "nonred creature" to "nongreen creature" or "plainswalk" to "swampwalk.")</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0342</id>
    <name>Whispers of the Muse</name>
    <text>Buyback {5} (You may pay an additional {5} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I followed her song only to find it was a dirge."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0343</id>
    <name>Wild Wurm</name>
    <text>When Wild Wurm enters the battlefield, flip a coin. If you lose the flip, return Wild Wurm to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Wurm heads appear
Wild wurm near
Wurm tails you see
Wild wurm flee</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0344</id>
    <name>Wind Dancer</name>
    <text>Flying

{T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Flying like a bird does not make you as free as one."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0345</id>
    <name>Wind Drake</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Orim regarded Gerrard coolly. "You are like the drake," she said, her expression unchanging. "It works hard to maintain its position, but to us it seems to glide along effortlessly. You must do the same."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0346</id>
    <name>Winds of Rath</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures that aren't enchanted. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"There shall be a vast shout and then a vaster silence."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0347</id>
    <name>Winged Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Everything around here has cut a deal with gravity."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0348</id>
    <name>Winter's Grasp</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>Summer is buried there, centuries deep;
A crypt of years where seasons sleep.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0349</id>
    <name>Wood Sage</name>
    <text>{T}: Name a creature card. Reveal the top four cards of your library and put all of them with that name into your hand. Put the rest into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TMP0350</id>
    <name>Worthy Cause</name>
    <text>Buyback {2} (You may pay an additional {2} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
As an additional cost to cast Worthy Cause, sacrifice a creature.
You gain life equal to the sacrificed creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>