<cards name="Torment">
  <item>
    <id>TOR0001</id>
    <name>Angel of Retribution</name>
    <text>Flying, first strike</text>
    <flavorText>Bitter vengeance never glowed so bright nor sang so sweet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0002</id>
    <name>Aven Trooper</name>
    <text>Flying
{2}{W}, Discard a card: Aven Trooper gets +1/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The very skies seethe with the aven's hatred for the Cabal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0003</id>
    <name>Cleansing Meditation</name>
    <text>Destroy all enchantments.
Threshold — If seven or more cards are in your graveyard, instead destroy all enchantments, then return all cards in your graveyard destroyed this way to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0004</id>
    <name>Equal Treatment</name>
    <text>If any source would deal 1 or more damage to a creature or player this turn, it deals 2 damage to that creature or player instead.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0005</id>
    <name>Floating Shield</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As Floating Shield enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Enchanted creature has protection from the chosen color. This effect doesn't remove Floating Shield.
Sacrifice Floating Shield: Target creature gains protection from the chosen color until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0006</id>
    <name>Frantic Purification</name>
    <text>Destroy target enchantment.
Madness {W} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>By definition, madness ends in one of two ways: clarity . . . or death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0007</id>
    <name>Hypochondria</name>
    <text>{W}, Discard a card: Prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.
{W}, Sacrifice Hypochondria: Prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0008</id>
    <name>Major Teroh</name>
    <text>Flying
{3}{W}{W}, Sacrifice Major Teroh: Exile all black creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"I am the holy wind that shall avenge the Cabal's victims."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0009</id>
    <name>Militant Monk</name>
    <text>Vigilance
{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0010</id>
    <name>Morningtide</name>
    <text>Exile all cards from all graveyards.</text>
    <flavorText>"The spirits of the righteous shall rise into the sky. Even dirtwalkers will fly like aven."
—Major Teroh</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0011</id>
    <name>Mystic Familiar</name>
    <text>Flying
Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Mystic Familiar gets +1/+1 and has protection from black.</text>
    <flavorText>They soar, and the mystics follow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0012</id>
    <name>Pay No Heed</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage a source of your choice would deal this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Inhale life. Exhale pain."
—Mystic elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0013</id>
    <name>Possessed Nomad</name>
    <text>Vigilance
Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Possessed Nomad gets +1/+1, is black, and has "{2}{B}, {T}: Destroy target white creature."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0014</id>
    <name>Reborn Hero</name>
    <text>Vigilance
Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Reborn Hero has "When Reborn Hero is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {W}{W}. If you do, return Reborn Hero to the battlefield under your control."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0015</id>
    <name>Spirit Flare</name>
    <text>Tap target untapped creature you control. If you do, it deals damage equal to its power to target attacking or blocking creature an opponent controls.
Flashback—{1}{W}, Pay 3 life. (You may cast this card from your graveyard for its flashback cost. Then exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0016</id>
    <name>Stern Judge</name>
    <text>{T}: Each player loses 1 life for each Swamp he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"How to punish the guilty is up to the Ancestor. Deciding who merits such punishment is up to me."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0017</id>
    <name>Strength of Isolation</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+2 and has protection from black.
Madness {W} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>Don't mistake isolation for safety.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0018</id>
    <name>Teroh's Faithful</name>
    <text>When Teroh's Faithful enters the battlefield, you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The light of reason follows them even into battle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0019</id>
    <name>Teroh's Vanguard</name>
    <text>Flash
Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Teroh's Vanguard has "When Teroh's Vanguard enters the battlefield, creatures you control gain protection from black until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0020</id>
    <name>Transcendence</name>
    <text>You don't lose the game for having 0 or less life.

When you have 20 or more life, you lose the game.

Whenever you lose life, you gain 2 life for each 1 life you lost. (Damage dealt to you causes you to lose life.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0021</id>
    <name>Vengeful Dreams</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Vengeful Dreams, discard X cards.
Exile X target attacking creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Teroh dreams of his enemies' doom.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0022</id>
    <name>Alter Reality</name>
    <text>Change the text of target spell or permanent by replacing all instances of one color word with another. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)
Flashback {1}{U} (You may cast this card from your graveyard for its flashback cost. Then exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0023</id>
    <name>Ambassador Laquatus</name>
    <text>{3}: Target player puts the top three cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"He smiles with poisoned lips."
—Empress Llawan</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0024</id>
    <name>Aquamoeba</name>
    <text>Discard a card: Switch Aquamoeba's power and toughness until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Some tides need no moon.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0025</id>
    <name>Balshan Collaborator</name>
    <text>Flying
{B}: Balshan Collaborator gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Power, gold, crackers—every bird has its price."
—Chainer, dementia master</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0026</id>
    <name>Breakthrough</name>
    <text>Draw four cards, then choose X cards in your hand and discard the rest.</text>
    <flavorText>The ideas came flooding in so fast that they couldn't all be contained.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0027</id>
    <name>Cephalid Aristocrat</name>
    <text>Whenever Cephalid Aristocrat becomes the target of a spell or ability, put the top two cards of your library into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>It's easy to tell the difference between the devious cephalids and the trustworthy ones. The trustworthy ones are dead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0028</id>
    <name>Cephalid Illusionist</name>
    <text>Whenever Cephalid Illusionist becomes the target of a spell or ability, put the top three cards of your library into your graveyard.
{2}{U}, {T}: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by target creature you control this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0029</id>
    <name>Cephalid Sage</name>
    <text>Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Cephalid Sage has "When Cephalid Sage enters the battlefield, draw three cards, then discard two cards."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0030</id>
    <name>Cephalid Snitch</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Cephalid Snitch: Target creature loses protection from black until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The cautious are wary of their enemies. The wise are also wary of their friends.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0031</id>
    <name>Cephalid Vandal</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a shred counter on Cephalid Vandal. Then put the top card of your library into your graveyard for each shred counter on Cephalid Vandal.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0032</id>
    <name>Churning Eddy</name>
    <text>Return target creature and target land to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>"Magic is like the tide—both ebb, both flow, and both serve my whims."
—Empress Llawan</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0033</id>
    <name>Circular Logic</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1} for each card in your graveyard.
Madness {U} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0034</id>
    <name>Compulsion</name>
    <text>{1}{U}, Discard a card: Draw a card.
{1}{U}, Sacrifice Compulsion: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0035</id>
    <name>Coral Net</name>
    <text>Enchant green or white creature
Enchanted creature has "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice this creature unless you discard a card."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0036</id>
    <name>Deep Analysis</name>
    <text>Target player draws two cards.
Flashback—{1}{U}, Pay 3 life. (You may cast this card from your graveyard for its flashback cost. Then exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The specimen seems to be broken."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0037</id>
    <name>False Memories</name>
    <text>Put the top seven cards of your library into your graveyard. At the beginning of the next end step, exile seven cards from your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"My enemies will forget everything but their anguish."
—Ambassador Laquatus</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0038</id>
    <name>Ghostly Wings</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has flying.
Discard a card: Return enchanted creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0039</id>
    <name>Hydromorph Guardian</name>
    <text>{U}, Sacrifice Hydromorph Guardian: Counter target spell that targets one or more creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>In front of every strong leader is a pool of loyal bodyguards.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0040</id>
    <name>Hydromorph Gull</name>
    <text>Flying
{U}, Sacrifice Hydromorph Gull: Counter target spell that targets one or more creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"The only kind of water that should fly through the air is rain."
—Kamahl, pit fighter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0041</id>
    <name>Liquify</name>
    <text>Counter target spell with converted mana cost 3 or less. If that spell is countered this way, exile it instead of putting it into its owner's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0042</id>
    <name>Llawan, Cephalid Empress</name>
    <text>When Llawan, Cephalid Empress enters the battlefield, return all blue creatures your opponents control to their owners' hands.
Your opponents can't cast blue creature spells.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0043</id>
    <name>Obsessive Search</name>
    <text>Draw a card.
Madness {U} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>The question strained his sanity. The answer snapped it in half.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0044</id>
    <name>Plagiarize</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, if target player would draw a card, instead that player skips that draw and you draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Are you thinking what I'm thinking?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0045</id>
    <name>Possessed Aven</name>
    <text>Flying
Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Possessed Aven gets +1/+1, is black, and has "{2}{B}, {T}: Destroy target blue creature."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0046</id>
    <name>Retraced Image</name>
    <text>Reveal a card in your hand, then put that card onto the battlefield if it has the same name as a permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>An army from a soldier, a flock from a bird, a school from a fish . . . a profit from an atrocity.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0047</id>
    <name>Skywing Aven</name>
    <text>Flying
Discard a card: Return Skywing Aven to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"I am as the wind that bears me: harsh yet gentle, fleeting yet ever-present. Together we fly beyond imagination."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0048</id>
    <name>Stupefying Touch</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Stupefying Touch enters the battlefield, draw a card.
Enchanted creature's activated abilities can't be activated.</text>
    <flavorText>Just because your eyes are open doesn't mean you're awake.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0049</id>
    <name>Turbulent Dreams</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Turbulent Dreams, discard X cards.
Return X target nonland permanents to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>Laquatus dreams of seizing control.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0050</id>
    <name>Boneshard Slasher</name>
    <text>Flying
Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Boneshard Slasher gets +2/+2 and has "When Boneshard Slasher becomes the target of a spell or ability, sacrifice it."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0051</id>
    <name>Cabal Ritual</name>
    <text>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.
Threshold — Add {B}{B}{B}{B}{B} to your mana pool instead if seven or more cards are in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"Each syllable chills your veins. Each word rattles your mind."
—Cabal Patriarch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0052</id>
    <name>Cabal Surgeon</name>
    <text>{2}{B}{B}, {T}, Exile two cards from your graveyard: Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Clerics give up when their patients die. Can I help it if I'm more compassionate?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0053</id>
    <name>Cabal Torturer</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}: Target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.
Threshold — {3}{B}{B}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn. Activate this ability only if seven or more cards are in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0054</id>
    <name>Carrion Rats</name>
    <text>Whenever Carrion Rats attacks or blocks, any player may exile a card from his or her graveyard. If a player does, Carrion Rats assigns no combat damage this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Just what I need—more competition."
—Cabal grave robber</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0055</id>
    <name>Carrion Wurm</name>
    <text>Whenever Carrion Wurm attacks or blocks, any player may exile three cards from his or her graveyard. If a player does, Carrion Wurm assigns no combat damage this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Since it eats only carrion, sometimes it needs to make some from scratch.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0056</id>
    <name>Chainer, Dementia Master</name>
    <text>Nightmare creatures get +1/+1.
{B}{B}{B}, Pay 3 life: Put target creature card from a graveyard onto the battlefield under your control. That creature is black and is a Nightmare in addition to its other creature types.
When Chainer, Dementia Master leaves the battlefield, exile all Nightmares.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0057</id>
    <name>Chainer's Edict</name>
    <text>Target player sacrifices a creature.
Flashback {5}{B}{B} (You may cast this card from your graveyard for its flashback cost. Then exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>The pits have their own form of mercy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0058</id>
    <name>Crippling Fatigue</name>
    <text>Target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn.
Flashback—{1}{B}, Pay 3 life. (You may cast this card from your graveyard for its flashback cost. Then exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0059</id>
    <name>Dawn of the Dead</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you lose 1 life.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield. That creature gains haste until end of turn. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0060</id>
    <name>Faceless Butcher</name>
    <text>When Faceless Butcher enters the battlefield, exile target creature other than Faceless Butcher.
When Faceless Butcher leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to the battlefield under its owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0061</id>
    <name>Gloomdrifter</name>
    <text>Flying
Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Gloomdrifter has "When Gloomdrifter enters the battlefield, nonblack creatures get -2/-2 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0062</id>
    <name>Gravegouger</name>
    <text>When Gravegouger enters the battlefield, exile up to two target cards from a single graveyard.
When Gravegouger leaves the battlefield, return the exiled cards to their owner's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0063</id>
    <name>Grotesque Hybrid</name>
    <text>Whenever Grotesque Hybrid deals combat damage to a creature, destroy that creature. It can't be regenerated.
Discard a card: Grotesque Hybrid gains flying and protection from green and from white until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0064</id>
    <name>Hypnox</name>
    <text>Flying
When Hypnox enters the battlefield, if you cast it from your hand, exile all cards from target opponent's hand.
When Hypnox leaves the battlefield, return the exiled cards to their owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0065</id>
    <name>Ichorid</name>
    <text>Haste
At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice Ichorid.
At the beginning of your upkeep, if Ichorid is in your graveyard, you may exile a black creature card other than Ichorid from your graveyard. If you do, return Ichorid to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0066</id>
    <name>Insidious Dreams</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Insidious Dreams, discard X cards.
Search your library for X cards. Then shuffle your library and put those cards on top of it in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>Chainer dreams of ultimate knowledge.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0067</id>
    <name>Laquatus's Champion</name>
    <text>When Laquatus's Champion enters the battlefield, target player loses 6 life.
When Laquatus's Champion leaves the battlefield, that player gains 6 life.
{B}: Regenerate Laquatus's Champion.</text>
    <flavorText>Chainer's dark gift to a darker soul.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0068</id>
    <name>Last Laugh</name>
    <text>Whenever a permanent other than Last Laugh is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, Last Laugh deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.

When no creatures are on the battlefield, sacrifice Last Laugh.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0069</id>
    <name>Mesmeric Fiend</name>
    <text>When Mesmeric Fiend enters the battlefield, target opponent reveals his or her hand and you choose a nonland card from it. Exile that card.
When Mesmeric Fiend leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0070</id>
    <name>Mind Sludge</name>
    <text>Target player discards a card for each Swamp you control.</text>
    <flavorText>When you get into the swamp, the swamp gets into you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0071</id>
    <name>Mortal Combat</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if twenty or more creature cards are in your graveyard, you win the game.</text>
    <flavorText>The crowd roared, the fighters bled, and the dead piled high in the pits. Only the Cabal could win.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0072</id>
    <name>Mortiphobia</name>
    <text>{1}{B}, Discard a card: Exile target card from a graveyard.
{1}{B}, Sacrifice Mortiphobia: Exile target card from a graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0073</id>
    <name>Mutilate</name>
    <text>All creatures get -1/-1 until end of turn for each Swamp you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"They appreciate my handiwork. I hear their joy in every scream."
—Chainer, dementia master</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0074</id>
    <name>Nantuko Shade</name>
    <text>{B}: Nantuko Shade gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"If the Nantuko only knew what awaits them beyond death, they would abandon all they hold dear."
—Cabal Patriarch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0075</id>
    <name>Organ Grinder</name>
    <text>{T}, Exile three cards from your graveyard: Target player loses 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>It knows what makes you tick. It knows how to make the ticking stop.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0076</id>
    <name>Psychotic Haze</name>
    <text>Psychotic Haze deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.
Madness {1}{B} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0077</id>
    <name>Putrid Imp</name>
    <text>Discard a card: Putrid Imp gains flying until end of turn.
Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Putrid Imp gets +1/+1 and can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0078</id>
    <name>Rancid Earth</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.
Threshold — If seven or more cards are in your graveyard, instead destroy that land and Rancid Earth deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0079</id>
    <name>Restless Dreams</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Restless Dreams, discard X cards.
Return X target creature cards from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Braids dreams of dark rebirth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0080</id>
    <name>Sengir Vampire</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Whenever a creature dealt damage by Sengir Vampire this turn is put into a graveyard, put a +1/+1 counter on Sengir Vampire.</text>
    <flavorText>Empires rise and fall, but evil is eternal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0081</id>
    <name>Shade's Form</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has "{B}: This creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn."
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, return that card to the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0082</id>
    <name>Shambling Swarm</name>
    <text>When Shambling Swarm is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, distribute three -1/-1 counters among one, two, or three target creatures. For each -1/-1 counter you put on a creature this way, remove a -1/-1 counter from that creature at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>Chainer's madness personified, it exists only to slaughter the innocent.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0083</id>
    <name>Sickening Dreams</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Sickening Dreams, discard X cards.
Sickening Dreams deals X damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>The Patriarch dreams of vile plague.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0084</id>
    <name>Slithery Stalker</name>
    <text>Swampwalk
When Slithery Stalker enters the battlefield, exile target green or white creature an opponent controls.
When Slithery Stalker leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to the battlefield under its owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0085</id>
    <name>Soul Scourge</name>
    <text>Flying
When Soul Scourge enters the battlefield, target player loses 3 life.
When Soul Scourge leaves the battlefield, that player gains 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0086</id>
    <name>Strength of Lunacy</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+1 and has protection from white.
Madness {B} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>Don't confuse lunacy with courage.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0087</id>
    <name>Unhinge</name>
    <text>Target player discards a card.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Don't let your mind wander—it might not come back."
—Braids, dementia summoner</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0088</id>
    <name>Waste Away</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Waste Away, discard a card.
Target creature gets -5/-5 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Chainer's insanity touched nearly every living thing—including viruses.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0089</id>
    <name>Zombie Trailblazer</name>
    <text>Tap an untapped Zombie you control: Target land becomes a Swamp until end of turn.
Tap an untapped Zombie you control: Target creature gains swampwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Some zombies are natural-reborn leaders.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0090</id>
    <name>Accelerate</name>
    <text>Target creature gains haste until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I've seen lightning move slower."
—Nomad sentry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0091</id>
    <name>Balthor the Stout</name>
    <text>Other Barbarian creatures get +1/+1.
{R}: Another target Barbarian creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I like to think of him as concentrated barbarian."
—Kamahl, pit fighter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0092</id>
    <name>Barbarian Outcast</name>
    <text>When you control no Swamps, sacrifice Barbarian Outcast.</text>
    <flavorText>"We offer power to anyone willing to take it. Sadly, few are unburdened enough by their prejudices to accept."
—Cabal surgeon</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0093</id>
    <name>Crackling Club</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+0.
Sacrifice Crackling Club: Crackling Club deals 1 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>It adds injury to injury.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0094</id>
    <name>Crazed Firecat</name>
    <text>When Crazed Firecat enters the battlefield, flip a coin until you lose a flip. Put a +1/+1 counter on Crazed Firecat for each flip you win.</text>
    <flavorText>"The longer it's caged, the madder it gets."
—Firecat handler</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0095</id>
    <name>Devastating Dreams</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Devastating Dreams, discard X cards at random.
Each player sacrifices X lands. Devastating Dreams deals X damage to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Kamahl dreams of storms of fire.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0096</id>
    <name>Enslaved Dwarf</name>
    <text>{R}, Sacrifice Enslaved Dwarf: Target black creature gets +1/+0 and gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Captive dwarves always regain their freedom, either through escape or through a desperate, fiery death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0097</id>
    <name>Fiery Temper</name>
    <text>Fiery Temper deals 3 damage to target creature or player.
Madness {R} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0098</id>
    <name>Flaming Gambit</name>
    <text>Flaming Gambit deals X damage to target player. That player may choose a creature he or she controls and have Flaming Gambit deal that damage to it instead.
Flashback {X}{R}{R} (You may cast this card from your graveyard for its flashback cost. Then exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0099</id>
    <name>Flash of Defiance</name>
    <text>Green creatures and white creatures can't block this turn.
Flashback—{1}{R}, Pay 3 life. (You may cast this card from your graveyard for its flashback cost. Then exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0100</id>
    <name>Grim Lavamancer</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}, Exile two cards from your graveyard: Grim Lavamancer deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Fools dig for water, corpses, or gold. The earth's real treasure is far deeper."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0101</id>
    <name>Hell-Bent Raider</name>
    <text>First strike, haste
Discard a card at random: Hell-Bent Raider gains protection from white until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>He doesn't slow until his spear is weighted with corpses.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0102</id>
    <name>Kamahl's Sledge</name>
    <text>Kamahl's Sledge deals 4 damage to target creature.
Threshold — If seven or more cards are in your graveyard, instead Kamahl's Sledge deals 4 damage to that creature and 4 damage to that creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0103</id>
    <name>Longhorn Firebeast</name>
    <text>When Longhorn Firebeast enters the battlefield, any opponent may have it deal 5 damage to him or her. If a player does, sacrifice Longhorn Firebeast.</text>
    <flavorText>Its blast can fuse armor to bone, leaving skeletons that glint brightly in the sun.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0104</id>
    <name>Overmaster</name>
    <text>The next instant or sorcery spell you cast this turn can't be countered by spells or abilities.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Trickery can't defeat raw power."
—Matoc, lavamancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0105</id>
    <name>Pardic Arsonist</name>
    <text>Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Pardic Arsonist has "When Pardic Arsonist enters the battlefield, it deals 3 damage to target creature or player."</text>
    <flavorText>Otaria's epidemic of insanity didn't affect certain barbarians—but no one noticed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0106</id>
    <name>Pardic Collaborator</name>
    <text>First strike
{B}: Pardic Collaborator gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We've been taught that strength is everything. So how can an alliance with the strongest be a betrayal?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0107</id>
    <name>Pardic Lancer</name>
    <text>Discard a card at random: Pardic Lancer gets +1/+0 and gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>He gets to the point right away.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0108</id>
    <name>Petradon</name>
    <text>When Petradon enters the battlefield, exile two target lands.
When Petradon leaves the battlefield, return the exiled cards to the battlefield under their owners' control.
{R}: Petradon gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0109</id>
    <name>Petravark</name>
    <text>When Petravark enters the battlefield, exile target land.
When Petravark leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to the battlefield under its owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0110</id>
    <name>Pitchstone Wall</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Whenever you discard a card, you may sacrifice Pitchstone Wall. If you do, return the discarded card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Its material may not be precious, but the minds it protects are.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0111</id>
    <name>Possessed Barbarian</name>
    <text>First strike
Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Possessed Barbarian gets +1/+1, is black, and has "{2}{B}, {T}: Destroy target red creature."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0112</id>
    <name>Pyromania</name>
    <text>{1}{R}, Discard a card at random: Pyromania deals 1 damage to target creature or player.
{1}{R}, Sacrifice Pyromania: Pyromania deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0113</id>
    <name>Radiate</name>
    <text>Choose target instant or sorcery spell that targets only a single permanent or player. Copy that spell for each other permanent or player the spell could target. Each copy targets a different one of those permanents and players.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0114</id>
    <name>Skullscorch</name>
    <text>Target player discards two cards at random unless that player has Skullscorch deal 4 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>"A good whack on the head usually has the same effect."
—Kamahl, pit fighter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0115</id>
    <name>Sonic Seizure</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Sonic Seizure, discard a card at random.
Sonic Seizure deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0116</id>
    <name>Temporary Insanity</name>
    <text>Untap target creature with power less than the number of cards in your graveyard and gain control of it until end of turn. That creature gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0117</id>
    <name>Violent Eruption</name>
    <text>Violent Eruption deals 4 damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.
Madness {1}{R}{R} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0118</id>
    <name>Acorn Harvest</name>
    <text>Put two 1/1 green Squirrel creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Flashback—{1}{G}, Pay 3 life. (You may cast this card from your graveyard for its flashback cost. Then exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0119</id>
    <name>Anurid Scavenger</name>
    <text>Protection from black
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Anurid Scavenger unless you put a card from your graveyard on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Krosa's topmost bottom feeder.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0120</id>
    <name>Arrogant Wurm</name>
    <text>Trample
Madness {2}{G} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>It's hard to be humble when the whole world is bite size.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0121</id>
    <name>Basking Rootwalla</name>
    <text>{1}{G}: Basking Rootwalla gets +2/+2 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.
Madness {0} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0122</id>
    <name>Centaur Chieftain</name>
    <text>Haste
Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Centaur Chieftain has "When Centaur Chieftain enters the battlefield, creatures you control get +1/+1 and gain trample until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0123</id>
    <name>Centaur Veteran</name>
    <text>Trample
{G}, Discard a card: Regenerate Centaur Veteran.</text>
    <flavorText>He wears his scars like badges of honor, warning his foes that he's not easily defeated.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0124</id>
    <name>Dwell on the Past</name>
    <text>Target player shuffles up to four target cards from his or her graveyard into his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>None can find what hasn't been lost.
—Nantuko teaching</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0125</id>
    <name>Far Wanderings</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.
Threshold — If seven or more cards are in your graveyard, instead search your library for three basic land cards and put them onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0126</id>
    <name>Gurzigost</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Gurzigost unless you put two cards from your graveyard on the bottom of your library.
{G}{G}, Discard a card: You may have Gurzigost assign its combat damage this turn as though it weren't blocked.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0127</id>
    <name>Insist</name>
    <text>The next creature spell you cast this turn can't be countered by spells or abilities.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Finesse is no match for brute force."
—Seton, centaur druid</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0128</id>
    <name>Invigorating Falls</name>
    <text>You gain life equal to the number of creature cards in all graveyards.</text>
    <flavorText>Krosan druids do not fear death, for they know that nature will only prosper from their passing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0129</id>
    <name>Krosan Constrictor</name>
    <text>Swampwalk
{T}: Target black creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's a slithering, coldblooded menace. I've gotta respect that."
—Braids, dementia summoner</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0130</id>
    <name>Krosan Restorer</name>
    <text>{T}: Untap target land.
Threshold — {T}: Untap up to three target lands. Activate this ability only if seven or more cards are in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0131</id>
    <name>Nantuko Blightcutter</name>
    <text>Protection from black
Threshold — Nantuko Blightcutter gets +1/+1 for each black permanent your opponents control as long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0132</id>
    <name>Nantuko Calmer</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}, Sacrifice Nantuko Calmer: Destroy target enchantment.
Threshold — Nantuko Calmer gets +1/+1 as long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0133</id>
    <name>Nantuko Cultivator</name>
    <text>When Nantuko Cultivator enters the battlefield, you may discard any number of land cards. Put that many +1/+1 counters on Nantuko Cultivator and draw that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0134</id>
    <name>Narcissism</name>
    <text>{G}, Discard a card: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.
{G}, Sacrifice Narcissism: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0135</id>
    <name>Nostalgic Dreams</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Nostalgic Dreams, discard X cards.
Return X target cards from your graveyard to your hand. Exile Nostalgic Dreams.</text>
    <flavorText>Seton dreams of life renewed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0136</id>
    <name>Parallel Evolution</name>
    <text>For each creature token on the battlefield, its controller puts a token that's a copy of that creature onto the battlefield.
Flashback {4}{G}{G}{G} (You may cast this card from your graveyard for its flashback cost. Then exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0137</id>
    <name>Possessed Centaur</name>
    <text>Trample
Threshold — As long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard, Possessed Centaur gets +1/+1, is black, and has "{2}{B}, {T}: Destroy target green creature."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0138</id>
    <name>Seton's Scout</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)
Threshold — Seton's Scout gets +2/+2 as long as seven or more cards are in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0139</id>
    <name>Cabal Coffers</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Add {B} to your mana pool for each Swamp you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Deep within the Cabal's vault, the Mirari pulsed like a dead sun—and its darkness radiated across Otaria.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0140</id>
    <name>Tainted Field</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {W} or {B} to your mana pool. Activate this ability only if you control a Swamp.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0141</id>
    <name>Tainted Isle</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool. Activate this ability only if you control a Swamp.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0142</id>
    <name>Tainted Peak</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool. Activate this ability only if you control a Swamp.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>TOR0143</id>
    <name>Tainted Wood</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {B} or {G} to your mana pool. Activate this ability only if you control a Swamp.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>