<cards name="Urza's Legacy">
  <item>
    <id>ULG0001</id>
    <name>Angelic Curator</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from artifacts</text>
    <flavorText>"Do not treat your people as you treat your artifacts. Let them go, and they will live; seal them here, and they will die."
—Urza, to Radiant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0002</id>
    <name>Blessed Reversal</name>
    <text>You gain 3 life for each creature attacking you.</text>
    <flavorText>Even an enemy is a valuable resource.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0003</id>
    <name>Burst of Energy</name>
    <text>Untap target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"I stand ready to die for our world. Who will stand with me?"
—Radiant, archangel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0004</id>
    <name>Cessation</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack.
When Cessation is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Cessation to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"The face of Light will shine upon them, and they will know war no more."
—Song of All, canto 918</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0005</id>
    <name>Defender of Law</name>
    <text>Flash
Protection from red</text>
    <flavorText>"It is not my place to question Radiant's rule. I exist to enforce her will."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0006</id>
    <name>Devout Harpist</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target Aura attached to a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The notes themselves are irrelevant. The music's effect, however, is worth ten armies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0007</id>
    <name>Erase</name>
    <text>Exile target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>Perception is more pleasing than truth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0008</id>
    <name>Expendable Troops</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Expendable Troops: Expendable Troops deals 2 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>No doubt in their minds, no fear in their hearts.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0009</id>
    <name>Hope and Glory</name>
    <text>Untap two target creatures. Each of them gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Serra ruled by faith. I cannot afford that luxury."
—Radiant, archangel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0010</id>
    <name>Iron Will</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +0/+4 until end of turn.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0011</id>
    <name>Karmic Guide</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from black
Echo {3}{W}{W} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Karmic Guide enters the battlefield, return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0012</id>
    <name>Knighthood</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>"He has returned. He who brought the dark ones. He who poisoned our paradise. How shall we greet him? With swift and certain death"
—Radiant, archangel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0013</id>
    <name>Martyr's Cause</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to target creature or player this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>Dying is a soldier's talent.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0014</id>
    <name>Mother of Runes</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature you control gains protection from the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"My family protects all families."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0015</id>
    <name>Opal Avenger</name>
    <text>When you have 10 or less life, if Opal Avenger is an enchantment, Opal Avenger becomes a 3/5 Soldier creature.</text>
    <flavorText>As the sun grew cold in the realm, the statue grew warm.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0016</id>
    <name>Opal Champion</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts a creature spell, if Opal Champion is an enchantment, Opal Champion becomes a 3/3 Knight creature with first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0017</id>
    <name>Peace and Quiet</name>
    <text>Destroy two target enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>"In time our realm will shine again. But it will gleam only when we scour away the taint of doubt."
—Radiant, archangel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0018</id>
    <name>Planar Collapse</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if there are four or more creatures on the battlefield, sacrifice Planar Collapse and destroy all creatures. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>With heavy heart, Urza doused one world's light to rekindle another's.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0019</id>
    <name>Purify</name>
    <text>Destroy all artifacts and enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our Mother The sky was Her hair; the sun, Her face. She danced on the grass and in the hills."
—Song of All, canto 23</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0020</id>
    <name>Radiant, Archangel</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance
Radiant, Archangel gets +1/+1 for each other creature with flying on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0021</id>
    <name>Radiant's Dragoons</name>
    <text>Echo {3}{W} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Radiant's Dragoons enters the battlefield, you gain 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0022</id>
    <name>Radiant's Judgment</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature with power 4 or greater.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0023</id>
    <name>Sustainer of the Realm</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Sustainer of the Realm blocks, it gets +0/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The harder you push, the stronger we become."
—Radiant, to Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0024</id>
    <name>Tragic Poet</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Tragic Poet: Return target enchantment card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"I would weep, but my tears have been stolen; I would shout, but my voice has been taken. Thus, I write."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0025</id>
    <name>Anthroplasm</name>
    <text>Anthroplasm enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it.
{X}, {T}: Remove all +1/+1 counters from Anthroplasm and put X +1/+1 counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>I never metamorphosis I didn't like.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0026</id>
    <name>Archivist</name>
    <text>{T}: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Some do. Some teach. The rest look it up.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0027</id>
    <name>Aura Flux</name>
    <text>Other enchantments have "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice this enchantment unless you pay {2}."</text>
    <flavorText>To some, the Tolarian sunrise was a blinding flash; to others, a lingering glow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0028</id>
    <name>Bouncing Beebles</name>
    <text>Bouncing Beebles is unblockable as long as defending player controls an artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>Beebles are frequently hurled against stone surfaces at high speed but always zing back into the air with a giggle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0029</id>
    <name>Cloud of Faeries</name>
    <text>Flying
When Cloud of Faeries enters the battlefield, untap up to two lands.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0030</id>
    <name>Delusions of Mediocrity</name>
    <text>When Delusions of Mediocrity enters the battlefield, you gain 10 life.
When Delusions of Mediocrity leaves the battlefield, you lose 10 life.</text>
    <flavorText>When nothing but second best will do.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0031</id>
    <name>Fleeting Image</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
{1}{U}: Return Fleeting Image to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Horas swore off drinking, but after meeting the creature a second time he decided he'd better start again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0032</id>
    <name>Frantic Search</name>
    <text>Draw two cards, then discard two cards. Untap up to three lands.</text>
    <flavorText>Motivation was high in the academy once students realized flunking their exams could kill them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0033</id>
    <name>Intervene</name>
    <text>Counter target spell that targets a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"At first I simply observed. But I found that without investment in others, life serves no purpose."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0034</id>
    <name>King Crab</name>
    <text>{1}{U}, {T}: Put target green creature on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'm allergic to shellfish—not only did it kill my entire village, it also gave me this nasty rash."
—Olivia, fisher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0035</id>
    <name>Levitation</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Barrin's pride in his apprentice was diminished somewhat when he had to get the others back down.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0036</id>
    <name>Miscalculation</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {2}.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0037</id>
    <name>Opportunity</name>
    <text>Target player draws four cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"He cocooned himself alone in his workshop for months. When he finally emerged, all broad grins and excited chatter, I knew he'd found his answer."
—Barrin, master wizard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0038</id>
    <name>Palinchron</name>
    <text>Flying
When Palinchron enters the battlefield, untap up to seven lands.
{2}{U}{U}: Return Palinchron to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0039</id>
    <name>Raven Familiar</name>
    <text>Flying
Echo {2}{U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Raven Familiar enters the battlefield, look at the top three cards of your library. Put one of them into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0040</id>
    <name>Rebuild</name>
    <text>Return all artifacts to their owners' hands.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0041</id>
    <name>Second Chance</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you have 5 or less life, sacrifice Second Chance and take an extra turn after this one.</text>
    <flavorText>The greatest gift is the opportunity to right one's wrongs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0042</id>
    <name>Slow Motion</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, that player sacrifices that creature unless he or she pays {2}.
When Slow Motion is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Slow Motion to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0043</id>
    <name>Snap</name>
    <text>Return target creature to its owner's hand. Untap up to two lands.</text>
    <flavorText>Good riddance.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0044</id>
    <name>Thornwind Faeries</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Thornwind Faeries deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Guarding the ship is the Thornwinds' first concern. Getting along with the locals ranks fourth or fifth at best.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0045</id>
    <name>Tinker</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Tinker, sacrifice an artifact.
Search your library for an artifact card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"I wonder how it feels to be bored."
—Jhoira, artificer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0046</id>
    <name>Vigilant Drake</name>
    <text>Flying

{2}{U}: Untap Vigilant Drake.</text>
    <flavorText>Awake and awing in the blink of an eye.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0047</id>
    <name>Walking Sponge</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature loses your choice of flying, first strike, or trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Not only does it catch fish, it cleans them too.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0048</id>
    <name>Weatherseed Faeries</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from red</text>
    <flavorText>Two days after the forge was completed, the faeries were immune to its flames.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0049</id>
    <name>Bone Shredder</name>
    <text>Flying
Echo {2}{B} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Bone Shredder enters the battlefield, destroy target nonartifact, nonblack creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0050</id>
    <name>Brink of Madness</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you have no cards in hand, sacrifice Brink of Madness and target opponent discards his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"The fools thought me dead. But I built an empire inside my tomb."
—Kerrick, sleeper agent</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0051</id>
    <name>Engineered Plague</name>
    <text>As Engineered Plague enters the battlefield, choose a creature type.

All creatures of the chosen type get -1/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>"The admixture of bitterwort in the viral brew has produced most favorable results."
—Phyrexian progress notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0052</id>
    <name>Eviscerator</name>
    <text>Protection from white
When Eviscerator enters the battlefield, you lose 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>It roamed the time bubble like a captured animal. Kerrick knew he must soon find a way to unleash it on Tolaria or destroy it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0053</id>
    <name>Fog of Gnats</name>
    <text>Flying
{B}: Regenerate Fog of Gnats.</text>
    <flavorText>You can swat a thousand gnats, but a thousand more will assail you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0054</id>
    <name>Giant Cockroach</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>If the sun ever hit the swamp, where would these scurry to?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0055</id>
    <name>Lurking Skirge</name>
    <text>When a creature is put into an opponent's graveyard from the battlefield, if Lurking Skirge is an enchantment, Lurking Skirge becomes a 3/2 Imp creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>They never miss a funeral.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0056</id>
    <name>No Mercy</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature deals damage to you, destroy it.</text>
    <flavorText>"We had years to prepare, while they had mere minutes."
—Kerrick, sleeper agent</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0057</id>
    <name>Ostracize</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You choose a creature card from it. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>Kerrick was to find that some borders can never be crossed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0058</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Broodlings</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice a creature: Put a +1/+1 counter on Phyrexian Broodlings.</text>
    <flavorText>With limited resources and near unlimited time, Kerrick used parts from one beast to build another.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0059</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Debaser</name>
    <text>Flying

{T}, Sacrifice Phyrexian Debaser: Target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The second stage of the illness: high fever and severe infectiousness."
—Phyrexian progress notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0060</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Defiler</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Phyrexian Defiler: Target creature gets -3/-3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The third stage of the illness: muscle aches and persistent cough."
—Phyrexian progress notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0061</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Denouncer</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Phyrexian Denouncer: Target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The first stage of the illness: rash and nausea."
—Phyrexian progress notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0062</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Plaguelord</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Phyrexian Plaguelord: Target creature gets -4/-4 until end of turn.
Sacrifice a creature: Target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The final stage of the illness: delirium, convulsions, and death."
—Phyrexian progress notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0063</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Reclamation</name>
    <text>{1}{B}, Pay 2 life: Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Death is no excuse to stop working.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0064</id>
    <name>Plague Beetle</name>
    <text>Swampwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Swamp.)</text>
    <flavorText>It is the harbinger of disease, not the carrier.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0065</id>
    <name>Rank and File</name>
    <text>When Rank and File enters the battlefield, green creatures get -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Left, right, left, right . . . hmm. Okay—left, left, left, left, . . ."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0066</id>
    <name>Sick and Tired</name>
    <text>Two target creatures each get -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Phyrexians' only interest in organic life is discerning its weakness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0067</id>
    <name>Sleeper's Guile</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has fear. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
When Sleeper's Guile is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Sleeper's Guile to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0068</id>
    <name>Subversion</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, each opponent loses 1 life. You gain life equal to the life lost this way.</text>
    <flavorText>Kerrick's corrupt domain swelled like a blister on Tolaria's skin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0069</id>
    <name>Swat</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature with power 2 or less.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0070</id>
    <name>Tethered Skirge</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Tethered Skirge becomes the target of a spell or ability, you lose 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>It bites the hand that leads it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0071</id>
    <name>Treacherous Link</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
All damage that would be dealt to enchanted creature is dealt to its controller instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"You cannot possibly know the toll your alliances will exact from you."
—Barrin, to Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0072</id>
    <name>Unearth</name>
    <text>Return target creature card with converted mana cost 3 or less from your graveyard to the battlefield.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0073</id>
    <name>About Face</name>
    <text>Switch target creature's power and toughness until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The overconfident are the most vulnerable.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0074</id>
    <name>Avalanche Riders</name>
    <text>Haste
Echo {3}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Avalanche Riders enters the battlefield, destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0075</id>
    <name>Defender of Chaos</name>
    <text>Flash
Protection from white</text>
    <flavorText>Some knights will not follow orders—only disorder.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0076</id>
    <name>Ghitu Fire-Eater</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Ghitu Fire-Eater: Ghitu Fire-Eater deals damage equal to its power to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"They are called ‘Mi'uto,' which means ‘one use.'"
—Jhoira, artificer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0077</id>
    <name>Ghitu Slinger</name>
    <text>Echo {2}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Ghitu Slinger enters the battlefield, it deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>If you survive a slinger attack, the slinger wished you to live.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0078</id>
    <name>Ghitu War Cry</name>
    <text>{R}: Target creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The war cry is not simply a shout but a sacrament.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0079</id>
    <name>Goblin Medics</name>
    <text>Whenever Goblin Medics becomes tapped, it deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"First, do some harm."
—Oath of Goblins</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0080</id>
    <name>Goblin Welder</name>
    <text>{T}: Choose target artifact a player controls and target artifact card in that player's graveyard. If both targets are still legal as this ability resolves, that player simultaneously sacrifices the artifact and returns the artifact card to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"I wrecked your metal guy, boss. But look I made you an ashtray."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0081</id>
    <name>Granite Grip</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 for each Mountain you control.</text>
    <flavorText>There's beauty in the desert—but it's best to view it from afar.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0082</id>
    <name>Impending Disaster</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if there are seven or more lands on the battlefield, sacrifice Impending Disaster and destroy all lands.</text>
    <flavorText>"The goblins are in charge of maintenance? Why not just set it on fire now and call it a day?"
—Whip Tongue, viashino technician</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0083</id>
    <name>Last-Ditch Effort</name>
    <text>Sacrifice any number of creatures. Last-Ditch Effort deals damage to target creature or player equal to the number of creatures sacrificed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you're gonna lose, at least make sure they don't win as much."
—Jula, goblin raider</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0084</id>
    <name>Lava Axe</name>
    <text>Lava Axe deals 5 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Catch"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0085</id>
    <name>Molten Hydra</name>
    <text>{1}{R}{R}: Put a +1/+1 counter on Molten Hydra.
{T}, Remove all +1/+1 counters from Molten Hydra: Molten Hydra deals damage to target creature or player equal to the number of counters removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>Keep off the glass.Hydra warning sign</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0086</id>
    <name>Parch</name>
    <text>Choose one — Parch deals 2 damage to target creature or player; or Parch deals 4 damage to target blue creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your porous flesh betrays you."
—Fire Eye, viashino bey</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0087</id>
    <name>Pygmy Pyrosaur</name>
    <text>Pygmy Pyrosaur can't block.

{R}: Pygmy Pyrosaur gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Do not judge a lizard by its size.
—Ghitu proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0088</id>
    <name>Pyromancy</name>
    <text>{3}, Discard a card at random: Pyromancy deals damage to target creature or player equal to the converted mana cost of the discarded card.</text>
    <flavorText>Who harnesses fire controls the world.
—Ghitu proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0089</id>
    <name>Rack and Ruin</name>
    <text>Destroy two target artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>"My people are bound by masters centuries dead. Each artifact we destroy is another link broken in that chain."
—Barb Tail, viashino heretic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0090</id>
    <name>Rivalry</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, if that player controls more lands than each other player, Rivalry deals 2 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>The goblins revered it; the viashino defended it. Only Urza understood it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0091</id>
    <name>Shivan Phoenix</name>
    <text>Flying
When Shivan Phoenix is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Shivan Phoenix to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>To strike down the phoenix is to slash at the flame.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0092</id>
    <name>Sluggishness</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't block.
When Sluggishness is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Sluggishness to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Vark decided to lie down and think of a good excuse to quit working.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0093</id>
    <name>Viashino Bey</name>
    <text>If Viashino Bey attacks, all creatures you control attack if able.</text>
    <flavorText>When the bey runs, match his stride.
—Viashino saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0094</id>
    <name>Viashino Cutthroat</name>
    <text>Haste
At the beginning of the end step, return Viashino Cutthroat to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"You guys go on ahead. I'll catch up with ya."
—Vark, goblin scout, last words</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0095</id>
    <name>Viashino Heretic</name>
    <text>{1}{R}, {T}: Destroy target artifact. Viashino Heretic deals damage to that artifact's controller equal to the artifact's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"The past is buried for good reason."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0096</id>
    <name>Viashino Sandscout</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)
At the beginning of the end step, return Viashino Sandscout to its owner's hand. (Return it only if it's on the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0097</id>
    <name>Bloated Toad</name>
    <text>Protection from blue
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0098</id>
    <name>Crop Rotation</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Crop Rotation, sacrifice a land.
Search your library for a land card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Hmm . . . maybe lotuses this year."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0099</id>
    <name>Darkwatch Elves</name>
    <text>Protection from black
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0100</id>
    <name>Defense of the Heart</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if an opponent controls three or more creatures, sacrifice Defense of the Heart, search your library for up to two creature cards, and put those cards onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0101</id>
    <name>Deranged Hermit</name>
    <text>Echo {3}{G}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Deranged Hermit enters the battlefield, put four 1/1 green Squirrel creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Squirrel creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0102</id>
    <name>Gang of Elk</name>
    <text>Whenever Gang of Elk becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn for each creature blocking it.</text>
    <flavorText>The elk is Gaea's favorite, who wears the forest on its brow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0103</id>
    <name>Harmonic Convergence</name>
    <text>Put all enchantments on top of their owners' libraries.</text>
    <flavorText>When the eternal stars align, can mere mortals resist?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0104</id>
    <name>Hidden Gibbons</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts an instant spell, if Hidden Gibbons is an enchantment, Hidden Gibbons becomes a 4/4 Ape creature.</text>
    <flavorText>When these apes want something, it's a matter of gibbon take.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0105</id>
    <name>Lone Wolf</name>
    <text>You may have Lone Wolf assign its combat damage as though it weren't blocked.</text>
    <flavorText>A wolf without a pack is either a survivor or a brute.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0106</id>
    <name>Might of Oaks</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +7/+7 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Suddenly, she couldn't see the acorns for the trees.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0107</id>
    <name>Multani, Maro-Sorcerer</name>
    <text>Shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)
Multani's power and toughness are each equal to the total number of cards in all players' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>"To make peace with the forest, make peace with me."
—Multani, to Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0108</id>
    <name>Multani's Acolyte</name>
    <text>Echo {G}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Multani's Acolyte enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0109</id>
    <name>Multani's Presence</name>
    <text>Whenever a spell you've cast is countered, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>When a tree falls in the forest, Multani hears it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0110</id>
    <name>Rancor</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+0 and has trample.
When Rancor is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Rancor to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Hatred outlives the hateful.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0111</id>
    <name>Repopulate</name>
    <text>Shuffle all creature cards from target player's graveyard into that player's library.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0112</id>
    <name>Silk Net</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +1/+1 and gains reach until end of turn. (It can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes it's possible to pull a meal out of thin air.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0113</id>
    <name>Simian Grunts</name>
    <text>Flash
Echo {2}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>These monkeys mean business.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0114</id>
    <name>Treefolk Mystic</name>
    <text>Whenever Treefolk Mystic blocks or becomes blocked by a creature, destroy all Auras attached to that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Urza's wards fell from him like autumn leaves as he entered the dreaming grove. He awoke imprisoned in living wood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0115</id>
    <name>Weatherseed Elf</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gains forestwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"My grandmother once told me the future of our world was inside the Weatherseed. When I touched it, I knew she was right."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0116</id>
    <name>Weatherseed Treefolk</name>
    <text>Trample
When Weatherseed Treefolk is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Weatherseed Treefolk to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0117</id>
    <name>Wing Snare</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Argoth's doom rained from a clear sky. Yavimaya will not share that fate."
—Multani, maro-sorcerer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0118</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Granger</name>
    <text>Echo {2}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Yavimaya Granger enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a basic land card, put that card onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0119</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Scion</name>
    <text>Protection from artifacts</text>
    <flavorText>Each time the saw blade bit, the tree spat it out.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0120</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Wurm</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>When the gorilla playfully grabbed the wurm's tail, the wurm doubled back and playfully ate the gorilla's head.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0121</id>
    <name>Angel's Trumpet</name>
    <text>All creatures have vigilance.
At the beginning of each player's end step, tap all untapped creatures that player controls that didn't attack this turn. Angel's Trumpet deals damage to the player equal to the number of creatures tapped this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0122</id>
    <name>Beast of Burden</name>
    <text>Beast of Burden's power and toughness are each equal to the number of creatures on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"If it is meant to be nothing but a machine," Karn finally asked Jhoira, "why did Urza build it to be like me?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0123</id>
    <name>Crawlspace</name>
    <text>No more than two creatures can attack you each combat.</text>
    <flavorText>The goblins did not understand their attraction to the mana rig. They simply knew it was where they belonged.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0124</id>
    <name>Damping Engine</name>
    <text>A player who controls more permanents than each other player can't play lands or cast artifact, creature, or enchantment spells. That player may sacrifice a permanent for that player to ignore this effect until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0125</id>
    <name>Defense Grid</name>
    <text>Each spell costs {3} more to cast except during its controller's turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We've managed to keep the goblins in their assigned areas, but there's little we can do about the smell."
—Whip Tongue, viashino technician</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0126</id>
    <name>Grim Monolith</name>
    <text>Grim Monolith doesn't untap during your untap step.

{T}: Add {3} to your mana pool.

{4}: Untap Grim Monolith.</text>
    <flavorText>Part prison, part home.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0127</id>
    <name>Iron Maiden</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each opponent's upkeep, Iron Maiden deals X damage to that player, where X is the number of cards in his or her hand minus 4.</text>
    <flavorText>The maiden is a jealous lover.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0128</id>
    <name>Jhoira's Toolbox</name>
    <text>{2}: Regenerate target artifact creature.</text>
    <flavorText>It entertained Jhoira to craft a kit that could bring her the tools.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0129</id>
    <name>Memory Jar</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Memory Jar: Each player exiles all cards from his or her hand face down and draws seven cards. At the beginning of the next end step, each player discards his or her hand and returns to his or her hand each card he or she exiled this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0130</id>
    <name>Quicksilver Amulet</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: You may put a creature card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Wonderful You got a lion on your first try. Now put it back."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0131</id>
    <name>Ring of Gix</name>
    <text>Echo {3} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
{1}, {T}: Tap target artifact, creature, or land.</text>
    <flavorText>Not every cage is made of bars.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0132</id>
    <name>Scrapheap</name>
    <text>Whenever an artifact or enchantment is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Junk heaps have rats, but scrapheaps have goblins.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0133</id>
    <name>Thran Lens</name>
    <text>All permanents are colorless.</text>
    <flavorText>"Every device in the rig is evidence of Thran enlightenment. All mana was the same to them, whether from rock or water, growth or decay. Can you imagine such unity of vision?"
—Urza, journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0134</id>
    <name>Thran War Machine</name>
    <text>Echo {4} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
Thran War Machine attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0135</id>
    <name>Thran Weaponry</name>
    <text>Echo {4} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
You may choose not to untap Thran Weaponry during your untap step.
{2}, {T}: All creatures get +2/+2 for as long as Thran Weaponry remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0136</id>
    <name>Ticking Gnomes</name>
    <text>Echo {3} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
Sacrifice Ticking Gnomes: Ticking Gnomes deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0137</id>
    <name>Urza's Blueprints</name>
    <text>Echo {6} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
{T}: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>From concept to paper to reality.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0138</id>
    <name>Wheel of Torture</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each opponent's upkeep, Wheel of Torture deals X damage to that player, where X is 3 minus the number of cards in his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'd like to buy a bowel."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0139</id>
    <name>Faerie Conclave</name>
    <text>Faerie Conclave enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.
{1}{U}: Faerie Conclave becomes a 2/1 blue Faerie creature with flying until end of turn. It's still a land. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0140</id>
    <name>Forbidding Watchtower</name>
    <text>Forbidding Watchtower enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.
{1}{W}: Forbidding Watchtower becomes a 1/5 white Soldier creature until end of turn. It's still a land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0141</id>
    <name>Ghitu Encampment</name>
    <text>Ghitu Encampment enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.
{1}{R}: Ghitu Encampment becomes a 2/1 red Warrior creature with first strike until end of turn. It's still a land. (It deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0142</id>
    <name>Spawning Pool</name>
    <text>Spawning Pool enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.
{1}{B}: Spawning Pool becomes a 1/1 black Skeleton creature with "{B}: Regenerate this creature" until end of turn. It's still a land. (If it regenerates, the next time it would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ULG0143</id>
    <name>Treetop Village</name>
    <text>Treetop Village enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{1}{G}: Treetop Village becomes a 3/3 green Ape creature with trample until end of turn. It's still a land. (If it would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>