<cards name="Weatherlight">
  <item>
    <id>WTH0001</id>
    <name>Abduction</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Abduction enters the battlefield, untap enchanted creature.
You control enchanted creature.
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, return that card to the battlefield under its owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0002</id>
    <name>Abeyance</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, target player can't cast instant or sorcery spells, and that player can't activate abilities that aren't mana abilities.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'm too modest a wizard to reveal the full extent of my abilities."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0003</id>
    <name>Abjure</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Abjure, sacrifice a blue permanent.
Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>Mirri's hackles rose as Ertai continued expounding his virtues. "If that arrogant brat doesn't shut up soon," she growled to herself, "I'm going to have to kill him."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0004</id>
    <name>Aboroth</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep—Put a -1/-1 counter on Aboroth. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>The Weatherlight banked sharply as the colossal beast rose up to crush the lone rider. "My bet's on the dirt," Gerrard said flatly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0005</id>
    <name>Abyssal Gatekeeper</name>
    <text>When Abyssal Gatekeeper is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, each player sacrifices a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"There are two ways for me to pass this gate. One involves you remaining conscious."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0006</id>
    <name>Æther Flash</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature enters the battlefield, Æther Flash deals 2 damage to it.</text>
    <flavorText>"You can't get there from here. Well, you can—it just won't be fun."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0007</id>
    <name>Agonizing Memories</name>
    <text>Look at target player's hand and choose two cards from it. Put them on top of that player's library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"An innocent man died because of my anger. That knowledge will haunt me for all eternity."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0008</id>
    <name>Alabaster Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
When Alabaster Dragon is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, shuffle Alabaster Dragon into its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0009</id>
    <name>Alms</name>
    <text>{1}, Exile the top card of your graveyard: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Helping people is mostly a matter of teaching them to help themselves."
—Sisay, journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0010</id>
    <name>Ancestral Knowledge</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
When Ancestral Knowledge enters the battlefield, look at the top ten cards of your library, then exile any number of them and put the rest back on top of your library in any order.
When Ancestral Knowledge leaves the battlefield, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0011</id>
    <name>Angelic Renewal</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, you may sacrifice Angelic Renewal. If you do, return that card to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0012</id>
    <name>Apathy</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, that player may discard a card at random. If he or she does, untap that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0013</id>
    <name>Arctic Wolves</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
When Arctic Wolves enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"No matter where we cat warriors go in the world, those stupid slobberers find us."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0014</id>
    <name>Ardent Militia</name>
    <text>Vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>"While the rest of us got paid to serve the Benalish army, the militia didn't. I used to say they stood for freedom—free and dumb."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0015</id>
    <name>Argivian Find</name>
    <text>Return target artifact or enchantment card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"We often bury our pasts, and then someone comes along and digs them up."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0016</id>
    <name>Argivian Restoration</name>
    <text>Return target artifact card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Argivian University taught me two things: always look to the past, and never dismiss what appears useless."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0017</id>
    <name>Aura of Silence</name>
    <text>Artifact and enchantment spells your opponents cast cost {2} more to cast.
Sacrifice Aura of Silence: Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0018</id>
    <name>Avizoa</name>
    <text>Flying
{0}: Avizoa gets +2/+2 until end of turn. You skip your next untap step. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Maybe we can trap them with bait," thought Tahngarth, eyeing Squee.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0019</id>
    <name>Barishi</name>
    <text>When Barishi is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, exile Barishi, then shuffle all creature cards from your graveyard into your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0020</id>
    <name>Barrow Ghoul</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Barrow Ghoul unless you exile the top creature card of your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"They killed my family to deny me a future. They fed on my ancestors to deny me a past."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0021</id>
    <name>Benalish Infantry</name>
    <text>Banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"My favorite part of getting into the infantry was getting out again."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0022</id>
    <name>Benalish Knight</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We called them ‘armored lightning.'"
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0023</id>
    <name>Benalish Missionary</name>
    <text>{1}{W}, {T}: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by target blocked creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"These horn-haters say no gods but theirs exist. I say let him find out for himself—right now"
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0024</id>
    <name>Betrothed of Fire</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Sacrifice an untapped creature: Enchanted creature gets +2/+0 until end of turn.
Sacrifice enchanted creature: Creatures you control get +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0025</id>
    <name>Bloodrock Cyclops</name>
    <text>Bloodrock Cyclops attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>"He's big an' dumb an' ready to fight. A lot like ol' Hornhead here."
—Squee, goblin cabin hand,
scouting report</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0026</id>
    <name>Blossoming Wreath</name>
    <text>You gain life equal to the number of creature cards in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"I place this wreath for you, my kin. Even in death, you give me strength to avenge you."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0027</id>
    <name>Bogardan Firefiend</name>
    <text>When Bogardan Firefiend is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, it deals 2 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The next one who tells me to relax and curl up by a fire is dead."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0028</id>
    <name>Boiling Blood</name>
    <text>Target creature attacks this turn if able.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Your father has no horns
Your mother wears a bell
You drink the milk of goats
—Talruum taunts</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0029</id>
    <name>Bone Dancer</name>
    <text>Whenever Bone Dancer attacks and isn't blocked, you may put the top creature card of defending player's graveyard onto the battlefield under your control. If you do, Bone Dancer assigns no combat damage this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0030</id>
    <name>Bösium Strip</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Until end of turn, if the top card of your graveyard is an instant or sorcery card, you may cast that card. If a card cast this way would be put into a graveyard this turn, exile it instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0031</id>
    <name>Briar Shield</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1.
Sacrifice Briar Shield: Enchanted creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>In all its forms, the forest is the elves' best protector.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0032</id>
    <name>Bubble Matrix</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt to creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"This device was commisioned by a king who desired peace. Unfortunately, the royal artificer was also the king's jester."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0033</id>
    <name>Buried Alive</name>
    <text>Search your library for up to three creature cards and put them into your graveyard. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Is it worse to walk while dead, or to be buried alive? I have witnessed both."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0034</id>
    <name>Call of the Wild</name>
    <text>{2}{G}{G}: Reveal the top card of your library. If it's a creature card, put it onto the battlefield. Otherwise, put it into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Thinking of dinner made Squee realize that the forest was probably thinking the same thing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0035</id>
    <name>Chimeric Sphere</name>
    <text>{2}: Until end of turn, Chimeric Sphere becomes a 2/1 Construct artifact creature with flying.
{2}: Until end of turn, Chimeric Sphere becomes a 3/2 Construct artifact creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0036</id>
    <name>Choking Vines</name>
    <text>Cast Choking Vines only during the declare blockers step.
X target attacking creatures become blocked. Choking Vines deals 1 damage to each of those creatures. (This spell works on unblockable creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0037</id>
    <name>Cinder Giant</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Cinder Giant deals 2 damage to each other creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"The giant wept tears of embers for the deaths of his allies."
—Azeworai, "The Lonely Giant"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0038</id>
    <name>Cinder Wall</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
When Cinder Wall blocks, destroy it at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"Easy. All ya gotta do is push somebody into it."
—Squee, goblin cabin hand,
scouting report</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0039</id>
    <name>Circling Vultures</name>
    <text>Flying
You may discard Circling Vultures any time you could cast an instant.
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Circling Vultures unless you exile the top creature card of your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0040</id>
    <name>Cloud Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying
Cloud Djinn can block only creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>As elusive as the footprint of a djinn
—Suq'Ata expression</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0041</id>
    <name>Coils of the Medusa</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/-1.
Sacrifice Coils of the Medusa: Destroy all non-Wall creatures blocking enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Serpentine locks shape ornate rocks.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0042</id>
    <name>Cone of Flame</name>
    <text>Cone of Flame deals 1 damage to target creature or player, 2 damage to another target creature or player, and 3 damage to a third target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mine is not the warmth of compassion."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0043</id>
    <name>Debt of Loyalty</name>
    <text>Regenerate target creature. You gain control of that creature if it regenerates this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"I killed him because I had to," Starke lied to Gerrard. "But now I pledge my loyalty to you."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0044</id>
    <name>Dense Foliage</name>
    <text>Creatures can't be the targets of spells.</text>
    <flavorText>"Big plants not only good for hidin', but full o' tasty bugs, too."
—Squee, goblin cabin hand</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0045</id>
    <name>Desperate Gambit</name>
    <text>Choose a source you control and flip a coin. If you win the flip, the next time that source would deal damage this turn, it deals double that damage instead. If you lose the flip, the next time it would deal damage this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0046</id>
    <name>Dingus Staff</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, Dingus Staff deals 2 damage to that creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>"A sharp conscience is the weapon of the soul."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0047</id>
    <name>Disrupt</name>
    <text>Counter target instant or sorcery spell unless its controller pays {1}.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Oh, I'm sorry—did I break your concentration?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0048</id>
    <name>Doomsday</name>
    <text>Search your library and graveyard for five cards and exile the rest. Put the chosen cards on top of your library in any order. You lose half your life, rounded up.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0049</id>
    <name>Downdraft</name>
    <text>{G}: Target creature loses flying until end of turn.

Sacrifice Downdraft: Downdraft deals 2 damage to each creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0050</id>
    <name>Duskrider Falcon</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from black</text>
    <flavorText>"Seaborne ships have their dolphins to dance in their wakes; I have my duskriders."
—Sisay, journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0051</id>
    <name>Dwarven Berserker</name>
    <text>Whenever Dwarven Berserker becomes blocked, it gets +3/+0 and gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I may be small, but I can kick your butt."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0052</id>
    <name>Dwarven Thaumaturgist</name>
    <text>{T}: Switch target creature's power and toughness until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0053</id>
    <name>Empyrial Armor</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 for each card in your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"An angel appeared in the smoldering skies above the fray, her clothes as flames, her armor as fire."
—"Hymn of Angelfire"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0054</id>
    <name>Ertai's Familiar</name>
    <text>Phasing (This phases in or out before you untap during each of your untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)
When Ertai's Familiar phases out or leaves the battlefield, put the top three cards of your library into your graveyard.
{U}: Until your next upkeep, Ertai's Familiar can't phase out.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0055</id>
    <name>Fallow Wurm</name>
    <text>When Fallow Wurm enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you discard a land card.</text>
    <flavorText>The wurm's wake
—Elvish expression meaning
"ruined crops"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0056</id>
    <name>Familiar Ground</name>
    <text>Each creature you control can't be blocked by more than one creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'd rather fight on foreign soil. That way, if I lose I can blame it on the terrain."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0057</id>
    <name>Fatal Blow</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature that was dealt damage this turn. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"What is crueler? To let a wound of the heart fester, or to simply cut it out?"
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0058</id>
    <name>Fervor</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have haste.</text>
    <flavorText>"If your blood doesn't run hot, I will make it run in the sands"
—Maraxus of Keld</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0059</id>
    <name>Festering Evil</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Festering Evil deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.

{B}{B}, Sacrifice Festering Evil: Festering Evil deals 3 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0060</id>
    <name>Fire Whip</name>
    <text>Enchant creature you control
Enchanted creature has "{T}: This creature deals 1 damage to target creature or player."
Sacrifice Fire Whip: Fire Whip deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0061</id>
    <name>Firestorm</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Firestorm, discard X cards.
Firestorm deals X damage to each of X target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>"Glok loved storms He'd sit an' watch an' laugh through the whole thing. I miss him."
—Squee, goblin cabin hand</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0062</id>
    <name>Fit of Rage</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 and gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Anger is fleeting; remorse is eternal."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0063</id>
    <name>Fledgling Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, Fledgling Djinn deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"The young can be quite dangerous. Trust me, I should know."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0064</id>
    <name>Flux</name>
    <text>Each player discards any number of cards, then draws that many cards.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Every spell has the potential to be worthless."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0065</id>
    <name>Fog Elemental</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
When Fog Elemental attacks or blocks, sacrifice it at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"I've seen fog so thick you could cut it, but none that could cut me."
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0066</id>
    <name>Foriysian Brigade</name>
    <text>Foriysian Brigade can block an additional creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"A double-edged sword lets you cut down your enemies with the backswing as well."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0067</id>
    <name>Fungus Elemental</name>
    <text>{G}, Sacrifice a Forest: Put a +2/+2 counter on Fungus Elemental. Activate this ability only if Fungus Elemental entered the battlefield this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>I rot growth and grow rot. What am I?
—Elvish riddle</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0068</id>
    <name>Gaea's Blessing</name>
    <text>Target player shuffles up to three target cards from his or her graveyard into his or her library.
Draw a card.
When Gaea's Blessing is put into your graveyard from your library, shuffle your graveyard into your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0069</id>
    <name>Gallowbraid</name>
    <text>Trample
Cumulative upkeep—Pay 1 life. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"If its skin looks like stone, it is only to match its heart."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0070</id>
    <name>Gemstone Mine</name>
    <text>Gemstone Mine enters the battlefield with three mining counters on it.
{T}, Remove a mining counter from Gemstone Mine: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. If there are no mining counters on Gemstone Mine, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0071</id>
    <name>Gerrard's Wisdom</name>
    <text>You gain 2 life for each card in your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Fighting without an army is called a duel, and you'll lose a duel if your enemy comes expecting a war."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0072</id>
    <name>Goblin Bomb</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may flip a coin. If you win the flip, put a fuse counter on Goblin Bomb. If you lose the flip, remove a fuse counter from Goblin Bomb.
Remove five fuse counters from Goblin Bomb, Sacrifice Goblin Bomb: Goblin Bomb deals 20 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0073</id>
    <name>Goblin Grenadiers</name>
    <text>Whenever Goblin Grenadiers attacks and isn't blocked, you may sacrifice it. If you do, destroy target creature and target land.</text>
    <flavorText>For once, Squee realized, he wasn't the dumb one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0074</id>
    <name>Goblin Vandal</name>
    <text>Whenever Goblin Vandal attacks and isn't blocked, you may pay {R}. If you do, destroy target artifact defending player controls and Goblin Vandal assigns no combat damage this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0075</id>
    <name>Guided Strike</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +1/+0 and gains first strike until end of turn.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you can kill your enemy with the first stroke, you save yourself the labor of the second."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0076</id>
    <name>Harvest Wurm</name>
    <text>When Harvest Wurm enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you return a basic land card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The wurm's weave
—Elvish expression meaning
"plowed fields"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0077</id>
    <name>Haunting Misery</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Haunting Misery, exile X creature cards from your graveyard.
Haunting Misery deals X damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>"I am condemned without end."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0078</id>
    <name>Heart of Bogardan</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
When Heart of Bogardan's cumulative upkeep isn't paid, it deals X damage to target player and each creature he or she controls, where X is twice the number of age counters on Heart of Bogardan minus two.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0079</id>
    <name>Heat Stroke</name>
    <text>At end of combat, destroy each creature that blocked or was blocked this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Stroke of heat or stroke of blade. Choose your fate, traitor."
—Maraxus of Keld, to Starke</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0080</id>
    <name>Heavy Ballista</name>
    <text>{T}: Heavy Ballista deals 2 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Archers, ballistae—you can't even get near the island of Avenant."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0081</id>
    <name>Hidden Horror</name>
    <text>When Hidden Horror enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you discard a creature card.</text>
    <flavorText>Lifespans are measured by its dreadful length.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0082</id>
    <name>Hurloon Shaman</name>
    <text>When Hurloon Shaman is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, each player sacrifices a land.</text>
    <flavorText>"I believe it when they say they're connected to the land—looks like somebody plowed her face."
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0083</id>
    <name>Infernal Tribute</name>
    <text>{2}, Sacrifice a nontoken permanent: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I would not barter my soul for any of the filth that they called power. So they took it from me and damned me to solitude."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0084</id>
    <name>Inner Sanctum</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep—Pay 2 life. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Prevent all damage that would be dealt to creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Save me from Maraxus," Starke pleaded, "or condemn me to his wrath. Either way, do not ignore me"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0085</id>
    <name>Jabari's Banner</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Target creature gains flanking until end of turn. (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0086</id>
    <name>Jangling Automaton</name>
    <text>Whenever Jangling Automaton attacks, untap all creatures defending player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"We always look upon our first creations as masterpieces, no matter how awful they are."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0087</id>
    <name>Kithkin Armor</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't be blocked by creatures with power 3 or greater.
Sacrifice Kithkin Armor: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to enchanted creature this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0088</id>
    <name>Lava Hounds</name>
    <text>Haste
When Lava Hounds enters the battlefield, it deals 4 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>What cats bury, dogs eat.
—Urborg aphorism</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0089</id>
    <name>Lava Storm</name>
    <text>Lava Storm deals 2 damage to each attacking creature or Lava Storm deals 2 damage to each blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>They say lava conquers all.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0090</id>
    <name>Liege of the Hollows</name>
    <text>When Liege of the Hollows is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, each player may pay any amount of mana. Then each player who paid mana this way puts that many 1/1 green Squirrel creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0091</id>
    <name>Llanowar Behemoth</name>
    <text>Tap an untapped creature you control: Llanowar Behemoth gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Most people can't build decent weapons out of stone or steel. Trust the elves to do it with only mud and vines."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0092</id>
    <name>Llanowar Druid</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Llanowar Druid: Untap all Forests.</text>
    <flavorText>"This forest means more to the druids than their own kin. The loss of a tree is like the loss of a child."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0093</id>
    <name>Llanowar Sentinel</name>
    <text>When Llanowar Sentinel enters the battlefield, you may pay {1}{G}. If you do, search your library for a card named Llanowar Sentinel and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"The forest has as many eyes as leaves."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0094</id>
    <name>Lotus Vale</name>
    <text>If Lotus Vale would enter the battlefield, sacrifice two untapped lands instead. If you do, put Lotus Vale onto the battlefield. If you don't, put it into its owner's graveyard.
{T}: Add three mana of any one color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>At what price beauty?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0095</id>
    <name>Mana Chains</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has "Cumulative upkeep {1}." (At the beginning of its controller's upkeep, that player puts an age counter on it, then sacrifices it unless he or she pays its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The Lord of the Wastes must be destroyed; I am bound to this destiny by the chains of fate. If only Gerrard would see his part."
—Sisay, journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0096</id>
    <name>Mana Web</name>
    <text>Whenever a land an opponent controls is tapped for mana, tap all lands that player controls that could produce any type of mana that land could produce.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0097</id>
    <name>Manta Ray</name>
    <text>Manta Ray can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.
Manta Ray can't be blocked except by blue creatures.
When you control no Islands, sacrifice Manta Ray.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0098</id>
    <name>Maraxus of Keld</name>
    <text>Maraxus of Keld's power and toughness are each equal to the number of untapped artifacts, creatures, and lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have no master. I am chaos."
—Maraxus of Keld</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0099</id>
    <name>Master of Arms</name>
    <text>First strike
{1}{W}: Tap target creature blocking Master of Arms. Prevent all combat damage that creature would deal this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Being the best usually means proving it to everyone."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0100</id>
    <name>Merfolk Traders</name>
    <text>When Merfolk Traders enters the battlefield, draw a card, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"As much as I hate water, I do love fish . . . ."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0101</id>
    <name>Mind Stone</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Mind Stone: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0102</id>
    <name>Mischievous Poltergeist</name>
    <text>Flying
Pay 1 life: Regenerate Mischievous Poltergeist.</text>
    <flavorText>"The past is a ghost that haunts you from the moment it exists until the moment you don't."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0103</id>
    <name>Mistmoon Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying
When Mistmoon Griffin is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, exile Mistmoon Griffin, then return the top creature card of your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0104</id>
    <name>Morinfen</name>
    <text>Flying
Cumulative upkeep—Pay 1 life. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I looked into its eyes, and its soul was so empty I saw no reflection, no light there."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0105</id>
    <name>Mwonvuli Ooze</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay {2} for each age counter on it.)
Mwonvuli Ooze's power and toughness are each equal to 1 plus twice the number of age counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Ewww"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0106</id>
    <name>Nature's Kiss</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{1}, Exile the top card of your graveyard: Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I cradle my rage even as the earth cradles my dead kin."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0107</id>
    <name>Nature's Resurgence</name>
    <text>Each player draws a card for each creature card in his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Spring follows winter
—Elvish expression meaning
"all things pass"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0108</id>
    <name>Necratog</name>
    <text>Exile the top creature card of your graveyard: Necratog gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The necratog can always dig up a meal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0109</id>
    <name>Noble Benefactor</name>
    <text>When Noble Benefactor is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, each player may search his or her library for a card and put that card into his or her hand. Then each player who searched his or her library this way shuffles it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0110</id>
    <name>Null Rod</name>
    <text>Activated abilities of artifacts can't be activated.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard: "But it doesn't do anything"
Hanna: "No—it does nothing."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0111</id>
    <name>Odylic Wraith</name>
    <text>Swampwalk
Whenever Odylic Wraith deals damage to a player, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>By the time you've seen it, you won't remember that you did.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0112</id>
    <name>Ophidian</name>
    <text>Whenever Ophidian attacks and isn't blocked, you may draw a card. If you do, Ophidian assigns no combat damage this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0113</id>
    <name>Orcish Settlers</name>
    <text>{X}{X}{R}, {T}, Sacrifice Orcish Settlers: Destroy X target lands.</text>
    <flavorText>They wouldn't know their house from a charred hole in the ground.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0114</id>
    <name>Paradigm Shift</name>
    <text>Exile all cards from your library. Then shuffle your graveyard into your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Barrin always said that reality is relative. ‘The world,' he cautioned, ‘is but pieces of one's perception.'"
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0115</id>
    <name>Peacekeeper</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Peacekeeper unless you pay {1}{W}.
Creatures can't attack.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have always imagined my mother as such a woman, strong and wise."
—Sisay, journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0116</id>
    <name>Pendrell Mists</name>
    <text>All creatures have "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice this creature unless you pay {1}."</text>
    <flavorText>As insubstantial—and as insistent—as appetite.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0117</id>
    <name>Phantom Warrior</name>
    <text>Phantom Warrior is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>"Fishtails infest the water, and mists walk the land. Give me simple solid rock any day."
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0118</id>
    <name>Phantom Wings</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has flying.
Sacrifice Phantom Wings: Return enchanted creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"But you said ‘when goats fly'" Squee whined.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0119</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Furnace</name>
    <text>{T}: Exile the bottom card of target player's graveyard.
{1}, Sacrifice Phyrexian Furnace: Exile target card from a graveyard. Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0120</id>
    <name>Psychic Vortex</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep—Draw a card. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
At the beginning of your end step, sacrifice a land and discard your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Tolaria floats upon a wheel of fortune."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0121</id>
    <name>Razortooth Rats</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Men and rats both hunger: we for our playthings; they, for us."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0122</id>
    <name>Redwood Treefolk</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"In the heart of Llanowar the magic is so strong that trees cannot stay rooted."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0123</id>
    <name>Relearn</name>
    <text>Return target instant or sorcery card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Barrin taught me that the hardest lessons to grasp are the ones you've already learned."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0124</id>
    <name>Revered Unicorn</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
When Revered Unicorn leaves the battlefield, you gain life equal to the number of age counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"I felt unworthy even to dream of it."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0125</id>
    <name>Roc Hatchling</name>
    <text>Roc Hatchling enters the battlefield with four shell counters on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a shell counter from Roc Hatchling.
As long as Roc Hatchling has no shell counters on it, it gets +3/+2 and has flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0126</id>
    <name>Rogue Elephant</name>
    <text>When Rogue Elephant enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you sacrifice a Forest.</text>
    <flavorText>"When are trees like grass?"
—The One Thousand Questions</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0127</id>
    <name>Sage Owl</name>
    <text>Flying
When Sage Owl enters the battlefield, look at the top four cards of your library, then put them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>The owl asks but never answers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0128</id>
    <name>Sawtooth Ogre</name>
    <text>Whenever Sawtooth Ogre blocks or becomes blocked by a creature, Sawtooth Ogre deals 1 damage to that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"You will sharpen your teeth on my enemies' bones," Maraxus promised them, and his ogres cheered.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0129</id>
    <name>Scorched Ruins</name>
    <text>If Scorched Ruins would enter the battlefield, sacrifice two untapped lands instead. If you do, put Scorched Ruins onto the battlefield. If you don't, put it into its owner's graveyard.
{T}: Add {4} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0130</id>
    <name>Serenity</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy all artifacts and enchantments. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Just think of me as the storm before the calm."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0131</id>
    <name>Serra's Blessing</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have vigilance. (Attacking doesn't cause them to tap.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I have seen your strength imbued in angels' wings, and I have felt your sorrow rain down on the ruins brought by the Lord of the Wastes."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0132</id>
    <name>Serrated Biskelion</name>
    <text>{T}: Put a -1/-1 counter on Serrated Biskelion and a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Whereas I was created to protect, the biskelion was created to destroy."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0133</id>
    <name>Shadow Rider</name>
    <text>Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>In its world of complete darkness, it has no shadows to fear.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0134</id>
    <name>Shattered Crypt</name>
    <text>Return X target creature cards from your graveyard to your hand. You lose X life.</text>
    <flavorText>"You must be mad to want one such as I aboard the Weatherlight. But I would be mad to remain here with my rotting family. I accept."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0135</id>
    <name>Soul Shepherd</name>
    <text>{W}, Exile a creature card from your graveyard: You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The sidar who raised me had a saying: ‘The first step into death is the hardest.'"
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0136</id>
    <name>Southern Paladin</name>
    <text>{W}{W}, {T}: Destroy target red permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"Look to the south; there you will find peace and serenity."
—The Book of Tal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0137</id>
    <name>Spinning Darkness</name>
    <text>You may exile the top three black cards of your graveyard rather than pay Spinning Darkness's mana cost.
Spinning Darkness deals 3 damage to target nonblack creature. You gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0138</id>
    <name>Steel Golem</name>
    <text>You can't cast creature spells.</text>
    <flavorText>"Although I would give my life to protect Gerrard, my conscience will not let me take another's. There are many who would not hesitate."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0139</id>
    <name>Strands of Night</name>
    <text>{B}{B}, Pay 2 life, Sacrifice a Swamp: Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have seen the night torn into thin darkling strips and woven into shapes too bleak for dreams."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0140</id>
    <name>Straw Golem</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts a creature spell, sacrifice Straw Golem.</text>
    <flavorText>"Don't look at me. I didn't build it."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0141</id>
    <name>Striped Bears</name>
    <text>When Striped Bears enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"The bear is never cautious—which is why it wasn't born a human."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0142</id>
    <name>Sylvan Hierophant</name>
    <text>When Sylvan Hierophant is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, exile Sylvan Hierophant, then return another target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0143</id>
    <name>Tariff</name>
    <text>Each player sacrifices the creature he or she controls with the highest converted mana cost unless he or she pays that creature's mana cost. If two creatures a player controls are tied for highest cost, that player chooses one.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0144</id>
    <name>Teferi's Veil</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control attacks, it phases out at end of combat. (While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist. It phases in before you untap during your next untap step.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I don't like to speak ill of 'walkers . . . but just what did Teferi think he was doing?"
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0145</id>
    <name>Tendrils of Despair</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Tendrils of Despair, sacrifice a creature.
Target opponent discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Because I am incapable of tears does not mean I have no need to shed them."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0146</id>
    <name>Thran Forge</name>
    <text>{2}: Until end of turn, target nonartifact creature gets +1/+0 and becomes an artifact in addition to its other types.</text>
    <flavorText>"This will work," Gerrard called to the elves as he used the forge to strengthen the aboroth, "but if it doesn't, we won't survive to care."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0147</id>
    <name>Thran Tome</name>
    <text>{5}, {T}: Reveal the top three cards of your library. Target opponent chooses one of those cards. Put that card into your graveyard, then draw two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Every line holds a tale, and between lie a thousand more.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0148</id>
    <name>Thunderbolt</name>
    <text>Choose one — Thunderbolt deals 3 damage to target player; or Thunderbolt deals 4 damage to target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Most wizards consider a thunderbolt to be a proper retort."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0149</id>
    <name>Thundermare</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack the turn it comes under your control.)
When Thundermare enters the battlefield, tap all other creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Its hooves strike lightning and the thunder follows quickly after.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0150</id>
    <name>Timid Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
When another creature enters the battlefield, return Timid Drake to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"I sneezed, and it bolted."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0151</id>
    <name>Tolarian Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
Phasing (This phases in or out before you untap during each of your untap steps. While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist.)</text>
    <flavorText>Many have been lost just in staring at its wings. What's seen differs from account to account, but madness is always part of the story.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0152</id>
    <name>Tolarian Entrancer</name>
    <text>Whenever Tolarian Entrancer becomes blocked by a creature, gain control of that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why should I boast? The bards will do it for me—and with music."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0153</id>
    <name>Tolarian Serpent</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put the top seven cards of your library into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"When the fishtails' threats of magic didn't move me, they set their pet on us."
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0154</id>
    <name>Touchstone</name>
    <text>{T}: Tap target artifact you don't control.</text>
    <flavorText>"One touch to the stone and the sidar's son turned me from stalwart to statue."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0155</id>
    <name>Tranquil Grove</name>
    <text>{1}{G}{G}: Destroy all other enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>"Even the fiercest storm has a peaceful eye."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0156</id>
    <name>Uktabi Efreet</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The Uktabi efreet and I have something in common: both of our mothers wanted to give us back."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0157</id>
    <name>Urborg Justice</name>
    <text>Target opponent sacrifices a creature for each creature put into your graveyard from the battlefield this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is a narrow line between justice and vengeance."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0158</id>
    <name>Urborg Stalker</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, if that player controls a nonblack, nonland permanent, Urborg Stalker deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>"May you be a stalker's dream."
—Urborg curse</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0159</id>
    <name>Veteran Explorer</name>
    <text>When Veteran Explorer is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, each player may search his or her library for up to two basic land cards and put them onto the battlefield. Then each player who searched his or her library this way shuffles it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0160</id>
    <name>Vitalize</name>
    <text>Untap all creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"After waking to the magic of Llanowar, no dreams can compare."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0161</id>
    <name>Vodalian Illusionist</name>
    <text>{U}{U}, {T}: Target creature phases out. (While it's phased out, it's treated as though it doesn't exist. It phases in before its controller untaps during his or her next untap step.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Torahn gore these shifty fishtails You can't even get close to one."
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0162</id>
    <name>Volunteer Reserves</name>
    <text>Banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)
Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I'm always a little leery of anyone who offers to kill other people for free."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0163</id>
    <name>Wave of Terror</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
At the beginning of your draw step, destroy each creature with converted mana cost equal to the number of age counters on Wave of Terror. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>The sea of fear has endless depths.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0164</id>
    <name>Well of Knowledge</name>
    <text>{2}: Draw a card. Any player may activate this ability but only during his or her draw step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0165</id>
    <name>Winding Canyons</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{2}, {T}: Until end of turn, you may play creature cards as though they had flash.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0166</id>
    <name>Xanthic Statue</name>
    <text>{5}: Until end of turn, Xanthic Statue becomes an 8/8 Golem artifact creature with trample.</text>
    <flavorText>"Until you have lived as a statue, do not talk to me of pigeons."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>WTH0167</id>
    <name>Zombie Scavengers</name>
    <text>Exile the top creature card of your graveyard: Regenerate Zombie Scavengers.</text>
    <flavorText>"Pick a shell upon my shore and put it to your ear. That sound isn't the sea, but the whispers of the fallen."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>