<cards name="Fourth Edition">
  <item>
    <id>4ED0001</id>
    <name>Abomination</name>
    <text>Whenever Abomination blocks or becomes blocked by a green or white creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0002</id>
    <name>Air Elemental</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>These spirits of the air are winsome and wild and cannot be truly contained. Only marginally intelligent, they often substitute whimsy for strategy, delighting in mischief and mayhem.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0003</id>
    <name>Alabaster Potion</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target player gains X life; or prevent the next X damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Healing is a matter of time, but it is sometimes also a matter of opportunity."
—D'Avenant proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0004</id>
    <name>Aladdin's Lamp</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: The next time you would draw a card this turn, instead look at the top X cards of your library, put all but one of them on the bottom of your library in a random order, then draw a card. X can't be 0.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0005</id>
    <name>Aladdin's Ring</name>
    <text>{8}, {T}: Aladdin's Ring deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"After these words the magician drew a ring off his finger, and put it on one of Aladdin's, saying: ‘It is a talisman against all evil, so long as you obey me.'"The Arabian Nights, Junior Classics trans.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0006</id>
    <name>Ali Baba</name>
    <text>{R}: Tap target Wall.</text>
    <flavorText>"When he reached the entrance of the cavern, he pronounced the words, ‘Open, Sesame'"
—The Arabian Nights, Junior Classics trans.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0007</id>
    <name>Amrou Kithkin</name>
    <text>Amrou Kithkin can't be blocked by creatures with power 3 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>Quick and agile, Amrou Kithkin can usually escape from even the most fearsome opponents.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0008</id>
    <name>Amulet of Kroog</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Among the first allies Urza gained were the people of Kroog. As a sign of friendship, Urza gave the healers of the city potent amulets; afterwards, thousands journeyed to Kroog in hope of healing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0009</id>
    <name>Angry Mob</name>
    <text>Trample
As long as it's your turn, Angry Mob's power and toughness are each equal to 2 plus the number of Swamps your opponents control. As long as it's not your turn, Angry Mob's power and toughness are each 2.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0010</id>
    <name>Animate Artifact</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact
As long as enchanted artifact isn't a creature, it's an artifact creature with power and toughness each equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0011</id>
    <name>Animate Dead</name>
    <text>Enchant creature card in a graveyard
When Animate Dead enters the battlefield, if it's on the battlefield, it loses "enchant creature card in a graveyard" and gains "enchant creature put onto the battlefield with Animate Dead." Return enchanted creature card to the battlefield under your control and attach Animate Dead to it. When Animate Dead leaves the battlefield, that creature's controller sacrifices it.
Enchanted creature gets -1/-0.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0012</id>
    <name>Animate Wall</name>
    <text>Enchant Wall
Enchanted Wall can attack as though it didn't have defender.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0013</id>
    <name>Ankh of Mishra</name>
    <text>Whenever a land enters the battlefield, Ankh of Mishra deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0014</id>
    <name>Apprentice Wizard</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}: Add {3} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0015</id>
    <name>Armageddon</name>
    <text>Destroy all lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0016</id>
    <name>Armageddon Clock</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a doom counter on Armageddon Clock.
At the beginning of your draw step, Armageddon Clock deals damage to each player equal to the number of doom counters on it.
{4}: Remove a doom counter from Armageddon Clock. Any player may activate this ability but only during any upkeep step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0017</id>
    <name>Ashes to Ashes</name>
    <text>Exile two target nonartifact creatures. Ashes to Ashes deals 5 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"All rivers eventually run to the sea. My job is to sort out who goes first."
—Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0018</id>
    <name>Ashnod's Battle Gear</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Ashnod's Battle Gear during your untap step.
{2}, {T}: Target creature you control gets +2/-2 for as long as Ashnod's Battle Gear remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>This invention shows why Ashnod was feared by her troops as well as her foes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0019</id>
    <name>Aspect of Wolf</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +X/+Y, where X is half the number of Forests you control, rounded down, and Y is half the number of Forests you control, rounded up.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0020</id>
    <name>Backfire</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage to you, Backfire deals that much damage to that creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0021</id>
    <name>Bad Moon</name>
    <text>Black creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0022</id>
    <name>Balance</name>
    <text>Each player chooses a number of lands he or she controls equal to the number of lands controlled by the player who controls the fewest, then sacrifices the rest. Players discard cards and sacrifice creatures the same way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0023</id>
    <name>Ball Lightning</name>
    <text>Trample (If this creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)
Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)
At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice Ball Lightning.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0024</id>
    <name>Battering Ram</name>
    <text>At the beginning of combat on your turn, Battering Ram gains banding until end of combat. (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's blocking.)
Whenever Battering Ram becomes blocked by a Wall, destroy that Wall at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>By the time Mishra was defeated, no mage was foolish enough to rely heavily on walls.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0025</id>
    <name>Benalish Hero</name>
    <text>Banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>Benalia has a complex caste system that changes with the lunar year. No matter what the season, the only caste that cannot be attained by either heredity or money is that of the Hero.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0026</id>
    <name>Bird Maiden</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Four things that never meet do here unite
To shed my blood and to ravage my heart,
A radiant brow and tresses that beguile
And rosy cheeks and a glittering smile."
—The Arabian Nights, trans. Haddawy</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0027</id>
    <name>Birds of Paradise</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0028</id>
    <name>Black Knight</name>
    <text>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)
Protection from white (This creature can't be blocked, targeted, dealt damage, or enchanted by anything white.)</text>
    <flavorText>Battle doesn't need a purpose; the battle is its own purpose. You don't ask why a plague spreads or a field burns. Don't ask why I fight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0029</id>
    <name>Black Mana Battery</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Black Mana Battery.

{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Black Mana Battery: Add {B} to your mana pool, then add an additional {B} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0030</id>
    <name>Black Vise</name>
    <text>As Black Vise enters the battlefield, choose an opponent.
At the beginning of the chosen player's upkeep, Black Vise deals X damage to that player, where X is the number of cards in his or her hand minus 4.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0031</id>
    <name>Black Ward</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has protection from black. This effect doesn't remove Black Ward.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0032</id>
    <name>Blessing</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{W}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0033</id>
    <name>Blight</name>
    <text>Enchant land
When enchanted land becomes tapped, destroy it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0034</id>
    <name>Blood Lust</name>
    <text>If target creature has toughness 5 or greater, it gets +4/-4 until end of turn. Otherwise, it gets +4/-X until end of turn, where X is its toughness minus 1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0035</id>
    <name>Blue Elemental Blast</name>
    <text>Choose one — Counter target red spell; or destroy target red permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0036</id>
    <name>Blue Mana Battery</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Blue Mana Battery.

{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Blue Mana Battery: Add {U} to your mana pool, then add an additional {U} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0037</id>
    <name>Blue Ward</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has protection from blue. This effect doesn't remove Blue Ward.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0038</id>
    <name>Bog Imp</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>On guard for larger dangers, we underestimated the power and speed of the Imp's muck-crusted claws.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0039</id>
    <name>Bog Wraith</name>
    <text>Swampwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Swamp.)</text>
    <flavorText>'Twas in the bogs of Cannelbrae
My mate did meet an early grave
'Twas nothing left for us to save
In the peat-filled bogs of Cannelbrae.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0040</id>
    <name>Bottle of Suleiman</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice Bottle of Suleiman: Flip a coin. If you lose the flip, Bottle of Suleiman deals 5 damage to you. If you win the flip, put a 5/5 colorless Djinn artifact creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0041</id>
    <name>Brainwash</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack unless its controller pays {3}.</text>
    <flavorText>"They're not your friends; they despise you. I'm the only one you can count on. Trust me."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0042</id>
    <name>Brass Man</name>
    <text>Brass Man doesn't untap during your untap step.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {1}. If you do, untap Brass Man.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0043</id>
    <name>Bronze Tablet</name>
    <text>Remove Bronze Tablet from your deck before playing if you're not playing for ante.
Bronze Tablet enters the battlefield tapped.
{4}, {T}: Exile Bronze Tablet and target nontoken permanent an opponent owns. That player may pay 10 life. If he or she does, put Bronze Tablet into its owner's graveyard. Otherwise, that player owns Bronze Tablet and you own the other exiled card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0044</id>
    <name>Brothers of Fire</name>
    <text>{1}{R}{R}: Brothers of Fire deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>Fire is never a gentle master.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0045</id>
    <name>Burrowing</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has mountainwalk.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0046</id>
    <name>Carnivorous Plant</name>
    <text>Defender</text>
    <flavorText>"It had a mouth like that of a great beast, and gnashed its teeth as it strained to reach us. I am thankful it possessed no means of locomotion."
—Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0047</id>
    <name>Carrion Ants</name>
    <text>{1}: Carrion Ants gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"War is no picnic," my father liked to say. But the Ants seemed to disagree.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0048</id>
    <name>Castle</name>
    <text>Untapped creatures you control get +0/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0049</id>
    <name>Cave People</name>
    <text>Whenever Cave People attacks, it gets +1/-2 until end of turn.
{1}{R}{R}, {T}: Target creature gains mountainwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0050</id>
    <name>Celestial Prism</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0051</id>
    <name>Channel</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, any time you could activate a mana ability, you may pay 1 life. If you do, add {1} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0052</id>
    <name>Chaoslace</name>
    <text>Target spell or permanent becomes red. (Its mana symbols remain unchanged.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0053</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Artifacts</name>
    <text>{2}: The next time an artifact source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0054</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Black</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a black source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0055</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Blue</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a blue source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0056</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Green</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a green source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0057</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Red</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a red source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0058</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: White</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a white source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0059</id>
    <name>Clay Statue</name>
    <text>{2}: Regenerate Clay Statue.</text>
    <flavorText>Tawnos won fame as Urza's greatest assistant. After he created these warriors, Urza ended his apprenticeship, promoting him directly to the rank of master.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0060</id>
    <name>Clockwork Avian</name>
    <text>Flying
Clockwork Avian enters the battlefield with four +1/+0 counters on it.
At end of combat, if Clockwork Avian attacked or blocked this combat, remove a +1/+0 counter from it.
{X}, {T}: Put up to X +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Avian. This ability can't cause the total number of +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Avian to be greater than four. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0061</id>
    <name>Clockwork Beast</name>
    <text>Clockwork Beast enters the battlefield with seven +1/+0 counters on it.
At end of combat, if Clockwork Beast attacked or blocked this combat, remove a +1/+0 counter from it.
{X}, {T}: Put up to X +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Beast. This ability can't cause the total number of +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Beast to be greater than seven. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0062</id>
    <name>Cockatrice</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Cockatrice blocks or becomes blocked by a non-Wall creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0063</id>
    <name>Colossus of Sardia</name>
    <text>Trample (If this creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)
Colossus of Sardia doesn't untap during your untap step.
{9}: Untap Colossus of Sardia. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>From the Sardian mountains wakes ancient doom:
Warrior born from a rocky womb.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0064</id>
    <name>Conservator</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to you this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0065</id>
    <name>Control Magic</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
You control enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0066</id>
    <name>Conversion</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Conversion unless you pay {W}{W}.
All Mountains are Plains.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0067</id>
    <name>Coral Helm</name>
    <text>{3}, Discard a card at random: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0068</id>
    <name>Cosmic Horror</name>
    <text>First strike
At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy Cosmic Horror unless you pay {3}{B}{B}{B}. If Cosmic Horror is destroyed this way, it deals 7 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>". . . Screams of horror rend th' affrighted skies."Alexander Pope, The Rape of the Lock</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0069</id>
    <name>Counterspell</name>
    <text>Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0070</id>
    <name>Craw Wurm</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The most terrifying thing about the Craw Wurm is probably the horrible crashing sound it makes as it speeds through the forest. This noise is so loud it echoes through the trees and seems to come from all directions at once.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0071</id>
    <name>Creature Bond</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, Creature Bond deals damage equal to that creature's toughness to the creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0072</id>
    <name>Crimson Manticore</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}, {T}: Crimson Manticore deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Noted neither for their good looks nor their charm, Manticores can be fearsome allies.  As dinner companions, however, they are best left alone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0073</id>
    <name>Crumble</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact. It can't be regenerated. That artifact's controller gains life equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>The spirits of Argoth grant new life to those who repent the folly of enslaving their labors to devices.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0074</id>
    <name>Crusade</name>
    <text>White creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0075</id>
    <name>Crystal Rod</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a blue spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0076</id>
    <name>Cursed Land</name>
    <text>Enchant land
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted land's controller, Cursed Land deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0077</id>
    <name>Cursed Rack</name>
    <text>As Cursed Rack enters the battlefield, choose an opponent.
The chosen player's maximum hand size is four.</text>
    <flavorText>Ashnod invented several torture techniques that could make victims even miles away beg for mercy as if the End had come.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0078</id>
    <name>Cyclopean Mummy</name>
    <text>When Cyclopean Mummy is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, exile Cyclopean Mummy.</text>
    <flavorText>The ritual of plucking out an eye to gain future sight is but a curse that enables the living to see their own deaths.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0079</id>
    <name>Dancing Scimitar</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Bobbing merrily from opponent to opponent, the scimitar began adding playful little flourishes to its strokes; it even turned a couple of somersaults.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0080</id>
    <name>Dark Ritual</name>
    <text>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0081</id>
    <name>Death Ward</name>
    <text>Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0082</id>
    <name>Deathgrip</name>
    <text>{B}{B}: Counter target green spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0083</id>
    <name>Deathlace</name>
    <text>Target spell or permanent becomes black. (Mana symbols on that permanent remain unchanged.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0084</id>
    <name>Desert Twister</name>
    <text>Destroy target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0085</id>
    <name>Detonate</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact with converted mana cost X. It can't be regenerated. Detonate deals X damage to that artifact's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0086</id>
    <name>Diabolic Machine</name>
    <text>{3}: Regenerate Diabolic Machine.</text>
    <flavorText>"The bolts of our ballistae smashed into the monstrous thing, but our hopes died in our chests as its gears continued turning."
—Sevti Mukul, The Fall of Alsoor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0087</id>
    <name>Dingus Egg</name>
    <text>Whenever a land is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, Dingus Egg deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0088</id>
    <name>Disenchant</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0089</id>
    <name>Disintegrate</name>
    <text>Disintegrate deals X damage to target creature or player. That creature can't be regenerated this turn. If the creature would be put into a graveyard this turn, exile it instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0090</id>
    <name>Disrupting Scepter</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target player discards a card. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0091</id>
    <name>Divine Transformation</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.</text>
    <flavorText>Glory surged through her and radiance surrounded her. All things were possible with the blessing of the Divine.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0092</id>
    <name>Dragon Engine</name>
    <text>{2}: Dragon Engine gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Those who believed the city of Kroog would never fall to Mishra's forces severely underestimated the might of his war machines.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0093</id>
    <name>Dragon Whelp</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}: Dragon Whelp gets +1/+0 until end of turn. If this ability has been activated four or more times this turn, sacrifice Dragon Whelp at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>"O to be a dragon . . . of silkworm size or immense . . ."Marianne Moore, "O to Be a Dragon"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0094</id>
    <name>Drain Life</name>
    <text>Spend only black mana on X.
Drain Life deals X damage to target creature or player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt, but not more life than the player's life total before Drain Life dealt damage or the creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0095</id>
    <name>Drain Power</name>
    <text>Target player activates a mana ability of each land he or she controls, then empties his or her mana pool. Add mana to your mana pool equal to the type and amount emptied from that player's mana pool this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0096</id>
    <name>Drudge Skeletons</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Drudge Skeletons. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>Bones scattered around us joined to form misshapen bodies. We struck at them repeatedly—they fell, but soon formed again, with the same mocking look on their faceless skulls.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0097</id>
    <name>Durkwood Boars</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"And the unclean spirits went out, and entered the swine: and the herd ran violently . . . ."
—Mark 5:13</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0098</id>
    <name>Dwarven Warriors</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature with power 2 or less is unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0099</id>
    <name>Earth Elemental</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Earth Elementals have the eternal strength of stone and the endurance of mountains. Primordially connected to the land they inhabit, they take a long-term view of things, scorning the impetuous haste of short-lived mortal creatures.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0100</id>
    <name>Earthquake</name>
    <text>Earthquake deals X damage to each creature without flying and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0101</id>
    <name>Ebony Horse</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Untap target attacking creature you control. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by that creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0102</id>
    <name>Elder Land Wurm</name>
    <text>Defender, trample
When Elder Land Wurm blocks, it loses defender.</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes it's best to let sleeping dragons lie.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0103</id>
    <name>El-Hajjâj</name>
    <text>Whenever El-Hajjâj deals damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0104</id>
    <name>Elven Riders</name>
    <text>Elven Riders can't be blocked except by Walls and/or creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Sometimes it is better to be swift of foot than strong of swordarm."
—Elven proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0105</id>
    <name>Elvish Archers</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>I tell you, there was so many arrows flying about you couldn't hardly see the sun. So I says to young Angus, "Well, at least now we're fighting in the shade"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0106</id>
    <name>Energy Flux</name>
    <text>All artifacts have "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice this artifact unless you pay {2}."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0107</id>
    <name>Energy Tap</name>
    <text>Tap target untapped creature you control. If you do, add {X} to your mana pool, where X is that creature's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0108</id>
    <name>Erg Raiders</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your end step, if Erg Raiders didn't attack this turn, Erg Raiders deals 2 damage to you unless it came under your control this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0109</id>
    <name>Erosion</name>
    <text>Enchant land
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted land's controller, destroy that land unless that player pays {1} or 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0110</id>
    <name>Eternal Warrior</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has vigilance.</text>
    <flavorText>Warriors of the Tsunami-nito School spend years in training to master the way of effortless effort.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0111</id>
    <name>Evil Presence</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Enchanted land is a Swamp.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0112</id>
    <name>Eye for an Eye</name>
    <text>The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, instead that source deals that much damage to you and Eye for an Eye deals that much damage to that source's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0113</id>
    <name>Fear</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has fear. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0114</id>
    <name>Feedback</name>
    <text>Enchant enchantment
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted enchantment's controller, Feedback deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0115</id>
    <name>Fellwar Stone</name>
    <text>{T}: Add to your mana pool one mana of any color that a land an opponent controls could produce.</text>
    <flavorText>"What do you have that I cannot obtain?"
—Mairsil, called the Pretender</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0116</id>
    <name>Fire Elemental</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Fire Elementals are ruthless infernos, annihilating and consuming their foes in a frenzied holocaust. Crackling and blazing, they sear swift, terrible paths, leaving the land charred and scorched in their wake.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0117</id>
    <name>Fireball</name>
    <text>Fireball deals X damage divided evenly, rounded down, among any number of target creatures and/or players.
Fireball costs {1} more to cast for each target beyond the first.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0118</id>
    <name>Firebreathing</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"And topples round the dreary west
A looming bastion fringed with fire."
—Alfred, Lord Tennyson, "In Memoriam"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0119</id>
    <name>Fissure</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature or land. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Must not all things at the last be swallowed up in death?"
—Plato</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0120</id>
    <name>Flashfires</name>
    <text>Destroy all Plains.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0121</id>
    <name>Flight</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has flying. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0122</id>
    <name>Flood</name>
    <text>{U}{U}: Tap target creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"A dash of cool water does wonders to clear a cluttered battlefield."
—Vibekke Ragnild, Witches and War</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0123</id>
    <name>Flying Carpet</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0124</id>
    <name>Fog</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0125</id>
    <name>Force of Nature</name>
    <text>Trample (If this creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, Force of Nature deals 8 damage to you unless you pay {G}{G}{G}{G}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0126</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0127</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0128</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0129</id>
    <name>Fortified Area</name>
    <text>Wall creatures you control get +1/+0 and have banding. (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0130</id>
    <name>Frozen Shade</name>
    <text>{B}: Frozen Shade gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"There are some qualities, some incorporate things, / That have a double life, which thus is made / A type of twin entity which springs / From matter and light, evinced in solid and shade."
—Edgar Allan Poe, "Silence"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0131</id>
    <name>Fungusaur</name>
    <text>Whenever Fungusaur is dealt damage, put a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>Rather than sheltering her young, the female Fungusaur often injures her own offspring, thereby ensuring their rapid growth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0132</id>
    <name>Gaea's Liege</name>
    <text>As long as Gaea's Liege isn't attacking, its power and toughness are each equal to the number of Forests you control. As long as Gaea's Liege is attacking, its power and toughness are each equal to the number of Forests defending player controls.
{T}: Target land becomes a Forest until Gaea's Liege leaves the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0133</id>
    <name>Gaseous Form</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>" . . . And gives to airy nothing
A local habitation and a name."
—William Shakespeare, A Midsummer-Night's Dream</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0134</id>
    <name>Ghost Ship</name>
    <text>Flying
{U}{U}{U}: Regenerate Ghost Ship.</text>
    <flavorText>"That phantom prow split the storm as lightning cast its long shadow on the battlefield below."
—Mireille Gaetane, The Valeriad</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0135</id>
    <name>Giant Growth</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0136</id>
    <name>Giant Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>While it possesses potent venom, the Giant Spider often chooses not to paralyze its victims. Perhaps the creature enjoys the gentle rocking motion caused by its captives' struggles to escape its web.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0137</id>
    <name>Giant Strength</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>"O it is excellent
To have a giant's strength, but it is tyrannous
To use it like a giant."
—William Shakespeare, Measure for Measure</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0138</id>
    <name>Giant Tortoise</name>
    <text>Giant Tortoise gets +0/+3 as long as it's untapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0139</id>
    <name>Glasses of Urza</name>
    <text>{T}: Look at target player's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0140</id>
    <name>Gloom</name>
    <text>White spells cost {3} more to cast.
Activated abilities of white enchantments cost {3} more to activate.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0141</id>
    <name>Goblin Balloon Brigade</name>
    <text>{R}: Goblin Balloon Brigade gains flying until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>"From up here we can drop rocks and arrows and more rocks"
"Uh, yeah boss, but how do we get down?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0142</id>
    <name>Goblin King</name>
    <text>Other Goblin creatures get +1/+1 and have mountainwalk. (They're unblockable as long as defending player controls a Mountain.)</text>
    <flavorText>To become king of the Goblins, one must assassinate the previous king. Thus, only the most foolish seek positions of leadership.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0143</id>
    <name>Goblin Rock Sled</name>
    <text>Trample
Goblin Rock Sled doesn't untap during your untap step if it attacked during your last turn.
Goblin Rock Sled can't attack unless defending player controls a Mountain.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0144</id>
    <name>Grapeshot Catapult</name>
    <text>{T}: Grapeshot Catapult deals 1 damage to target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Recent research suggests these creatures were invented by Urza's and Mishra's original master, Tocasia, and that both brothers used them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0145</id>
    <name>Gray Ogre</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The Ogre philosopher Gnerdel believed the purpose of life was to live as high on the food chain as possible. She refused to eat vegetarians, preferring to live entirely on creatures that preyed on sentient beings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0146</id>
    <name>Greed</name>
    <text>{B}, Pay 2 life: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is no calamity greater than lavish desires. . . . And there is no greater disaster than greed."
—Tao Tê Ching 46</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0147</id>
    <name>Green Mana Battery</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Green Mana Battery.

{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Green Mana Battery: Add {G} to your mana pool, then add an additional {G} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0148</id>
    <name>Green Ward</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has protection from green. This effect doesn't remove Green Ward.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0149</id>
    <name>Grizzly Bears</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Don't try to outrun one of Dominia's Grizzlies; it'll catch you, knock you down, and eat you. Of course, you could run up a tree. In that case you'll get a nice view before it knocks the tree down and eats you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0150</id>
    <name>Healing Salve</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target player gains 3 life; or prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0151</id>
    <name>Helm of Chatzuk</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Target creature gains banding until end of turn. (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding a player controls are blocking or being blocked by a creature, that player divides that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0152</id>
    <name>Hill Giant</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Fortunately, Hill Giants have large blind spots in which a human can easily hide. Unfortunately, these blind spots are beneath the bottoms of their feet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0153</id>
    <name>Holy Armor</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +0/+2.
{W}: Enchanted creature gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0154</id>
    <name>Holy Strength</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0155</id>
    <name>Howl from Beyond</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0156</id>
    <name>Howling Mine</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's draw step, if Howling Mine is untapped, that player draws an additional card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0157</id>
    <name>Hurkyl's Recall</name>
    <text>Return all artifacts target player owns to his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>This spell, like many attributed to Drafna, was actually the work of his wife and former student, Hurkyl.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0158</id>
    <name>Hurloon Minotaur</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The Minotaurs of the Hurloon Mountains are known for their love of battle. They are also known for their hymns to the dead, sung for friend and foe alike. These hymns can last for days, filling the mountain valleys with their low, haunting sounds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0159</id>
    <name>Hurr Jackal</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature can't be regenerated this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0160</id>
    <name>Hurricane</name>
    <text>Hurricane deals X damage to each creature with flying and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0161</id>
    <name>Hypnotic Specter</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Hypnotic Specter deals damage to an opponent, that player discards a card at random.</text>
    <flavorText>". . . There was no trace
Of aught on that illumined face . . . ."
—Samuel Coleridge, "Phantom"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0162</id>
    <name>Immolation</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/-2.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0163</id>
    <name>Inferno</name>
    <text>Inferno deals 6 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Any scrap of compassion that still existed in my soul was permanently snuffed out when they cast me out into the flames."
—Mairsil, called the Pretender</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0164</id>
    <name>Instill Energy</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has haste.
{0}: Untap enchanted creature. Activate this ability only during your turn and only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0165</id>
    <name>Iron Star</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a red spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0166</id>
    <name>Ironclaw Orcs</name>
    <text>Ironclaw Orcs can't block creatures with power 2 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>Generations of genetic weeding have given rise to the deviously cowardly Ironclaw clan. To say that Orcs in general are vicious, depraved, and ignoble does not do justice to the Ironclaw.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0167</id>
    <name>Ironroot Treefolk</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The mating habits of Treefolk, particularly the stalwart Ironroot Treefolk, are truly absurd. Molasses comes to mind. It's amazing the species can survive at all given such protracted periods of mate selection, conjugation, and gestation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0168</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0169</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0170</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0171</id>
    <name>Island Fish Jasconius</name>
    <text>Island Fish Jasconius can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.
Island Fish Jasconius doesn't untap during your untap step.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {U}{U}{U}. If you do, untap Island Fish Jasconius.
When you control no Islands, sacrifice Island Fish Jasconius.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0172</id>
    <name>Island Sanctuary</name>
    <text>If you would draw a card during your draw step, instead you may skip that draw. If you do, until your next turn, you can't be attacked except by creatures with flying and/or islandwalk.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0173</id>
    <name>Ivory Cup</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a white spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0174</id>
    <name>Ivory Tower</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you gain X life, where X is the number of cards in your hand minus four.</text>
    <flavorText>Valuing scholarship above all else, the inhabitants of the Ivory Tower reward those who sacrifice power for knowledge.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0175</id>
    <name>Jade Monolith</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to target creature this turn, that source deals that damage to you instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0176</id>
    <name>Jandor's Saddlebags</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Untap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Each day of their journey, Jandor opened the saddlebags and found them full of mutton, quinces, cheese, date rolls, wine, and all manner of delicious and satisfying foods.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0177</id>
    <name>Jayemdae Tome</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0178</id>
    <name>Jump</name>
    <text>Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0179</id>
    <name>Junún Efreet</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Junún Efreet unless you pay {B}{B}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0180</id>
    <name>Karma</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Karma deals damage to that player equal to the number of Swamps he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0181</id>
    <name>Keldon Warlord</name>
    <text>Keldon Warlord's power and toughness are each equal to the number of non-Wall creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0182</id>
    <name>Killer Bees</name>
    <text>Flying
{G}: Killer Bees gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The communal mind produces a savage strategy, yet no one could predict that this vicious crossbreed would unravel the secret of steel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0183</id>
    <name>Kismet</name>
    <text>Artifacts, creatures, and lands your opponents control enter the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0184</id>
    <name>Kormus Bell</name>
    <text>All Swamps are 1/1 creatures that are still lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0185</id>
    <name>Land Leeches</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>"The standard cure for leeches requires the application of burning embers. Alternative methods must be devised should an ember of sufficient size prove more harmful than the leech."
—Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0186</id>
    <name>Land Tax</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if an opponent controls more lands than you, you may search your library for up to three basic land cards, reveal them, and put them into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0187</id>
    <name>Leviathan</name>
    <text>Trample
Leviathan enters the battlefield tapped and doesn't untap during your untap step.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may sacrifice two Islands. If you do, untap Leviathan.
Leviathan can't attack unless you sacrifice two Islands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0188</id>
    <name>Ley Druid</name>
    <text>{T}: Untap target land.</text>
    <flavorText>After years of training, the Druid becomes one with nature, drawing power form the land and returning it when needed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0189</id>
    <name>Library of Leng</name>
    <text>You have no maximum hand size.
If an effect causes you to discard a card, discard it, but you may put it on top of your library instead of into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0190</id>
    <name>Lifeforce</name>
    <text>{G}{G}: Counter target black spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0191</id>
    <name>Lifelace</name>
    <text>Target spell or permanent becomes green. (Mana symbols on that permanent remain unchanged.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0192</id>
    <name>Lifetap</name>
    <text>Whenever a Forest an opponent controls becomes tapped, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0193</id>
    <name>Lightning Bolt</name>
    <text>Lightning Bolt deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0194</id>
    <name>Living Artifact</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact
Whenever you're dealt damage, put that many vitality counters on Living Artifact.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may remove a vitality counter from Living Artifact. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0195</id>
    <name>Living Lands</name>
    <text>All Forests are 1/1 creatures that are still lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0196</id>
    <name>Llanowar Elves</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Hardened by their life in the haunted Llanowar Forest, these fierce beings are outcasts among elvenkind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0197</id>
    <name>Lord of Atlantis</name>
    <text>Other Merfolk creatures get +1/+1 and have islandwalk.</text>
    <flavorText>A master of tactics, the Lord of Atlantis makes his people bold in battle merely by arriving to lead them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0198</id>
    <name>Lord of the Pit</name>
    <text>Flying, trample
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice a creature other than Lord of the Pit. If you can't, Lord of the Pit deals 7 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0199</id>
    <name>Lost Soul</name>
    <text>Swampwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Her hand gently beckons,
she whispers your name—
But those who go with her
are never the same.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0200</id>
    <name>Lure</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
All creatures able to block enchanted creature do so.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0201</id>
    <name>Magical Hack</name>
    <text>Change the text of target spell or permanent by replacing all instances of one basic land type with another. (For example, you may change "swampwalk" to "plainswalk." This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0202</id>
    <name>Magnetic Mountain</name>
    <text>Blue creatures don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.
At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player may choose any number of tapped blue creatures he or she controls and pay {4} for each creature chosen this way. If the player does, untap those creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0203</id>
    <name>Mahamoti Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Of royal blood among the spirits of the air, the Mahamoti Djinn rides on the wings of the winds. As dangerous in the gambling hall as he is in battle, he is a master of trickery and misdirection.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0204</id>
    <name>Mana Clash</name>
    <text>You and target opponent each flip a coin. Mana Clash deals 1 damage to each player whose coin comes up tails. Repeat this process until both players' coins come up heads on the same flip.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0205</id>
    <name>Mana Flare</name>
    <text>Whenever a player taps a land for mana, that player adds one mana to his or her mana pool of any type that land produced.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0206</id>
    <name>Mana Short</name>
    <text>Tap all lands target player controls and empty his or her mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0207</id>
    <name>Mana Vault</name>
    <text>Mana Vault doesn't untap during your untap step.

At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {4}. If you do, untap Mana Vault.

At the beginning of your draw step, if Mana Vault is tapped, it deals 1 damage to you.

{T}: Add {3} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0208</id>
    <name>Manabarbs</name>
    <text>Whenever a player taps a land for mana, Manabarbs deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0209</id>
    <name>Marsh Gas</name>
    <text>All creatures get -2/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Comes right outta th' ground. If ya can smell it, it's too late."
—Keevy Bogsbury</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0210</id>
    <name>Marsh Viper</name>
    <text>Whenever Marsh Viper deals damage to an opponent, that player gets two poison counters. (A player with ten or more poison counters loses the game.)</text>
    <flavorText>"All we had left were their black and bloated bodies."
—Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0211</id>
    <name>Meekstone</name>
    <text>Creatures with power 3 or greater don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0212</id>
    <name>Merfolk of the Pearl Trident</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Most human scholars believe that Merfolk are the survivors of sunken Atlantis, humans adapted to the water. Merfolk, however, believe that humans sprang forth from Merfolk who adapted themselves in order to explore their last frontier.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0213</id>
    <name>Mesa Pegasus</name>
    <text>Flying; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>Before a woman marries in the village of Sursi, she must visit the land of the Mesa Pegasus. Legend has it that if the woman is pure of heart and her love is true, a Mesa Pegasus will appear, blessing her family with long life and good fortune.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0214</id>
    <name>Millstone</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target player puts the top two cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>More than one mage was driven insane by the sound of the Millstone relentlessly grinding away.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0215</id>
    <name>Mind Bomb</name>
    <text>Each player may discard up to three cards. Mind Bomb deals damage to each player equal to 3 minus the number of cards he or she discarded this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0216</id>
    <name>Mind Twist</name>
    <text>Target player discards X cards at random.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0217</id>
    <name>Mishra's Factory</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}: Mishra's Factory becomes a 2/2 Assembly-Worker artifact creature until end of turn. It's still a land.
{T}: Target Assembly-Worker creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0218</id>
    <name>Mishra's War Machine</name>
    <text>Banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, unless you discard a card, tap Mishra's War Machine and it deals 3 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0219</id>
    <name>Mons's Goblin Raiders</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The intricate dynamics of Rundvelt Goblin affairs are often confused with anarchy. The chaos, however, is the chaos of a thundercloud, and direction will sporadically and violently appear. Pashalik Mons and his Raiders are the thunderhead that leads in the storm.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0220</id>
    <name>Morale</name>
    <text>Attacking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"After Lacjsi's speech, the Knights grew determined to crush their ancient enemies clan by clan."
—Tivadar of Thorn, History of the Goblin Wars</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0221</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0222</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0223</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0224</id>
    <name>Murk Dwellers</name>
    <text>Whenever Murk Dwellers attacks and isn't blocked, it gets +2/+0 until end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>When Raganorn unsealed the catacombs, he found more than the dead and their treasures.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0225</id>
    <name>Nafs Asp</name>
    <text>Whenever Nafs Asp deals damage to a player, that player loses 1 life at the beginning of his or her next draw step unless he or she pays {1} before that draw step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0226</id>
    <name>Nether Shadow</name>
    <text>Haste
At the beginning of your upkeep, if Nether Shadow is in your graveyard with three or more creature cards above it, you may put Nether Shadow onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0227</id>
    <name>Nevinyrral's Disk</name>
    <text>Nevinyrral's Disk enters the battlefield tapped.
{1}, {T}: Destroy all artifacts, creatures, and enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0228</id>
    <name>Nightmare</name>
    <text>Flying
Nightmare's power and toughness are each equal to the number of Swamps you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The Nightmare arises from its lair in the swamps. As the poisoned land spreads, so does the Nightmare's rage and terrifying strength.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0229</id>
    <name>Northern Paladin</name>
    <text>{W}{W}, {T}: Destroy target black permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"Look to the north; there you will find aid and comfort."The Book of Tal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0230</id>
    <name>Oasis</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0231</id>
    <name>Obsianus Golem</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"The foot stone is connected to the ankle stone, the ankle stone is connected to the leg stone . . . ."
—Song of the Artificer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0232</id>
    <name>Onulet</name>
    <text>When Onulet is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>An early inspiration for Urza, Tocasia's Onulets contained magical essences that could be cannibalized after they stopped functioning.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0233</id>
    <name>Orcish Artillery</name>
    <text>{T}: Orcish Artillery deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>In a rare display of ingenuity, the Orcs invented an incredibly destructive weapon. Most Orcish artillerists are those who dared criticize its effectiveness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0234</id>
    <name>Orcish Oriflamme</name>
    <text>Attacking creatures you control get +1/+0.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0235</id>
    <name>Ornithopter</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Many scholars believe that these creatures were the result of Urza's first attempt at mechanical life, perhaps created in his early days as an apprentice to Tocasia.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0236</id>
    <name>Osai Vultures</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of each end step, if a creature was put into a graveyard from the battlefield this turn, put a carrion counter on Osai Vultures.
Remove two carrion counters from Osai Vultures: Osai Vultures gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0237</id>
    <name>Paralyze</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Paralyze enters the battlefield, tap enchanted creature.
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, that player may pay {4}. If he or she does, untap the creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0238</id>
    <name>Pearled Unicorn</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"‘Do you know, I always thought Unicorns were fabulous monsters, too? I never saw one alive before' ‘Well, now that we have seen each other,' said the Unicorn, ‘if you'll believe in me, I'll believe in you.'"
—Lewis Carroll</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0239</id>
    <name>Personal Incarnation</name>
    <text>{0}: The next 1 damage that would be dealt to Personal Incarnation this turn is dealt to its owner instead. Any player may activate this ability, but only if he or she owns Personal Incarnation.
When Personal Incarnation is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, its owner loses half his or her life, rounded up.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0240</id>
    <name>Pestilence</name>
    <text>At the beginning of the end step, if no creatures are on the battlefield, sacrifice Pestilence.
{B}: Pestilence deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0241</id>
    <name>Phantasmal Forces</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Phantasmal Forces unless you pay {U}.</text>
    <flavorText>These beings embody the essence of true heroes long dead. Summoned from the dreamrealms, they rise to meet their enemies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0242</id>
    <name>Phantasmal Terrain</name>
    <text>Enchant land
As Phantasmal Terrain enters the battlefield, choose a basic land type.
Enchanted land is the chosen type.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0243</id>
    <name>Phantom Monster</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"While, like a ghastly rapid river,
Through the pale door,
A hideous throng rush out forever,
And laugh—but smile no more."
—Edgar Allan Poe, "The Haunted Palace"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0244</id>
    <name>Piety</name>
    <text>Blocking creatures get +0/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Whoever obeys God and His Prophet, fears God and does his duty to Him, will surely find success."
—The Qur'an, 24:52</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0245</id>
    <name>Pikemen</name>
    <text>First strike; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"As the cavalry bore down, we faced them with swords drawn and pikes hidden in the grass at our feet. ‘Don't lift your pikes 'til I give the word,' I said."
—Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0246</id>
    <name>Pirate Ship</name>
    <text>Pirate Ship can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.
{T}: Pirate Ship deals 1 damage to target creature or player.
When you control no Islands, sacrifice Pirate Ship.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0247</id>
    <name>Pit Scorpion</name>
    <text>Whenever Pit Scorpion deals damage to a player, that player gets a poison counter. (A player with ten or more poison counters loses the game.)</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes the smallest nuisance can be the greatest pain.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0248</id>
    <name>Plague Rats</name>
    <text>Plague Rats's power and toughness are each equal to the number of creatures named Plague Rats on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>During the dark times, the rats seemed to grow ever stronger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0249</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0250</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0251</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0252</id>
    <name>Power Leak</name>
    <text>Enchant enchantment
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted enchantment's controller, that player may pay any amount of mana. Power Leak deals 2 damage to that player. Prevent X of that damage, where X is the amount of mana that player paid this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0253</id>
    <name>Power Sink</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}. If he or she doesn't, that player taps all lands with mana abilities he or she controls and empties his or her mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0254</id>
    <name>Power Surge</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Power Surge deals X damage to that player, where X is the number of untapped lands he or she controlled at the beginning of this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0255</id>
    <name>Pradesh Gypsies</name>
    <text>{1}{G}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0256</id>
    <name>Primal Clay</name>
    <text>As Primal Clay enters the battlefield, it becomes your choice of a 3/3 artifact creature, a 2/2 artifact creature with flying, or a 1/6 Shapeshifter Wall artifact creature with defender.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0257</id>
    <name>Prodigal Sorcerer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prodigal Sorcerer deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Occasionally a member of the Institute of Arcane Study acquires a taste for worldly pleasures. Seldom do they have trouble finding employment.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0258</id>
    <name>Psionic Entity</name>
    <text>{T}: Psionic Entity deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to itself.</text>
    <flavorText>Creatures of the Æther are notorious for neglecting their own well-being.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0259</id>
    <name>Psychic Venom</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land becomes tapped, Psychic Venom deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0260</id>
    <name>Purelace</name>
    <text>Target spell or permanent becomes white. (Mana symbols on that permanent remain unchanged.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0261</id>
    <name>Pyrotechnics</name>
    <text>Pyrotechnics deals 4 damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>"Hi ni ya Behold the man of flint, that's me
Four lightnings zigzag from me, strike and return."
—Navajo war chant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0262</id>
    <name>Radjan Spirit</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature loses flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0263</id>
    <name>Rag Man</name>
    <text>{B}{B}{B}, {T}: Target opponent reveals his or her hand and discards a creature card at random. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Aw, he's just a silly, dirty little man. What's to be afraid of?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0264</id>
    <name>Raise Dead</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0265</id>
    <name>Rebirth</name>
    <text>Remove Rebirth from your deck before playing if you're not playing for ante.

Each player may put the top card of his or her library into the ante. If a player does, his or her life total becomes 20.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0266</id>
    <name>Red Elemental Blast</name>
    <text>Choose one — Counter target blue spell; or destroy target blue permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0267</id>
    <name>Red Mana Battery</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Red Mana Battery.

{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Red Mana Battery: Add {R} to your mana pool, then add an additional {R} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0268</id>
    <name>Red Ward</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has protection from red. This effect doesn't remove Red Ward.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0269</id>
    <name>Regeneration</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
{G}: Regenerate enchanted creature. (The next time that creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0270</id>
    <name>Relic Bind</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact an opponent controls
Whenever enchanted artifact becomes tapped, choose one — Relic Bind deals 1 damage to target player; or target player gains 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0271</id>
    <name>Reverse Damage</name>
    <text>The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage. You gain life equal to the damage prevented this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0272</id>
    <name>Righteousness</name>
    <text>Target blocking creature gets +7/+7 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0273</id>
    <name>Rod of Ruin</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Rod of Ruin deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0274</id>
    <name>Royal Assassin</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target tapped creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Trained in the arts of stealth, the Royal Assassins choose their victims carefully, relying on timing and precision rather than brute force.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0275</id>
    <name>Samite Healer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Healers ultimately acquire the divine gifts of spiritual and physical wholeness. The most devout are also granted the ability to pass physical wholeness on to others.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0276</id>
    <name>Sandstorm</name>
    <text>Sandstorm deals 1 damage to each attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Even the landscape turned against Sarsour, first rising up and pelting him, then rearranging itself so he could no longer find his way.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0277</id>
    <name>Savannah Lions</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The traditional kings of the jungle command a healthy respect in other climates as well. Relying mainly on their stealth and speed, Savannah Lions can take a victim by surprise, even in the endless, flat plains of their homeland.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0278</id>
    <name>Scathe Zombies</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"They groaned, they stirred, they all uprose,
Nor spake, nor moved their eyes;
It had been strange, even in a dream,
To have seen those dead men rise."
—Samuel Coleridge, "The Rime of the Ancient Mariner"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0279</id>
    <name>Scavenging Ghoul</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each end step, put a corpse counter on Scavenging Ghoul for each creature put into a graveyard from the battlefield this turn.
Remove a corpse counter from Scavenging Ghoul: Regenerate Scavenging Ghoul.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0280</id>
    <name>Scryb Sprites</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>The only sound was the gentle clicking of the Faeries' wings. Then those intruders who were still standing turned and fled. One thing was certain: they didn't think the Scryb were very funny anymore.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0281</id>
    <name>Sea Serpent</name>
    <text>Sea Serpent can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.

When you control no Islands, sacrifice Sea Serpent.</text>
    <flavorText>Legend has it that Serpents used to be bigger, but how could that be?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0282</id>
    <name>Seeker</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or white creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0283</id>
    <name>Segovian Leviathan</name>
    <text>Islandwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Leviathan, too Can you catch him with a fish-hook or run a line round his tongue?"
—Job 40:25</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0284</id>
    <name>Sengir Vampire</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Whenever a creature dealt damage by Sengir Vampire this turn is put into a graveyard, put a +1/+1 counter on Sengir Vampire.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0285</id>
    <name>Serra Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
Vigilance (Attacking doesn't cause this creature to tap.)</text>
    <flavorText>Born with wings of light and a sword of faith, this heavenly incarnation embodies both fury and purity.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0286</id>
    <name>Shanodin Dryads</name>
    <text>Forestwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Moving without sound, swift figures pass through branches and undergrowth completely unhindered. One with the trees around them, the Dryads of Shanodin Forest are seen only when they wish to be.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0287</id>
    <name>Shapeshifter</name>
    <text>As Shapeshifter enters the battlefield, choose a number between 0 and 7.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may choose a number between 0 and 7.
Shapeshifter's power is equal to the last chosen number and its toughness is equal to 7 minus that number.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0288</id>
    <name>Shatter</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0289</id>
    <name>Shivan Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}: Shivan Dragon gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>While it's true most Dragons are cruel, the Shivan Dragon seems to take particular glee in the misery of others, often tormenting its victims much like a cat plays with a mouse before delivering the final blow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0290</id>
    <name>Simulacrum</name>
    <text>You gain life equal to the damage dealt to you this turn. Simulacrum deals damage to target creature you control equal to the damage dealt to you this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0291</id>
    <name>Sindbad</name>
    <text>{T}: Draw a card and reveal it. If it isn't a land card, discard it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0292</id>
    <name>Siren's Call</name>
    <text>Cast Siren's Call only during an opponent's turn, before attackers are declared.
Creatures the active player controls attack this turn if able.
At the beginning of the next end step, destroy all non-Wall creatures that player controls that didn't attack this turn. Ignore this effect for each creature the player didn't control continuously since the beginning of the turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0293</id>
    <name>Sisters of the Flame</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>We are many wicks sharing a common tallow; we feed the skies with the ashes of our prey.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0294</id>
    <name>Sleight of Mind</name>
    <text>Change the text of target spell or permanent by replacing all instances of one color word with another. (For example, you may change "target black spell" to "target blue spell." This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0295</id>
    <name>Smoke</name>
    <text>Players can't untap more than one creature during their untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0296</id>
    <name>Sorceress Queen</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature other than Sorceress Queen becomes 0/2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0297</id>
    <name>Soul Net</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0298</id>
    <name>Spell Blast</name>
    <text>Counter target spell with converted mana cost X.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0299</id>
    <name>Spirit Link</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0300</id>
    <name>Spirit Shackle</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature becomes tapped, put a -0/-2 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0301</id>
    <name>Stasis</name>
    <text>Players skip their untap steps.

At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Stasis unless you pay {U}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0302</id>
    <name>Steal Artifact</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact
You control enchanted artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0303</id>
    <name>Stone Giant</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature you control with toughness less than Stone Giant's power gains flying until end of turn. Destroy that creature at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0304</id>
    <name>Stone Rain</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0305</id>
    <name>Stream of Life</name>
    <text>Target player gains X life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0306</id>
    <name>Strip Mine</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{T}, Sacrifice Strip Mine: Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>Unlike previous conflicts, the war between Urza and Mishra made Dominia itself a casualty of war.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0307</id>
    <name>Sunglasses of Urza</name>
    <text>You may spend white mana as though it were red mana.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0308</id>
    <name>Sunken City</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Sunken City unless you pay {U}{U}.
Blue creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0309</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0310</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0311</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0312</id>
    <name>Swords to Plowshares</name>
    <text>Exile target creature. Its controller gains life equal to its power.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0313</id>
    <name>Sylvan Library</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your draw step, you may draw two additional cards. If you do, choose two cards in your hand drawn this turn. For each of those cards, pay 4 life or put the card on top of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0314</id>
    <name>Tawnos's Wand</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target creature with power 2 or less is unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0315</id>
    <name>Tawnos's Weaponry</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Tawnos's Weaponry during your untap step.
{2}, {T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 for as long as Tawnos's Weaponry remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>When war machines became too costly, Tawnos's Weaponry replaced them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0316</id>
    <name>Tempest Efreet</name>
    <text>Remove Tempest Efreet from your deck before playing if you're not playing for ante.
{T}, Sacrifice Tempest Efreet: Target opponent may pay 10 life. If that player doesn't, he or she reveals a card at random from his or her hand. Exchange ownership of the revealed card and Tempest Efreet. Put the revealed card into your hand and Tempest Efreet from anywhere into that player's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0317</id>
    <name>Terror</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonartifact, nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0318</id>
    <name>Tetravus</name>
    <text>Flying
Tetravus enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may remove any number of +1/+1 counters from Tetravus. If you do, put that many 1/1 colorless Tetravite artifact creature tokens onto the battlefield. They each have flying and "This creature can't be enchanted."
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may exile any number of tokens put onto the battlefield with Tetravus. If you do, put that many +1/+1 counters on Tetravus.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0319</id>
    <name>The Brute</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+0.
{R}{R}{R}: Regenerate enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Union may be strength, but it is mere blind brute strength unless wisely directed."
—Samuel Butler</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0320</id>
    <name>The Hive</name>
    <text>{5}, {T}: Put a 1/1 colorless Insect artifact creature token with flying named Wasp onto the battlefield. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0321</id>
    <name>The Rack</name>
    <text>As The Rack enters the battlefield, choose an opponent.
At the beginning of the chosen player's upkeep, The Rack deals X damage to that player, where X is 3 minus the number of cards in his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Invented in Mishra's earlier days, the Rack was once his most feared creation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0322</id>
    <name>Thicket Basilisk</name>
    <text>Whenever Thicket Basilisk blocks or becomes blocked by a non-Wall creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>Moss-covered statues littered the area, a macabre monument to the Basilisk's power.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0323</id>
    <name>Thoughtlace</name>
    <text>Target spell or permanent becomes blue. (Mana symbols on that permanent remain unchanged.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0324</id>
    <name>Throne of Bone</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a black spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0325</id>
    <name>Timber Wolves</name>
    <text>Banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>Though many think of Wolves as solitary predators, they are actually extremely social animals. During a hunt they often call to each other, which can be quite unsettling for their prey.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0326</id>
    <name>Time Elemental</name>
    <text>When Time Elemental attacks or blocks, at end of combat, sacrifice it and it deals 5 damage to you.
{2}{U}{U}, {T}: Return target permanent that isn't enchanted to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0327</id>
    <name>Titania's Song</name>
    <text>Each noncreature artifact loses its abilities and becomes an artifact creature with power and toughness each equal to its converted mana cost. If Titania's Song leaves the battlefield, this effect continues until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0328</id>
    <name>Tranquility</name>
    <text>Destroy all enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0329</id>
    <name>Triskelion</name>
    <text>Triskelion enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it.
Remove a +1/+1 counter from Triskelion: Triskelion deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>A brainchild of Tawnos, the Triskelion later proved both versatile and useful.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0330</id>
    <name>Tsunami</name>
    <text>Destroy all Islands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0331</id>
    <name>Tundra Wolves</name>
    <text>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>I heard their eerie howling, the wolves calling their kindred across the frozen plains.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0332</id>
    <name>Tunnel</name>
    <text>Destroy target Wall. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0333</id>
    <name>Twiddle</name>
    <text>You may tap or untap target artifact, creature, or land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0334</id>
    <name>Uncle Istvan</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt to Uncle Istvan by creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Solitude drove the old hermit insane. Now he only keeps company with those he can catch.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0335</id>
    <name>Unholy Strength</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0336</id>
    <name>Unstable Mutation</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, put a -1/-1 counter on that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0337</id>
    <name>Unsummon</name>
    <text>Return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0338</id>
    <name>Untamed Wilds</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0339</id>
    <name>Urza's Avenger</name>
    <text>{0}: Urza's Avenger gets -1/-1 and gains your choice of banding, flying, first strike, or trample until end of turn. (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>Unable to settle on just one design, Urza decided to create one versatile being.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0340</id>
    <name>Uthden Troll</name>
    <text>{R}: Regenerate Uthden Troll.</text>
    <flavorText>"Oi oi oi, me gotta hurt in 'ere,
Oi oi oi, me smell a ting is near,
Gonna bosh 'n gonna nosh
'n da hurt'll disappear."
—Troll chant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0341</id>
    <name>Vampire Bats</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
{B}: Vampire Bats gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Activate this ability no more than twice each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"For something is amiss or out of place
When mice with wings can wear a human face."
—Theodore Roethke, "The Bat"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0342</id>
    <name>Venom</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature blocks or becomes blocked by a non-Wall creature, destroy the other creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"I told him it was just a flesh wound, but the next time I looked at him, poor Tadhg was dead and gone."
—Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0343</id>
    <name>Verduran Enchantress</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an enchantment spell, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Some say magic was first practiced by women, who have always felt strong ties to the land.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0344</id>
    <name>Visions</name>
    <text>Look at the top five cards of target player's library. You may then have that player shuffle that library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Visions of glory, spare my aching sight,
Ye unborn ages, crowd not on my soul"
—Thomas Gray, "The Bard"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0345</id>
    <name>Volcanic Eruption</name>
    <text>Destroy X target Mountains. Volcanic Eruption deals damage to each creature and each player equal to the number of Mountains destroyed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0346</id>
    <name>Wall of Air</name>
    <text>Defender, flying (This creature can't attack, and it can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>"This ‘standing windstorm' can hold us off indefinitely? Ridiculous" Saying nothing, she put a pinch of salt on the table. With a bang she clapped her hands, and the salt disappeared, blown away.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0347</id>
    <name>Wall of Bone</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{B}: Regenerate Wall of Bone. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>The Wall of Bone is said to be an aspect of the Great Wall in Hel, where the bones of all sinners wait for Ragnarok, when Hela will call them forth for the final battle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0348</id>
    <name>Wall of Brambles</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{G}: Regenerate Wall of Brambles.</text>
    <flavorText>"What else, when chaos
draws all forces inward
to shape a single leaf."
—Conrad Aiken</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0349</id>
    <name>Wall of Dust</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Whenever Wall of Dust blocks a creature, that creature can't attack during its controller's next turn.</text>
    <flavorText>An ever-moving swarm of dust engulfs and disorients anything that comes near.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0350</id>
    <name>Wall of Fire</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{R}: Wall of Fire gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Conjured from the bowels of hell, the fiery wall forms an impassable barrier, searing the soul of any creature attempting to pass through its terrible bursts of flame.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0351</id>
    <name>Wall of Ice</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</text>
    <flavorText>"And through the drifts the snowy cliffs
Did send a dismal sheen:
Nor shapes of men nor beasts we ken—
The ice was all between."
—Samuel Coleridge, "The Rime of the Ancient Mariner"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0352</id>
    <name>Wall of Spears</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
First strike</text>
    <flavorText>Even the most conservative generals revised their tactics after the Battle of Sarinth, during which a handful of peasant-pikemen held off a trio of rampaging Craw Wurms.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0353</id>
    <name>Wall of Stone</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</text>
    <flavorText>The Earth herself lends her strength to these walls of living stone, which possess the stability of ancient mountains. These mighty bulwarks thwart ground-based troops, providing welcome relief for weary warriors who defend the land.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0354</id>
    <name>Wall of Swords</name>
    <text>Defender, flying (This creature can't attack, and it can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>Just as the evil ones approached to slay Justina, she cast a great spell, imbuing her weapons with her own life force. Thus she fulfilled the prophecy: "In the death of your savior will you find salvation."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0355</id>
    <name>Wall of Water</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{U}: Wall of Water gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A deafening roar arose as the fury of an enormous vertical river supplanted our serenity. Eddies turned into whirling geysers, leveling everything in their path.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0356</id>
    <name>Wall of Wood</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</text>
    <flavorText>Everybody knows that to ward off trouble, you knock on wood. But usually it's better to make a wall out of the wood and let trouble do the knocking.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0357</id>
    <name>Wanderlust</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, Wanderlust deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0358</id>
    <name>War Mammoth</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>I didn't think Mammoths could ever hold a candle to a well-trained battle horse. Then one day I turned my back on a drunken soldier. His blow never landed; Mi'cha flung the brute over ten meters.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0359</id>
    <name>Warp Artifact</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted artifact's controller, Warp Artifact deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0360</id>
    <name>Water Elemental</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Unpredictable as the sea itself, Water Elementals shift without warning from tranquility to tempest. Capricious and fickle, they flow restlessly from one shape to another, expressing their moods with their physical forms.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0361</id>
    <name>Weakness</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets -2/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0362</id>
    <name>Web</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature gets +0/+2 and has reach. (It can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0363</id>
    <name>Whirling Dervish</name>
    <text>Protection from black
At the beginning of each end step, if Whirling Dervish dealt damage to an opponent this turn, put a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0364</id>
    <name>White Knight</name>
    <text>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)
Protection from black (This creature can't be blocked, targeted, dealt damage, or enchanted by anything black.)</text>
    <flavorText>Out of the blackness and stench of the engulfing swamp emerged a shimmering figure. Only the splattered armor and ichor-stained sword hinted at the unfathomable evil the Knight had just laid waste.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0365</id>
    <name>White Mana Battery</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on White Mana Battery.

{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from White Mana Battery: Add {W} to your mana pool, then add an additional {W} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0366</id>
    <name>White Ward</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has protection from white. This effect doesn't remove White Ward.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0367</id>
    <name>Wild Growth</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds {G} to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0368</id>
    <name>Will-o'-the-Wisp</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
{B}: Regenerate Will-o'-the-Wisp. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>"About, about in reel and rout
The death-fires danced at night;
The water, like a witch's oils,
Burnt green, and blue and white."
—Samuel Coleridge, "The Rime of the Ancient Mariner"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0369</id>
    <name>Winds of Change</name>
    <text>Each player shuffles the cards from his or her hand into his or her library, then draws that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"'Tis the set of sails, and not the gales, Which tells us the way to go."
—Ella Wheeler Wilcox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0370</id>
    <name>Winter Blast</name>
    <text>Tap X target creatures. Winter Blast deals 2 damage to each of those creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Blow, winds, and crack your cheeks rage blow"
—William Shakespeare, King Lear</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0371</id>
    <name>Winter Orb</name>
    <text>As long as Winter Orb is untapped, players can't untap more than one land during their untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0372</id>
    <name>Wooden Sphere</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a green spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0373</id>
    <name>Word of Binding</name>
    <text>Tap X target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"That was the worst experience of my days: standing there helpless as they killed my whole troop."
—Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0374</id>
    <name>Wrath of God</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0375</id>
    <name>Xenic Poltergeist</name>
    <text>{T}: Until your next upkeep, target noncreature artifact becomes an artifact creature with power and toughness each equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0376</id>
    <name>Yotian Soldier</name>
    <text>Vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>After Kroog was destroyed while most of its defenders were at his side, Urza vowed that none of his allies would ever need to fear for their own defense again, even while laying siege to a city far from their homes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0377</id>
    <name>Zephyr Falcon</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>Although greatly prized among falconers, the Zephyr Falcon is capricious and not easily tamed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>4ED0378</id>
    <name>Zombie Master</name>
    <text>Other Zombie creatures have swampwalk.
Other Zombies have "{B}: Regenerate this permanent."</text>
    <flavorText>They say the Zombie Master controlled these foul creatures even before his own death, but now that he is one of them, nothing can make them betray him.</flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>