<cards name="Classic Sixth Edition">
  <item>
    <id>6ED0001</id>
    <name>Animate Wall</name>
    <text>Enchant Wall
Enchanted Wall can attack as though it didn't have defender.</text>
    <flavorText>"When you have been bitten with fangs of granite, you start to long for the ivory sabers of tigers."
—Norin the Wary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0002</id>
    <name>Archangel</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>"My mother once told me angels sing their swords' names with each strike."
—Sisay, Captain of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0003</id>
    <name>Ardent Militia</name>
    <text>Vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>Some fight for honor and some for gold, but the militia fight for hearth and home.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0004</id>
    <name>Armageddon</name>
    <text>Destroy all lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0005</id>
    <name>Armored Pegasus</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Asked how it survived a run-in with a bog imp, the pegasus just shook its mane and burped.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0006</id>
    <name>Castle</name>
    <text>Untapped creatures you control get +0/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>"Hang out our banners on the outward walls; / The cry is still, ‘They come'; our castle's strength / Will laugh a siege to scorn."
—William Shakespeare, Macbeth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0007</id>
    <name>Celestial Dawn</name>
    <text>Lands you control are Plains.
Nonland cards you own that aren't on the battlefield, spells you control, and nonland permanents you control are white.
You may spend white mana as though it were mana of any color. You may spend other mana only as though it were colorless mana.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0008</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Black</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a black source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0009</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Blue</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a blue source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0010</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Green</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a green source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0011</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: Red</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a red source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0012</id>
    <name>Circle of Protection: White</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a white source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0013</id>
    <name>Crusade</name>
    <text>White creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0014</id>
    <name>D'Avenant Archer</name>
    <text>{T}: D'Avenant Archer deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Avenant's archers are also trained as poets, so that each arrow is guided by a fragment of verse.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0015</id>
    <name>Daraja Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying
Sacrifice Daraja Griffin: Destroy target black creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"And the flamingos said, ‘Get out of our nest—we can't be seen with the likes of you' So, the griffin ate them."
—Azeworai, "The Ugly Bird"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0016</id>
    <name>Disenchant</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0017</id>
    <name>Divine Transformation</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.</text>
    <flavorText>Glory surged through her and radiance surrounded her. All things were possible with the blessing of the Divine.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0018</id>
    <name>Ekundu Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying, first strike</text>
    <flavorText>"My goat was a small price to pay for the chance to see the hunting griffin dive and seize it."
—Suq'Ata trader</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0019</id>
    <name>Enlightened Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for an artifact or enchantment card and reveal that card. Shuffle your library, then put the card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>"I do not teach. I simply reveal."
—Daudi, Femeref tutor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0020</id>
    <name>Ethereal Champion</name>
    <text>Pay 1 life: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to Ethereal Champion this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"If I have learned anything as a wizard it is this: never fight your own battles."
—Waffa, sorcerer of Nyomba</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0021</id>
    <name>Exile</name>
    <text>Exile target nonwhite attacking creature. You gain life equal to its toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0022</id>
    <name>Healing Salve</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target player gains 3 life; or prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0023</id>
    <name>Heavy Ballista</name>
    <text>{T}: Heavy Ballista deals 2 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Archers, balliste—you can't even get near the island of Avenant."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0024</id>
    <name>Hero's Resolve</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+5.</text>
    <flavorText>"Destiny, chance, fate, fortune—they're all just ways of claiming your successes without claiming your failures."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0025</id>
    <name>Icatian Town</name>
    <text>Put four 1/1 white Citizen creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Icatia's once-peaceful towns faced increasing attacks from orcs and goblins as the climate cooled. By the time the empire fell, they were little more than armed camps.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0026</id>
    <name>Infantry Veteran</name>
    <text>{T}: Target attacking creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The true dishonor for a soldier is surviving the war."
—Telim'Tor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0027</id>
    <name>Kismet</name>
    <text>Artifacts, creatures, and lands your opponents control enter the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>"Make people wait for what they want, and you have power over them. This is as true for merchants and militia as it is for cooks and couples."
—Gwendlyn Di Corci</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0028</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Royal Guard</name>
    <text>{T}: All combat damage that would be dealt to you by unblocked creatures this turn is dealt to Kjeldoran Royal Guard instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Honorable in battle, generous in death.
—Motto of the Kjeldoran Royal Guard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0029</id>
    <name>Light of Day</name>
    <text>Black creatures can't attack or block.</text>
    <flavorText>"I do not miss sunlight. The very memory of it burns my eyes."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0030</id>
    <name>Longbow Archer</name>
    <text>First strike; reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>"If it bears wings, I will pin it to the skies over Tefemburu."
—Roya, Zhalfirin archer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0031</id>
    <name>Mesa Falcon</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{W}: Mesa Falcon gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The faith of Serra is borne on wings of hope."
—Gulsen, abbey matron</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0032</id>
    <name>Order of the Sacred Torch</name>
    <text>{T}, Pay 1 life: Counter target black spell.</text>
    <flavorText>A blazing light to drive out the shadows.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0033</id>
    <name>Pacifism</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block.</text>
    <flavorText>For the first time in his life, Grakk felt a little warm and fuzzy inside.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0034</id>
    <name>Pearl Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{W}: Pearl Dragon gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"They knew Bantau was lost when, to hide the pearl he had found on the beach, he swallowed it—and soon grew wings."
—Hakim, Loreweaver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0035</id>
    <name>Regal Unicorn</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Unicorns don't care if you believe in them any more than you care if they believe in you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0036</id>
    <name>Remedy</name>
    <text>Prevent the next 5 damage that would be dealt this turn to any number of target creatures and/or players, divided as you choose.</text>
    <flavorText>"These things will protect you while I'm gone, remind you of my love for you."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0037</id>
    <name>Reprisal</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature with power 4 or greater. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"The meek shall fight as one, and they shall overcome even the greatest of foes."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0038</id>
    <name>Resistance Fighter</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Resistance Fighter: Prevent all combat damage target creature would deal this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"My soldiers fought without hesitation, died without doubt."
—Sidar Jabari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0039</id>
    <name>Reverse Damage</name>
    <text>The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage. You gain life equal to the damage prevented this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0040</id>
    <name>Samite Healer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Healers ultimately acquire the divine gifts of spiritual and physical wholeness. The most devout are also granted the ability to pass physical wholeness on to others.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0041</id>
    <name>Serenity</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy all artifacts and enchantments. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Just think of me as the storm before the calm."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0042</id>
    <name>Serra's Blessing</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have vigilance. (Attacking doesn't cause them to tap.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I have seen your strength imbued in angels' wings, and I have felt your sorrow rain down on the ruins brought by the Lord of the Wastes."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0043</id>
    <name>Spirit Link</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0044</id>
    <name>Standing Troops</name>
    <text>Vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>The less you have, the harder you fight for it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0045</id>
    <name>Staunch Defenders</name>
    <text>When Staunch Defenders enters the battlefield, you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Hold your position Leave doubt for the dying"
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0046</id>
    <name>Sunweb</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Flying
Sunweb can't block creatures with power 2 or less.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is no sweeter music than the wails of a dying dragon."
—Rashida Scalebane</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0047</id>
    <name>Tariff</name>
    <text>Each player sacrifices the creature he or she controls with the highest converted mana cost unless he or she pays that creature's mana cost. If two creatures a player controls are tied for highest cost, that player chooses one.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0048</id>
    <name>Tundra Wolves</name>
    <text>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>I heard their eerie howling, the wolves calling their kindred across the frozen plains.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0049</id>
    <name>Unyaro Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying

Sacrifice Unyaro Griffin: Counter target red instant or sorcery spell.</text>
    <flavorText>The griffin's shadow gives courage to the righteous and dread to the idle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0050</id>
    <name>Venerable Monk</name>
    <text>When Venerable Monk enters the battlefield, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>His presence brings not only a strong arm but also renewed hope.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0051</id>
    <name>Wall of Swords</name>
    <text>Defender, flying (This creature can't attack, and it can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>Sharper than wind, lighter than air.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0052</id>
    <name>Warmth</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a red spell, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Flame grows gentle with but a little distance."
—Orim, Samite healer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0053</id>
    <name>Warrior's Honor</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0054</id>
    <name>Wrath of God</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0055</id>
    <name>Abduction</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Abduction enters the battlefield, untap enchanted creature.
You control enchanted creature.
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, return that card to the battlefield under its owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0056</id>
    <name>Air Elemental</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>As insubstantial, and as powerful, as the wind that carries it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0057</id>
    <name>Ancestral Memories</name>
    <text>Look at the top seven cards of your library. Put two of them into your hand and the rest into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0058</id>
    <name>Boomerang</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>A lie always returns; be careful how you catch it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0059</id>
    <name>Browse</name>
    <text>{2}{U}{U}: Look at the top five cards of your library, put one of them into your hand, and exile the rest.</text>
    <flavorText>"Once great literature—now great litter."
—Jaya Ballard, task mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0060</id>
    <name>Chill</name>
    <text>Red spells cost {2} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>"Temper, temper."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0061</id>
    <name>Counterspell</name>
    <text>Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0062</id>
    <name>Daring Apprentice</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Daring Apprentice: Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>In front of every great wizard is a doomed apprentice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0063</id>
    <name>Deflection</name>
    <text>Change the target of target spell with a single target.</text>
    <flavorText>Up and down,
over and through,
back around—
the joke's on you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0064</id>
    <name>Desertion</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. If an artifact or creature spell is countered this way, put that card onto the battlefield under your control instead of into its owner's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>First the insult, then the injury.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0065</id>
    <name>Diminishing Returns</name>
    <text>Each player shuffles his or her hand and graveyard into his or her library. You exile the top ten cards of your library. Then each player draws up to seven cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0066</id>
    <name>Dream Cache</name>
    <text>Draw three cards, then put two cards from your hand both on top of your library or both on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Dreams' riches are easily spent.
—Suq'Ata adage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0067</id>
    <name>Flash</name>
    <text>You may put a creature card from your hand onto the battlefield. If you do, sacrifice it unless you pay its mana cost reduced by up to {2}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0068</id>
    <name>Flight</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has flying. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0069</id>
    <name>Fog Elemental</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
When Fog Elemental attacks or blocks, sacrifice it at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"I've seen fog so thick you could cut it, but none that could cut me."
—Tahngarth of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0070</id>
    <name>Forget</name>
    <text>Target player discards two cards, then draws as many cards as he or she discarded this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0071</id>
    <name>Gaseous Form</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0072</id>
    <name>Glacial Wall</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Huge walls of ice block further travel. We can't believe they are natural."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0073</id>
    <name>Harmattan Efreet</name>
    <text>Flying

{1}{U}{U}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"One moment I was walking along the beach, and the next I was high in the air, staring into a hideous smiling face."
—Tarub, Suq'Ata sailor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0074</id>
    <name>Horned Turtle</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"So like men are they: a hardened shell with fragile flesh beneath."
—Selenia, dark angel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0075</id>
    <name>Insight</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a green spell, you draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"We can fight with you or against you. After my day, I'd prefer the former."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0076</id>
    <name>Inspiration</name>
    <text>Target player draws two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Madness and genius are separated only by degrees of success."
—Sidar Jabari</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0077</id>
    <name>Juxtapose</name>
    <text>You and target player exchange control of the creature you each control with the highest converted mana cost. Then exchange control of artifacts the same way. If two or more permanents a player controls are tied for highest cost, their controller chooses one of them.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0078</id>
    <name>Library of Lat-Nam</name>
    <text>An opponent chooses one — You draw three cards at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep; or you search your library for a card, put that card into your hand, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0079</id>
    <name>Lord of Atlantis</name>
    <text>Other Merfolk creatures get +1/+1 and have islandwalk.</text>
    <flavorText>A master of tactics, the lord of Atlantis makes his people bold in battle merely by arriving to lead them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0080</id>
    <name>Mana Short</name>
    <text>Tap all lands target player controls and empty his or her mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0081</id>
    <name>Memory Lapse</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. If that spell is countered this way, put it on top of its owner's library instead of into that player's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"Um . . . oh . . . what was I saying?"
—Reveka, wizard savant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0082</id>
    <name>Merfolk of the Pearl Trident</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Are merfolk humans with fins, or are humans merfolk with feet?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0083</id>
    <name>Mystical Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for an instant or sorcery card and reveal that card. Shuffle your library, then put the card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>"To the tutors, a ‘poem of sand' was of little account, a ‘poem of ivory,' priceless."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0084</id>
    <name>Phantasmal Terrain</name>
    <text>Enchant land
As Phantasmal Terrain enters the battlefield, choose a basic land type.
Enchanted land is the chosen type.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0085</id>
    <name>Phantom Warrior</name>
    <text>Phantom Warrior is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>The phantom warrior comes from nowhere and returns there just as quickly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0086</id>
    <name>Polymorph</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature. It can't be regenerated. Its controller reveals cards from the top of his or her library until he or she reveals a creature card. The player puts that card onto the battlefield, then shuffles all other cards revealed this way into his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Ahh Opposable digits"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0087</id>
    <name>Power Sink</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}. If he or she doesn't, that player taps all lands with mana abilities he or she controls and empties his or her mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0088</id>
    <name>Prodigal Sorcerer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prodigal Sorcerer deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Occasionally members of the Institute of Arcane Study acquire a taste for worldly pleasures. Seldom do they have trouble finding employment.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0089</id>
    <name>Prosperity</name>
    <text>Each player draws X cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Wealth is a good thing, compared to poverty—your food is better, your robes are softer, and your companions have bathed more recently."
—Kukemssa pirate</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0090</id>
    <name>Psychic Transfer</name>
    <text>If the difference between your life total and target player's life total is 5 or less, exchange life totals with that player.</text>
    <flavorText>"The memory of your existence will fade like the final stars of morning."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0091</id>
    <name>Psychic Venom</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land becomes tapped, Psychic Venom deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0092</id>
    <name>Recall</name>
    <text>Discard X cards, then return a card from your graveyard to your hand for each card discarded this way. Exile Recall.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0093</id>
    <name>Relearn</name>
    <text>Return target instant or sorcery card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Barrin taught me that the hardest lessons to grasp are the ones you've already learned."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0094</id>
    <name>Remove Soul</name>
    <text>Counter target creature spell.</text>
    <flavorText>Nethya stiffened suddenly, head cocked as if straining to hear some distant sound, then fell lifeless to the ground.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0095</id>
    <name>Sage Owl</name>
    <text>Flying
When Sage Owl enters the battlefield, look at the top four cards of your library, then put them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>The owl asks but never answers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0096</id>
    <name>Sea Monster</name>
    <text>Sea Monster can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.</text>
    <flavorText>Water is life. Or perhaps it is just something to wash it down with.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0097</id>
    <name>Segovian Leviathan</name>
    <text>Islandwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Leviathan, too Can you catch him with a fish-hook or run a line round his tongue?"
—The Bible, Job 41:1</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0098</id>
    <name>Sibilant Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Sibilant Spirit attacks, defending player may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>She had expected death to roar, to thunder, to growl. She did not recognize it when it came hissing to her side.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0099</id>
    <name>Soldevi Sage</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice two lands: Draw three cards, then discard one of them.</text>
    <flavorText>"To hide the truth is more than folly—it is fatal."
—Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi heretic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0100</id>
    <name>Spell Blast</name>
    <text>Counter target spell with converted mana cost X.</text>
    <flavorText>Call it the thinking mage's version of brute force.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0101</id>
    <name>Storm Crow</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Storm crow descending, winter unending.
Storm crow departing, summer is starting.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0102</id>
    <name>Tidal Surge</name>
    <text>Tap up to three target creatures without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is nature that gives us our boundaries and nature that enforces them."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0103</id>
    <name>Unsummon</name>
    <text>Return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0104</id>
    <name>Vodalian Soldiers</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Vodalian rank is displayed by the colors and patterns of their skin. Beware the color red; that is the badge of the empress's favor."
—Corbio, pearl diver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0105</id>
    <name>Wall of Air</name>
    <text>Defender, flying (This creature can't attack, and it can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>When no falcons fly, beware the sky.
—Femeref aphorism</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0106</id>
    <name>Wind Drake</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"No bird soars too high, if he soars with his own wings."
—William Blake,
The Marriage of Heaven and Hell</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0107</id>
    <name>Wind Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying
Wind Spirit can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>" . . . When the trees bow down their heads,
The wind is passing by."
—Christina Rossetti,
"Who Has Seen the Wind?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0108</id>
    <name>Zur's Weirding</name>
    <text>Players play with their hands revealed.
If a player would draw a card, he or she reveals it instead. Then any other player may pay 2 life. If a player does, put that card into its owner's graveyard. Otherwise, that player draws a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0109</id>
    <name>Abyssal Hunter</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}: Tap target creature. Abyssal Hunter deals damage equal to Abyssal Hunter's power to that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Some smiles show cheer; some merely show teeth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0110</id>
    <name>Abyssal Specter</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Abyssal Specter deals damage to a player, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0111</id>
    <name>Agonizing Memories</name>
    <text>Look at target player's hand and choose two cards from it. Put them on top of that player's library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"An innocent man died because of my anger. That knowledge will haunt me for all eternity."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0112</id>
    <name>Ashen Powder</name>
    <text>Put target creature card from an opponent's graveyard onto the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>"What you call decay, I call ripening. You'll gain no sustenance from this harvest."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0113</id>
    <name>Blight</name>
    <text>Enchant land
When enchanted land becomes tapped, destroy it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0114</id>
    <name>Blighted Shaman</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a Swamp: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
{T}, Sacrifice a creature: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0115</id>
    <name>Blood Pet</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Blood Pet: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"You are wrong," Volrath said. "I do not hate the living. They often prove quite useful to me." And then he laughed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0116</id>
    <name>Bog Imp</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Don't be fooled by their looks. Think of them as little knives with wings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0117</id>
    <name>Bog Rats</name>
    <text>Bog Rats can't be blocked by Walls.</text>
    <flavorText>Their stench was vile and strong enough, but not nearly as powerful as their hunger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0118</id>
    <name>Bog Wraith</name>
    <text>Swampwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Swamp.)</text>
    <flavorText>It moved through the troops leaving no footprints, save on their souls.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0119</id>
    <name>Coercion</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You choose a card from it. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>A rhino's bargain
—Femeref expression meaning
"a situation with no choices"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0120</id>
    <name>Derelor</name>
    <text>Black spells you cast cost {B} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>"Strength it has, but at the cost of a continuous supply of energy. Such failure can bear only one result."
—Execution order of Endrek Sahr,
master breeder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0121</id>
    <name>Doomsday</name>
    <text>Search your library and graveyard for five cards and exile the rest. Put the chosen cards on top of your library in any order. You lose half your life, rounded up.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0122</id>
    <name>Dread of Night</name>
    <text>White creatures get -1/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>"These moonless, foreign skies keep me in thrall. Dark whispers echo in the night, and I cannot resist."
—Selenia, dark angel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0123</id>
    <name>Drudge Skeletons</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Drudge Skeletons. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The dead make good soldiers. They can't disobey orders, they never surrender, and they don't stop fighting when a random body part falls off."
—Nevinyrral, Necromancer's Handbook</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0124</id>
    <name>Dry Spell</name>
    <text>Dry Spell deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Wherever water is lacking, all things suffer."
—Autumn Willow</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0125</id>
    <name>Enfeeblement</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature gets -2/-2.</text>
    <flavorText>"If it is weak, either kill it or ignore it. Anything else honors it."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0126</id>
    <name>Evil Eye of Orms-by-Gore</name>
    <text>Non-Eye creatures you control can't attack.
Evil Eye of Orms-by-Gore can't be blocked except by Walls.</text>
    <flavorText>The highway of fear is the shortest route to defeat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0127</id>
    <name>Fallen Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
Sacrifice a creature: Fallen Angel gets +2/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Angels are simply extensions of truth upon the fabric of life—and there is far more dark than light."Baron Sengir</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0128</id>
    <name>Fatal Blow</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature that was dealt damage this turn. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"What is crueler? To let a wound of the heart fester, or to simply cut it out?"
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0129</id>
    <name>Fear</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has fear. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0130</id>
    <name>Feast of the Unicorn</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +4/+0.</text>
    <flavorText>"Could there be a fouler act? No doubt the baron knows of one."
—Autumn Willow</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0131</id>
    <name>Feral Shadow</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Not all shadows are cast by light—some are cast by darkness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0132</id>
    <name>Forbidden Crypt</name>
    <text>If you would draw a card, return a card from your graveyard to your hand instead. If you can't, you lose the game.
If a card would be put into your graveyard from anywhere, exile that card instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0133</id>
    <name>Gravebane Zombie</name>
    <text>If Gravebane Zombie would be put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put Gravebane Zombie on top of its owner's library instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0134</id>
    <name>Gravedigger</name>
    <text>When Gravedigger enters the battlefield, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>A full coffin is like a full coffer—both are attractive to thieves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0135</id>
    <name>Greed</name>
    <text>{B}, Pay 2 life: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is no calamity greater than lavish desires. There is no greater guilt than discontentment. And there is no greater disaster than greed."
—Lao Tsu, Tao Te Ching, (trans. Chan)</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0136</id>
    <name>Hecatomb</name>
    <text>When Hecatomb enters the battlefield, sacrifice Hecatomb unless you sacrifice four creatures.
Tap an untapped Swamp you control: Hecatomb deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0137</id>
    <name>Hidden Horror</name>
    <text>When Hidden Horror enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you discard a creature card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0138</id>
    <name>Howl from Beyond</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0139</id>
    <name>Infernal Contract</name>
    <text>Draw four cards. You lose half your life, rounded up.</text>
    <flavorText>"But I signed nothing"
—Taraneh, Suq'Ata mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0140</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Dead</name>
    <text>When Kjeldoran Dead enters the battlefield, sacrifice a creature.
{B}: Regenerate Kjeldoran Dead.</text>
    <flavorText>"They shall drink sorrow's dregs. They shall kill those whom once they loved."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0141</id>
    <name>Leshrac's Rite</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has swampwalk.</text>
    <flavorText>"Bind me to thee, my soul to thine. I am your servant and your slave. Blood for blood, flesh for flesh, Leshrac, my lord."
—Lim-Dûl, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0142</id>
    <name>Lost Soul</name>
    <text>Swampwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Her hand gently beckons, she whispers your name—but those who go with her are never the same.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0143</id>
    <name>Mind Warp</name>
    <text>Look at target player's hand and choose X cards from it. That player discards those cards.</text>
    <flavorText>The hardest of wizards can have the softest of minds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0144</id>
    <name>Mischievous Poltergeist</name>
    <text>Flying
Pay 1 life: Regenerate Mischievous Poltergeist.</text>
    <flavorText>"The past is a ghost that haunts you from the moment it exists until the moment you don't."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0145</id>
    <name>Necrosavant</name>
    <text>{3}{B}{B}, Sacrifice a creature: Return Necrosavant from your graveyard to the battlefield. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0146</id>
    <name>Nightmare</name>
    <text>Flying
Nightmare's power and toughness are each equal to the number of Swamps you control.</text>
    <flavorText>As the poisoned land spreads, so does the nightmare's rage and terrifying strength.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0147</id>
    <name>Painful Memories</name>
    <text>Look at target opponent's hand and choose a card from it. Put that card on top of that player's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is terrible how one brief action can live forever in memory."
—Jolrael</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0148</id>
    <name>Perish</name>
    <text>Destroy all green creatures. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"There will come a time when the voices of soil and seedling will sing only laments."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0149</id>
    <name>Pestilence</name>
    <text>At the beginning of the end step, if no creatures are on the battlefield, sacrifice Pestilence.
{B}: Pestilence deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0150</id>
    <name>Python</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"How can you claim the gods are merciless when they robbed the snake of its limbs to give the other creatures a sporting chance?"
—Hakim, Loreweaver</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0151</id>
    <name>Rag Man</name>
    <text>{B}{B}{B}, {T}: Target opponent reveals his or her hand and discards a creature card at random. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Aw, he's just a silly, dirty little man. What's to be afraid of?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0152</id>
    <name>Raise Dead</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The earth cannot hold that which magic commands.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0153</id>
    <name>Razortooth Rats</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Men and rats both hunger: we for our playthings; they, for us."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0154</id>
    <name>Scathe Zombies</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"They groaned, they stirred, they all uprose,
Nor spake, nor moved their eyes;
It had been strange, even in a dream,
To have seen those dead men rise."
—Samuel Coleridge,
"The Rime of the Ancient Mariner"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0155</id>
    <name>Sengir Autocrat</name>
    <text>When Sengir Autocrat enters the battlefield, put three 0/1 black Serf creature tokens onto the battlefield.
When Sengir Autocrat leaves the battlefield, exile all Serf tokens.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0156</id>
    <name>Strands of Night</name>
    <text>{B}{B}, Pay 2 life, Sacrifice a Swamp: Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have seen the night torn into thin darkling strips and woven into shapes too bleak for dreams."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0157</id>
    <name>Stromgald Cabal</name>
    <text>{T}, Pay 1 life: Counter target white spell.</text>
    <flavorText>When the alliance between Balduvia and Kjeldor deprived Stromgald of easy victories, its agents were forced to fuel their rituals with their own flesh.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0158</id>
    <name>Stupor</name>
    <text>Target opponent discards a card at random, then discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>There are medicines for all afflictions but idleness.
—Suq'Ata saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0159</id>
    <name>Syphon Soul</name>
    <text>Syphon Soul deals 2 damage to each other player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0160</id>
    <name>Terror</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonartifact, nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0161</id>
    <name>Vampiric Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for a card, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it. You lose 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"I write upon clean white parchment with a sharp quill and the blood of my students, divining their secrets."
—Shauku, Endbringer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0162</id>
    <name>Zombie Master</name>
    <text>Other Zombie creatures have swampwalk.
Other Zombies have "{B}: Regenerate this permanent."</text>
    <flavorText>He controlled the zombies even before his own death; now nothing can make them betray him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0163</id>
    <name>Æther Flash</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature enters the battlefield, Æther Flash deals 2 damage to it.</text>
    <flavorText>"You can't get there from here. Well, you can—it just won't be fun."
—Ertai, wizard adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0164</id>
    <name>Anaba Bodyguard</name>
    <text>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Not all minotaurs are tribal. Some are freelance."
—Eron the Relentless</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0165</id>
    <name>Anaba Shaman</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}: Anaba Shaman deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"The shamans? Ha They are craven cows not capable of true magic."
—Irini Sengir</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0166</id>
    <name>Balduvian Barbarians</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Barbarian raids were a concern to those living in the northwest provinces, but the skyknights never dealt with the problem in a systematic way. They thought of the Balduvians as an ‘amusing model' of their forebears' culture."
—Kjeldor: Ice Civilization</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0167</id>
    <name>Balduvian Horde</name>
    <text>When Balduvian Horde enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you discard a card at random.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0168</id>
    <name>Blaze</name>
    <text>Blaze deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Fire never dies alone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0169</id>
    <name>Boil</name>
    <text>Destroy all Islands.</text>
    <flavorText>"The fishers will throw out their nets and draw them back filled with dust."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0170</id>
    <name>Burrowing</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has mountainwalk.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0171</id>
    <name>Conquer</name>
    <text>Enchant land
You control enchanted land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why do we trade with those despicable elves? You don't live in forests, you burn them"
—Avram Garrisson,
Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0172</id>
    <name>Crimson Hellkite</name>
    <text>Flying

{X}, {T}: Crimson Hellkite deals X damage to target creature. Spend only red mana this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"Dragonfire forged me a warrior."
—Rashida Scalebane</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0173</id>
    <name>Earthquake</name>
    <text>Earthquake deals X damage to each creature without flying and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0174</id>
    <name>Fervor</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have haste.</text>
    <flavorText>"If your blood doesn't run hot, I will make it run in the sands"
—Maraxus of Keld</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0175</id>
    <name>Final Fortune</name>
    <text>Take an extra turn after this one. At the beginning of that turn's end step, you lose the game.</text>
    <flavorText>Want all, lose all.
—Zhalfirin aphorism</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0176</id>
    <name>Fire Elemental</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Fire elementals are ruthless infernos, annihilating and consuming their foes in a frenzied holocaust. Crackling and blazing, they sear swift, terrible paths, leaving the land charred and scorched in their wake.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0177</id>
    <name>Firebreathing</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Magic's only part of it, my friend. Diet does the rest."
—Suq'Ata trader</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0178</id>
    <name>Fit of Rage</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 and gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Anger is fleeting; remorse is eternal."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0179</id>
    <name>Flame Spirit</name>
    <text>{R}: Flame Spirit gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The spirit of the flame is the spirit of change."
—Lovisa Coldeyes,
Balduvian chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0180</id>
    <name>Flashfires</name>
    <text>Destroy all Plains.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0181</id>
    <name>Giant Strength</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>"O it is excellent / To have a giant's strength, but it is tyrannous / To use it like a giant."
—William Shakespeare,
Measure for Measure</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0182</id>
    <name>Goblin Digging Team</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Goblin Digging Team: Destroy target Wall.</text>
    <flavorText>"From down here we can make the whole wall collapse"
"Uh, yeah, boss, but how do we get out?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0183</id>
    <name>Goblin Elite Infantry</name>
    <text>Whenever Goblin Elite Infantry blocks or becomes blocked, it gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>They talk a good fight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0184</id>
    <name>Goblin Hero</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"When you're a goblin, you don't have to step forward to be a hero—everyone else just has to step back"
—Biggum Flodrot, goblin veteran</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0185</id>
    <name>Goblin King</name>
    <text>Other Goblin creatures get +1/+1 and have mountainwalk. (They're unblockable as long as defending player controls a Mountain.)</text>
    <flavorText>To be king, Numsgil did in Blog, who did in Unkful, who did in Viddle, who did in Loll, who did in Alrok . . . ."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0186</id>
    <name>Goblin Recruiter</name>
    <text>When Goblin Recruiter enters the battlefield, search your library for any number of Goblin cards and reveal those cards. Shuffle your library, then put them on top of it in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"Next"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0187</id>
    <name>Goblin Warrens</name>
    <text>{2}{R}, Sacrifice two Goblins: Put three 1/1 red Goblin creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Goblins bred underground, their numbers hidden from the enemy until it was too late."    Sarpadian Empires, vol. IV</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0188</id>
    <name>Hammer of Bogardan</name>
    <text>Hammer of Bogardan deals 3 damage to target creature or player.
{2}{R}{R}{R}: Return Hammer of Bogardan from your graveyard to your hand. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0189</id>
    <name>Hulking Cyclops</name>
    <text>Hulking Cyclops can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>Anyone can get around a cyclops, but few can stand in its way.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0190</id>
    <name>Illicit Auction</name>
    <text>Each player may bid life for control of target creature. You start the bidding with a bid of 0. In turn order, each player may top the high bid. The bidding ends if the high bid stands. The high bidder loses life equal to the high bid and gains control of the creature. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0191</id>
    <name>Inferno</name>
    <text>Inferno deals 6 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Some have said there is no subtlety to destruction. You know what? They're dead."  Jaya Ballard, task mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0192</id>
    <name>Jokulhaups</name>
    <text>Destroy all artifacts, creatures, and lands. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"The raging waters had swept away trees, bridges, and even houses. My healers had much work to do."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0193</id>
    <name>Lightning Blast</name>
    <text>Lightning Blast deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those who fear the darkness have never seen what the light can do."
—Selenia, dark angel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0194</id>
    <name>Manabarbs</name>
    <text>Whenever a player taps a land for mana, Manabarbs deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0195</id>
    <name>Mountain Goat</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Only the heroic and the mad follow mountain goat trails.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0196</id>
    <name>Orcish Artillery</name>
    <text>{T}: Orcish Artillery deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>In a rare display of ingenuity, the orcs invented an incredibly destructive weapon. Most orcish artillerists are those who dared criticize its effectiveness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0197</id>
    <name>Orcish Oriflamme</name>
    <text>Attacking creatures you control get +1/+0.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0198</id>
    <name>Pillage</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or land. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0199</id>
    <name>Pyrotechnics</name>
    <text>Pyrotechnics deals 4 damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>"Hiniya Behold the man of flint, that's me / Four lightnings zigzag from me, strike and return."
—Navajo war chant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0200</id>
    <name>Raging Goblin</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)</text>
    <flavorText>He raged at the world, at his family, at his life. But mostly he just raged.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0201</id>
    <name>Reckless Embermage</name>
    <text>{1}{R}: Reckless Embermage deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to itself.</text>
    <flavorText>Many mages have been consumed by their work.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0202</id>
    <name>Relentless Assault</name>
    <text>Untap all creatures that attacked this turn. After this main phase, there is an additional combat phase followed by an additional main phase.</text>
    <flavorText>"Flog and Squee / Up the tree / See the army / Flee, flee, flee."
—Goblin nursery rhyme/war cry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0203</id>
    <name>Sabretooth Tiger</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>"I fear anything with teeth measured in handspans"
—Norin the Wary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0204</id>
    <name>Shatter</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0205</id>
    <name>Shatterstorm</name>
    <text>Destroy all artifacts. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>Chains of leaping fire and sizzling lightning laid waste the artificers' handiwork, sparing not a single device.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0206</id>
    <name>Shock</name>
    <text>Shock deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Lightning tethers souls to the world.
—Kor saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0207</id>
    <name>Spitting Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}: Spitting Drake gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It prefers its meals cooked.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0208</id>
    <name>Spitting Earth</name>
    <text>Spitting Earth deals damage equal to the number of Mountains you control to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"There are times solid ground gives precious little comfort."
—Talibah, embermage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0209</id>
    <name>Stone Rain</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0210</id>
    <name>Talruum Minotaur</name>
    <text>Haste</text>
    <flavorText>Don't insult a Talruum unless your mount is swift.
—Suq'Ata saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0211</id>
    <name>Tremor</name>
    <text>Tremor deals 1 damage to each creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Where do you run when the earth becomes your enemy?"
—Naimag, Femeref philosopher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0212</id>
    <name>Vertigo</name>
    <text>Vertigo deals 2 damage to target creature with flying. That creature loses flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I saw the wizard gesturing, but I didn't guess his plan until my aesthir cried out and went into a dive."
—Arna Kennerüd, skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0213</id>
    <name>Viashino Warrior</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"When traveling the Great Desert avoid wearing the scales of lizards, for the Viashino rule the sands and look poorly on the skinning of their cousins."
—Zhalfirin Guide to the Desert</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0214</id>
    <name>Volcanic Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying, haste</text>
    <flavorText>Speed and fire are always a deadly combination.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0215</id>
    <name>Volcanic Geyser</name>
    <text>Volcanic Geyser deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>My thunder comes before the lightning; my lightning comes before the clouds; my rain dries all the land it touches. What am I?
—Femeref riddle</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0216</id>
    <name>Wall of Fire</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{R}: Wall of Fire gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Struggle, and you will only fan the flames."
—Talibah, embermage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0217</id>
    <name>Birds of Paradise</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0218</id>
    <name>Call of the Wild</name>
    <text>{2}{G}{G}: Reveal the top card of your library. If it's a creature card, put it onto the battlefield. Otherwise, put it into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Thinking of dinner made Squee realize that the forest was probably thinking the same thing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0219</id>
    <name>Cat Warriors</name>
    <text>Forestwalk</text>
    <flavorText>These stealthy felines have survived so many battles that some believe they must possess many lives.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0220</id>
    <name>Creeping Mold</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact, enchantment, or land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mold could catch you."
—Suq'Ata insult</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0221</id>
    <name>Dense Foliage</name>
    <text>Creatures can't be the targets of spells.</text>
    <flavorText>"Big plants not only good for hidin', but full o' tasty bugs, too."
—Squee, goblin cabin hand</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0222</id>
    <name>Early Harvest</name>
    <text>Target player untaps all basic lands he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"Tonight we'll have a farewell feast. Cold corn porridge is not enough. / Let's peel papayas, pineapples, and mangoes, drink coconut milk, / and bake bananas."
—"Love Song of Night and Day"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0223</id>
    <name>Elder Druid</name>
    <text>{3}{G}, {T}: You may tap or untap target artifact, creature, or land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Did clouds dance in his eyes,
did thorns play at his fingertips?"
—Shesul Fass, faerie bard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0224</id>
    <name>Elven Cache</name>
    <text>Return target card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Elves know where to harvest the best of the forest, for they planted it there themselves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0225</id>
    <name>Elven Riders</name>
    <text>Elven Riders can't be blocked except by Walls and/or creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes it is better to be swift of foot than strong of swordarm.
—Elven proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0226</id>
    <name>Elvish Archers</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>"I tell you, there was so many arrows flying about you couldn't hardly see the sun. So I says to young Angus, ‘Well, at least now we're fighting in the shade'"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0227</id>
    <name>Fallow Earth</name>
    <text>Put target land on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>". . . and when the farmer awoke the next morning, all the seeds from his field were once again in their sacks."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0228</id>
    <name>Familiar Ground</name>
    <text>Each creature you control can't be blocked by more than one creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'd rather fight on foreign soil. That way, if I lose I can blame it on the terrain."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0229</id>
    <name>Femeref Archers</name>
    <text>{T}: Femeref Archers deals 4 damage to target attacking creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"They say a Zhalfirin archer can split the eye of a griffin. Nonsense, of course; they have no faith to guide their darts."
—Nuru, Femeref archer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0230</id>
    <name>Fog</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0231</id>
    <name>Fyndhorn Brownie</name>
    <text>{2}{G}, {T}: Untap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"I've been insulted by drunks in a hundred inns, but never as skillfully or annoyingly as by those blasted brownies."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0232</id>
    <name>Fyndhorn Elder</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Do we know what we're doing? Yes—the will of Freyalise."
—Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0233</id>
    <name>Giant Growth</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0234</id>
    <name>Giant Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>It's not far into the trap, as the crow flies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0235</id>
    <name>Gorilla Chieftain</name>
    <text>{1}{G}: Regenerate Gorilla Chieftain.</text>
    <flavorText>"In the soil of leadership sprout the seeds of immortality."
—Kaysa, Elder Druid of the Juniper</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0236</id>
    <name>Grizzly Bears</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Don't try to outrun one of Dominaria's grizzlies; it'll catch you, knock you down, and eat you. Of course, you could run up a tree. In that case you'll get a nice view before it knocks the tree down and eats you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0237</id>
    <name>Hurricane</name>
    <text>Hurricane deals X damage to each creature with flying and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0238</id>
    <name>Living Lands</name>
    <text>All Forests are 1/1 creatures that are still lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0239</id>
    <name>Llanowar Elves</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>One bone broken for every twig snapped underfoot.
—Llanowar penalty for trespassing</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0240</id>
    <name>Lure</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
All creatures able to block enchanted creature do so.</text>
    <flavorText>When setting a snare, success depends not on the quality of the trap, but the quality of the bait.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0241</id>
    <name>Maro</name>
    <text>Maro's power and toughness are each equal to the number of cards in your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>No two see the same Maro.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0242</id>
    <name>Nature's Resurgence</name>
    <text>Each player draws a card for each creature card in his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Spring follows winter
—Elvish expression meaning
"all things pass"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0243</id>
    <name>Panther Warriors</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The dogs of war are nothing compared to the cats.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0244</id>
    <name>Pradesh Gypsies</name>
    <text>{1}{G}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"A mysterious people indeed. Their origins are as secret as their traditions."
—Lord Magnus of Llanowar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0245</id>
    <name>Radjan Spirit</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature loses flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0246</id>
    <name>Rampant Growth</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Rath forces plants from its surface as one presses whey from cheese.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0247</id>
    <name>Redwood Treefolk</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The soldiers chopped and chopped, and still the great tree stood, frowning down at them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0248</id>
    <name>Regeneration</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
{G}: Regenerate enchanted creature. (The next time that creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0249</id>
    <name>River Boa</name>
    <text>Islandwalk
{G}: Regenerate River Boa.</text>
    <flavorText>"But no one heard the snake's gentle hiss for peace over the elephant's trumpeting of war."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0250</id>
    <name>Rowen</name>
    <text>Reveal the first card you draw each turn. Whenever you reveal a basic land card this way, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I've dreamt of a second harvest but fear I will not see it."
—Asmira, holy avenger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0251</id>
    <name>Scaled Wurm</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Flourishing during the Ice Age, these wurms were the bane of all Kjeldorans. Their great size and ferocity made them the subject of countless nightmares—they embodied the worst of the Ice Age."
—Kjeldor: Ice Civilization</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0252</id>
    <name>Shanodin Dryads</name>
    <text>Forestwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Moving without sound, swift figures pass through branches and undergrowth completely unhindered. One with the trees around them, the dryads of Shanodin Forest are seen only when they wish to be.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0253</id>
    <name>Stalking Tiger</name>
    <text>Stalking Tiger can't be blocked by more than one creature.</text>
    <flavorText>In the Jamuraan jungles, there is often no separating beauty from danger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0254</id>
    <name>Stream of Life</name>
    <text>Target player gains X life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0255</id>
    <name>Summer Bloom</name>
    <text>You may play up to three additional lands this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Summer sends its kiss with warmth and blooming life.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0256</id>
    <name>Thicket Basilisk</name>
    <text>Whenever Thicket Basilisk blocks or becomes blocked by a non-Wall creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>Moss-covered statues littered the area, a macabre monument to the basilisk's terrible power.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0257</id>
    <name>Trained Armodon</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>These are its last days. Better to grow broad and heavy. Better that the enemy is crushed beneath its carcass.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0258</id>
    <name>Tranquil Grove</name>
    <text>{1}{G}{G}: Destroy all other enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0259</id>
    <name>Tranquility</name>
    <text>Destroy all enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0260</id>
    <name>Uktabi Orangutan</name>
    <text>When Uktabi Orangutan enters the battlefield, destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>"Is it true that the apes wear furs of gold when they marry?"
—Rana, Suq'Ata market fool</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0261</id>
    <name>Uktabi Wildcats</name>
    <text>Uktabi Wildcats's power and toughness are each equal to the number of Forests you control.
{G}, Sacrifice a Forest: Regenerate Uktabi Wildcats.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0262</id>
    <name>Unseen Walker</name>
    <text>Forestwalk

{1}{G}{G}: Target creature gains forestwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"To pass through the jungle: silence, courtesy, ferocity, as the occasion demands."
—Kamau, "Proper Passage"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0263</id>
    <name>Untamed Wilds</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0264</id>
    <name>Verduran Enchantress</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an enchantment spell, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Some say magic was first practiced by women, who have always felt strong ties to the land.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0265</id>
    <name>Vitalize</name>
    <text>Untap all creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"After waking to the magic of Llanowar, no dreams can compare."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0266</id>
    <name>Waiting in the Weeds</name>
    <text>Each player puts a 1/1 green Cat creature token onto the battlefield for each untapped Forest he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>The trees have ears, eyes, and teeth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0267</id>
    <name>Warthog</name>
    <text>Swampwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Too much work—it takes a long time to break them in, and more than a few recruits."
—Grebog, goblin swine-rider</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0268</id>
    <name>Wild Growth</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds {G} to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0269</id>
    <name>Worldly Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for a creature card and reveal that card. Shuffle your library, then put the revealed card back on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Aselbo soon had the rhino eating from his palm and the snake waiting at his heels."
—Afari, Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0270</id>
    <name>Wyluli Wolf</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"When one wolf calls, others follow. Who wants to fight creatures that eat scorpions?"
—Maimun al-Wyluli, diary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0271</id>
    <name>Aladdin's Ring</name>
    <text>{8}, {T}: Aladdin's Ring deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>". . . The magician drew a ring off his finger . . . , saying: ‘It is a talisman against all evil, so long as you obey me.'"
—The Arabian Nights,
Junior Classics trans.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0272</id>
    <name>Amber Prison</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Amber Prison during your untap step.
{4}, {T}: Tap target artifact, creature, or land. That permanent doesn't untap during its controller's untap step for as long as Amber Prison remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0273</id>
    <name>Ankh of Mishra</name>
    <text>Whenever a land enters the battlefield, Ankh of Mishra deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>Tawnos finally cracked the puzzle: the strange structures did not house Mishra's malevolent creations but were themselves among his creations.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0274</id>
    <name>Ashnod's Altar</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: Add {2} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The Brothers' War scarred the land, but Ashnod left her mark in the bloodlines of those she tortured.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0275</id>
    <name>Bottle of Suleiman</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice Bottle of Suleiman: Flip a coin. If you lose the flip, Bottle of Suleiman deals 5 damage to you. If you win the flip, put a 5/5 colorless Djinn artifact creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0276</id>
    <name>Charcoal Diamond</name>
    <text>Charcoal Diamond enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0277</id>
    <name>Crystal Rod</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a blue spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0278</id>
    <name>Cursed Totem</name>
    <text>Activated abilities of creatures can't be activated.</text>
    <flavorText>Pass me from soul to soul, / soldier to herder, herder to beast, beast to soil / until I am everywhere. / Then pass me those souls.
—Totem inscription (translated)</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0279</id>
    <name>Dancing Scimitar</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Bobbing merrily from opponent to opponent, the scimitar began adding playful little flourishes to its strokes; it even turned a couple of somersaults.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0280</id>
    <name>Dingus Egg</name>
    <text>Whenever a land is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, Dingus Egg deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0281</id>
    <name>Disrupting Scepter</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target player discards a card. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0282</id>
    <name>Dragon Engine</name>
    <text>{2}: Dragon Engine gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"How is it the legged engines seem so much more alive than their wheeled counterparts? Simply, they were born, not made."
—Mishra</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0283</id>
    <name>Dragon Mask</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target creature you control gets +2/+2 until end of turn. Return it to its owner's hand at the beginning of the next end step. (Return it only if it's on the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>"With no further options, I was forced to don the mask."
—Rashida Scalebane</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0284</id>
    <name>Fire Diamond</name>
    <text>Fire Diamond enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0285</id>
    <name>Flying Carpet</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0286</id>
    <name>Fountain of Youth</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The fountain had stood in the town square for centuries, but only the pigeons knew its secret.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0287</id>
    <name>Glasses of Urza</name>
    <text>{T}: Look at target player's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0288</id>
    <name>Grinning Totem</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Grinning Totem: Search target opponent's library for a card and exile it. Then that player shuffles his or her library. Until the beginning of your next upkeep, you may play that card. At the beginning of your next upkeep, if you haven't played it, put it into its owner's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0289</id>
    <name>Howling Mine</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's draw step, if Howling Mine is untapped, that player draws an additional card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0290</id>
    <name>Iron Star</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a red spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0291</id>
    <name>Ivory Cup</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a white spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0292</id>
    <name>Jade Monolith</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to target creature this turn, that source deals that damage to you instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0293</id>
    <name>Jalum Tome</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Draw a card, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>This timeworn relic was responsible for many of Urza's victories, though he never fully comprehended its mystic runes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0294</id>
    <name>Jayemdae Tome</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0295</id>
    <name>Lead Golem</name>
    <text>Whenever Lead Golem attacks, it doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>Slow and heavy swings the club.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0296</id>
    <name>Mana Prism</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{1}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0297</id>
    <name>Marble Diamond</name>
    <text>Marble Diamond enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0298</id>
    <name>Meekstone</name>
    <text>Creatures with power 3 or greater don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>When the mighty sleep, the lowly prowl.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0299</id>
    <name>Millstone</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Target player puts the top two cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>More than one mage has been driven insane by the sound of the millstone relentlessly grinding away.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0300</id>
    <name>Moss Diamond</name>
    <text>Moss Diamond enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0301</id>
    <name>Mystic Compass</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Target land becomes the basic land type of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0302</id>
    <name>Obsianus Golem</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"The foot stone is connected to the ankle stone, the ankle stone is connected to the leg stone . . . ."
—"Song of the Artificer"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0303</id>
    <name>Ornithopter</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"It has been my honor to improve on the Thran's original design. Perhaps history will remember me in some small part for my work."
—Urza, in his apprenticeship</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0304</id>
    <name>Patagia Golem</name>
    <text>{3}: Patagia Golem gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It scattered falcons like a lion hunting among jackals.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0305</id>
    <name>Pentagram of the Ages</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>A mirror, a shield, a promise, a great distance, and a kind word—five ways to avoid harm.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0306</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Vault</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"The secrets of Phyrexia are expensive. You will pay in brass and bone, steel and sinew."
—Kaervek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0307</id>
    <name>Primal Clay</name>
    <text>As Primal Clay enters the battlefield, it becomes your choice of a 3/3 artifact creature, a 2/2 artifact creature with flying, or a 1/6 Shapeshifter Wall artifact creature with defender.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0308</id>
    <name>Rod of Ruin</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Rod of Ruin deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0309</id>
    <name>Skull Catapult</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Skull Catapult deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"What manner of fiend would design such a sadistic device?"
—Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi heretic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0310</id>
    <name>Sky Diamond</name>
    <text>Sky Diamond enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0311</id>
    <name>Snake Basket</name>
    <text>{X}, Sacrifice Snake Basket: Put X 1/1 green Snake creature tokens onto the battlefield. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>"Uh, does anyone have a flute?"
—Rana, Suq'Ata market fool</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0312</id>
    <name>Soul Net</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0313</id>
    <name>Storm Cauldron</name>
    <text>Each player may play an additional land during each of his or her turns.
Whenever a land is tapped for mana, return it to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0314</id>
    <name>Teferi's Puzzle Box</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's draw step, that player puts the cards in his or her hand on the bottom of his or her library in any order, then draws that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0315</id>
    <name>The Hive</name>
    <text>{5}, {T}: Put a 1/1 colorless Insect artifact creature token with flying named Wasp onto the battlefield. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Mouths and wings beyond numbering, but a single mind to guide them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0316</id>
    <name>Throne of Bone</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a black spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0317</id>
    <name>Wand of Denial</name>
    <text>{T}: Look at the top card of target player's library. If it's a nonland card, you may pay 2 life. If you do, put it into that player's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>You'll never miss what you never had.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0318</id>
    <name>Wooden Sphere</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a green spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0319</id>
    <name>Adarkar Wastes</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool. Adarkar Wastes deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0320</id>
    <name>Brushland</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool. Brushland deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0321</id>
    <name>City of Brass</name>
    <text>Whenever City of Brass becomes tapped, it deals 1 damage to you.
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0322</id>
    <name>Crystal Vein</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{T}, Sacrifice Crystal Vein: Add {2} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0323</id>
    <name>Dwarven Ruins</name>
    <text>Dwarven Ruins enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Dwarven Ruins: Add {R}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0324</id>
    <name>Ebon Stronghold</name>
    <text>Ebon Stronghold enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Ebon Stronghold: Add {B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0325</id>
    <name>Havenwood Battleground</name>
    <text>Havenwood Battleground enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Havenwood Battleground: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0326</id>
    <name>Karplusan Forest</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool. Karplusan Forest deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0327</id>
    <name>Ruins of Trokair</name>
    <text>Ruins of Trokair enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Ruins of Trokair: Add {W}{W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0328</id>
    <name>Sulfurous Springs</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool. Sulfurous Springs deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0329</id>
    <name>Svyelunite Temple</name>
    <text>Svyelunite Temple enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Svyelunite Temple: Add {U}{U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0330</id>
    <name>Underground River</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool. Underground River deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0331</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0332</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0333</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0334</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0335</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0336</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0337</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0338</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0339</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0340</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0341</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0342</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0343</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0344</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0345</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0346</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0347</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0348</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0349</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>6ED0350</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>