<cards name="Shards of Alara">
  <item>
    <id>ALA0001</id>
    <name>Akrasan Squire</name>
    <text>Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>Bant's armies are primarily composed of members of the Mortar caste, loyal commoners who haven't yet earned a sigil.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0002</id>
    <name>Angel's Herald</name>
    <text>{2}{W}, {T}, Sacrifice a green creature, a white creature, and a blue creature: Search your library for a card named Empyrial Archangel and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Rigorous faith and belief are rewarded on occasion, and richly so.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0003</id>
    <name>Angelic Benediction</name>
    <text>Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)
Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, you may tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Even in single combat, I am never alone."
—Rafiq of the Many</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0004</id>
    <name>Angelsong</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>Clash of sword and cry of beast fall mute when angels sound the call to prayer.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0005</id>
    <name>Bant Battlemage</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: Target creature gains trample until end of turn.
{U}, {T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"A night attack will be easy. We'll make an air raid over the Akrasan border. Just get me some flint to light the war torches."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0006</id>
    <name>Battlegrace Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)
Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, it gains lifelink until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0007</id>
    <name>Cradle of Vitality</name>
    <text>Whenever you gain life, you may pay {1}{W}. If you do, put a +1/+1 counter on target creature for each 1 life you gained.</text>
    <flavorText>Naya's trees grow tall and sturdy. Their foliage intertwines to form dewcups, rainwater pools where the elves gather to celebrate life.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0008</id>
    <name>Dispeller's Capsule</name>
    <text>{2}{W}, {T}, Sacrifice Dispeller's Capsule: Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"I find its symmetry pleasing. It rids our world of offensive refuse while disposing of itself."
—Dolomarus, Proctor of the Clean</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0009</id>
    <name>Elspeth, Knight-Errant</name>
    <text>+1: Put a 1/1 white Soldier creature token onto the battlefield.
+1: Target creature gets +3/+3 and gains flying until end of turn.
-8: For the rest of the game, artifacts, creatures, enchantments, and lands you control are indestructible.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0010</id>
    <name>Ethersworn Canonist</name>
    <text>Each player who has cast a nonartifact spell this turn can't cast additional nonartifact spells.</text>
    <flavorText>"The noble work of our order is to infuse all life on Esper with etherium. Our goal will be reached more rapidly if new life is . . . suppressed."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0011</id>
    <name>Excommunicate</name>
    <text>Put target creature on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>Rebels and other malcontents forced into the ritual awake lost in Topa's vast savannahs. Those who find their way back return humble and repentant.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0012</id>
    <name>Guardians of Akrasa</name>
    <text>Defender
Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Only by the bravery of those who put loyalty above glory is our home kept safe."
—Elspeth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0013</id>
    <name>Gustrider Exuberant</name>
    <text>Flying
Sacrifice Gustrider Exuberant: Creatures you control with power 5 or greater gain flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The elves claim the canopy. The nacatl claim the mountains. I suppose you think we ought to stay on the jungle floor?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0014</id>
    <name>Invincible Hymn</name>
    <text>Count the number of cards in your library. Your life total becomes that number.</text>
    <flavorText>Bantians believe those who are born into the highest caste and live a life of discipline and virtue can ascend to become angels.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0015</id>
    <name>Knight of the Skyward Eye</name>
    <text>{3}{G}: Knight of the Skyward Eye gets +3/+3 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Order of the Skyward Eye does the bidding of an evil force, unwittingly stirring fear and mistrust across Bant in accordance with his plans.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0016</id>
    <name>Knight of the White Orchid</name>
    <text>First strike
When Knight of the White Orchid enters the battlefield, if an opponent controls more lands than you, you may search your library for a Plains card, put it onto the battlefield, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Both guide and guard on open plain.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0017</id>
    <name>Knight-Captain of Eos</name>
    <text>When Knight-Captain of Eos enters the battlefield, put two 1/1 white Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield.
{W}, Sacrifice a Soldier: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The strength of Bant's caste system is the unfailing loyalty of its meekest members.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0018</id>
    <name>Marble Chalice</name>
    <text>{T}: You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The cup was a gift from the sphinx Tameron, who hoped that those who drank from it would live long enough to decrypt the sphinxes' wisdom.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0019</id>
    <name>Metallurgeon</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Regenerate target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>"By the time I got there, the heart had stopped. Fortunately, I was able to replace it with something better."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0020</id>
    <name>Oblivion Ring</name>
    <text>When Oblivion Ring enters the battlefield, exile another target nonland permanent.
When Oblivion Ring leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to the battlefield under its owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>A circle of light and a word of confinement.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0021</id>
    <name>Ranger of Eos</name>
    <text>When Ranger of Eos enters the battlefield, you may search your library for up to two creature cards with converted mana cost 1 or less, reveal them, and put them into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>At his side, humble beasts become weapons more deadly than sharpened steel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0022</id>
    <name>Resounding Silence</name>
    <text>Exile target attacking creature.
Cycling {5}{G}{W}{U} ({5}{G}{W}{U}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
When you cycle Resounding Silence, exile up to two target attacking creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0023</id>
    <name>Rockcaster Platoon</name>
    <text>{4}{G}: Rockcaster Platoon deals 2 damage to each creature with flying and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Aven bandits can be sly. You've got to fill the sky with boulders—and then seek cover immediately."
—Knight-Captain Wyhorn</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0024</id>
    <name>Sanctum Gargoyle</name>
    <text>Flying
When Sanctum Gargoyle enters the battlefield, you may return target artifact card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>As their supplies of etherium dwindled, mechanists sent gargoyles farther and farther afield in search of salvage.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0025</id>
    <name>Scourglass</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Scourglass: Destroy all permanents except for artifacts and lands. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"Soon I will sleep, eyes closing to a world tarnished with flesh, and then wake to a polished vision."
—Sharuum</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0026</id>
    <name>Sighted-Caste Sorcerer</name>
    <text>Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)
{U}: Sighted-Caste Sorcerer gains shroud until end of turn. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0027</id>
    <name>Sigiled Paladin</name>
    <text>First strike
Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>Each sigil marks the recognition of a great deed and signifies a duty owed to the one who granted it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0028</id>
    <name>Soul's Grace</name>
    <text>You gain life equal to target creature's power.</text>
    <flavorText>An avatar he sculpts of fellowship and light.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0029</id>
    <name>Sunseed Nurturer</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your end step, if you control a creature with power 5 or greater, you may gain 2 life.
{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Sunseeders quest for areas of open sky. They train plowbeasts to beat back the dense jungle long enough to cultivate a crop.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0030</id>
    <name>Welkin Guide</name>
    <text>Flying
When Welkin Guide enters the battlefield, target creature gets +2/+2 and gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those talons really dig into your skin, but it's better than being dropped."
—Rafiq of the Many</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0031</id>
    <name>Yoked Plowbeast</name>
    <text>Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>"It is sacrilege to confine a gargantuan to the grinding of straight lines. I will pray that it remembers who is the master of this land."
—Syeena, elvish godtoucher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0032</id>
    <name>Call to Heel</name>
    <text>Return target creature to its owner's hand. Its controller draws a card.</text>
    <flavorText>On Bant, a sigil is both a prize of honor and a bond of duty. The one who bears it may be called to fulfill that charge at any moment.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0033</id>
    <name>Cancel</name>
    <text>Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"What you are attempting is not against the law. It is, however, extremely foolish."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0034</id>
    <name>Cathartic Adept</name>
    <text>{T}: Target player puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"Forget. Only then will there be space for hope between the pain and fear."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0035</id>
    <name>Cloudheath Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{W}: Cloudheath Drake gains vigilance until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A permanent storm rages over the plain of Cloudheath, and drakes ride its currents—two reminders that some elements of Esper will not be controlled.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0036</id>
    <name>Coma Veil</name>
    <text>Enchant artifact or creature
Enchanted permanent doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>Etherium does not know sleep. Only magic can teach it the resting state of cold steel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0037</id>
    <name>Courier's Capsule</name>
    <text>{1}{U}, {T}, Sacrifice Courier's Capsule: Draw two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>In ages past, Esper couriers bore messages written on ornate scrolls. The medium has grown more sophisticated, but the principle remains the same.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0038</id>
    <name>Covenant of Minds</name>
    <text>Reveal the top three cards of your library. Target opponent may choose to put those cards into your hand. If he or she doesn't, put those cards into your graveyard and draw five cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Before signing anything on Grixis, always read the fine print.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0039</id>
    <name>Dawnray Archer</name>
    <text>Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)
{W}, {T}: Dawnray Archer deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Their shots are fired most often as signals—or at those who didn't get the message.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0040</id>
    <name>Esper Battlemage</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to you this turn.
{B}, {T}: Target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>She can heal the flesh, or exploit its many weaknesses.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0041</id>
    <name>Etherium Astrolabe</name>
    <text>Flash
{B}, {T}, Sacrifice an artifact: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Speculation is foolish when the tools of certainty are available."
—Cinna, vedalken consul</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0042</id>
    <name>Etherium Sculptor</name>
    <text>Artifact spells you cast cost {1} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>The greatest masters of the craft abandon tools altogether, shaping metal with hand and mind alone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0043</id>
    <name>Fatestitcher</name>
    <text>{T}: You may tap or untap another target permanent.
Unearth {U} ({U}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0044</id>
    <name>Filigree Sages</name>
    <text>{2}{U}: Untap target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>"We of the Sanctum Arcanum have pondered every word on every page of the Filigree Texts. If you can't say the same, don't bother speaking."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0045</id>
    <name>Gather Specimens</name>
    <text>If a creature would enter the battlefield under an opponent's control this turn, it enters the battlefield under your control instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's free to do whatever it wants. I've merely told it what that is."
—Xorin, Architect of Will</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0046</id>
    <name>Jhessian Lookout</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>She stands ready, always watchful, knowing that weeks of peace and serenity can be overturned by a single distant sail.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0047</id>
    <name>Kathari Screecher</name>
    <text>Flying
Unearth {2}{U} ({2}{U}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0048</id>
    <name>Kederekt Leviathan</name>
    <text>When Kederekt Leviathan enters the battlefield, return all other nonland permanents to their owners' hands.
Unearth {6}{U} ({6}{U}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0049</id>
    <name>Master of Etherium</name>
    <text>Master of Etherium's power and toughness are each equal to the number of artifacts you control.
Other artifact creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>"Only a mind unfettered with the concerns of the flesh can see the world as it truly is."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0050</id>
    <name>Memory Erosion</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a spell, that player puts the top two cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Filigree Texts do not compel you to act in accordance with their precepts. They only specify the consequences should you fail."
—Lodus of the Ethersworn</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0051</id>
    <name>Mindlock Orb</name>
    <text>Players can't search libraries.</text>
    <flavorText>Rogue mechanists once rummaged through the wastes of the Tidehollow, constructing unauthorized golems to threaten the hegemony of the sphinxes. The orbs put a stop to that.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0052</id>
    <name>Outrider of Jhess</name>
    <text>Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>The island nation of Jhess is under constant siege from Valeron on the mainland. Riders traverse the coastline, always on the lookout for sails or aven.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0053</id>
    <name>Protomatter Powder</name>
    <text>{4}{W}, {T}, Sacrifice Protomatter Powder: Return target artifact card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is no such thing as scrap metal. All such material can be repaired with the proper bonding agent."
—Quennus, metallurgeon</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0054</id>
    <name>Resounding Wave</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.
Cycling {5}{W}{U}{B} ({5}{W}{U}{B}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
When you cycle Resounding Wave, return two target permanents to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0055</id>
    <name>Sharding Sphinx</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever an artifact creature you control deals combat damage to a player, you may put a 1/1 blue Thopter artifact creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Whether mechanical or biological, life finds a way to propagate itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0056</id>
    <name>Skill Borrower</name>
    <text>Play with the top card of your library revealed.
As long as the top card of your library is an artifact or creature card, Skill Borrower has all activated abilities of that card. (If any of the abilities use that card's name, use this creature's name instead.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0057</id>
    <name>Spell Snip</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1}.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Magic cast through a hand of flesh is just as weak as the flesh itself."
—Lodus of the Ethersworn</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0058</id>
    <name>Sphinx's Herald</name>
    <text>{2}{U}, {T}, Sacrifice a white creature, a blue creature, and a black creature: Search your library for a card named Sphinx Sovereign and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>He calls a riddle through the gaps of cloven clouds, hoping for an answer.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0059</id>
    <name>Steelclad Serpent</name>
    <text>Steelclad Serpent can't attack unless you control another artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>"From the highest towers to the deepest sea, all life must be touched by etherium."
—Lodus of the Ethersworn</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0060</id>
    <name>Tezzeret the Seeker</name>
    <text>+1: Untap up to two target artifacts.
-X: Search your library for an artifact card with converted mana cost X or less and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.
-5: Artifacts you control become 5/5 artifact creatures until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0061</id>
    <name>Tortoise Formation</name>
    <text>Creatures you control gain shroud until end of turn. (They can't be the targets of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>At sea, the Jhessian fleet strikes swiftly and decisively. On land, facing the elite cavalry of Valeron, its marines must rely on more cautious strategies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0062</id>
    <name>Vectis Silencers</name>
    <text>{2}{B}: Vectis Silencers gains deathtouch until end of turn. (Creatures dealt damage by this creature are destroyed. You can divide its combat damage among any of the creatures blocking or blocked by it.)</text>
    <flavorText>Even on Esper, there are those who eschew the use of magic in favor of simpler methods.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0063</id>
    <name>Ad Nauseam</name>
    <text>Reveal the top card of your library and put that card into your hand. You lose life equal to its converted mana cost. You may repeat this process any number of times.</text>
    <flavorText>When the task spilled over into undeath, he stopped calling it his life's work.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0064</id>
    <name>Archdemon of Unx</name>
    <text>Flying, trample
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice a non-Zombie creature, then put a 2/2 black Zombie creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The necropolis at Unx was once a living city, its streets untrodden by death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0065</id>
    <name>Banewasp Affliction</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, that creature's controller loses life equal to its toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>The consuming undeath of Grixis terrifies the survivors of Vithia, but its fauna is just as fearsome.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0066</id>
    <name>Blister Beetle</name>
    <text>When Blister Beetle enters the battlefield, target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Warriors of the Rip Clan wear their beetle-acid scars proudly, even modifying clothing and armor to better display the trophy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0067</id>
    <name>Bone Splinters</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Bone Splinters, sacrifice a creature.
Destroy target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Witches of the Split-Eye Coven speak of a future when Grixis will overflow with life energy. For now, they must harvest vis from the living to fuel their dark magics.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0068</id>
    <name>Corpse Connoisseur</name>
    <text>When Corpse Connoisseur enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a creature card and put that card into your graveyard. If you do, shuffle your library.
Unearth {3}{B} ({3}{B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0069</id>
    <name>Cunning Lethemancer</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, each player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Give me your memories, and you will have release from the suffering they bring you."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0070</id>
    <name>Death Baron</name>
    <text>Skeleton creatures you control and other Zombie creatures you control get +1/+1 and have deathtouch.</text>
    <flavorText>For the necromancer barons, killing and recruitment are one and the same.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0071</id>
    <name>Deathgreeter</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The bones of allies grant wisdom. The bones of enemies grant strength. The bones of dragons grant life eternal."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0072</id>
    <name>Demon's Herald</name>
    <text>{2}{B}, {T}, Sacrifice a blue creature, a black creature, and a red creature: Search your library for a card named Prince of Thralls and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"May these deaths be the first of many."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0073</id>
    <name>Dreg Reaver</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"On our thirty-fourth day of digging, we unearthed a chamber that contained the intact remains of several species long extinct from Grixis. One in particular should make a fine siege engine . . . ."
—Last notes of Shungus Nod, fleshcrafter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0074</id>
    <name>Dregscape Zombie</name>
    <text>Unearth {B} ({B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>The undead of Grixis are fueled by their hatred of the living.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0075</id>
    <name>Executioner's Capsule</name>
    <text>{1}{B}, {T}, Sacrifice Executioner's Capsule: Destroy target nonblack creature.</text>
    <flavorText>There is always a moment of trepidation before opening a message capsule, for fear of the judgment that might be contained within.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0076</id>
    <name>Fleshbag Marauder</name>
    <text>When Fleshbag Marauder enters the battlefield, each player sacrifices a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Grixis is a world where the only things found in abundance are death and decay. Corpses, whole or in part, are the standard currency among necromancers and demons.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0077</id>
    <name>Glaze Fiend</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever another artifact enters the battlefield under your control, Glaze Fiend gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Before the zealots of the Ethersworn came to power, Esper illusionists dreamed up creations to mimic a variety of substances.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0078</id>
    <name>Grixis Battlemage</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}: Draw a card, then discard a card.
{R}, {T}: Target creature can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Vitals of Grixis who eschew undeath must scrape and scratch to retain their mortality. The result is a breed of inventive mages.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0079</id>
    <name>Immortal Coil</name>
    <text>{T}, Exile two cards from your graveyard: Draw a card.
If damage would be dealt to you, prevent that damage. Exile a card from your graveyard for each 1 damage prevented this way.
When there are no cards in your graveyard, you lose the game.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0080</id>
    <name>Infest</name>
    <text>All creatures get -2/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"This is why we don't go out in banewasp weather."
—Rannon, Vithian holdout</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0081</id>
    <name>Onyx Goblet</name>
    <text>{T}: Target player loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The goblet was a gift from the sphinx Gorael, who hoped humans and vedalken would eventually destroy each other to acquire it, leaving all of Esper to her own kind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0082</id>
    <name>Puppet Conjurer</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}: Put a 0/1 blue Homunculus artifact creature token onto the battlefield.
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice a Homunculus.</text>
    <flavorText>He scowls at his imperfect creation, then crushes it to scrap. He salvages the etherium and begins anew.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0083</id>
    <name>Resounding Scream</name>
    <text>Target player discards a card at random.
Cycling {5}{U}{B}{R} ({5}{U}{B}{R}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
When you cycle Resounding Scream, target player discards two cards at random.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0084</id>
    <name>Salvage Titan</name>
    <text>You may sacrifice three artifacts rather than pay Salvage Titan's mana cost.
Exile three artifact cards from your graveyard: Return Salvage Titan from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0085</id>
    <name>Scavenger Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever another creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Scavenger Drake.</text>
    <flavorText>Dragons consider drakes to be mockeries of their perfection, destroying them on sight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0086</id>
    <name>Shadowfeed</name>
    <text>Exile target card from a graveyard. You gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The future is a snake, devouring your life backwards through time. And when you die, believe me, it doesn't stop feeding."
—Sedris, the Traitor King</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0087</id>
    <name>Shore Snapper</name>
    <text>{U}: Shore Snapper gains islandwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Kathari, the sickly aven of Grixis, have learned that the corpses by the shoreline are more trap than treat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0088</id>
    <name>Skeletal Kathari</name>
    <text>Flying
{B}, Sacrifice a creature: Regenerate Skeletal Kathari.</text>
    <flavorText>Undeath doesn't end the kathari's search for carrion; it only removes one corpse from the Dregscape.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0089</id>
    <name>Tar Fiend</name>
    <text>Devour 2 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with twice that many +1/+1 counters on it.)
When Tar Fiend enters the battlefield, target player discards a card for each creature it devoured.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0090</id>
    <name>Undead Leotau</name>
    <text>{R}: Undead Leotau gets +1/-1 until end of turn.
Unearth {2}{B} ({2}{B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0091</id>
    <name>Vein Drinker</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}, {T}: Vein Drinker deals damage equal to its power to target creature. That creature deals damage equal to its power to Vein Drinker.
Whenever a creature dealt damage by Vein Drinker this turn is put into a graveyard, put a +1/+1 counter on Vein Drinker.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0092</id>
    <name>Viscera Dragger</name>
    <text>Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
Unearth {1}{B} ({1}{B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0093</id>
    <name>Bloodpyre Elemental</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Bloodpyre Elemental: Bloodpyre Elemental deals 4 damage to target creature. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>Elementals born of Jund are as cruel and unstable as the plane itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0094</id>
    <name>Bloodthorn Taunter</name>
    <text>Haste
{T}: Target creature with power 5 or greater gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Naya's celebrants stoke the gargantuans into a rage, loosing a tide of muscle with the precision of an arrow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0095</id>
    <name>Caldera Hellion</name>
    <text>Devour 1 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with that many +1/+1 counters on it.)
When Caldera Hellion enters the battlefield, it deals 3 damage to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0096</id>
    <name>Crucible of Fire</name>
    <text>Dragon creatures you control get +3/+3.</text>
    <flavorText>"The dragon is a perfect marriage of power and the will to use it."
—Sarkhan Vol</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0097</id>
    <name>Dragon Fodder</name>
    <text>Put two 1/1 red Goblin creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Goblins journey to the sacrificial peaks in pairs so that the rare survivor might be able to relate the details of the other's grisly demise.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0098</id>
    <name>Dragon's Herald</name>
    <text>{2}{R}, {T}, Sacrifice a black creature, a red creature, and a green creature: Search your library for a card named Hellkite Overlord and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The penultimate step of the ritual involves bathing in a delicious glaze.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0099</id>
    <name>Exuberant Firestoker</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your end step, if you control a creature with power 5 or greater, you may have Exuberant Firestoker deal 2 damage to target player.
{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The artistry of Etlan's firedancers is more spectacular when behemoths join in.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0100</id>
    <name>Flameblast Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Flameblast Dragon attacks, you may pay {X}{R}. If you do, Flameblast Dragon deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Dragon lords of Jund rule by edicts of flame.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0101</id>
    <name>Goblin Assault</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a 1/1 red Goblin creature token with haste onto the battlefield.
Goblin creatures attack each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>A goblin raid is a delicate gambit—a blend of stealth, precision, and screaming death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0102</id>
    <name>Goblin Mountaineer</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Goblin lairs sit high in Jund's mountains. This gives the goblins easy access to the sacrificial peaks above and lets them build up a head of steam before attacking prey down below.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0103</id>
    <name>Hell's Thunder</name>
    <text>Flying, haste
At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice Hell's Thunder.
Unearth {4}{R} ({4}{R}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0104</id>
    <name>Hissing Iguanar</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may have Hissing Iguanar deal 1 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Viashino thrashes keep iguanars as hunting companions, giving them wounded captives as playthings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0105</id>
    <name>Incurable Ogre</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Each mutation causes the incurables to look vastly different from one another. They are left with only one thing in common: their insatiable lust for the slaughter.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0106</id>
    <name>Jund Battlemage</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}: Target player loses 1 life.
{G}, {T}: Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Of your blood I will make my mead, an offering to the thirsty jungle."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0107</id>
    <name>Lightning Talons</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+0 and has first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>"This is going to hurt a lot, but on the bright side, you'll be dead soon."
—Sedris, the Traitor King</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0108</id>
    <name>Magma Spray</name>
    <text>Magma Spray deals 2 damage to target creature. If that creature would be put into a graveyard this turn, exile it instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"Jund is a wounded world. Beware its searing blood spilling out onto the surface."
—Rakka Mar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0109</id>
    <name>Predator Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying, haste
Devour 2 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with twice that many +1/+1 counters on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>Dragons make for spiteful gods.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0110</id>
    <name>Resounding Thunder</name>
    <text>Resounding Thunder deals 3 damage to target creature or player.
Cycling {5}{B}{R}{G} ({5}{B}{R}{G}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
When you cycle Resounding Thunder, it deals 6 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0111</id>
    <name>Ridge Rannet</name>
    <text>Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Only those with the strength to seize their destiny deserve to have one."
—Nacatl scratchforms</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0112</id>
    <name>Rockslide Elemental</name>
    <text>First strike
Whenever another creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Rockslide Elemental.</text>
    <flavorText>On Jund, even the landscape is a deadly hunter. Volcanoes, tar pits, and rock slides seem to prey upon the living.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0113</id>
    <name>Scourge Devil</name>
    <text>When Scourge Devil enters the battlefield, creatures you control get +1/+0 until end of turn.
Unearth {2}{R} ({2}{R}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0114</id>
    <name>Skeletonize</name>
    <text>Skeletonize deals 3 damage to target creature. When a creature dealt damage this way is put into a graveyard this turn, put a 1/1 black Skeleton creature token onto the battlefield with "{B}: Regenerate this creature."</text>
    <flavorText>Fire burns away both flesh and freedom.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0115</id>
    <name>Soul's Fire</name>
    <text>Target creature you control on the battlefield deals damage equal to its power to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>An avatar he sculpts of anger and flame.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0116</id>
    <name>Thorn-Thrash Viashino</name>
    <text>Devour 2 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with twice that many +1/+1 counters on it.)
{G}: Thorn-Thrash Viashino gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0117</id>
    <name>Thunder-Thrash Elder</name>
    <text>Devour 3 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with three times that many +1/+1 counters on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>Viashino thrashes are led by elders who have survived countless challenges.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0118</id>
    <name>Viashino Skeleton</name>
    <text>{1}{B}, Discard a card: Regenerate Viashino Skeleton.</text>
    <flavorText>Underneath the Dregscape lay the remains of creatures long extinct from Grixis.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0119</id>
    <name>Vicious Shadows</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may have Vicious Shadows deal damage to target player equal to the number of cards in that player's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Thrashes of the ancient past still linger in spirit and shadow, desperate to sink their claws into our souls."
—Rakka Mar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0120</id>
    <name>Vithian Stinger</name>
    <text>{T}: Vithian Stinger deals 1 damage to target creature or player.
Unearth {1}{R} ({1}{R}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0121</id>
    <name>Volcanic Submersion</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or land.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>A dragon's death is almost as feared as its life. Old, dying dragons throw themselves into volcanoes, causing massive upheaval and widespread disaster.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0122</id>
    <name>Where Ancients Tread</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature with power 5 or greater enters the battlefield under your control, you may have Where Ancients Tread deal 5 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Never subtle nor cryptic is the reckoning of the mighty."
—Mayael the Anima</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0123</id>
    <name>Algae Gharial</name>
    <text>Shroud
Whenever another creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Algae Gharial.</text>
    <flavorText>It lurks just under the surface, using the algae-choked tar pits of Jund as both home and hunting blind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0124</id>
    <name>Behemoth's Herald</name>
    <text>{2}{G}, {T}, Sacrifice a red creature, a green creature, and a white creature: Search your library for a card named Godsire and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mine is an insatiable god, with appetites as magnificent as the jungle itself."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0125</id>
    <name>Cavern Thoctar</name>
    <text>{1}{R}: Cavern Thoctar gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Natives of Naya know better than to loiter near the mouth of a cave. Two glowing red eyes and the stench of foul breath are all the warning you're likely to get.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0126</id>
    <name>Court Archers</name>
    <text>Reach (This can block creatures with flying.)
Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>The Sun-Dappled Court of Valeron stands secure behind a wall of steel-tipped arrows.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0127</id>
    <name>Cylian Elf</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>From her sunsail tent high above the forest floor, an elf harkener can hear the footfalls of a single creature through the cacophony of Naya's jungle sounds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0128</id>
    <name>Druid of the Anima</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {R}, {G}, or {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Although the Anima herself remains at the Sacellum, her druids roam Naya, collecting mana bonds with every location in the world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0129</id>
    <name>Drumhunter</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your end step, if you control a creature with power 5 or greater, you may draw a card.
{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"I feel the vine-rhythm as my friends drive the beast to me. I will not miss my mark."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0130</id>
    <name>Elvish Visionary</name>
    <text>When Elvish Visionary enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Before any major undertaking, a Cylian elf seeks the guidance of a visionary to learn the will of the gargantuan ancients.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0131</id>
    <name>Feral Hydra</name>
    <text>Feral Hydra enters the battlefield with X +1/+1 counters on it.
{3}: Put a +1/+1 counter on Feral Hydra. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>It shreds its prey as each head fights for the choicest bits.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0132</id>
    <name>Gift of the Gargantuan</name>
    <text>Look at the top four cards of your library. You may reveal a creature card and/or a land card from among them and put the revealed cards into your hand. Put the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0133</id>
    <name>Godtoucher</name>
    <text>{1}{W}, {T}: Prevent all damage that would be dealt to target creature with power 5 or greater this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Gargantuans die not in moments but in moons. There is still time to aid this noble ancient."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0134</id>
    <name>Jungle Weaver</name>
    <text>Reach (This can block creatures with flying.)
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>Weavers' webs wall off swaths of territory more effectively than any portcullis made of iron.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0135</id>
    <name>Keeper of Progenitus</name>
    <text>Whenever a player taps a Mountain, Forest, or Plains for mana, that player adds one mana to his or her mana pool of any type that land produced.</text>
    <flavorText>He watches over the valley where Progenitus sleeps, culling signs from its steaming breaths.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0136</id>
    <name>Lush Growth</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Enchanted land is a Mountain, Forest, and Plains.</text>
    <flavorText>Naya's bounty spills over upon itself. Each leaf and flower struggles against the next with thrashing thorns, acidic pollen, and strangling roots.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0137</id>
    <name>Mighty Emergence</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature with power 5 or greater enters the battlefield under your control, you may put two +1/+1 counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>Why settle for mere enormity?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0138</id>
    <name>Manaplasm</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a spell, Manaplasm gets +X/+X until end of turn, where X is that spell's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>Urak froze when he heard it. That was his first mistake. He turned and cast a dramatic ward spell. That was his last.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0139</id>
    <name>Mosstodon</name>
    <text>{1}: Target creature with power 5 or greater gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Whether gargantuans are the manifested will of Progenitus or simply the result of overabundant resources is moot when a herd of them is thundering at you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0140</id>
    <name>Mycoloth</name>
    <text>Devour 2 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with twice that many +1/+1 counters on it.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield for each +1/+1 counter on Mycoloth.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0141</id>
    <name>Naturalize</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>The idols of old are rich in minerals and magic. They are torn apart when nature aims to eat well.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0142</id>
    <name>Naya Battlemage</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}: Target creature gets +2/+0 until end of turn.
{W}, {T}: Tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have trained in all three schools of magic."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0143</id>
    <name>Ooze Garden</name>
    <text>{1}{G}, Sacrifice a non-Ooze creature: Put an X/X green Ooze creature token onto the battlefield, where X is the sacrificed creature's power. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>Jund has little necromancy. Instead, the flesh of its dead gives rise to algal fiends.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0144</id>
    <name>Resounding Roar</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.
Cycling {5}{R}{G}{W} ({5}{R}{G}{W}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
When you cycle Resounding Roar, target creature gets +6/+6 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0145</id>
    <name>Rhox Charger</name>
    <text>Trample
Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Momentum is a great ally."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0146</id>
    <name>Sacellum Godspeaker</name>
    <text>{T}: Reveal any number of creature cards with power 5 or greater from your hand. Add {G} to your mana pool for each card revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>Her connection to the gargantuans puts her in line to become Anima, a sacred but daunting duty.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0147</id>
    <name>Savage Hunger</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 and has trample.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0148</id>
    <name>Skullmulcher</name>
    <text>Devour 1 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with that many +1/+1 counters on it.)
When Skullmulcher enters the battlefield, draw a card for each creature it devoured.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0149</id>
    <name>Soul's Might</name>
    <text>Put X +1/+1 counters on target creature, where X is that creature's power.</text>
    <flavorText>An avatar he sculpts of instinct and force.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0150</id>
    <name>Spearbreaker Behemoth</name>
    <text>Spearbreaker Behemoth is indestructible.
{1}: Target creature with power 5 or greater is indestructible this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Few Nayans dare hunt the gargantuans. They're regarded not as animals but as forces of nature, like landslides or typhoons.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0151</id>
    <name>Topan Ascetic</name>
    <text>Tap an untapped creature you control: Topan Ascetic gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Monks from Topa wander all of Bant, encouraging the Unbeholden to find their place in society through honorable combat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0152</id>
    <name>Wild Nacatl</name>
    <text>Wild Nacatl gets +1/+1 as long as you control a Mountain.
Wild Nacatl gets +1/+1 as long as you control a Plains.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Cloud Nacatl sit and think, a bunch of soft paws. We are the Claws of Marisi, stalking, pouncing, drawing blood."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0153</id>
    <name>Agony Warp</name>
    <text>Target creature gets -3/-0 until end of turn.
Target creature gets -0/-3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Life's circle has become inverted in Grixis. The same energy is endlessly recycled and becomes more stagnant with each pass.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0154</id>
    <name>Ajani Vengeant</name>
    <text>+1: Target permanent doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.
-2: Ajani Vengeant deals 3 damage to target creature or player and you gain 3 life.
-7: Destroy all lands target player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0155</id>
    <name>Bant Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Destroy target artifact; or put target creature on the bottom of its owner's library; or counter target instant spell.</text>
    <flavorText>Bant is a world where death and chaos hold no sway.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0156</id>
    <name>Blightning</name>
    <text>Blightning deals 3 damage to target player. That player discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>While the smell of burning flesh is common in Grixis, the odor of smoldering brain matter is a rare treat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0157</id>
    <name>Blood Cultist</name>
    <text>{T}: Blood Cultist deals 1 damage to target creature.
Whenever a creature dealt damage by Blood Cultist this turn is put into a graveyard, put a +1/+1 counter on Blood Cultist.</text>
    <flavorText>"To immortality."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0158</id>
    <name>Branching Bolt</name>
    <text>Choose one or both — Branching Bolt deals 3 damage to target creature with flying; and/or Branching Bolt deals 3 damage to target creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Lightning lives in everything, in living flesh and growing things. It must be set free."
—Rakka Mar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0159</id>
    <name>Brilliant Ultimatum</name>
    <text>Exile the top five cards of your library. An opponent separates those cards into two piles. You may play any number of cards from one of those piles without paying their mana costs.</text>
    <flavorText>Revealing the truth only deepened Tezzeret's curiosity for the secrets still buried.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0160</id>
    <name>Broodmate Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
When Broodmate Dragon enters the battlefield, put a 4/4 red Dragon creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Frozen in fear, the goblins stared upward at the circling hunter—and were promptly eaten by its diving mate.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0161</id>
    <name>Bull Cerodon</name>
    <text>Vigilance, haste</text>
    <flavorText>It holds motionless vigil, watching Naya in silence through the screen of the whitecover. When it senses anything amiss, it launches forward with the uncanny sound of torn fog.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0162</id>
    <name>Carrion Thrash</name>
    <text>When Carrion Thrash is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {2}. If you do, return another target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Viashino hunt in gangs called thrashes. Not all thrashes hunt the freshest game.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0163</id>
    <name>Clarion Ultimatum</name>
    <text>Choose five permanents you control. For each of those permanents, you may search your library for a card with the same name as that permanent. Put those cards onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Be worthy of a single blessing, and many more will follow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0164</id>
    <name>Cruel Ultimatum</name>
    <text>Target opponent sacrifices a creature, discards three cards, then loses 5 life. You return a creature card from your graveyard to your hand, draw three cards, then gain 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>There is always a greater power.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0165</id>
    <name>Deft Duelist</name>
    <text>First strike
Shroud (This creature can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>Some Serul Cove rogues traffic in stolen sigils, which fetch a high price from those who would rather pay for honor than earn it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0166</id>
    <name>Empyrial Archangel</name>
    <text>Flying, shroud
All damage that would be dealt to you is dealt to Empyrial Archangel instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Her wings are the prayers of the devoted; her sword, the despair of the vile.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0167</id>
    <name>Esper Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Destroy target enchantment; or draw two cards; or target player discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Thoughts are commodities. Someone will pay a good price for them. Even ones as simplistic as yours . . ."
—Ennor, mentalist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0168</id>
    <name>Fire-Field Ogre</name>
    <text>First strike
Unearth {U}{B}{R} ({U}{B}{R}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0169</id>
    <name>Goblin Deathraiders</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>Every once in a while, when they aren't getting incinerated in lava, crushed under rock slides, or devoured by dragons, goblins experience moments of unmitigated glory in battle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0170</id>
    <name>Godsire</name>
    <text>Vigilance
{T}: Put an 8/8 Beast creature token that's red, green, and white onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Lay sacrifice to the godsire that it may spare us, but save some for his progeny who also will hunger."
—Syeena, elvish godtoucher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0171</id>
    <name>Grixis Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Return target permanent to its owner's hand; or target creature gets -4/-4 until end of turn; or creatures you control get +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"So many choices. Shall I choose loathing, hate, or malice today?"
—Eliza of the Keep</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0172</id>
    <name>Hellkite Overlord</name>
    <text>Flying, trample, haste
{R}: Hellkite Overlord gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
{B}{G}: Regenerate Hellkite Overlord.</text>
    <flavorText>"The dragon has no pretense of compassion, no false mask of civilization—just hunger, heat, and need."
—Sarkhan Vol</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0173</id>
    <name>Hindering Light</name>
    <text>Counter target spell that targets you or a permanent you control.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Centuries of careful practice have elevated the casting of protective spells to an art form. What little offensive magic remains on Bant stands little chance of breaching them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0174</id>
    <name>Jhessian Infiltrator</name>
    <text>Jhessian Infiltrator is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>The Jhessian navy makes successful raids on Valeron's coastal towns thanks to their spies planted during peacetime.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0175</id>
    <name>Jund Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Exile all cards from target player's graveyard; or Jund Charm deals 2 damage to each creature; or put two +1/+1 counters on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Jund pulses with raw energy, waiting for shamans to shape it into useful form.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0176</id>
    <name>Kederekt Creeper</name>
    <text>Deathtouch (Creatures dealt damage by this creature are destroyed. You can divide this creature's combat damage among any of the creatures blocking or blocked by it.)
Kederekt Creeper can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Bloated with venom, it crawls Grixis looking for victims to ooze onto.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0177</id>
    <name>Kiss of the Amesha</name>
    <text>Target player gains 7 life and draws two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Once a year, Akrasa holds a joust that draws knights and their leotaus from every nation on Bant. The prize is an Akrasan sigil, but the true reward is the angel's kiss.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0178</id>
    <name>Kresh the Bloodbraided</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may put X +1/+1 counters on Kresh the Bloodbraided, where X is that creature's power.</text>
    <flavorText>Each of his twenty-two braids is bound with bone and leather from a foe.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0179</id>
    <name>Mayael the Anima</name>
    <text>{3}{R}{G}{W}, {T}: Look at the top five cards of your library. You may put a creature card with power 5 or greater from among them onto the battlefield. Put the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>The sacred Anima's eyes are blind to all but the grandest truths.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0180</id>
    <name>Naya Charm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Naya Charm deals 3 damage to target creature; or return target card from a graveyard to its owner's hand; or tap all creatures target player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Deep in nature's core lies a potential unsullied by greed or civilization.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0181</id>
    <name>Necrogenesis</name>
    <text>{2}: Exile target creature card from a graveyard. Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those may be the squirms of one life ending or of another beginning. Either way, I'd leave it alone."
—Rakka Mar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0182</id>
    <name>Prince of Thralls</name>
    <text>Whenever a permanent an opponent controls is put into a graveyard, put that card onto the battlefield under your control unless that opponent pays 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"There are none alive that I cannot crush. There are none dead that I do not command."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0183</id>
    <name>Punish Ignorance</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. Its controller loses 3 life and you gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Amateurish. Nearsighted. A waste of my time and everyone else's."
—Indra, nullmage of Vectis</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0184</id>
    <name>Qasali Ambusher</name>
    <text>Reach
If a creature is attacking you and you control a Forest and a Plains, you may cast Qasali Ambusher without paying its mana cost and as though it had flash.</text>
    <flavorText>The surprise of a battle cry can be as deadly as a blade.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0185</id>
    <name>Rafiq of the Many</name>
    <text>Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)
Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, it gains double strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Many sigils, one purpose.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0186</id>
    <name>Rakeclaw Gargantuan</name>
    <text>{1}: Target creature with power 5 or greater gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Naya teems with gargantuans, titanic monsters to whom both nature and civilization defer.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0187</id>
    <name>Realm Razer</name>
    <text>When Realm Razer enters the battlefield, exile all lands.
When Realm Razer leaves the battlefield, return the exiled cards to the battlefield tapped under their owners' control.</text>
    <flavorText>The behemoth roared, and the world was blasted free of empires and tyrants.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0188</id>
    <name>Rhox War Monk</name>
    <text>Lifelink</text>
    <flavorText>Rhox monks are dedicated to spiritual growth and learning, and most bear the sigils of many students. However, they do not gladly suffer fools or those who disagree with their carefully wrought dogma.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0189</id>
    <name>Rip-Clan Crasher</name>
    <text>Haste</text>
    <flavorText>If you breathe, she will fight you. If you breathe fire, she must fight you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0190</id>
    <name>Sangrite Surge</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 and gains double strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Some believe the spiky crystal called sangrite is concentrated dragon's breath. Others think it's crystallized life energy. The clans care only about the power it unleashes when crushed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0191</id>
    <name>Sarkhan Vol</name>
    <text>+1: Creatures you control get +1/+1 and gain haste until end of turn.
-2: Gain control of target creature until end of turn. Untap that creature. It gains haste until end of turn.
-6: Put five 4/4 red Dragon creature tokens with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0192</id>
    <name>Sedraxis Specter</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Sedraxis Specter deals combat damage to a player, that player discards a card.
Unearth {1}{B} ({1}{B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0193</id>
    <name>Sedris, the Traitor King</name>
    <text>Each creature card in your graveyard has unearth {2}{B}. ({2}{B}: Return the card to the battlefield. The creature gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>He bids his minions rise from their graves to their knees.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0194</id>
    <name>Sharuum the Hegemon</name>
    <text>Flying
When Sharuum the Hegemon enters the battlefield, you may return target artifact card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>To gain audience with the hegemon, one must bring a riddle she has not heard.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0195</id>
    <name>Sigil Blessing</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, target creature you control gets +3/+3 and other creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>"For unwavering commitment and unflinching strength, the Order of the White Orchid confers its sigil. Rise, knight-captain, and do your duty."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0196</id>
    <name>Sphinx Sovereign</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your end step, you gain 3 life if Sphinx Sovereign is untapped. Otherwise, each opponent loses 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"What rises without legs, whispers without a voice, bites without teeth, and dies without having life?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0197</id>
    <name>Sprouting Thrinax</name>
    <text>When Sprouting Thrinax is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put three 1/1 green Saproling creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The vast network of predation on Jund has actually caused some strange creatures to adapt to being eaten.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0198</id>
    <name>Steward of Valeron</name>
    <text>Vigilance
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Knight-stewards guard the Sun-Dappled Court, a grove of immense, sculptured olive trees that represent Valeron's twelve noble families.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0199</id>
    <name>Stoic Angel</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance
Players can't untap more than one creature during their untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>Even the most battle-hardened soldiers pause in her presence for a moment of introspection.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0200</id>
    <name>Swerve</name>
    <text>Change the target of target spell with a single target.</text>
    <flavorText>"We can't beat the necromancers in numbers or raw power. We must beat them with ingenuity and timing."
—Rannon, Vithian holdout</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0201</id>
    <name>Thoughtcutter Agent</name>
    <text>{U}{B}, {T}: Target player loses 1 life and reveals his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Agents of the Architects of Will mark their victims as a reminder that their secrets are secret no longer.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0202</id>
    <name>Tidehollow Sculler</name>
    <text>When Tidehollow Sculler enters the battlefield, target opponent reveals his or her hand and you choose a nonland card from it. Exile that card.
When Tidehollow Sculler leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0203</id>
    <name>Tidehollow Strix</name>
    <text>Flying
Deathtouch (Creatures dealt damage by this creature are destroyed. You can divide this creature's combat damage among any of the creatures blocking or blocked by it.)</text>
    <flavorText>The scullers beneath Esper keep strixes as trained pets, and set them loose when a fare refuses to pay.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0204</id>
    <name>Titanic Ultimatum</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, creatures you control get +5/+5 and gain first strike, lifelink, and trample.</text>
    <flavorText>"Retribution is best delivered by claws and rage, with both magnified."
—Ajani</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0205</id>
    <name>Tower Gargoyle</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"Esper, like any work of art, can be truly appreciated only from a distance."
—Tezzeret</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0206</id>
    <name>Violent Ultimatum</name>
    <text>Destroy three target permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>"Words are a waste of time. Destruction is a language everyone understands."
—Sarkhan Vol</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0207</id>
    <name>Waveskimmer Aven</name>
    <text>Flying
Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>The greatest gift you can give a sea aven is solitude.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0208</id>
    <name>Windwright Mage</name>
    <text>Lifelink (Damage dealt by this creature also causes you to gain that much life.)
Windwright Mage has flying as long as an artifact card is in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>She knows the names and secrets of each of Esper's twenty-three winds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0209</id>
    <name>Woolly Thoctar</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>One of the most ferocious and deadly gargantuans, the thoctar never sees its worshippers, but it often awakens surrounded by gifts and sacrifices.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0210</id>
    <name>Lich's Mirror</name>
    <text>If you would lose the game, instead shuffle your hand, your graveyard, and all permanents you own into your library, then draw seven cards and your life total becomes 20.</text>
    <flavorText>It shows not what you are but what you were.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0211</id>
    <name>Minion Reflector</name>
    <text>Whenever a nontoken creature enters the battlefield under your control, you may pay {2}. If you do, put a token that's a copy of that creature onto the battlefield. That token has haste and "At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice this permanent."</text>
    <flavorText>To crack a mirror is to provide an opening for the reflection to escape.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0212</id>
    <name>Obelisk of Bant</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G}, {W}, or {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Whether incorporated into the structure of castles or admired as lone symbols, the obelisks stand for Bant's values of loyalty, honor, and truth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0213</id>
    <name>Obelisk of Esper</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {W}, {U}, or {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>It is a monument as austere, unyielding, and inscrutable as Esper itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0214</id>
    <name>Obelisk of Grixis</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {U}, {B}, or {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Like most features of Grixis, the obelisks that remain from the time of Alara now exist only for dark exploitation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0215</id>
    <name>Obelisk of Jund</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {B}, {R}, or {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Volcanic ash-winds batter it, climbing vines overwhelm it, dragonfire roasts it, and yet it still stands as a testament to a forgotten world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0216</id>
    <name>Obelisk of Naya</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {R}, {G}, or {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Centuries have passed since the plane shattered, yet the obelisks of each shard faithfully serve their long-forgotten purpose.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0217</id>
    <name>Quietus Spike</name>
    <text>Equipped creature has deathtouch.
Whenever equipped creature deals combat damage to a player, that player loses half his or her life, rounded up.
Equip {3}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0218</id>
    <name>Relic of Progenitus</name>
    <text>{T}: Target player exiles a card from his or her graveyard.
{1}, Exile Relic of Progenitus: Exile all cards from all graveyards. Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Elves believe the hydra-god Progenitus sleeps beneath Naya, feeding on forgotten magics.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0219</id>
    <name>Sigil of Distinction</name>
    <text>Sigil of Distinction enters the battlefield with X charge counters on it.
Equipped creature gets +1/+1 for each charge counter on Sigil of Distinction.
Equip—Remove a charge counter from Sigil of Distinction.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0220</id>
    <name>Arcane Sanctum</name>
    <text>Arcane Sanctum enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {W}, {U}, or {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"We must rely on our own knowledge, not on the dogma of the seekers or the mutterings of the sphinxes."
—Tullus of Palandius</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0221</id>
    <name>Bant Panorama</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Bant Panorama: Search your library for a basic Forest, Plains, or Island card and put it onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Bant's hearts are as pure as its air and as bright as its skies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0222</id>
    <name>Crumbling Necropolis</name>
    <text>Crumbling Necropolis enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U}, {B}, or {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"They say the ruins of Sedraxis were once a shining capital in Vithia. Now it is a blight, a place to be avoided by the living."
—Olcot, Rider of Joffik</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0223</id>
    <name>Esper Panorama</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Esper Panorama: Search your library for a basic Plains, Island, or Swamp card and put it onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Esper is an expansive canvas painted by precise, controlling hands.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0224</id>
    <name>Grixis Panorama</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Grixis Panorama: Search your library for a basic Island, Swamp, or Mountain card and put it onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>There is no height above Grixis that is free from the stench of death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0225</id>
    <name>Jund Panorama</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Jund Panorama: Search your library for a basic Swamp, Mountain, or Forest card and put it onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The sky is the dragon's throne, the seat from which it issues its fiery decrees.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0226</id>
    <name>Jungle Shrine</name>
    <text>Jungle Shrine enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R}, {G}, or {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>On Naya, ambition and treachery are scarce, hunted nearly to extinction by the awe owed to terrestrial gods.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0227</id>
    <name>Naya Panorama</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Naya Panorama: Search your library for a basic Mountain, Forest, or Plains card and put it onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Between the thunderous footfalls of Naya's behemoths lie moments of perfect quiet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0228</id>
    <name>Savage Lands</name>
    <text>Savage Lands enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B}, {R}, or {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Jund is a world as cruel as those who call it home. Their brutal struggles scar the land even as it carves them in its image, a vicious circle spiraling out of control.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0229</id>
    <name>Seaside Citadel</name>
    <text>Seaside Citadel enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G}, {W}, or {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>For wisdom's sake, it was built high to gaze on all things. For glory's sake, it was built high as a testament of power. For strength's sake, it was built high to repel all attacks.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0230</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0231</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0232</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0233</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0234</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0235</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0236</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0237</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0238</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0239</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0240</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0241</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0242</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0243</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0244</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0245</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0246</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0247</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0248</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ALA0249</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>