<cards name="Apocalypse">
  <item>
    <id>APC0001</id>
    <name>Angelfire Crusader</name>
    <text>{R}: Angelfire Crusader gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Nothing burns hotter than the fires of holy rage.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0002</id>
    <name>Coalition Flag</name>
    <text>Enchant creature you control
Enchanted creature is a Flagbearer.
While choosing targets as part of casting a spell or activating an ability, your opponents must choose at least one Flagbearer on the battlefield if able.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0003</id>
    <name>Coalition Honor Guard</name>
    <text>While choosing targets as part of casting a spell or activating an ability, your opponents must choose at least one Flagbearer on the battlefield if able.</text>
    <flavorText>Giving little thought to their own defense, they carried the flag that united their army.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0004</id>
    <name>Dega Disciple</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.
{R}, {T}: Target creature gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is no true equity of power. There is only more and less."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0005</id>
    <name>Dega Sanctuary</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control a black or red permanent, you gain 2 life. If you control a black permanent and a red permanent, you gain 4 life instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0006</id>
    <name>Degavolver</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{B} and/or {R} (You may pay an additional {1}{B} and/or {R} as you cast this spell.)
If Degavolver was kicked with its {1}{B} kicker, Degavolver enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it and with "Pay 3 life: Regenerate Degavolver."
If Degavolver was kicked with its {R} kicker, Degavolver enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it and with first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0007</id>
    <name>Diversionary Tactics</name>
    <text>Tap two untapped creatures you control: Tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's the oldest trick in the book," said Guff. "And I ought to know—I wrote it."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0008</id>
    <name>Divine Light</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt this turn to creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Phyrexia is an unforgiving place, and I am an angry lord in an unforgiving mood."
—Lord Windgrace</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0009</id>
    <name>Enlistment Officer</name>
    <text>First strike
When Enlistment Officer enters the battlefield, reveal the top four cards of your library. Put all Soldier cards revealed this way into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0010</id>
    <name>False Dawn</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, spells and abilities you control that would add colored mana to your mana pool add that much white mana instead. Until end of turn, you may spend white mana as though it were mana of any color.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0011</id>
    <name>Gerrard Capashen</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you gain 1 life for each card in target opponent's hand.
{3}{W}: Tap target creature. Activate this ability only if Gerrard Capashen is attacking.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0012</id>
    <name>Haunted Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
When Haunted Angel is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, exile Haunted Angel and each other player puts a 3/3 black Angel creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0013</id>
    <name>Helionaut</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Hope kept the defenders aloft, but only courage kept them in the fight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0014</id>
    <name>Manacles of Decay</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack.
{B}: Enchanted creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.
{R}: Enchanted creature can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0015</id>
    <name>Orim's Thunder</name>
    <text>Kicker {R} (You may pay an additional {R} as you cast this spell.)
Destroy target artifact or enchantment. If Orim's Thunder was kicked, it deals damage equal to that permanent's converted mana cost to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0016</id>
    <name>Shield of Duty and Reason</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has protection from green and from blue.</text>
    <flavorText>The duty: to defend. The reason: to survive.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0017</id>
    <name>Spectral Lynx</name>
    <text>Protection from green
{B}: Regenerate Spectral Lynx.</text>
    <flavorText>A shadowy version of its corporeal cousin, this lynx hunts souls, not meals.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0018</id>
    <name>Standard Bearer</name>
    <text>While choosing targets as part of casting a spell or activating an ability, your opponents must choose at least one Flagbearer on the battlefield if able.</text>
    <flavorText>The standard was a rallying point for the army and a target for the enemy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0019</id>
    <name>Ceta Disciple</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}: Target creature gets +2/+0 until end of turn.
{G}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"The sea holds all that you need. You simply must know how to ask for it."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0020</id>
    <name>Ceta Sanctuary</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control a red or green permanent, draw a card, then discard a card. If you control a red permanent and a green permanent, instead draw two cards, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0021</id>
    <name>Cetavolver</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{R} and/or {G} (You may pay an additional {1}{R} and/or {G} as you cast this spell.)
If Cetavolver was kicked with its {1}{R} kicker, it enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it and with first strike.
If Cetavolver was kicked with its {G} kicker, it enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it and with trample.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0022</id>
    <name>Coastal Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{U}, {T}: Return target Kavu to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>When the kavu emerged from their ancient nests, food chains long dormant became vibrant again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0023</id>
    <name>Evasive Action</name>
    <text>Domain — Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1} for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Effective use of terrain is a lesson good commanders learn quickly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0024</id>
    <name>Ice Cave</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a spell, any other player may pay that spell's mana cost. If a player does, counter the spell. (Mana cost includes color.)</text>
    <flavorText>Even the oppresive cold of the cave could not temper Eladamri's ire.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0025</id>
    <name>Index</name>
    <text>Look at the top five cards of your library, then put them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let's see . . . Mercadia, mercenary, merfolk . . . you know, I really need a better filing system."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0026</id>
    <name>Jaded Response</name>
    <text>Counter target spell if it shares a color with a creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Calm down everyone; it's nothing we haven't seen before."
—Sisay</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0027</id>
    <name>Jilt</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{R} (You may pay an additional {1}{R} as you cast this spell.)
Return target creature to its owner's hand. If Jilt was kicked, it deals 2 damage to another target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"You're not my Hanna"
—Gerrard, to Yawgmoth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0028</id>
    <name>Living Airship</name>
    <text>Flying
{2}{G}: Regenerate Living Airship.</text>
    <flavorText>The ship has a crew of three: the pilot, the gunner, and the ship itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0029</id>
    <name>Reef Shaman</name>
    <text>{T}: Target land becomes the basic land type of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>With one gesture, she can render a thousand years of navigational charts obsolete.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0030</id>
    <name>Shimmering Mirage</name>
    <text>Target land becomes the basic land type of your choice until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Oh, is that all you need? Why didn't you just say so?"
—Reef shaman</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0031</id>
    <name>Tidal Courier</name>
    <text>When Tidal Courier enters the battlefield, reveal the top four cards of your library. Put all Merfolk cards revealed this way into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library.
{3}{U}: Tidal Courier gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0032</id>
    <name>Unnatural Selection</name>
    <text>{1}: Choose a creature type other than Wall. Target creature becomes that type until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>What nature makes, magic can modify.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0033</id>
    <name>Vodalian Mystic</name>
    <text>{T}: Target instant or sorcery spell becomes the color of your choice.</text>
    <flavorText>"Sometimes when I look at the ocean, I could swear it changes colors."
—Sisay</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0034</id>
    <name>Whirlpool Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
When Whirlpool Drake enters the battlefield, shuffle the cards from your hand into your library, then draw that many cards.
When Whirlpool Drake is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, shuffle the cards from your hand into your library, then draw that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0035</id>
    <name>Whirlpool Rider</name>
    <text>When Whirlpool Rider enters the battlefield, shuffle the cards from your hand into your library, then draw that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Where the wind meets the water, change is inevitable.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0036</id>
    <name>Whirlpool Warrior</name>
    <text>When Whirlpool Warrior enters the battlefield, shuffle the cards from your hand into your library, then draw that many cards.
{R}, Sacrifice Whirlpool Warrior: Each player shuffles the cards from his or her hand into his or her library, then draws that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0037</id>
    <name>Dead Ringers</name>
    <text>Destroy two target nonblack creatures unless either one is a color the other isn't. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Beautiful, isn't it?" crowed Crovax. "They fought together. Now they will die together."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0038</id>
    <name>Desolation Angel</name>
    <text>Kicker {W}{W} (You may pay an additional {W}{W} as you cast this spell.)
Flying
When Desolation Angel enters the battlefield, destroy all lands you control. If it was kicked, destroy all lands instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0039</id>
    <name>Foul Presence</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets -1/-1 and has "{T}: Target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>The Phyrexians have one word that means both "evolution" and "pain."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0040</id>
    <name>Grave Defiler</name>
    <text>When Grave Defiler enters the battlefield, reveal the top four cards of your library. Put all Zombie cards revealed this way into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library.
{1}{B}: Regenerate Grave Defiler.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0041</id>
    <name>Last Caress</name>
    <text>Target player loses 1 life and you gain 1 life.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0042</id>
    <name>Mind Extraction</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Mind Extraction, sacrifice a creature.
Target player reveals his or her hand and discards all cards of each of the sacrificed creature's colors.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0043</id>
    <name>Mournful Zombie</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Target player gains 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Treated with a powerful mix of herbs and potions, its wrappings have a remarkable preservative effect, even for the living.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0044</id>
    <name>Necra Disciple</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.
{W}, {T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The darkness merely hides the light."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0045</id>
    <name>Necra Sanctuary</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control a green or white permanent, target player loses 1 life. If you control a green permanent and a white permanent, that player loses 3 life instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0046</id>
    <name>Necravolver</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{G} and/or {W} (You may pay an additional {1}{G} and/or {W} as you cast this spell.)
If Necravolver was kicked with its {1}{G} kicker, it enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it and with trample.
If Necravolver was kicked with its {W} kicker, it enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it and with "Whenever Necravolver deals damage, you gain that much life."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0047</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Arena</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you draw a card and you lose 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>An audience of one with the malice of thousands.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0048</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Gargantua</name>
    <text>When Phyrexian Gargantua enters the battlefield, you draw two cards and you lose 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Other Phyrexians have nightmares about the gargantua.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0049</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Rager</name>
    <text>When Phyrexian Rager enters the battlefield, you draw a card and you lose 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>It takes no prisoners, but it keeps the choicest bits for Phyrexia.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0050</id>
    <name>Planar Despair</name>
    <text>Domain — All creatures get -1/-1 until end of turn for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>All of Dominaria recoiled as Yawgmoth and his retainers arrived.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0051</id>
    <name>Quagmire Druid</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>As the druids had devoted their lives to preserving Dominaria, so did they devote their deaths.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0052</id>
    <name>Suppress</name>
    <text>Target player exiles all cards from his or her hand face down. At the beginning of the end step of that player's next turn, that player returns those cards to his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0053</id>
    <name>Urborg Uprising</name>
    <text>Return up to two target creature cards from your graveyard to your hand.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>In Urborg, few things are less permanent than death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0054</id>
    <name>Zombie Boa</name>
    <text>{1}{B}: Choose a color. Whenever Zombie Boa becomes blocked by a creature of that color this turn, destroy that creature. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>It doesn't need to feed, but still it hungers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0055</id>
    <name>Bloodfire Colossus</name>
    <text>{R}, Sacrifice Bloodfire Colossus: Bloodfire Colossus deals 6 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>It took all its strength to contain the fire within.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0056</id>
    <name>Bloodfire Dwarf</name>
    <text>{R}, Sacrifice Bloodfire Dwarf: Bloodfire Dwarf deals 1 damage to each creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>For them, the only honorable death is one that leaves a crater.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0057</id>
    <name>Bloodfire Infusion</name>
    <text>Enchant creature you control
{R}, Sacrifice enchanted creature: Bloodfire Infusion deals damage equal to the sacrificed creature's power to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0058</id>
    <name>Bloodfire Kavu</name>
    <text>{R}, Sacrifice Bloodfire Kavu: Bloodfire Kavu deals 2 damage to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Heart of fire, blood of lava, teeth of stone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0059</id>
    <name>Desolation Giant</name>
    <text>Kicker {W}{W} (You may pay an additional {W}{W} as you cast this spell.)
When Desolation Giant enters the battlefield, destroy all other creatures you control. If it was kicked, destroy all other creatures instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0060</id>
    <name>Dwarven Landslide</name>
    <text>Kicker—{2}{R}, Sacrifice a land. (You may pay {2}{R} and sacrifice a land in addition to any other costs as you cast this spell.)
Destroy target land. If Dwarven Landslide was kicked, destroy another target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0061</id>
    <name>Dwarven Patrol</name>
    <text>Dwarven Patrol doesn't untap during your untap step.
Whenever you cast a nonred spell, untap Dwarven Patrol.</text>
    <flavorText>Dwarves never worry about who watches their backs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0062</id>
    <name>Goblin Ringleader</name>
    <text>Haste
When Goblin Ringleader enters the battlefield, reveal the top four cards of your library. Put all Goblin cards revealed this way into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0063</id>
    <name>Illuminate</name>
    <text>Kicker {2}{R} and/or {3}{U} (You may pay an additional {2}{R} and/or {3}{U} as you cast this spell.)
Illuminate deals X damage to target creature. If Illuminate was kicked with its {2}{R} kicker, it deals X damage to that creature's controller. If Illuminate was kicked with its {3}{U} kicker, you draw X cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0064</id>
    <name>Kavu Glider</name>
    <text>{W}: Kavu Glider gets +0/+1 until end of turn.
{U}: Kavu Glider gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0065</id>
    <name>Minotaur Tactician</name>
    <text>Haste
Minotaur Tactician gets +1/+1 as long as you control a white creature.
Minotaur Tactician gets +1/+1 as long as you control a blue creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0066</id>
    <name>Raka Disciple</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.
{U}, {T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The strong can also be subtle."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0067</id>
    <name>Raka Sanctuary</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control a white or blue permanent, Raka Sanctuary deals 1 damage to target creature. If you control a white permanent and a blue permanent, Raka Sanctuary deals 3 damage to that creature instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0068</id>
    <name>Rakavolver</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{W} and/or {U} (You may pay an additional {1}{W} and/or {U} as you cast this spell.)
If Rakavolver was kicked with its {1}{W} kicker, it enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it and with "Whenever Rakavolver deals damage, you gain that much life."
If Rakavolver was kicked with its {U} kicker, it enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it and with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0069</id>
    <name>Smash</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"They're ugly, and they're in my way."
—Tahngarth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0070</id>
    <name>Tahngarth's Glare</name>
    <text>Look at the top three cards of target opponent's library, then put them back in any order. That player looks at the top three cards of your library, then puts them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0071</id>
    <name>Tundra Kavu</name>
    <text>{T}: Target land becomes a Plains or an Island until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A cross between a jaguar and an armadillo.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0072</id>
    <name>Wild Research</name>
    <text>{1}{W}: Search your library for an enchantment card and reveal that card. Put it into your hand, then discard a card at random. Then shuffle your library.
{1}{U}: Search your library for an instant card and reveal that card. Put it into your hand, then discard a card at random. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0073</id>
    <name>Ana Disciple</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.
{B}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The blessings of Gaea alone are no longer enough."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0074</id>
    <name>Ana Sanctuary</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control a blue or black permanent, target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn. If you control a blue permanent and a black permanent, that creature gets +5/+5 until end of turn instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0075</id>
    <name>Anavolver</name>
    <text>Kicker {1}{U} and/or {B} (You may pay an additional {1}{U} and/or {B} as you cast this spell.)
If Anavolver was kicked with its {1}{U} kicker, it enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it and with flying.
If Anavolver was kicked with its {B} kicker, it enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it and with "Pay 3 life: Regenerate Anavolver."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0076</id>
    <name>Bog Gnarr</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a black spell, Bog Gnarr gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Not all of Dominaria's defenders were nourished by the light.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0077</id>
    <name>Gaea's Balance</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Gaea's Balance, sacrifice five lands.
Search your library for a land card of each basic land type and put them onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0078</id>
    <name>Glade Gnarr</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a blue spell, Glade Gnarr gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Long thought merely a legend, the appearance of the gnarr was seen by the defenders as a sign of good luck.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0079</id>
    <name>Kavu Howler</name>
    <text>When Kavu Howler enters the battlefield, reveal the top four cards of your library. Put all Kavu cards revealed this way into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0080</id>
    <name>Kavu Mauler</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Kavu Mauler attacks, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each other attacking Kavu.</text>
    <flavorText>To the kavu, all Phyrexians are merely crunchy snacks.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0081</id>
    <name>Lay of the Land</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Victory favors neither the righteous nor the wicked. It favors the prepared.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0082</id>
    <name>Penumbra Bobcat</name>
    <text>When Penumbra Bobcat is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a 2/1 black Cat creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>This cat has two lives and it's hunting for more.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0083</id>
    <name>Penumbra Kavu</name>
    <text>When Penumbra Kavu is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a 3/3 black Kavu creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"These kavu are so stubborn they even refuse to die."
—Tahngarth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0084</id>
    <name>Penumbra Wurm</name>
    <text>Trample
When Penumbra Wurm is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a 6/6 black Wurm creature token with trample onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0085</id>
    <name>Savage Gorilla</name>
    <text>{U}{B}, {T}, Sacrifice Savage Gorilla: Target creature gets -3/-3 until end of turn. Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>These omnivorous gorillas have no qualms about a diet composed of equal parts fruit and Phyrexians.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0086</id>
    <name>Strength of Night</name>
    <text>Kicker {B} (You may pay an additional {B} as you cast this spell.)
Creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn. If Strength of Night was kicked, Zombie creatures you control get an additional +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0087</id>
    <name>Sylvan Messenger</name>
    <text>Trample
When Sylvan Messenger enters the battlefield, reveal the top four cards of your library. Put all Elf cards revealed this way into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0088</id>
    <name>Symbiotic Deployment</name>
    <text>Skip your draw step.

{1}, Tap two untapped creatures you control: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"You know your orders. I know your hearts. Now the stronghold will know defeat."
—Eladamri</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0089</id>
    <name>Tranquil Path</name>
    <text>Destroy all enchantments.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Freyalise bought the planeswalkers the time they needed by clearing a path through the misshapen hell of Phyrexia.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0090</id>
    <name>Urborg Elf</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G}, {U}, or {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The elves of Urborg are as deadly and capricious as the swamp itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0091</id>
    <name>Æther Mutation</name>
    <text>Return target creature to its owner's hand. Put X 1/1 green Saproling creature tokens onto the battlefield, where X is that creature's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0092</id>
    <name>Captain's Maneuver</name>
    <text>The next X damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn is dealt to another target creature or player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Sisay discovered that the mirrored hull of the Weatherlight could be used as a defensive weapon.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0093</id>
    <name>Consume Strength</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn. Another target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>As Multani's troops invaded Urborg, the decay of the swamp became a feast for the living.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0094</id>
    <name>Cromat</name>
    <text>{W}{B}: Destroy target creature blocking or blocked by Cromat.
{U}{R}: Cromat gains flying until end of turn.
{B}{G}: Regenerate Cromat.
{R}{W}: Cromat gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
{G}{U}: Put Cromat on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0095</id>
    <name>Death Grasp</name>
    <text>Death Grasp deals X damage to target creature or player. You gain X life.</text>
    <flavorText>Yawgmoth's greatest joy came from watching one hero defeat another.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0096</id>
    <name>Death Mutation</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated. Put X 1/1 green Saproling creature tokens onto the battlefield, where X is that creature's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0097</id>
    <name>Ebony Treefolk</name>
    <text>{B}{G}: Ebony Treefolk gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Its roots are equally happy to drink the water of a clear stream or the oily blood of a Phyrexian warrior.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0098</id>
    <name>Fervent Charge</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control attacks, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Crovax was nearly buried beneath the weight of his opponents.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0099</id>
    <name>Flowstone Charger</name>
    <text>Whenever Flowstone Charger attacks, it gets +3/-3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A mane of flowstone and a mien of fury.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0100</id>
    <name>Fungal Shambler</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Fungal Shambler deals damage to an opponent, you draw a card and that opponent discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0101</id>
    <name>Gaea's Skyfolk</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>The grace of the forest and the spirit of the sea.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0102</id>
    <name>Gerrard's Verdict</name>
    <text>Target player discards two cards. You gain 3 life for each land card discarded this way.</text>
    <flavorText>A heart of light and a soul of darkness cannot coexist.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0103</id>
    <name>Goblin Legionnaire</name>
    <text>{R}, Sacrifice Goblin Legionnaire: Goblin Legionnaire deals 2 damage to target creature or player.
{W}, Sacrifice Goblin Legionnaire: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0104</id>
    <name>Goblin Trenches</name>
    <text>{2}, Sacrifice a land: Put two 1/1 red and white Goblin Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The ground rose and formed into thousands of tiny warriors. This fight was far from over.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0105</id>
    <name>Guided Passage</name>
    <text>Reveal the cards in your library. An opponent chooses from among them a creature card, a land card, and a noncreature, nonland card. You put the chosen cards into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0106</id>
    <name>Jungle Barrier</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
When Jungle Barrier enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>A massive pull of mana caused all of Dominaria to pause—Multani had transplanted Yavimaya to Urborg's edge.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0107</id>
    <name>Last Stand</name>
    <text>Target opponent loses 2 life for each Swamp you control. Last Stand deals damage equal to the number of Mountains you control to target creature. Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield for each Forest you control. You gain 2 life for each Plains you control. Draw a card for each Island you control, then discard that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0108</id>
    <name>Lightning Angel</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance, haste</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0109</id>
    <name>Llanowar Dead</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Just as leaves fall from the branches of a living tree, so too do the dead leave the elfhame.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0110</id>
    <name>Martyrs' Tomb</name>
    <text>Pay 2 life: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Honor the brave who fought,
Honor the dead who fell,
Honor the world they saved.
—Memorial inscription</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0111</id>
    <name>Minotaur Illusionist</name>
    <text>{1}{U}: Minotaur Illusionist gains shroud until end of turn. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)
{R}, Sacrifice Minotaur Illusionist: Minotaur Illusionist deals damage equal to its power to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0112</id>
    <name>Mystic Snake</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
When Mystic Snake enters the battlefield, counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>Its fangs are in your flesh before its hiss leaves your ears.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0113</id>
    <name>Overgrown Estate</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a land: You gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The decay of Crovax's ancestral home matched the state of his soul.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0114</id>
    <name>Pernicious Deed</name>
    <text>{X}, Sacrifice Pernicious Deed: Destroy each artifact, creature, and enchantment with converted mana cost X or less.</text>
    <flavorText>"Yawgmoth," Freyalise whispered as she set the bomb, "now you will pay for your treachery."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0115</id>
    <name>Powerstone Minefield</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature attacks or blocks, Powerstone Minefield deals 2 damage to it.</text>
    <flavorText>"We have fought this far and lost too much. We will not turn back."
—Grizzlegom</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0116</id>
    <name>Prophetic Bolt</name>
    <text>Prophetic Bolt deals 4 damage to target creature or player. Look at the top four cards of your library. Put one of those cards into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0117</id>
    <name>Putrid Warrior</name>
    <text>Whenever Putrid Warrior deals damage, choose one — each player loses 1 life; or each player gains 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"I do not like it," said Grizzlegom, "but I will take every soldier I can get."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0118</id>
    <name>Quicksilver Dagger</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has "{T}: This creature deals 1 damage to target player. You draw a card."</text>
    <flavorText>The dwarves call their quicksilver techniques "improvisational weaponsmithing."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0119</id>
    <name>Razorfin Hunter</name>
    <text>{T}: Razorfin Hunter deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>No one knew if they'd been lurking under the sea all along, or if they'd been created by the Phyrexian overlay.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0120</id>
    <name>Soul Link</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage, you gain that much life.
Whenever enchanted creature is dealt damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>They danced like puppets to a tune only Yawgmoth could hear.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0121</id>
    <name>Spiritmonger</name>
    <text>Whenever Spiritmonger deals damage to a creature, put a +1/+1 counter on Spiritmonger.
{B}: Regenerate Spiritmonger.
{G}: Spiritmonger becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0122</id>
    <name>Squee's Embrace</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2.
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, return that card to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0123</id>
    <name>Squee's Revenge</name>
    <text>Choose a number. Flip a coin that many times or until you lose a flip, whichever comes first. If you win all the flips, draw two cards for each flip.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0124</id>
    <name>Suffocating Blast</name>
    <text>Counter target spell and Suffocating Blast deals 3 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0125</id>
    <name>Temporal Spring</name>
    <text>Put target permanent on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>One splash of the spring's water knocks you clear into last week.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0126</id>
    <name>Vindicate</name>
    <text>Destroy target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"Don't mourn for me. This is my destiny."
—Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0127</id>
    <name>Yavimaya's Embrace</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
You control enchanted creature.
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and has trample.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0128</id>
    <name>Fire</name>
    <text>Fire deals 2 damage divided as you choose among one or two target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0129</id>
    <name>Fire</name>
    <text>Fire deals 2 damage divided as you choose among one or two target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0130</id>
    <name>Ice</name>
    <text>Fire deals 2 damage divided as you choose among one or two target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0131</id>
    <name>Ice</name>
    <text>Fire deals 2 damage divided as you choose among one or two target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0132</id>
    <name>Illusion</name>
    <text>Target spell or permanent becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0133</id>
    <name>Illusion</name>
    <text>Target spell or permanent becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0134</id>
    <name>Reality</name>
    <text>Target spell or permanent becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0135</id>
    <name>Reality</name>
    <text>Target spell or permanent becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0136</id>
    <name>Death</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield. You lose life equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0137</id>
    <name>Death</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield. You lose life equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0138</id>
    <name>Life</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield. You lose life equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0139</id>
    <name>Life</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield. You lose life equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0140</id>
    <name>Day</name>
    <text>Creatures target player controls get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0141</id>
    <name>Day</name>
    <text>Creatures target player controls get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0142</id>
    <name>Night</name>
    <text>Creatures target player controls get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0143</id>
    <name>Night</name>
    <text>Creatures target player controls get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0144</id>
    <name>Chaos</name>
    <text>Creatures can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0145</id>
    <name>Chaos</name>
    <text>Creatures can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0146</id>
    <name>Order</name>
    <text>Creatures can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0147</id>
    <name>Order</name>
    <text>Creatures can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0148</id>
    <name>Brass Herald</name>
    <text>As Brass Herald enters the battlefield, choose a creature type.
When Brass Herald enters the battlefield, reveal the top four cards of your library. Put all creature cards of the chosen type revealed this way into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.
Creatures of the chosen type get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0149</id>
    <name>Dodecapod</name>
    <text>If a spell or ability an opponent controls causes you to discard Dodecapod, put it onto the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it instead of putting it into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0150</id>
    <name>Dragon Arch</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: You may put a multicolored creature card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>In their hunger for the arch's power, mages often forget that it only makes dragons easier to summon. It doesn't make them easier to control.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0151</id>
    <name>Emblazoned Golem</name>
    <text>Kicker {X} (You may pay an additional {X} as you cast this spell.)
Spend only colored mana on X. No more than one mana of each color may be spent this way.
If Emblazoned Golem was kicked, it enters the battlefield with X +1/+1 counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0152</id>
    <name>Legacy Weapon</name>
    <text>{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}: Exile target permanent.
If Legacy Weapon would be put into a graveyard from anywhere, reveal Legacy Weapon and shuffle it into its owner's library instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0153</id>
    <name>Mask of Intolerance</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, if there are four or more basic land types among lands that player controls, Mask of Intolerance deals 3 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0154</id>
    <name>Battlefield Forge</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {R} or {W} to your mana pool. Battlefield Forge deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0155</id>
    <name>Caves of Koilos</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {W} or {B} to your mana pool. Caves of Koilos deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0156</id>
    <name>Llanowar Wastes</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {B} or {G} to your mana pool. Llanowar Wastes deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0157</id>
    <name>Shivan Reef</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {U} or {R} to your mana pool. Shivan Reef deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>APC0158</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Coast</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {G} or {U} to your mana pool. Yavimaya Coast deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>