<cards name="Conflux">
  <item>
    <id>CFX0001</id>
    <name>Aerie Mystics</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{G}{U}: Creatures you control gain shroud until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>They are cautious with their body language and facial expressions. Any stray movement could betray the positions of the troops they protect and cost many lives.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0002</id>
    <name>Asha's Favor</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has flying, first strike, and vigilance.</text>
    <flavorText>As his new wings lifted him high above Bant, Taric felt his earthly aspirations transform into heavenly resolve.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0003</id>
    <name>Aven Squire</name>
    <text>Flying
Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>When the meek charge into battle, courage becomes infectious.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0004</id>
    <name>Aven Trailblazer</name>
    <text>Flying
Domain — Aven Trailblazer's toughness is equal to the number of basic land types among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"The bird wore the form of a man, bereft of filigree. Why do the Texts not speak of it?"
—Belator of Esper</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0005</id>
    <name>Celestial Purge</name>
    <text>Exile target black or red permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"This new chaos confounds us. We must fling it into our winds, our storms. These we can control."
—Bezzit Plar, Esper stormcaller</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0006</id>
    <name>Court Homunculus</name>
    <text>Court Homunculus gets +1/+1 as long as you control another artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>Mages of Esper measure their wealth and status by the number of servants in their retinues.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0007</id>
    <name>Darklit Gargoyle</name>
    <text>Flying
{B}: Darklit Gargoyle gets +2/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It shines in the darkness of its master's ambitions.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0008</id>
    <name>Gleam of Resistance</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +1/+2 until end of turn. Untap those creatures.
Basic landcycling {1}{W} ({1}{W}, Discard this card: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0009</id>
    <name>Lapse of Certainty</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. If that spell is countered this way, put it on top of its owner's library instead of into that player's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Without a connection of mind and body, magic is just an idea stuck in the head, a word on the tip of a tongue.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0010</id>
    <name>Mark of Asylum</name>
    <text>Prevent all noncombat damage that would be dealt to creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>A paragon of honor, Galo Aher fell to a blast of fire. The Order of the White Orchid was so saddened that they forged a new sigil in his likeness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0011</id>
    <name>Martial Coup</name>
    <text>Put X 1/1 white Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield. If X is 5 or more, destroy all other creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Their war forgotten, the nations of Bant stood united in the face of a common threat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0012</id>
    <name>Mirror-Sigil Sergeant</name>
    <text>Trample
At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control a blue permanent, you may put a token that's a copy of Mirror-Sigil Sergeant onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"If I had many lives, I would give them all for Bant."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0013</id>
    <name>Nacatl Hunt-Pride</name>
    <text>Vigilance
{R}, {T}: Target creature can't block this turn.
{G}, {T}: Target creature blocks this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>"We must hunt and kill the dragon before it can return to raze our ancient city."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0014</id>
    <name>Paragon of the Amesha</name>
    <text>First strike
{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}: Until end of turn, Paragon of the Amesha becomes an Angel, gets +3/+3, and gains flying and lifelink.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let my lance sing with the voices of angels and the heathen cower before my shield, for I will teach this land the meaning of honor."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0015</id>
    <name>Path to Exile</name>
    <text>Exile target creature. Its controller may search his or her library for a basic land card, put that card onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0016</id>
    <name>Rhox Meditant</name>
    <text>When Rhox Meditant enters the battlefield, if you control a green permanent, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The weight of her conviction balances on the harmony of her soul.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0017</id>
    <name>Scepter of Dominance</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Tap target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"Whether or not you will bow to me is not open to debate. The question is, will I ever let you rise?"
—Fridius, telemin master</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0018</id>
    <name>Sigil of the Empty Throne</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an enchantment spell, put a 4/4 white Angel creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>When Asha left Bant, she ensured that the world would have protection and order in her absence.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0019</id>
    <name>Valiant Guard</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>As the outsiders invaded Bant, soldiers who once saw sigils as the highest marks of glory began to see the scars of battle as tokens of equal worth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0020</id>
    <name>Wall of Reverence</name>
    <text>Defender, flying
At the beginning of your end step, you may gain life equal to the power of target creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The lives of elves are long, but their memories are longer. Even after death, they do not desert their homes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0021</id>
    <name>Brackwater Elemental</name>
    <text>When Brackwater Elemental attacks or blocks, sacrifice it at the beginning of the next end step.
Unearth {2}{U} ({2}{U}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0022</id>
    <name>Constricting Tendrils</name>
    <text>Target creature gets -3/-0 until end of turn.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>Priests of Bant protect their temples with traps more elaborate than any mosaic floor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0023</id>
    <name>Controlled Instincts</name>
    <text>Enchant red or green creature
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>Togk Manytooth struggled helplessly as the kathari circled above him. For a warrior, immobilization is a fate worse than death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0024</id>
    <name>Cumber Stone</name>
    <text>Creatures your opponents control get -1/-0.</text>
    <flavorText>"The stone is more potent than ever. The flesh that creeps into our land will become even more slovenly and weak."
—Niclavs, archmage of Esper</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0025</id>
    <name>Esperzoa</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, return an artifact you control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The more metal it digests, the more its jelly will fetch on the alchemists' market.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0026</id>
    <name>Ethersworn Adjudicator</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{W}{B}, {T}: Destroy target creature or enchantment.
{2}{U}: Untap Ethersworn Adjudicator.</text>
    <flavorText>Esper mages devised their weapons to be so devastating that war seemed unnecessary.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0027</id>
    <name>Faerie Mechanist</name>
    <text>Flying
When Faerie Mechanist enters the battlefield, look at the top three cards of your library. You may reveal an artifact card from among them and put it into your hand. Put the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0028</id>
    <name>Frontline Sage</name>
    <text>Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)
{U}, {T}: Draw a card, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The battle was won in the commander's head before the first weapon was drawn.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0029</id>
    <name>Grixis Illusionist</name>
    <text>{T}: Target land you control becomes the basic land type of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's simple, really. If they can't find us, they can't kill us."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0030</id>
    <name>Inkwell Leviathan</name>
    <text>Islandwalk, trample, shroud</text>
    <flavorText>"Into its maw went the seventh sea, never to be seen again while the world remains."
—Esper fable</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0031</id>
    <name>Master Transmuter</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}, Return an artifact you control to its owner's hand: You may put an artifact card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Wasted potential surrounds us. Lend me that bauble, and let me see what it can be made to be."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0032</id>
    <name>Parasitic Strix</name>
    <text>Flying
When Parasitic Strix enters the battlefield, if you control a black permanent, target player loses 2 life and you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>After finding no sustenance on the edges of Grixis, it turned to the skies of Bant.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0033</id>
    <name>Scepter of Insight</name>
    <text>{3}{U}, {T}: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"The road to truth has many branches, and so must the cane with which I walk it."
—Voln the Elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0034</id>
    <name>Scornful Æther-Lich</name>
    <text>{W}{B}: Scornful Æther-Lich gains fear and vigilance until end of turn. (Attacking doesn't cause it to tap, and it can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>"With no flesh, there is no pain, no hesitation, no emotion of any kind. He is crafted perfection."
—Tezzeret</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0035</id>
    <name>Telemin Performance</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals cards from the top of his or her library until he or she reveals a creature card. That player puts all noncreature cards revealed this way into his or her graveyard, then you put the creature card onto the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0036</id>
    <name>Traumatic Visions</name>
    <text>Counter target spell.
Basic landcycling {1}{U} ({1}{U}, Discard this card: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0037</id>
    <name>Unsummon</name>
    <text>Return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Send it back to its own strange world so we can avoid another inglorious combat with these wicked beings."
—Captain Valek of Jhess</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0038</id>
    <name>View from Above</name>
    <text>Target creature gains flying until end of turn. If you control a white permanent, return View from Above to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"This air feels so heavy and thick. There are no winds to speak of. I fear the knowledge that comes from a place like this."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0039</id>
    <name>Worldly Counsel</name>
    <text>Domain — Look at the top X cards of your library, where X is the number of basic land types among lands you control. Put one of those cards into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>Every horizon hides a new possibility.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0040</id>
    <name>Absorb Vis</name>
    <text>Target player loses 4 life and you gain 4 life.
Basic landcycling {1}{B} ({1}{B}, Discard this card: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0041</id>
    <name>Corrupted Roots</name>
    <text>Enchant Forest or Plains
Whenever enchanted land becomes tapped, its controller loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The bones of Jund's dead resurfaced in Naya, poisoning the jungle and killing the sunseeders' crops.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0042</id>
    <name>Drag Down</name>
    <text>Domain — Target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The barbarians of Jund believe the bottomless tar pits extend forever into other, darker worlds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0043</id>
    <name>Dreadwing</name>
    <text>{1}{U}{R}: Dreadwing gets +3/+0 and gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Dreadwings spring from lofty perches to surprise kathari in midflight. They smother their prey and then consume it as they glide gently toward the ground.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0044</id>
    <name>Extractor Demon</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever another creature leaves the battlefield, you may have target player put the top two cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.
Unearth {2}{B} ({2}{B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0045</id>
    <name>Fleshformer</name>
    <text>{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}: Fleshformer gets +2/+2 and gains fear until end of turn. Target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn. Activate this ability only during your turn. (A creature with fear can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>Necromancers who discovered the new sources of mana were quick to dream up new nightmares with them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0046</id>
    <name>Grixis Slavedriver</name>
    <text>When Grixis Slavedriver leaves the battlefield, put a 2/2 black Zombie creature token onto the battlefield.
Unearth {3}{B} ({3}{B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0047</id>
    <name>Infectious Horror</name>
    <text>Whenever Infectious Horror attacks, each opponent loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Not once in the history of Grixis has anyone died of old age.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0048</id>
    <name>Kederekt Parasite</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent draws a card, if you control a red permanent, you may have Kederekt Parasite deal 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>When the smell of passing thoughts piques its hunger, its maw becomes primed with acid and a taste for brains.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0049</id>
    <name>Nyxathid</name>
    <text>As Nyxathid enters the battlefield, choose an opponent.
Nyxathid gets -1/-1 for each card in the chosen player's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Born of volcanic forces, it thrives on the absolute panic it inspires.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0050</id>
    <name>Pestilent Kathari</name>
    <text>Flying
Deathtouch (Creatures dealt damage by this creature are destroyed. You can divide this creature's combat damage among any of the creatures blocking or blocked by it.)
{2}{R}: Pestilent Kathari gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0051</id>
    <name>Rotting Rats</name>
    <text>When Rotting Rats enters the battlefield, each player discards a card.
Unearth {1}{B} ({1}{B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0052</id>
    <name>Salvage Slasher</name>
    <text>Salvage Slasher gets +1/+0 for each artifact card in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Esper artificers never imagined that one day their scraps would be pressed against their soft and fragile throats.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0053</id>
    <name>Scepter of Fugue</name>
    <text>{1}{B}, {T}: Target player discards a card. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>One goes to Tidehollow either to forget or to be forgotten. Either way, the scullers will oblige.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0054</id>
    <name>Sedraxis Alchemist</name>
    <text>When Sedraxis Alchemist enters the battlefield, if you control a blue permanent, return target nonland permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The problem with a liquid that can dissolve anything is finding something to carry it in.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0055</id>
    <name>Voices from the Void</name>
    <text>Domain — Target player discards a card for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>As Grixis collided with the rest of Alara, the worlds began to hear the hateful whispers of the forgotten dead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0056</id>
    <name>Wretched Banquet</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature if it has the least power or is tied for least power among creatures on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"The meek inherit nothing."
—Sedris, the Traitor King</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0057</id>
    <name>Yoke of the Damned</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, destroy enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The demon's yoke is part leash, part noose.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0058</id>
    <name>Banefire</name>
    <text>Banefire deals X damage to target creature or player.
If X is 5 or more, Banefire can't be countered by spells or abilities and the damage can't be prevented.</text>
    <flavorText>For Sarkhan Vol, the dragon is the purest expression of life's savage splendor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0059</id>
    <name>Bloodhall Ooze</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control a black permanent, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Bloodhall Ooze.
At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control a green permanent, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Bloodhall Ooze.</text>
    <flavorText>A drop of blood spilled from the first dragon.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0060</id>
    <name>Canyon Minotaur</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>On Jund, the deep canyons were the best places to hide. When the goblins wandered into Naya, they found that was not so true.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0061</id>
    <name>Dark Temper</name>
    <text>Dark Temper deals 2 damage to target creature. If you control a black permanent, destroy the creature instead.</text>
    <flavorText>When you've got the temperament of a dragon, every argument is one you'll win.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0062</id>
    <name>Dragonsoul Knight</name>
    <text>First strike
{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}: Until end of turn, Dragonsoul Knight becomes a Dragon, gets +5/+3, and gains flying and trample.</text>
    <flavorText>The farther he roamed from Jund and its dragons, the more he felt their essence in himself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0063</id>
    <name>Fiery Fall</name>
    <text>Fiery Fall deals 5 damage to target creature.
Basic landcycling {1}{R} ({1}{R}, Discard this card: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)</text>
    <flavorText>Jund feasts on the unprepared.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0064</id>
    <name>Goblin Razerunners</name>
    <text>{1}{R}, Sacrifice a land: Put a +1/+1 counter on Goblin Razerunners.
At the beginning of your end step, you may have Goblin Razerunners deal damage equal to the number of +1/+1 counters on it to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Finding themselves in a new and unexplored world, they immediately set it on fire.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0065</id>
    <name>Hellspark Elemental</name>
    <text>Trample, haste
At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice Hellspark Elemental.
Unearth {1}{R} ({1}{R}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0066</id>
    <name>Ignite Disorder</name>
    <text>Ignite Disorder deals 3 damage divided as you choose among one, two, or three target white and/or blue creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"Bant is a world imprisoned by polished stone and tyrannical rule. It yearns to strike back against those who restrain it."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0067</id>
    <name>Kranioceros</name>
    <text>{1}{W}: Kranioceros gets +0/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"A surly beast, the kranioceros will raise its defenses at the smallest threat. Stay out of sight and downwind, or you'll disrupt its natural migrations."
—Ebrel, godtoucher mentor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0068</id>
    <name>Maniacal Rage</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>The spikes of sangrite made the goblin stronger, but they didn't make him any smarter.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0069</id>
    <name>Molten Frame</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact creature.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>The metal filigree in his body glowed red-hot, and his flesh soon followed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0070</id>
    <name>Quenchable Fire</name>
    <text>Quenchable Fire deals 3 damage to target player. It deals an additional 3 damage to that player at the beginning of your next upkeep step unless he or she pays {U} before that step.</text>
    <flavorText>You'd better know how to pray for rain.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0071</id>
    <name>Rakka Mar</name>
    <text>Haste
{R}, {T}: Put a 3/1 red Elemental creature token with haste onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"The finest pawns are those with pawns of their own."
—Nicol Bolas</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0072</id>
    <name>Toxic Iguanar</name>
    <text>Toxic Iguanar has deathtouch as long as you control a green permanent. (Creatures dealt damage by this creature are destroyed. You can divide its combat damage among any of the creatures blocking or blocked by it.)</text>
    <flavorText>There are no "weak" creatures on Jund. Even the smallest can strike a deadly blow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0073</id>
    <name>Viashino Slaughtermaster</name>
    <text>Double strike
{B}{G}: Viashino Slaughtermaster gets +1/+1 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'll fight two at once, and then lick their guts from my blades."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0074</id>
    <name>Volcanic Fallout</name>
    <text>Volcanic Fallout can't be countered.
Volcanic Fallout deals 2 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>"How can we outrun the sky?"
—Hadran, sunseeder of Naya</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0075</id>
    <name>Voracious Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
Devour 1 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with that many +1/+1 counters on it.)
When Voracious Dragon enters the battlefield, it deals damage to target creature or player equal to twice the number of Goblins it devoured.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0076</id>
    <name>Wandering Goblins</name>
    <text>Domain — {3}: Wandering Goblins gets +1/+0 until end of turn for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Tired of waiting for a dragon to eat them, some hardy goblins struck out to become meals for the unknown.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0077</id>
    <name>Worldheart Phoenix</name>
    <text>Flying
You may cast Worldheart Phoenix from your graveyard by paying {W}{U}{B}{R}{G} rather than paying its mana cost. If you do, it enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0078</id>
    <name>Beacon Behemoth</name>
    <text>{1}: Target creature with power 5 or greater gains vigilance until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>When its smoky plumes light Naya's sky, every creature from the smallest pip fawn to the largest rannet heeds the warning.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0079</id>
    <name>Cliffrunner Behemoth</name>
    <text>Cliffrunner Behemoth has haste as long as you control a red permanent.
Cliffrunner Behemoth has lifelink as long as you control a white permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>It's revered for its power, celebrated for its grace, and feared for the avalanches triggered by its thunderous feet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0080</id>
    <name>Cylian Sunsinger</name>
    <text>{R}{G}{W}: Cylian Sunsinger and each other creature with the same name as it get +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The sun shines bright upon the strong."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0081</id>
    <name>Ember Weaver</name>
    <text>Reach (This can block creatures with flying.)
As long as you control a red permanent, Ember Weaver gets +1/+0 and has first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>"Each night, the sun unravels and blows away. Each day, the spiders set a new one in the sky."
—Sunseeder myth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0082</id>
    <name>Filigree Fracture</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment. If that permanent was blue or black, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The sphinx tyrannized Bant until a rhox mage tested the hardiness of her shiny parts.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0083</id>
    <name>Gluttonous Slime</name>
    <text>Flash
Devour 1 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with that many +1/+1 counters on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>On Jund, everything eventually ends up in something else's stomach.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0084</id>
    <name>Matca Rioters</name>
    <text>Domain — Matca Rioters's power and toughness are each equal to the number of basic land types among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>When outsiders interrupted the matca championship, things got ugly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0085</id>
    <name>Might of Alara</name>
    <text>Domain — Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The combined strength of all five planes spawned creations none had seen before.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0086</id>
    <name>Nacatl Savage</name>
    <text>Protection from artifacts</text>
    <flavorText>"Blades dull and armor dents. Marisi taught us that instinct is the only thing a true warrior needs."
—Ajani</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0087</id>
    <name>Noble Hierarch</name>
    <text>Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)
{T}: Add {G}, {W}, or {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>She protects the sacred groves from blight, drought, and the Unbeholden.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0088</id>
    <name>Paleoloth</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature with power 5 or greater enters the battlefield under your control, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Gods do not sleep soundly in the earth's embrace."
—Mayael the Anima</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0089</id>
    <name>Sacellum Archers</name>
    <text>{R}{W}, {T}: Sacellum Archers deals 2 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our arrows are aimed not at the sacred behemoths but at those who dare to dream of such a trophy."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0090</id>
    <name>Scattershot Archer</name>
    <text>{T}: Scattershot Archer deals 1 damage to each creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>To train her elves for war, Mayael would drop a sackful of acorns from the tree canopy. Each archer tried to split as many as possible before the acorns hit the forest floor below.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0091</id>
    <name>Shard Convergence</name>
    <text>Search your library for a Plains card, an Island card, a Swamp card, and a Mountain card. Reveal those cards and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Alara is broken no more.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0092</id>
    <name>Soul's Majesty</name>
    <text>Draw cards equal to the power of target creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>An avatar he sculpts of wisdom and strength.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0093</id>
    <name>Spore Burst</name>
    <text>Domain — Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield for each basic land type among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Seeds from Jund don't drift gently on the wind. They get up and stampede.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0094</id>
    <name>Sylvan Bounty</name>
    <text>Target player gains 8 life.
Basic landcycling {1}{G} ({1}{G}, Discard this card: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)</text>
    <flavorText>Some who scouted new lands chose to stay.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0095</id>
    <name>Thornling</name>
    <text>{G}: Thornling gains haste until end of turn.
{G}: Thornling gains trample until end of turn.
{G}: Thornling is indestructible this turn.
{1}: Thornling gets +1/-1 until end of turn.
{1}: Thornling gets -1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0096</id>
    <name>Tukatongue Thallid</name>
    <text>When Tukatongue Thallid is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Jund's thallids tried to disguise their deliciousness by covering themselves in spines harvested from the tukatongue tree.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0097</id>
    <name>Wild Leotau</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Wild Leotau unless you pay {G}.</text>
    <flavorText>"Leotau that were born wild make the best mounts. It's like riding a thunderstorm."
—Rafiq of the Many</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0098</id>
    <name>Apocalypse Hydra</name>
    <text>Apocalypse Hydra enters the battlefield with X +1/+1 counters on it. If X is 5 or more, it enters the battlefield with an additional X +1/+1 counters on it.
{1}{R}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Apocalypse Hydra: Apocalypse Hydra deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0099</id>
    <name>Blood Tyrant</name>
    <text>Flying, trample
At the beginning of your upkeep, each player loses 1 life. Put a +1/+1 counter on Blood Tyrant for each 1 life lost this way.
Whenever a player loses the game, put five +1/+1 counters on Blood Tyrant.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0100</id>
    <name>Charnelhoard Wurm</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Charnelhoard Wurm deals damage to an opponent, you may return target card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Jund's dragons hoard only sangrite crystals. Its wurms aren't so picky.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0101</id>
    <name>Child of Alara</name>
    <text>Trample
When Child of Alara is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, destroy all nonland permanents. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>The progeny of the Maelstrom shows no allegiance—and no mercy—to any of the five shards.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0102</id>
    <name>Conflux</name>
    <text>Search your library for a white card, a blue card, a black card, a red card, and a green card. Reveal those cards and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>After years of world-bending machinations, Bolas's triumph is at hand.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0103</id>
    <name>Countersquall</name>
    <text>Counter target noncreature spell. Its controller loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Each of the twenty-three winds of Esper is named and chronicled, and every possible interaction with the flow of magic is exhaustively detailed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0104</id>
    <name>Elder Mastery</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3 and has flying.
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage to a player, that player discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Taste his power, hunger for his command.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0105</id>
    <name>Esper Cormorants</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"The smiths of this land must be mad to reach so far and so high for another creature to decorate."
—Cagen Vargan, Jhessian sea scout</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0106</id>
    <name>Exploding Borders</name>
    <text>Domain — Search your library for a basic land card, put that card onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle your library. Exploding Borders deals X damage to target player, where X is the number of basic land types among lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Reuniting a world is not a gentle process.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0107</id>
    <name>Fusion Elemental</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>As the shards merged into the Maelstrom, their mana energies fused into new monstrosities.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0108</id>
    <name>Giltspire Avenger</name>
    <text>Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)
{T}: Destroy target creature that dealt damage to you this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"To trespass so far from home is to ask for a lonesome grave."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0109</id>
    <name>Goblin Outlander</name>
    <text>Protection from white</text>
    <flavorText>Egbol stared in wonder at Naya's landscape. So much to eat. So much to steal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0110</id>
    <name>Gwafa Hazid, Profiteer</name>
    <text>{W}{U}, {T}: Put a bribery counter on target creature you don't control. Its controller draws a card.
Creatures with bribery counters on them can't attack or block.</text>
    <flavorText>"Everyone has a price."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0111</id>
    <name>Hellkite Hatchling</name>
    <text>Devour 1 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with that many +1/+1 counters on it.)
Hellkite Hatchling has flying and trample if it devoured a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>A killing machine from birth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0112</id>
    <name>Jhessian Balmgiver</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.
{T}: Target creature is unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"You have two choices: heed my advice now or need my healing later."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0113</id>
    <name>Knight of the Reliquary</name>
    <text>Knight of the Reliquary gets +1/+1 for each land card in your graveyard.
{T}, Sacrifice a Forest or Plains: Search your library for a land card, put it onto the battlefield, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Knowledge of Bant's landscape and ruins is a weapon that the invaders can't comprehend."
—Elspeth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0114</id>
    <name>Knotvine Mystic</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Add {R}{G}{W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The elves of Naya were the last to acknowledge the massive shift of mana in their world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0115</id>
    <name>Maelstrom Archangel</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Maelstrom Archangel deals combat damage to a player, you may cast a nonland card from your hand without paying its mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>There is no world where angels fear to tread.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0116</id>
    <name>Magister Sphinx</name>
    <text>Flying
When Magister Sphinx enters the battlefield, target player's life total becomes 10.</text>
    <flavorText>"These benighted worlds are thick with ignorance. I will educate them. They will listen, or they will die."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0117</id>
    <name>Malfegor</name>
    <text>Flying
When Malfegor enters the battlefield, discard your hand. Each opponent sacrifices a creature for each card discarded this way.</text>
    <flavorText>A demon cannot be trusted, and a dragon will not be ruled.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0118</id>
    <name>Meglonoth</name>
    <text>Vigilance, trample
Whenever Meglonoth blocks a creature, Meglonoth deals damage to that creature's controller equal to Meglonoth's power.</text>
    <flavorText>When the shards merged, Mayael found herself the general of Naya's mightiest army.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0119</id>
    <name>Nacatl Outlander</name>
    <text>Protection from blue</text>
    <flavorText>Survival in the wilds of Naya left Tiyan well equipped to win the civilized battles of Bant.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0120</id>
    <name>Nicol Bolas, Planeswalker</name>
    <text>+3: Destroy target noncreature permanent.
-2: Gain control of target creature.
-9: Nicol Bolas, Planeswalker deals 7 damage to target player. That player discards seven cards, then sacrifices seven permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0121</id>
    <name>Progenitus</name>
    <text>Protection from everything
If Progenitus would be put into a graveyard from anywhere, reveal Progenitus and shuffle it into its owner's library instead.</text>
    <flavorText>The Soul of the World has returned.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0122</id>
    <name>Rhox Bodyguard</name>
    <text>Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)
When Rhox Bodyguard enters the battlefield, you gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>An enlightened soul caged in a body made for battle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0123</id>
    <name>Scarland Thrinax</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: Put a +1/+1 counter on Scarland Thrinax.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is only one way of life in Jund: feed on the weak until you are cut down by something stronger."
—Jorshu of Clan Nel Toth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0124</id>
    <name>Shambling Remains</name>
    <text>Shambling Remains can't block.
Unearth {B}{R} ({B}{R}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0125</id>
    <name>Skyward Eye Prophets</name>
    <text>Vigilance
{T}: Reveal the top card of your library. If it's a land card, put it onto the battlefield. Otherwise, put it into your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>They lament the doom that is coming to Bant without realizing the part their own leaders have played in it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0126</id>
    <name>Sludge Strider</name>
    <text>Whenever another artifact enters the battlefield under your control or another artifact you control leaves the battlefield, you may pay {1}. If you do, target player loses 1 life and you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Underneath the cities of Esper are cycles of life unseen by those who feed them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0127</id>
    <name>Sphinx Summoner</name>
    <text>Flying
When Sphinx Summoner enters the battlefield, you may search your library for an artifact creature card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0128</id>
    <name>Suicidal Charge</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Suicidal Charge: Creatures your opponents control get -1/-1 until end of turn. Those creatures attack this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>"They think they're winning. But they're just lining up to be dinner."
—Rakka Mar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0129</id>
    <name>Vagrant Plowbeasts</name>
    <text>{1}: Regenerate target creature with power 5 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>Plowbeasts of Naya escaped their harnesses in droves, content to snack on the conveniently cultivated fields of Eos and Valeron.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0130</id>
    <name>Valeron Outlander</name>
    <text>Protection from black</text>
    <flavorText>After years of honing her philosophy in debate with stubborn rhoxes, Niella was ready to convert any heathen.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0131</id>
    <name>Vectis Agents</name>
    <text>{U}{B}: Vectis Agents gets -2/-0 until end of turn and is unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>With their life energy suppressed under their etherium enhancements, thieves from Esper found it surprisingly easy to explore the ruins of Grixis.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0132</id>
    <name>Vedalken Outlander</name>
    <text>Protection from red</text>
    <flavorText>The Seekers of Carmot searched across the unknown lands for the mystical red stone that could reforge Esper in ethereal perfection.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0133</id>
    <name>Zombie Outlander</name>
    <text>Protection from green</text>
    <flavorText>The ripe smell of life drifted into Grixis. The dead caught the scent and with reckless hunger followed it back into Jund.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0134</id>
    <name>Armillary Sphere</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Armillary Sphere: Search your library for up to two basic land cards, reveal them, and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The mysterious purpose of two of the rings had eluded Esper mages—until now.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0135</id>
    <name>Bone Saw</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +1/+0.
Equip {1} ({1}: Attach to target creature you control. Equip only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>In a world where death is always violent, cruel weapons are as common as rocks.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0136</id>
    <name>Font of Mythos</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's draw step, that player draws two additional cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Those who drink from Malfegor's cup are tainted with hunger and stained with lies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0137</id>
    <name>Kaleidostone</name>
    <text>When Kaleidostone enters the battlefield, draw a card.
{5}, {T}, Sacrifice Kaleidostone: Add {W}{U}{B}{R}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Once broken, who knows what worlds might grow from its shards?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0138</id>
    <name>Mana Cylix</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Those who dismiss the cylix as an ordinary wooden bowl are blind to the true measure of its worth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0139</id>
    <name>Manaforce Mace</name>
    <text>Domain — Equipped creature gets +1/+1 for each basic land type among lands you control.
Equip {3}</text>
    <flavorText>As the shards merged, relics once thought mundane regained forgotten powers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0140</id>
    <name>Obelisk of Alara</name>
    <text>{1}{W}, {T}: You gain 5 life.
{1}{U}, {T}: Draw a card, then discard a card.
{1}{B}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn.
{1}{R}, {T}: Obelisk of Alara deals 3 damage to target player.
{1}{G}, {T}: Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0141</id>
    <name>Ancient Ziggurat</name>
    <text>{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast creature spells.</text>
    <flavorText>Built in honor of Alara's creatures, the ziggurat vanished long ago. When Progenitus awakened, the temple emerged again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0142</id>
    <name>Exotic Orchard</name>
    <text>{T}: Add to your mana pool one mana of any color that a land an opponent controls could produce.</text>
    <flavorText>"It was a strange morning. When we awoke, we found our trees transformed. We didn't know whether to water them or polish them."
—Pulan, Bant orchardist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0143</id>
    <name>Reliquary Tower</name>
    <text>You have no maximum hand size.
{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>When the aven scouts located the tower in Esper, the Knights of the Reliquary set off on a righteous crusade to recover their lost treasures.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0144</id>
    <name>Rupture Spire</name>
    <text>Rupture Spire enters the battlefield tapped.
When Rupture Spire enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you pay {1}.
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>CFX0145</id>
    <name>Unstable Frontier</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Target land you control becomes the basic land type of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The goblins went to sleep in Jund and awoke in Grixis. They'd never seen a zombie before. They would never see one again.</flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>