<cards name="Dissension">
  <item>
    <id>DIS0001</id>
    <name>Aurora Eidolon</name>
    <text>{W}, Sacrifice Aurora Eidolon: Prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.
Whenever you cast a multicolored spell, you may return Aurora Eidolon from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0002</id>
    <name>Azorius Herald</name>
    <text>Azorius Herald is unblockable.
When Azorius Herald enters the battlefield, you gain 4 life.
When Azorius Herald enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless {U} was spent to cast it.</text>
    <flavorText>"As peace should be—gentle yet unstoppable."
—Augustin IV</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0003</id>
    <name>Beacon Hawk</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Beacon Hawk deals combat damage to a player, you may untap target creature.
{W}: Beacon Hawk gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0004</id>
    <name>Blessing of the Nephilim</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 for each of its colors.</text>
    <flavorText>"Before the first stone was laid or the first elf-child born, the power of the nephilim was gathering. Let that power be spread by my hands."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0005</id>
    <name>Brace for Impact</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt to target multicolored creature this turn. For each 1 damage prevented this way, put a +1/+1 counter on that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Flesh can be tempered by spellcraft and forged ever stronger by the hammers of foes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0006</id>
    <name>Carom</name>
    <text>The next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn is dealt to another target creature instead.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Her enemy's strength is her own.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0007</id>
    <name>Celestial Ancient</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever you cast an enchantment spell, put a +1/+1 counter on each creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"We thought the clouds had moved from the night sky. Then the night sky moved, and the horizon grew wings."
—Josuri</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0008</id>
    <name>Condemn</name>
    <text>Put target attacking creature on the bottom of its owner's library. Its controller gains life equal to its toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>"No doubt the arbiters would put you away, after all the documents are signed. But I will have justice now"
—Alovnek, Boros guildmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0009</id>
    <name>Freewind Equenaut</name>
    <text>Flying
As long as Freewind Equenaut is enchanted, it has "{T}: Freewind Equenaut deals 2 damage to target attacking or blocking creature."</text>
    <flavorText>Confront her, and feel the hooves of her steed. Ignore her, and feel the sting of her arrow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0010</id>
    <name>Guardian of the Guildpact</name>
    <text>Protection from monocolored</text>
    <flavorText>The magic of the Guildpact gives aegis to the spirits pressed into its service. Upon entering the afterlife, they find new focus and are charged with defending the Guildpact against those who would see it broken.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0011</id>
    <name>Haazda Exonerator</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Haazda Exonerator: Destroy target Aura.</text>
    <flavorText>"This aura threatens the sanctity of your soul. Wrenching it free won't be easy on either of us. If you're ready, we'll begin."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0012</id>
    <name>Haazda Shield Mate</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Haazda Shield Mate unless you pay {W}{W}.
{W}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>The Haazda shield is broad, protecting both the free and the guilded.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0013</id>
    <name>Mistral Charger</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Some sky steeds break from the thundering herd to ride free on the open winds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0014</id>
    <name>Paladin of Prahv</name>
    <text>Whenever Paladin of Prahv deals damage, you gain that much life.
Forecast — {1}{W}, Reveal Paladin of Prahv from your hand: Whenever target creature deals damage this turn, you gain that much life. (Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only once each turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0015</id>
    <name>Proclamation of Rebirth</name>
    <text>Return up to three target creature cards with converted mana cost 1 or less from your graveyard to the battlefield.
Forecast — {5}{W}, Reveal Proclamation of Rebirth from your hand: Return target creature card with converted mana cost 1 or less from your graveyard to the battlefield. (Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only once each turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0016</id>
    <name>Proper Burial</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you gain life equal to that creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>Properly honored dead gain the peace of the grave and freedom from the call of the Ghost Quarter.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0017</id>
    <name>Soulsworn Jury</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{1}{U}, Sacrifice Soulsworn Jury: Counter target creature spell.</text>
    <flavorText>In death, as in life, they protect the Grand Arbiter from exposure to contrary points of view.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0018</id>
    <name>Steeling Stance</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn.
Forecast — {W}, Reveal Steeling Stance from your hand: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn. (Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only once each turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0019</id>
    <name>Stoic Ephemera</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Flying
When Stoic Ephemera blocks, sacrifice it at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"Life is fleeting, and so is death. Only the oath is eternal."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0020</id>
    <name>Valor Made Real</name>
    <text>Target creature can block any number of creatures this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"As my father taught, ‘Training will raise your shield to the blow, but courage fills the gaps the shield leaves open.'"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0021</id>
    <name>Wakestone Gargoyle</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Flying
{1}{W}: Creatures you control with defender can attack this turn as though they didn't have defender.</text>
    <flavorText>Its pulsating cry shatters bonds of iron, granite, and servitude.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0022</id>
    <name>Court Hussar</name>
    <text>Vigilance
When Court Hussar enters the battlefield, look at the top three cards of your library, then put one of them into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.
When Court Hussar enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless {W} was spent to cast it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0023</id>
    <name>Cytoplast Manipulator</name>
    <text>Graft 2 (This creature enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)
{U}, {T}: Gain control of target creature with a +1/+1 counter on it for as long as Cytoplast Manipulator remains on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0024</id>
    <name>Enigma Eidolon</name>
    <text>{U}, Sacrifice Enigma Eidolon: Target player puts the top three cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.
Whenever you cast a multicolored spell, you may return Enigma Eidolon from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0025</id>
    <name>Govern the Guildless</name>
    <text>Gain control of target monocolored creature.
Forecast — {1}{U}, Reveal Govern the Guildless from your hand: Target creature becomes the color or colors of your choice until end of turn. (Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only once each turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0026</id>
    <name>Helium Squirter</name>
    <text>Graft 3 (This creature enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)
{1}: Target creature with a +1/+1 counter on it gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0027</id>
    <name>Novijen Sages</name>
    <text>Graft 4 (This creature enters the battlefield with four +1/+1 counters on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)
{1}, Remove two +1/+1 counters from among creatures you control: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0028</id>
    <name>Ocular Halo</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has "{T}: Draw a card."
{W}: Enchanted creature gains vigilance until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>While the soldier dreams, the eyes stand watch.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0029</id>
    <name>Plaxmanta</name>
    <text>Flash
When Plaxmanta enters the battlefield, creatures you control gain shroud until end of turn. (They can't be the targets of spells or abilities.)
When Plaxmanta enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless {G} was spent to cast it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0030</id>
    <name>Psychic Possession</name>
    <text>Enchant opponent
Skip your draw step.
Whenever enchanted opponent draws a card, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"You will do the thinking for the both of us"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0031</id>
    <name>Silkwing Scout</name>
    <text>Flying
{G}, Sacrifice Silkwing Scout: Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0032</id>
    <name>Skyscribing</name>
    <text>Each player draws X cards.
Forecast — {2}{U}, Reveal Skyscribing from your hand: Each player draws a card. (Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only once each turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0033</id>
    <name>Spell Snare</name>
    <text>Counter target spell with converted mana cost 2.</text>
    <flavorText>Every culture has its unlucky numbers. In a city where you're either alone, in a crowd, or being stabbed in the back, two is the worst number of all.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0034</id>
    <name>Tidespout Tyrant</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever you cast a spell, return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>He unmakes the world in his own image.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0035</id>
    <name>Vigean Graftmage</name>
    <text>Graft 2 (This creature enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)
{1}{U}: Untap target creature with a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0036</id>
    <name>Vision Skeins</name>
    <text>Each player draws two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"I could see in the other mage's eyes that he'd thought of it too. Then it became a race to exploit the knowledge first."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0037</id>
    <name>Writ of Passage</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature attacks, if its power is 2 or less, it's unblockable this turn.
Forecast — {1}{U}, Reveal Writ of Passage from your hand: Target creature with power 2 or less is unblockable this turn. (Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only once each turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0038</id>
    <name>Bond of Agony</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Bond of Agony, pay X life.
Each other player loses X life.</text>
    <flavorText>The Rakdos are unique in designing torture equipment they can operate while "suffering" alongside their victims.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0039</id>
    <name>Brain Pry</name>
    <text>Name a nonland card. Target player reveals his or her hand. That player discards a card with that name. If he or she can't, you draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>To the Rakdos, the fun is in the shakedown. The loot is usually discarded.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0040</id>
    <name>Crypt Champion</name>
    <text>Double strike
When Crypt Champion enters the battlefield, each player puts a creature card with converted mana cost 3 or less from his or her graveyard onto the battlefield.
When Crypt Champion enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless {R} was spent to cast it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0041</id>
    <name>Delirium Skeins</name>
    <text>Each player discards three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>There came a rush, a sudden fire in the mind. Then the two saw only the sooty fog of madness, heard only the crackling of their last thoughts burning away.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0042</id>
    <name>Demon's Jester</name>
    <text>Flying
Hellbent — Demon's Jester gets +2/+1 as long as you have no cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>They knock 'em dead, with or without the punch line.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0043</id>
    <name>Drekavac</name>
    <text>When Drekavac enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you discard a noncreature card.</text>
    <flavorText>Like a vulture's scalp, the face of a drekavac is oily and hairless. The filth and disease of its carrion diet slip off its blood-slick skin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0044</id>
    <name>Enemy of the Guildpact</name>
    <text>Protection from multicolored</text>
    <flavorText>Guilds often exterminate those who saw or knew too much. Some vindictive souls retain their knowledge, using it in the afterlife to crush the guilded and the vile bargain that gives them power.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0045</id>
    <name>Entropic Eidolon</name>
    <text>{B}, Sacrifice Entropic Eidolon: Target player loses 1 life and you gain 1 life.
Whenever you cast a multicolored spell, you may return Entropic Eidolon from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0046</id>
    <name>Infernal Tutor</name>
    <text>Reveal a card from your hand. Search your library for a card with the same name as that card, reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library.
Hellbent — If you have no cards in hand, instead search your library for a card, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0047</id>
    <name>Macabre Waltz</name>
    <text>Return up to two target creature cards from your graveyard to your hand, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"All dead move to the hollow rhythm of necromancy."
—Savra</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0048</id>
    <name>Nettling Curse</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature attacks or blocks, its controller loses 3 life.
{1}{R}: Enchanted creature attacks this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>"I call them ‘Poke' and ‘Prod.'"
—Chagrach, Rakdos cursemage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0049</id>
    <name>Nightcreep</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, all creatures become black and all lands become Swamps.</text>
    <flavorText>"Please tell me I'm hallucinating. I'd rather be crazy than here."
—Gorev Hadszak, Wojek investigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0050</id>
    <name>Nihilistic Glee</name>
    <text>{2}{B}, Discard a card: Target opponent loses 1 life and you gain 1 life.
Hellbent — {1}, Pay 2 life: Draw a card. Activate this ability only if you have no cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"All ends in obliteration—love in hatred, life in death, and light in empty darkness."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0051</id>
    <name>Ragamuffyn</name>
    <text>Hellbent — {T}, Sacrifice a creature or land: Draw a card. Activate this ability only if you have no cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>They cut the stitches and give her sips of her brew. Then they sew her up again, and she's back to stirring.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0052</id>
    <name>Ratcatcher</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may search your library for a Rat card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>An ogre's poisonous stench is like fine Kashkaval cheese to the noses lowest to the ground.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0053</id>
    <name>Seal of Doom</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Seal of Doom: Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"A basilisk's gaze is effective, but disposing of physical remains is a tiresome task. It's far more discrete to dissolve one's victim entirely."
—Szadek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0054</id>
    <name>Slaughterhouse Bouncer</name>
    <text>Hellbent — When Slaughterhouse Bouncer is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if you have no cards in hand, target creature gets -3/-3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A Rakdos party is a flop if anyone lives to talk about it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0055</id>
    <name>Slithering Shade</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{B}: Slithering Shade gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
Hellbent — Slithering Shade can attack as though it didn't have defender as long as you have no cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0056</id>
    <name>Unliving Psychopath</name>
    <text>{B}: Unliving Psychopath gets +1/-1 until end of turn.
{B}, {T}: Destroy target creature with power less than Unliving Psychopath's power.</text>
    <flavorText>"The victim bears the marks of the ‘Ktozok Impaler'. . . but he was executed years ago"
—Gorev Hadszak, Wojek investigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0057</id>
    <name>Vesper Ghoul</name>
    <text>{T}, Pay 1 life: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Nature's exceptions remind us not to think in absolutes. Just as the orchid blossoms on blackened stone, so does the gift of mana occasionally manifest in the undead."
—Bougrat, druid of the Cult of Yore</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0058</id>
    <name>Wit's End</name>
    <text>Target player discards his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Some images are so powerful that one glance burns them into your mind forever. Come, let us gaze on nothingness."
—Szadek</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0059</id>
    <name>Cackling Flames</name>
    <text>Cackling Flames deals 3 damage to target creature or player.
Hellbent — Cackling Flames deals 5 damage to that creature or player instead if you have no cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"I like a little entertainment with my dinner."
—Rakdos</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0060</id>
    <name>Demonfire</name>
    <text>Demonfire deals X damage to target creature or player. If a creature dealt damage this way would be put into a graveyard this turn, exile it instead.
Hellbent — If you have no cards in hand, Demonfire can't be countered by spells or abilities and the damage can't be prevented.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0061</id>
    <name>Flame-Kin War Scout</name>
    <text>When another creature enters the battlefield, sacrifice Flame-Kin War Scout. If you do, Flame-Kin War Scout deals 4 damage to that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The forward flame-kin are popping. We have incoming"
—Svar, Boros signaler</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0062</id>
    <name>Flaring Flame-Kin</name>
    <text>As long as Flaring Flame-Kin is enchanted, it gets +2/+2, has trample, and has "{R}: Flaring Flame-Kin gets +1/+0 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>A flame-kin is always formidable, but feeding its fire with a sorcerous gift grants it the power to devastate armies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0063</id>
    <name>Gnat Alley Creeper</name>
    <text>Gnat Alley Creeper can't be blocked by creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Despite its diminutive name, Gnat Alley is the longest street in Ravnica. Mile after twisting mile, it threads its way among the broader, safer thoroughfares like a parasite.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0064</id>
    <name>Ignorant Bliss</name>
    <text>Exile all cards from your hand face down. At the beginning of the next end step, return those cards to your hand, then draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"A quick step beyond oblivion lies a place so full of thoughts that it leaves no room for your own."
—Quyzl, chronarch prodigy</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0065</id>
    <name>Kill-Suit Cultist</name>
    <text>Kill-Suit Cultist attacks each turn if able.
{B}, Sacrifice Kill-Suit Cultist: The next time damage would be dealt to target creature this turn, destroy that creature instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Dressed to kill.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0066</id>
    <name>Kindle the Carnage</name>
    <text>Discard a card at random. If you do, Kindle the Carnage deals damage equal to that card's converted mana cost to each creature. You may repeat this process any number of times.</text>
    <flavorText>"Start knockin' heads, boys, and don't stop 'til the ragamuffyn sings"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0067</id>
    <name>Ogre Gatecrasher</name>
    <text>When Ogre Gatecrasher enters the battlefield, destroy target creature with defender.</text>
    <flavorText>A popular game among ogres is to see how many revolutions a head can make before it pops off.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0068</id>
    <name>Psychotic Fury</name>
    <text>Target multicolored creature gains double strike until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Rage, my servants. Our ancient power is renewed in blood."
—Rakdos</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0069</id>
    <name>Rakdos Pit Dragon</name>
    <text>{R}{R}: Rakdos Pit Dragon gains flying until end of turn.
{R}: Rakdos Pit Dragon gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
Hellbent — Rakdos Pit Dragon has double strike as long as you have no cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0070</id>
    <name>Sandstorm Eidolon</name>
    <text>{R}, Sacrifice Sandstorm Eidolon: Target creature can't block this turn.
Whenever you cast a multicolored spell, you may return Sandstorm Eidolon from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0071</id>
    <name>Seal of Fire</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Seal of Fire: Seal of Fire deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"If it breathes, it will burn."
—Rakdos pyromancers' creed</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0072</id>
    <name>Squealing Devil</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
When Squealing Devil enters the battlefield, you may pay {X}. If you do, target creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn.
When Squealing Devil enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless {B} was spent to cast it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0073</id>
    <name>Stalking Vengeance</name>
    <text>Haste
Whenever another creature you control is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, it deals damage equal to its power to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Something roams the killing places, sniffing the guilt of the slayers, stalking them on iron paws.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0074</id>
    <name>Stormscale Anarch</name>
    <text>{2}{R}, Discard a card at random: Stormscale Anarch deals 2 damage to target creature or player. If the discarded card was multicolored, Stormscale Anarch deals 4 damage to that creature or player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0075</id>
    <name>Taste for Mayhem</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+0.
Hellbent — Enchanted creature gets an additional +2/+0 as long as you have no cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The taste of blood breaks down what little self-control the Rakdos possess.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0076</id>
    <name>Utvara Scalper</name>
    <text>Flying
Utvara Scalper attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>He wages war wherever the wind carries him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0077</id>
    <name>War's Toll</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent taps a land for mana, tap all lands that player controls.
If a creature an opponent controls attacks, all creatures that opponent controls attack if able.</text>
    <flavorText>Razia, archangel of war, demands total commitment.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0078</id>
    <name>Weight of Spires</name>
    <text>Weight of Spires deals damage to target creature equal to the number of nonbasic lands that creature's controller controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"Finally, a good use for an Azorius courthouse."
—Ghut Rak, Gruul guildmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0079</id>
    <name>Whiptail Moloch</name>
    <text>When Whiptail Moloch enters the battlefield, it deals 3 damage to target creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"It wags its tail when it's happy. It wags its tail when it's angry. Nope, there's no good time to be around a whiptail."
—Rugar, Leaguehall Infirmary patient</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0080</id>
    <name>Aquastrand Spider</name>
    <text>Graft 2 (This creature enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)
{G}: Target creature with a +1/+1 counter on it gains reach until end of turn. (It can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0081</id>
    <name>Cytoplast Root-Kin</name>
    <text>Graft 4 (This creature enters the battlefield with four +1/+1 counters on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)
When Cytoplast Root-Kin enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on each other creature you control that has a +1/+1 counter on it.
{2}: Move a +1/+1 counter from target creature you control onto Cytoplast Root-Kin.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0082</id>
    <name>Cytospawn Shambler</name>
    <text>Graft 6 (This creature enters the battlefield with six +1/+1 counters on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)
{G}: Target creature with a +1/+1 counter on it gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0083</id>
    <name>Elemental Resonance</name>
    <text>Enchant permanent
At the beginning of your precombat main phase, add mana equal to enchanted permanent's mana cost to your mana pool. (Mana cost includes color. If a mana symbol has multiple colors, choose one.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0084</id>
    <name>Fertile Imagination</name>
    <text>Choose a card type. Target opponent reveals his or her hand. Put two 1/1 green Saproling creature tokens onto the battlefield for each card of the chosen type revealed this way. (The card types are artifact, creature, enchantment, instant, land, planeswalker, sorcery, and tribal.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0085</id>
    <name>Flash Foliage</name>
    <text>Cast Flash Foliage only during combat after blockers are declared.
Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield blocking target creature attacking you.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"This undemanding vegetation takes root in a mote of dust but grows incredibly quickly."
—Simic research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0086</id>
    <name>Indrik Stomphowler</name>
    <text>When Indrik Stomphowler enters the battlefield, destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"An indrik's howl has destructive power much subtler than that of its crushing foot. The sound is mundane, but inaudible vibrations scatter and sunder magical contrivances."
—Simic research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0087</id>
    <name>Loaming Shaman</name>
    <text>When Loaming Shaman enters the battlefield, target player shuffles any number of target cards from his or her graveyard into his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>His work determines who is remembered and who feeds the worms.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0088</id>
    <name>Might of the Nephilim</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn for each of its colors.</text>
    <flavorText>"Send a runner to Tin Street, and tell 'em the delivery has been . . . uh . . . held up."
—Bonmod, caravan rear guard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0089</id>
    <name>Patagia Viper</name>
    <text>Flying
When Patagia Viper enters the battlefield, put two 1/1 green and blue Snake creature tokens onto the battlefield.
When Patagia Viper enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless {U} was spent to cast it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0090</id>
    <name>Protean Hulk</name>
    <text>When Protean Hulk is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, search your library for any number of creature cards with total converted mana cost 6 or less and put them onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Meat and eggs. We eat"
—Borborygmos</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0091</id>
    <name>Simic Basilisk</name>
    <text>Graft 3 (This creature enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)
{1}{G}: Until end of turn, target creature with a +1/+1 counter on it gains "Whenever this creature deals combat damage to a creature, destroy that creature at end of combat."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0092</id>
    <name>Simic Initiate</name>
    <text>Graft 1 (This creature enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)</text>
    <flavorText>Simic initiates begin their training as experimental subjects. Failures are flushed to the undersewers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0093</id>
    <name>Simic Ragworm</name>
    <text>{U}: Untap Simic Ragworm.</text>
    <flavorText>"Infused with autochthon blood for size and hellion cells for speed, the ragworm is perfect for clearing the undergardens of both rats and vagrants."
—Yolov, Simic bioengineer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0094</id>
    <name>Sporeback Troll</name>
    <text>Graft 2 (This creature enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)
{1}{G}: Regenerate target creature with a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0095</id>
    <name>Sprouting Phytohydra</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Whenever Sprouting Phytohydra is dealt damage, you may put a token that's a copy of Sprouting Phytohydra onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>A hydra tender's problem isn't having enough defenses but enough pots.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0096</id>
    <name>Stomp and Howl</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact and target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mizzium may be impervious to fire, but obviously certain other things can . . . modify its form."
—Ivos Koba, indrik handler</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0097</id>
    <name>Street Savvy</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +0/+2 and can block creatures with landwalk abilities as though they didn't have those abilities.</text>
    <flavorText>"It takes more than swift feet and dark shadows to slip by me unnoticed."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0098</id>
    <name>Thrive</name>
    <text>Put a +1/+1 counter on each of X target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>The most successful of Simic creations is cytoplasm, a living, symbiotic substance that feeds off genetic rhythms and strengthens its host in return.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0099</id>
    <name>Utopia Sprawl</name>
    <text>Enchant Forest
As Utopia Sprawl enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Whenever enchanted Forest is tapped for mana, its controller adds one mana of the chosen color to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0100</id>
    <name>Verdant Eidolon</name>
    <text>{G}, Sacrifice Verdant Eidolon: Add three mana of any one color to your mana pool.
Whenever you cast a multicolored spell, you may return Verdant Eidolon from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0101</id>
    <name>Æthermage's Touch</name>
    <text>Reveal the top four cards of your library. You may put a creature card from among them onto the battlefield. It has "At the beginning of your end step, return this creature to its owner's hand." Then put the rest of the cards revealed this way on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0102</id>
    <name>Anthem of Rakdos</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control attacks, it gets +2/+0 until end of turn and Anthem of Rakdos deals 1 damage to you.
Hellbent — As long as you have no cards in hand, if a source you control would deal damage to a creature or player, it deals double that damage to that creature or player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0103</id>
    <name>Assault Zeppelid</name>
    <text>Flying, trample</text>
    <flavorText>"Show them to Razia and then to the Azorius sky marshals. We could create a fine bidding war—enough to fund the final stages of Project Kraj."
—Momir Vig</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0104</id>
    <name>Azorius Æthermage</name>
    <text>Whenever a permanent is returned to your hand, you may pay {1}. If you do, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>In her single metasphere are bound the records of every Ætheric transaction since the time of Azor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0105</id>
    <name>Azorius First-Wing</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from enchantments</text>
    <flavorText>With a steady diet of lawbreakers, Azorius griffins inevitably develop a resistance to the contraband magic that taints much of their prey.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0106</id>
    <name>Azorius Ploy</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage target creature would deal this turn.
Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Azorius military tactics, like their legal tactics, capitalize on delay and nullification.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0107</id>
    <name>Coiling Oracle</name>
    <text>When Coiling Oracle enters the battlefield, reveal the top card of your library. If it's a land card, put it onto the battlefield. Otherwise, put that card into your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Snaking remnants of nature directed by a body of thought and progress, the oracles embody all that is Simic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0108</id>
    <name>Cytoshape</name>
    <text>Choose a nonlegendary creature on the battlefield. Target creature becomes a copy of that creature until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Though highly effective at reshaping flesh, these specially bred cytoplasts leave the subject reeking of omnibian mucus."
—Simic research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0109</id>
    <name>Dread Slag</name>
    <text>Trample
Dread Slag gets -4/-4 for each card in your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>A thousand phobias sopped from the city and wrung from Rix Maadi as one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0110</id>
    <name>Experiment Kraj</name>
    <text>Experiment Kraj has all activated abilities of each other creature with a +1/+1 counter on it.
{T}: Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Of course it will grow beyond control—it was designed to choose its own evolution."
—Momir Vig</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0111</id>
    <name>Gobhobbler Rats</name>
    <text>Hellbent — As long as you have no cards in hand, Gobhobbler Rats gets +1/+0 and has "{B}: Regenerate Gobhobbler Rats."</text>
    <flavorText>Lyzolda's pet rats eat better than the average citizen. In fact, they can usually be found eating the average citizen.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0112</id>
    <name>Grand Arbiter Augustin IV</name>
    <text>White spells you cast cost {1} less to cast.
Blue spells you cast cost {1} less to cast.
Spells your opponents cast cost {1} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>The Arbiter is a conduit of justice, a will so disciplined that it dispenses justice without ego or remorse.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0113</id>
    <name>Hellhole Rats</name>
    <text>Haste
When Hellhole Rats enters the battlefield, target player discards a card. Hellhole Rats deals damage to that player equal to that card's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"I must speak with Momir Vig about creating a water-spouting watchdog."
—Mathvan, Prahv scrollwarden</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0114</id>
    <name>Isperia the Inscrutable</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Isperia the Inscrutable deals combat damage to a player, name a card. That player reveals his or her hand. If he or she reveals the named card, search your library for a creature card with flying, reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0115</id>
    <name>Jagged Poppet</name>
    <text>Whenever Jagged Poppet is dealt damage, discard that many cards.
Hellbent — Whenever Jagged Poppet deals combat damage to a player, if you have no cards in hand, that player discards cards equal to the damage.</text>
    <flavorText>Few puppets are so willing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0116</id>
    <name>Leafdrake Roost</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Enchanted land has "{G}{U}, {T}: Put a 2/2 green and blue Drake creature token with flying onto the battlefield."</text>
    <flavorText>"The best experiments are those whose successes replicate themselves."
—Yolov, Simic bioengineer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0117</id>
    <name>Lyzolda, the Blood Witch</name>
    <text>{2}, Sacrifice a creature: Lyzolda, the Blood Witch deals 2 damage to target creature or player if the sacrificed creature was red. Draw a card if the sacrificed creature was black.</text>
    <flavorText>Sacrificial rites take place before an audience of cheering cultists, each begging to be the next on stage.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0118</id>
    <name>Momir Vig, Simic Visionary</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a green creature spell, you may search your library for a creature card and reveal it. If you do, shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.
Whenever you cast a blue creature spell, reveal the top card of your library. If it's a creature card, put that card into your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0119</id>
    <name>Omnibian</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature becomes a 3/3 Frog until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"This creature has hyperevolved chameleonic abilities. It no longer mimics its surroundings, instead forcing them to take on its form."
—Simic research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0120</id>
    <name>Overrule</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}. You gain X life.</text>
    <flavorText>With one commanding word, the spell was put down and a fine collected for its casting.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0121</id>
    <name>Pain Magnification</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent is dealt 3 or more damage by a single source, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The Rakdos make sure their victims remember their pain—or at least give up a little bit of their sanity in order to forget.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0122</id>
    <name>Palliation Accord</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature an opponent controls becomes tapped, put a shield counter on Palliation Accord.
Remove a shield counter from Palliation Accord: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to you this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0123</id>
    <name>Plaxcaster Frogling</name>
    <text>Graft 3 (This creature enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)
{2}: Target creature with a +1/+1 counter on it gains shroud until end of turn. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0124</id>
    <name>Plumes of Peace</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.
Forecast — {W}{U}, Reveal Plumes of Peace from your hand: Tap target creature. (Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only once each turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0125</id>
    <name>Pride of the Clouds</name>
    <text>Flying
Pride of the Clouds gets +1/+1 for each other creature with flying on the battlefield.
Forecast — {2}{W}{U}, Reveal Pride of the Clouds from your hand: Put a 1/1 white and blue Bird creature token with flying onto the battlefield. (Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only once each turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0126</id>
    <name>Rain of Gore</name>
    <text>If a spell or ability would cause its controller to gain life, that player loses that much life instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"Stay indoors, away from what seeps over the thresholds. This is the Demon's work, and only ill can come of it."
—Belko, owner of Titan's Keg tavern</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0127</id>
    <name>Rakdos Augermage</name>
    <text>First strike
{T}: Reveal your hand and discard a card of target opponent's choice. Then that player reveals his or her hand and discards a card of your choice. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>"Great minds bleed alike."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0128</id>
    <name>Rakdos Ickspitter</name>
    <text>{T}: Rakdos Ickspitter deals 1 damage to target creature and that creature's controller loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our thrulls dissolve from the inside out in a matter of days. Shoddy work, but they're a scream while they last."
—Uzric, Rakdos guildmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0129</id>
    <name>Rakdos the Defiler</name>
    <text>Flying, trample
Whenever Rakdos the Defiler attacks, sacrifice half the non-Demon permanents you control, rounded up.
Whenever Rakdos deals combat damage to a player, that player sacrifices half the non-Demon permanents he or she controls, rounded up.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0130</id>
    <name>Simic Sky Swallower</name>
    <text>Flying; trample; shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We've bred out the shortcomings of the species' natural form and replaced them with assets of our own design."
—Momir Vig</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0131</id>
    <name>Sky Hussar</name>
    <text>Flying
When Sky Hussar enters the battlefield, untap all creatures you control.
Forecast — Tap two untapped white and/or blue creatures you control, Reveal Sky Hussar from your hand: Draw a card. (Activate this ability only during your upkeep and only once each turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0132</id>
    <name>Swift Silence</name>
    <text>Counter all other spells. Draw a card for each spell countered this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"This world may not know peace, but in my presence you will know quiet."
—Augustin IV</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0133</id>
    <name>Trygon Predator</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Trygon Predator deals combat damage to a player, you may destroy target artifact or enchantment that player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Held aloft by metabolized magic, trygons are ravenous for sources of mystic fuel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0134</id>
    <name>Twinstrike</name>
    <text>Twinstrike deals 2 damage to each of two target creatures.
Hellbent — Destroy those creatures instead if you have no cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>They're dying left and right.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0135</id>
    <name>Vigean Hydropon</name>
    <text>Graft 5 (This creature enters the battlefield with five +1/+1 counters on it. Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may move a +1/+1 counter from this creature onto it.)
Vigean Hydropon can't attack or block.</text>
    <flavorText>Fruits of magic, roots in science.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0136</id>
    <name>Vigean Intuition</name>
    <text>Choose a card type, then reveal the top four cards of your library. Put all cards of the chosen type revealed this way into your hand and the rest into your graveyard. (The card types are artifact, creature, enchantment, instant, land, planeswalker, sorcery, and tribal.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0137</id>
    <name>Voidslime</name>
    <text>Counter target spell, activated ability, or triggered ability. (Mana abilities can't be targeted.)</text>
    <flavorText>"It is technically an ooze, but its lifespan measures only seconds. In that short time, its appetite for magic is extraordinary."
—Simic research notes</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0138</id>
    <name>Windreaver</name>
    <text>Flying
{W}: Windreaver gains vigilance until end of turn.
{W}: Windreaver gets +0/+1 until end of turn.
{U}: Switch Windreaver's power and toughness until end of turn.
{U}: Return Windreaver to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0139</id>
    <name>Wrecking Ball</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature or land.</text>
    <flavorText>Rakdos festivals almost leave enough rubble in their wake to hide the bodies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0140</id>
    <name>Avatar of Discord</name>
    <text>({BR} can be paid with either {B} or {R}.)
Flying
When Avatar of Discord enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you discard two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Such is the power of Rakdos that even his shadow takes on a cruel life of its own.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0141</id>
    <name>Azorius Guildmage</name>
    <text>({WU} can be paid with either {W} or {U}.)
{2}{W}: Tap target creature.
{2}{U}: Counter target activated ability. (Mana abilities can't be targeted.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0142</id>
    <name>Biomantic Mastery</name>
    <text>({GU} can be paid with either {G} or {U}.)
Draw a card for each creature target player controls, then draw a card for each creature another target player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"Look beyond, to the vascular awareness that all life is a map to greater knowledge."
—Momir Vig, Biomancy, vol. I</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0143</id>
    <name>Dovescape</name>
    <text>({WU} can be paid with either {W} or {U}.)
Whenever a player casts a noncreature spell, counter that spell. That player puts X 1/1 white and blue Bird creature tokens with flying onto the battlefield, where X is the spell's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0144</id>
    <name>Minister of Impediments</name>
    <text>({WU} can be paid with either {W} or {U}.)
{T}: Tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>When it takes forever to learn all the rules, no time is left for breaking them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0145</id>
    <name>Rakdos Guildmage</name>
    <text>({BR} can be paid with either {B} or {R}.)
{3}{B}, Discard a card: Target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn.
{3}{R}: Put a 2/1 red Goblin creature token with haste onto the battlefield. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0146</id>
    <name>Riot Spikes</name>
    <text>({BR} can be paid with either {B} or {R}.)
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>Most auramancers would have let the spikes hover just above the skin. Having the spikes rip through the skin from beneath was a touch added by Rakdos himself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0147</id>
    <name>Shielding Plax</name>
    <text>({GU} can be paid with either {G} or {U}.)
Enchant creature
When Shielding Plax enters the battlefield, draw a card.
Enchanted creature can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0148</id>
    <name>Simic Guildmage</name>
    <text>({GU} can be paid with either {G} or {U}.)
{1}{G}: Move a +1/+1 counter from target creature onto another target creature with the same controller.
{1}{U}: Attach target Aura enchanting a permanent to another permanent with the same controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0149</id>
    <name>Bound</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature. Return up to X cards from your graveyard to your hand, where X is the number of colors that creature was. Exile this card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0150</id>
    <name>Determined</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature. Return up to X cards from your graveyard to your hand, where X is the number of colors that creature was. Exile this card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0151</id>
    <name>Crime</name>
    <text>Destroy each artifact, creature, and enchantment with converted mana cost X.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0152</id>
    <name>Punishment</name>
    <text>Destroy each artifact, creature, and enchantment with converted mana cost X.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0153</id>
    <name>Hide</name>
    <text>Search target opponent's library for a card and exile it. You gain life equal to its converted mana cost. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0154</id>
    <name>Seek</name>
    <text>Search target opponent's library for a card and exile it. You gain life equal to its converted mana cost. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0155</id>
    <name>Hit</name>
    <text>Attacking creatures you control get +1/+0 until end of turn for each other attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0156</id>
    <name>Run</name>
    <text>Attacking creatures you control get +1/+0 until end of turn for each other attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0157</id>
    <name>Ends</name>
    <text>Target player sacrifices two attacking creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0158</id>
    <name>Odds</name>
    <text>Target player sacrifices two attacking creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0159</id>
    <name>Pure</name>
    <text>Destroy all Auras and Equipment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0160</id>
    <name>Simple</name>
    <text>Destroy all Auras and Equipment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0161</id>
    <name>Development</name>
    <text>Put a 3/1 red Elemental creature token onto the battlefield unless any opponent has you draw a card. Repeat this process two more times.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0162</id>
    <name>Research</name>
    <text>Put a 3/1 red Elemental creature token onto the battlefield unless any opponent has you draw a card. Repeat this process two more times.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0163</id>
    <name>Fall</name>
    <text>Target player reveals two cards at random from his or her hand, then discards each nonland card revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0164</id>
    <name>Rise</name>
    <text>Target player reveals two cards at random from his or her hand, then discards each nonland card revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0165</id>
    <name>Demand</name>
    <text>Search your library for a multicolored card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0166</id>
    <name>Supply</name>
    <text>Search your library for a multicolored card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0167</id>
    <name>Error</name>
    <text>Counter target multicolored spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0168</id>
    <name>Trial</name>
    <text>Counter target multicolored spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0169</id>
    <name>Azorius Signet</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Add {W}{U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The maze-like design embodies the core of Azorius law—strict structure designed to test wills and stall change.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0170</id>
    <name>Bronze Bombshell</name>
    <text>When a player other than Bronze Bombshell's owner controls it, that player sacrifices it. If the player does, Bronze Bombshell deals 7 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>"Ooh, shiny Let's pull off the chain and take her with us."
—Ukl, Gruul raider, last words</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0171</id>
    <name>Evolution Vat</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Tap target creature and put a +1/+1 counter on it. Until end of turn, that creature gains "{2}{G}{U}: Double the number of +1/+1 counters on this creature."</text>
    <flavorText>The vats are self-contained worlds, bubbling and churning with unnatural speed, boiling down eons of change into moments.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0172</id>
    <name>Magewright's Stone</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Untap target creature that has an activated ability with {T} in its cost.</text>
    <flavorText>The stones hark back to an age before civilization, when the living earth blessed all who trod its untamed wilds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0173</id>
    <name>Muse Vessel</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target player exiles a card from his or her hand. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.
{1}: Choose a card exiled with Muse Vessel. You may play that card this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0174</id>
    <name>Rakdos Riteknife</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +1/+0 for each blood counter on Rakdos Riteknife and has "{T}, Sacrifice a creature: Put a blood counter on Rakdos Riteknife."
{B}{R}, Sacrifice Rakdos Riteknife: Target player sacrifices a permanent for each blood counter on Rakdos Riteknife.
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0175</id>
    <name>Rakdos Signet</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Add {B}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Made of bone and boiled in blood, a Rakdos signet is not considered finished until it has been used as a murder weapon.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0176</id>
    <name>Simic Signet</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Add {G}{U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>For the Simic Combine, its sigil serves not as an emblem of honor but as a trademark. Its familiar image on any biological commodity attests to superb craftsmanship, ingenious innovation, and higher cost.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0177</id>
    <name>Skullmead Cauldron</name>
    <text>{T}: You gain 1 life.
{T}, Discard a card: You gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Once tasted, the flavor of skullmead lingers in the throat, a secret brand of guilt for those who partake in forbidden pleasures.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0178</id>
    <name>Transguild Courier</name>
    <text>Transguild Courier is all colors (even if this card isn't on the battlefield).</text>
    <flavorText>Reluctant to meet face to face, the leaders of the ten guilds prefer to do official business through a go-between immune to bribes and threats.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0179</id>
    <name>Walking Archive</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Walking Archive enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.
At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player draws a card for each +1/+1 counter on Walking Archive.
{2}{W}{U}: Put a +1/+1 counter on Walking Archive.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0180</id>
    <name>Azorius Chancery</name>
    <text>Azorius Chancery enters the battlefield tapped.
When Azorius Chancery enters the battlefield, return a land you control to its owner's hand.
{T}: Add {W}{U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0181</id>
    <name>Blood Crypt</name>
    <text>({T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool.)
As Blood Crypt enters the battlefield, you may pay 2 life. If you don't, Blood Crypt enters the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0182</id>
    <name>Breeding Pool</name>
    <text>({T}: Add {G} or {U} to your mana pool.)
As Breeding Pool enters the battlefield, you may pay 2 life. If you don't, Breeding Pool enters the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0183</id>
    <name>Ghost Quarter</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice Ghost Quarter: Destroy target land. Its controller may search his or her library for a basic land card, put it onto the battlefield, then shuffle his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>Where wasted life cries out to be reborn.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0184</id>
    <name>Hallowed Fountain</name>
    <text>({T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool.)
As Hallowed Fountain enters the battlefield, you may pay 2 life. If you don't, Hallowed Fountain enters the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0185</id>
    <name>Novijen, Heart of Progress</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{G}{U}, {T}: Put a +1/+1 counter on each creature that entered the battlefield this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The unnatural pressures of life in this city are best withstood by lifeforms that adapt with unnatural swiftness."
—Momir Vig</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0186</id>
    <name>Pillar of the Paruns</name>
    <text>{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast multicolored spells.</text>
    <flavorText>Built on the very ground where the Ten signed the Guildpact, the tower is a monument to the past and a reminder of who holds power in the present.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0187</id>
    <name>Prahv, Spires of Order</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{4}{W}{U}, {T}: Prevent all damage a source of your choice would deal this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Prahv, where much work is done to make sure nothing is accomplished.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0188</id>
    <name>Rakdos Carnarium</name>
    <text>Rakdos Carnarium enters the battlefield tapped.
When Rakdos Carnarium enters the battlefield, return a land you control to its owner's hand.
{T}: Add {B}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0189</id>
    <name>Rix Maadi, Dungeon Palace</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}{B}{R}, {T}: Each player discards a card. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>Even miles away, if you put your ear to the sewer vents, you can hear the screams and the tempestuous laughter.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>DIS0190</id>
    <name>Simic Growth Chamber</name>
    <text>Simic Growth Chamber enters the battlefield tapped.
When Simic Growth Chamber enters the battlefield, return a land you control to its owner's hand.
{T}: Add {G}{U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>