<cards name="Eventide">
  <item>
    <id>EVE0001</id>
    <name>Archon of Justice</name>
    <text>Flying
When Archon of Justice is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, exile target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>In dark times, Truth bears a blade.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0002</id>
    <name>Ballynock Trapper</name>
    <text>{T}: Tap target creature.
Whenever you cast a white spell, you may untap Ballynock Trapper.</text>
    <flavorText>No matter how large or small, fierce or fleeting, the kithkin have a trap for it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0003</id>
    <name>Cenn's Enlistment</name>
    <text>Put two 1/1 white Kithkin Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>The more the scarier.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0004</id>
    <name>Endless Horizons</name>
    <text>When Endless Horizons enters the battlefield, search your library for any number of Plains cards and exile them. Then shuffle your library.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a card you own exiled with Endless Horizons into your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0005</id>
    <name>Endure</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you and permanents you control this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Aurora had lessened the kithkins' kindness, deepened their paranoia, and dulled their sense of pain.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0006</id>
    <name>Flickerwisp</name>
    <text>Flying
When Flickerwisp enters the battlefield, exile another target permanent. Return that card to the battlefield under its owner's control at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>Its wings disturb more than air.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0007</id>
    <name>Hallowed Burial</name>
    <text>Put all creatures on the bottom of their owners' libraries.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'd rather hear the screams of battle than the quiet that follows."
—Talara, elvish safewright</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0008</id>
    <name>Kithkin Spellduster</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{W}, Sacrifice Kithkin Spellduster: Destroy target enchantment.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0009</id>
    <name>Kithkin Zealot</name>
    <text>When Kithkin Zealot enters the battlefield, you gain 1 life for each black and/or red permanent target opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>The more his flock fears, the more power he wields.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0010</id>
    <name>Light from Within</name>
    <text>Chroma — Each creature you control gets +1/+1 for each white mana symbol in its mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"Muscle does not make one strong. It only masks the soul's light. True strength lies in purity of purpose."
—Donal Alloway, cenn of Kinscaer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0011</id>
    <name>Loyal Gyrfalcon</name>
    <text>Defender, flying
Whenever you cast a white spell, Loyal Gyrfalcon loses defender until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It's tethered not to keep it from fleeing but to keep it from eating everything in sight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0012</id>
    <name>Patrol Signaler</name>
    <text>{1}{W}, {untap}: Put a 1/1 white Kithkin Soldier creature token onto the battlefield. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>Many a keen-eared bogle has run afoul of a clever and silently orchestrated kithkin ambush.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0013</id>
    <name>Recumbent Bliss</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Kithkin somnomancers enjoy the peaceful dreams wafting from their victims.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0014</id>
    <name>Spirit of the Hearth</name>
    <text>Flying
You can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.</text>
    <flavorText>Thieves know that a snarl in the night means, "Rob another house."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0015</id>
    <name>Springjack Shepherd</name>
    <text>Chroma — When Springjack Shepherd enters the battlefield, put a 0/1 white Goat creature token onto the battlefield for each white mana symbol in the mana costs of permanents you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Better for a doun to lose its cenn than its springjacks."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0016</id>
    <name>Suture Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying
{WB}{WB}{WB}: Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Is her need to heal born out of compassion or penance?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0017</id>
    <name>Banishing Knack</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, target creature gains "{T}: Return target nonland permanent to its owner's hand."</text>
    <flavorText>Suddenly he realized that everything was connected by invisible strings, strings that could be pulled—or cut.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0018</id>
    <name>Cache Raiders</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, return a permanent you control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>What the current doesn't take, they do.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0019</id>
    <name>Dream Fracture</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. Its controller draws a card.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Creation is a paradox. It hatches from its opposite."
—Olka, Mistmeadow witch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0020</id>
    <name>Dream Thief</name>
    <text>Flying
When Dream Thief enters the battlefield, draw a card if you've cast another blue spell this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Awylla's salvaged dreams would finally be put to good use.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0021</id>
    <name>Glamerdye</name>
    <text>Change the text of target spell or permanent by replacing all instances of one color word with another.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0022</id>
    <name>Glen Elendra Archmage</name>
    <text>Flying
{U}, Sacrifice Glen Elendra Archmage: Counter target noncreature spell.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0023</id>
    <name>Idle Thoughts</name>
    <text>{2}: Draw a card if you have no cards in hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Inspiration strikes the uncluttered mind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0024</id>
    <name>Indigo Faerie</name>
    <text>Flying
{U}: Target permanent becomes blue in addition to its other colors until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"You should see your face right now."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0025</id>
    <name>Inundate</name>
    <text>Return all nonblue creatures to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>"For years, the landfolk have emptied their refuse into the waters. It's time to return the favor."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0026</id>
    <name>Merrow Levitator</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.
Whenever you cast a blue spell, you may untap Merrow Levitator.</text>
    <flavorText>He fancies himself a master thief, claiming to "steal the ground" from his victims.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0027</id>
    <name>Oona's Grace</name>
    <text>Target player draws a card.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>Oona grants her favored subjects a dream from her own guarded heart.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0028</id>
    <name>Razorfin Abolisher</name>
    <text>{1}{U}, {T}: Return target creature with a counter on it to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Once you have been marked by the merrow, you are not long for their waters.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0029</id>
    <name>Sanity Grinding</name>
    <text>Chroma — Reveal the top ten cards of your library. For each blue mana symbol in the mana costs of the revealed cards, target opponent puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard. Then put the cards you revealed this way on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0030</id>
    <name>Talonrend</name>
    <text>Flying
{UR}: Talonrend gets +1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Change is a denizen of Shadowmoor as much as ouphes and noggles are.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0031</id>
    <name>Wake Thrasher</name>
    <text>Whenever a permanent you control becomes untapped, Wake Thrasher gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Anyone who thinks merrows have more brains than brawn has never been run over by one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0032</id>
    <name>Wilderness Hypnotist</name>
    <text>{T}: Target red or green creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I felt as if I were moving in brackish water, as if I were drowning, even though I knew I stood on dry land."
—Dindun of Kulrath Mine</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0033</id>
    <name>Ashling, the Extinguisher</name>
    <text>Whenever Ashling, the Extinguisher deals combat damage to a player, choose target creature that player controls. He or she sacrifices that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The Aurora had transformed her into a relentless force of destruction.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0034</id>
    <name>Creakwood Ghoul</name>
    <text>{BG}{BG}: Exile target card from a graveyard. You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Some eat the living. Some eat the dead. It eats the past.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0035</id>
    <name>Crumbling Ashes</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy target creature with a -1/-1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"I was there to watch my brothers' quenching. I drew the slightest warmth from their dying rage."
—Illulia of Nighthearth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0036</id>
    <name>Lingering Tormentor</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>The bogeyman doesn't disappear when you close your eyes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0037</id>
    <name>Merrow Bonegnawer</name>
    <text>{T}: Target player exiles a card from his or her graveyard.
Whenever you cast a black spell, you may untap Merrow Bonegnawer.</text>
    <flavorText>Banished to the Dark Meanders for hideous crimes, some merrows find a taste for the darkness . . . and the dead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0038</id>
    <name>Necroskitter</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Whenever a creature an opponent controls with a -1/-1 counter on it is put into a graveyard, you may return that card to the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0039</id>
    <name>Needle Specter</name>
    <text>Flying
Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Whenever Needle Specter deals combat damage to a player, that player discards that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0040</id>
    <name>Nightmare Incursion</name>
    <text>Search target player's library for up to X cards, where X is the number of Swamps you control, and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0041</id>
    <name>Raven's Crime</name>
    <text>Target player discards a card.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>It plucks away memories like choice bits of carrion.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0042</id>
    <name>Smoldering Butcher</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>A cinder's axe bears no marks from parrying a foe's blade.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0043</id>
    <name>Soot Imp</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever a player casts a nonblack spell, that player loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"If one gets in your chimney, you're going to need a long wick and a barrel of bangstuff to get it out."
—Hob Heddil</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0044</id>
    <name>Soul Reap</name>
    <text>Destroy target nongreen creature. Its controller loses 3 life if you've cast another black spell this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Their thoughtweft carried Darial's last thoughts back to his doun. They sorely wished it had not.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0045</id>
    <name>Soul Snuffers</name>
    <text>When Soul Snuffers enters the battlefield, put a -1/-1 counter on each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>They once sought to unite with the flame of transcendence. Now they seek only to extinguish the lights of others.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0046</id>
    <name>Syphon Life</name>
    <text>Target player loses 2 life and you gain 2 life.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>Leeches never tire of feeding.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0047</id>
    <name>Talara's Bane</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You choose a green or white creature card from it. You gain life equal that creature card's toughness, then that player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your thoughts betray you."
—Illulia of Nighthearth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0048</id>
    <name>Umbra Stalker</name>
    <text>Chroma — Umbra Stalker's power and toughness are each equal to the number of black mana symbols in the mana costs of cards in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Don't venture into the darkness, lest it decide not to let you leave.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0049</id>
    <name>Chaotic Backlash</name>
    <text>Chaotic Backlash deals damage to target player equal to twice the number of white and/or blue permanents he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>The concept of thoughtweft fascinates the Nighthearth cult. Imagine, bringing agony to an entire people by torturing just one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0050</id>
    <name>Cinder Pyromancer</name>
    <text>{T}: Cinder Pyromancer deals 1 damage to target player.
Whenever you cast a red spell, you may untap Cinder Pyromancer.</text>
    <flavorText>"If the whole world burns, I'll never grow cold."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0051</id>
    <name>Duergar Cave-Guard</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
{RW}: Duergar Cave-Guard gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Duergars who grow too large to live in the tunnels are sent topside to defend the entrances from intruders.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0052</id>
    <name>Fiery Bombardment</name>
    <text>Chroma — {2}, Sacrifice a creature: Fiery Bombardment deals damage to target creature or player equal to the number of red mana symbols in the sacrificed creature's mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>It kills two beasts with one thrown.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0053</id>
    <name>Flame Jab</name>
    <text>Flame Jab deals 1 damage to target creature or player.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Fire's out. Should be safe now."
—Gnarltrunk</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0054</id>
    <name>Hatchet Bully</name>
    <text>{2}{R}, {T}, Put a -1/-1 counter on a creature you control: Hatchet Bully deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's not much for eating, but I think we can find somethin' to do with it."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0055</id>
    <name>Hateflayer</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
{2}{R}, {untap}: Hateflayer deals damage equal to its power to target creature or player. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>It has no safe side.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0056</id>
    <name>Heartlash Cinder</name>
    <text>Haste
Chroma — When Heartlash Cinder enters the battlefield, it gets +X/+0 until end of turn, where X is the number of red mana symbols in the mana costs of permanents you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0057</id>
    <name>Hotheaded Giant</name>
    <text>Haste
Hotheaded Giant enters the battlefield with two -1/-1 counters on it unless you've cast another red spell this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>As he races the moon each night, he draws a glowing equator across the world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0058</id>
    <name>Impelled Giant</name>
    <text>Trample
Tap an untapped red creature you control other than Impelled Giant: Impelled Giant gets +X/+0 until end of turn, where X is the power of the creature tapped this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0059</id>
    <name>Outrage Shaman</name>
    <text>Chroma — When Outrage Shaman enters the battlefield, it deals damage to target creature equal to the number of red mana symbols in the mana costs of permanents you control.</text>
    <flavorText>A boggart's mind is a tinderbox of volatile thoughts, hungry for a spark.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0060</id>
    <name>Puncture Blast</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Puncture Blast deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Gnarltrunk didn't remember having quite that many knotholes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0061</id>
    <name>Rekindled Flame</name>
    <text>Rekindled Flame deals 4 damage to target creature or player.
At the beginning of your upkeep, if an opponent has no cards in hand, you may return Rekindled Flame from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0062</id>
    <name>Stigma Lasher</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Whenever Stigma Lasher deals damage to a player, that player can't gain life for the rest of the game.</text>
    <flavorText>The Extinguisher's curse lasted long after her departure.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0063</id>
    <name>Thunderblust</name>
    <text>Haste
Thunderblust has trample as long as it has a -1/-1 counter on it.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0064</id>
    <name>Unwilling Recruit</name>
    <text>Gain control of target creature until end of turn. Untap that creature. It gets +X/+0 and gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Frorn didn't want to be kept, but he didn't want to be thrown back either.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0065</id>
    <name>Aerie Ouphes</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Aerie Ouphes: Aerie Ouphes deals damage equal to its power to target creature with flying.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0066</id>
    <name>Bloom Tender</name>
    <text>{T}: For each color among permanents you control, add one mana of that color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Beauty is a seed, waiting to blossom under her capable hands.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0067</id>
    <name>Duskdale Wurm</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>"Last time, it tore up the Wilt-Leaf, turned Mistmeadow into a mudhole, and made the river jump its banks. On the bright side, we were eating venison for weeks."
—Donal Alloway, cenn of Kinscaer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0068</id>
    <name>Helix Pinnacle</name>
    <text>Shroud
{X}: Put X tower counters on Helix Pinnacle.
At the beginning of your upkeep, if there are 100 or more tower counters on Helix Pinnacle, you win the game.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0069</id>
    <name>Marshdrinker Giant</name>
    <text>When Marshdrinker Giant enters the battlefield, destroy target Island or Swamp an opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>When giants rise from their long slumbers, they rarely remember how fragile the waking world can be.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0070</id>
    <name>Monstrify</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>Gackt came to regret keeping his pet toads on his head.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0071</id>
    <name>Nettle Sentinel</name>
    <text>Nettle Sentinel doesn't untap during your untap step.
Whenever you cast a green spell, you may untap Nettle Sentinel.</text>
    <flavorText>Though Shadowmoor's monster-haunted wilds beckon, she never leaves her post.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0072</id>
    <name>Phosphorescent Feast</name>
    <text>Chroma — Reveal any number of cards in your hand. You gain 2 life for each green mana symbol in those cards' mana costs.</text>
    <flavorText>The boggarts gorged themselves until their bellies glowed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0073</id>
    <name>Primalcrux</name>
    <text>Trample
Chroma — Primalcrux's power and toughness are each equal to the number of green mana symbols in the mana costs of permanents you control.</text>
    <flavorText>When nature is backed into a corner, just like its children, it lashes out.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0074</id>
    <name>Regal Force</name>
    <text>When Regal Force enters the battlefield, draw a card for each green creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>It rarely moves, standing stock still in its clearing. When it does stir, ravens stop their cawing and crickets their chirping. All of nature watches in awed silence.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0075</id>
    <name>Savage Conception</name>
    <text>Put a 3/3 green Beast creature token onto the battlefield.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>Some beasts are born not of a mother, but of magic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0076</id>
    <name>Swirling Spriggan</name>
    <text>{GU}{GU}: Target creature you control becomes the color or colors of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>After its encounter with the spriggan, the patrol was red with anger, green with envy, white with fear, and painfully black and blue.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0077</id>
    <name>Talara's Battalion</name>
    <text>Trample
Cast Talara's Battalion only if you've cast another green spell this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The safewright Talara protects a delicate woodland waterfall. She has vowed to send wave after wave of warriors to slay any who would dare disturb its beauty.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0078</id>
    <name>Tilling Treefolk</name>
    <text>When Tilling Treefolk enters the battlefield, you may return up to two target land cards from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>He digs his roots into barren ground, searching for old seeds that never had the chance to sprout.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0079</id>
    <name>Twinblade Slasher</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
{1}{G}: Twinblade Slasher gets +2/+2 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Righteous anger hones a humble soul.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0080</id>
    <name>Wickerbough Elder</name>
    <text>Wickerbough Elder enters the battlefield with a -1/-1 counter on it.
{G}, Remove a -1/-1 counter from Wickerbough Elder: Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"Living scarecrows make a mockery of the natural order. Dead ones make fine hats."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0081</id>
    <name>Batwing Brume</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn if {W} was spent to cast Batwing Brume. Each player loses 1 life for each attacking creature he or she controls if {B} was spent to cast Batwing Brume. (Do both if {W}{B} was spent.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0082</id>
    <name>Beckon Apparition</name>
    <text>Exile target card from a graveyard. Put a 1/1 white and black Spirit creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>When a graveyard is full, the gwyllions rattle the tombs and unleash the spirits into the sky.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0083</id>
    <name>Bloodied Ghost</name>
    <text>Flying
Bloodied Ghost enters the battlefield with a -1/-1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Only a knife left for a fortnight in the hollow of a ghastbark tree can inflict a wound so grave."
—Kithkin superstition</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0084</id>
    <name>Cauldron Haze</name>
    <text>Choose any number of target creatures. Each of those creatures gains persist until end of turn. (When it's put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0085</id>
    <name>Deathbringer Liege</name>
    <text>Other white creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other black creatures you control get +1/+1.
Whenever you cast a white spell, you may tap target creature.
Whenever you cast a black spell, you may destroy target creature if it's tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0086</id>
    <name>Divinity of Pride</name>
    <text>Flying, lifelink
Divinity of Pride gets +4/+4 as long as you have 25 or more life.</text>
    <flavorText>"She spoke of mystery and portent, of such unfathomable things that my mind screamed for pity."
—The Seer's Parables</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0087</id>
    <name>Edge of the Divinity</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As long as enchanted creature is white, it gets +1/+2.
As long as enchanted creature is black, it gets +2/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>The divinity's patronage confers both wicked grace and graceful wickedness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0088</id>
    <name>Evershrike</name>
    <text>Flying
Evershrike gets +2/+2 for each Aura attached to it.
{X}{WB}{WB}: Return Evershrike from your graveyard to the battlefield. You may put an Aura card with converted mana cost X or less from your hand onto the battlefield attached to it. If you don't, exile Evershrike.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0089</id>
    <name>Gwyllion Hedge-Mage</name>
    <text>When Gwyllion Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Plains, you may put a 1/1 white Kithkin Soldier creature token onto the battlefield.
When Gwyllion Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Swamps, you may put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0090</id>
    <name>Harvest Gwyllion</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>She speaks only in vile epithets, spitting out curses and obscenities that harm others just by the hearing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0091</id>
    <name>Nightsky Mimic</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a spell that's both white and black, Nightsky Mimic becomes 4/4 and gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A mimic need only touch a being to learn its shape, but touching usually leads to mauling and messily eating.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0092</id>
    <name>Nip Gwyllion</name>
    <text>Lifelink (Damage dealt by this creature also causes you to gain that much life.)</text>
    <flavorText>Once your life and all your worldly possessions have been surrendered to her, a gwyllion can be surprisingly civilized.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0093</id>
    <name>Pyrrhic Revival</name>
    <text>Each player returns each creature card from his or her graveyard to the battlefield with an additional -1/-1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>They found themselves alive again, still bearing their mortal wounds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0094</id>
    <name>Restless Apparition</name>
    <text>{WB}{WB}{WB}: Restless Apparition gets +3/+3 until end of turn.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0095</id>
    <name>Stillmoon Cavalier</name>
    <text>Protection from white and from black
{WB}: Stillmoon Cavalier gains flying until end of turn.
{WB}: Stillmoon Cavalier gains first strike until end of turn.
(w/b){WB}: Stillmoon Cavalier gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0096</id>
    <name>Unmake</name>
    <text>Exile target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>A gwyllion's favorite trap is the vanity mirror. A bewitched piece of glass traps the looker's soul and does away with the body.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0097</id>
    <name>Voracious Hatchling</name>
    <text>Lifelink
Voracious Hatchling enters the battlefield with four -1/-1 counters on it.
Whenever you cast a white spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Voracious Hatchling.
Whenever you cast a black spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Voracious Hatchling.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0098</id>
    <name>Call the Skybreaker</name>
    <text>Put a 5/5 blue and red Elemental creature token with flying onto the battlefield.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>It hears and answers every orison across Shadowmoor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0099</id>
    <name>Clout of the Dominus</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As long as enchanted creature is blue, it gets +1/+1 and has shroud. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)
As long as enchanted creature is red, it gets +1/+1 and has haste.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0100</id>
    <name>Crackleburr</name>
    <text>{UR}{UR}, {T}, Tap two untapped red creatures you control: Crackleburr deals 3 damage to target creature or player.
{UR}{UR}, {untap}, Untap two tapped blue creatures you control: Return target creature to its owner's hand. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0101</id>
    <name>Crag Puca</name>
    <text>{UR}: Switch Crag Puca's power and toughness until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Be happy when you see a puca shaped like mischief. It's far better than one shaped like death."
—Dindun of Kulrath Mine</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0102</id>
    <name>Dominus of Fealty</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may gain control of target permanent until end of turn. If you do, untap it and it gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Nothing is truly your own. It is his, whether you know it or not."
—The Seer's Parables</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0103</id>
    <name>Inside Out</name>
    <text>Switch target creature's power and toughness until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Seyden's temperament didn't take well to the puca's magic. Nor did his face.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0104</id>
    <name>Mindwrack Liege</name>
    <text>Other blue creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other red creatures you control get +1/+1.
{UR}{UR}{UR}{UR}: You may put a blue or red creature card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0105</id>
    <name>Mirror Sheen</name>
    <text>{1}{UR}{UR}: Copy target instant or sorcery spell that targets you. You may choose new targets for the copy.</text>
    <flavorText>Even treefolk witches steer clear of the unpredictable woods near Glen Elendra. Spells refract off the glamer-polished trees and the eyes of lurking pucas.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0106</id>
    <name>Noggle Bandit</name>
    <text>Noggle Bandit can't be blocked except by creatures with defender.</text>
    <flavorText>Noggles believe that they were the first race ever to walk Shadowmoor. They don't "steal." They just take back what's rightfully theirs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0107</id>
    <name>Noggle Bridgebreaker</name>
    <text>When Noggle Bridgebreaker enters the battlefield, return a land you control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's always funny till someone gets hurt. Then it's hilarious."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0108</id>
    <name>Noggle Hedge-Mage</name>
    <text>When Noggle Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Islands, you may tap two target permanents.
When Noggle Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Mountains, you may have Noggle Hedge-Mage deal 2 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0109</id>
    <name>Noggle Ransacker</name>
    <text>When Noggle Ransacker enters the battlefield, each player draws two cards, then discards a card at random.</text>
    <flavorText>Noggles live purely by what they can scavenge. There is not a single thing a noggle eats, wears, or uses that did not once belong to another.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0110</id>
    <name>Nucklavee</name>
    <text>When Nucklavee enters the battlefield, you may return target red sorcery card from your graveyard to your hand.
When Nucklavee enters the battlefield, you may return target blue instant card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>It loathes all tastes but two: spells and flesh.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0111</id>
    <name>Riverfall Mimic</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a spell that's both blue and red, Riverfall Mimic becomes 3/3 and is unblockable until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Mimics don't hide their natural form well, but their disguises work well enough on boggarts.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0112</id>
    <name>Shrewd Hatchling</name>
    <text>Shrewd Hatchling enters the battlefield with four -1/-1 counters on it.
{UR}: Target creature can't block Shrewd Hatchling this turn.
Whenever you cast a blue spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Shrewd Hatchling.
Whenever you cast a red spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Shrewd Hatchling.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0113</id>
    <name>Stream Hopper</name>
    <text>{UR}: Stream Hopper gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Like many who dwell in Shadowmoor now, he was robbed of his better half by the Aurora.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0114</id>
    <name>Unnerving Assault</name>
    <text>Creatures your opponents control get -1/-0 until end of turn if {U} was spent to cast Unnerving Assault, and creatures you control get +1/+0 until end of turn if {R} was spent to cast it. (Do both if {U}{R} was spent.)</text>
    <flavorText>The scales of battle rarely balance.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0115</id>
    <name>Canker Abomination</name>
    <text>As Canker Abomination enters the battlefield, choose an opponent. Canker Abomination enters the battlefield with a -1/-1 counter on it for each creature that player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Once the hideous disease takes hold, it spreads through both bark and mind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0116</id>
    <name>Cankerous Thirst</name>
    <text>If {B} was spent to cast Cankerous Thirst, you may have target creature get -3/-3 until end of turn. If {G} was spent to cast Cankerous Thirst, you may have target creature get +3/+3 until end of turn. (Do both if {B}{G} was spent.)</text>
    <flavorText>Nothing warms the bark on a chilly day like a draught of elf.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0117</id>
    <name>Creakwood Liege</name>
    <text>Other black creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other green creatures you control get +1/+1.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a 1/1 black and green Worm creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0118</id>
    <name>Deity of Scars</name>
    <text>Trample
Deity of Scars enters the battlefield with two -1/-1 counters on it.
{BG}, Remove a -1/-1 counter from Deity of Scars: Regenerate Deity of Scars.</text>
    <flavorText>"His skin cuts swords."
—The Seer's Parables</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0119</id>
    <name>Desecrator Hag</name>
    <text>When Desecrator Hag enters the battlefield, return to your hand the creature card in your graveyard with the greatest power. If two or more cards are tied for greatest power, you choose one of them.</text>
    <flavorText>Loose earth is not a burial but an appetizer.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0120</id>
    <name>Doomgape</name>
    <text>Trample
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice a creature. You gain life equal to that creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>It eats and eats until the juiciest morsel it can find is itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0121</id>
    <name>Drain the Well</name>
    <text>Destroy target land. You gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Trows have learned that it's not wise to eat cinders without a bucket or two of water nearby.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0122</id>
    <name>Gift of the Deity</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As long as enchanted creature is black, it gets +1/+1 and has deathtouch. (Creatures dealt damage by this creature are destroyed. You can divide its combat damage among any of the creatures blocking or blocked by it.)
As long as enchanted creature is green, it gets +1/+1 and all creatures able to block it do so.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0123</id>
    <name>Hag Hedge-Mage</name>
    <text>When Hag Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Swamps, you may have target player discard a card.
When Hag Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Forests, you may put target card from your graveyard on top of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0124</id>
    <name>Noxious Hatchling</name>
    <text>Noxious Hatchling enters the battlefield with four -1/-1 counters on it.
Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Whenever you cast a black spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Noxious Hatchling.
Whenever you cast a green spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Noxious Hatchling.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0125</id>
    <name>Odious Trow</name>
    <text>{1}{BG}: Regenerate Odious Trow.</text>
    <flavorText>Trows are the vile trolls that lurk in the bogs of Shadowmoor. They reappear each night to frighten the living and gnaw the dead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0126</id>
    <name>Quillspike</name>
    <text>{BG}, Remove a -1/-1 counter from a creature you control: Quillspike gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>While it's true that a quillspike does heal the sick, it's just because it finds them tastier that way.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0127</id>
    <name>Rendclaw Trow</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0128</id>
    <name>Sapling of Colfenor</name>
    <text>Sapling of Colfenor is indestructible.
Whenever Sapling of Colfenor attacks, reveal the top card of your library. If it's a creature card, you gain life equal to that card's toughness, lose life equal to its power, then put it into your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Her plans may yet bear fruit.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0129</id>
    <name>Stalker Hag</name>
    <text>Swampwalk, forestwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Her hunt is silent until a bone snaps or flesh tears. Her victims never know to scream.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0130</id>
    <name>Woodlurker Mimic</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a spell that's both black and green, Woodlurker Mimic becomes 4/5 and gains wither until end of turn. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>A mimic's disguise fools its victims just long enough to draw them within range of its venomous tentacles.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0131</id>
    <name>Worm Harvest</name>
    <text>Put a 1/1 black and green Worm creature token onto the battlefield for each land card in your graveyard.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0132</id>
    <name>Balefire Liege</name>
    <text>Other red creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other white creatures you control get +1/+1.
Whenever you cast a red spell, Balefire Liege deals 3 damage to target player.
Whenever you cast a white spell, you gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0133</id>
    <name>Battlegate Mimic</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a spell that's both red and white, Battlegate Mimic becomes 4/2 and gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Mimics don't need perfect disguises. They need only the perfect victims: the naive, the young, or the poor of sight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0134</id>
    <name>Belligerent Hatchling</name>
    <text>First strike
Belligerent Hatchling enters the battlefield with four -1/-1 counters on it.
Whenever you cast a red spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Belligerent Hatchling.
Whenever you cast a white spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Belligerent Hatchling.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0135</id>
    <name>Double Cleave</name>
    <text>Target creature gains double strike until end of turn. (It deals both first-strike and regular combat damage.)</text>
    <flavorText>"When in doubt, kill 'em twice."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0136</id>
    <name>Duergar Assailant</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Duergar Assailant: Duergar Assailant deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Some duergars dismiss the world above as a fable. They react violently when their comfortable illusions are dispelled.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0137</id>
    <name>Duergar Hedge-Mage</name>
    <text>When Duergar Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Mountains, you may destroy target artifact.
When Duergar Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Plains, you may destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0138</id>
    <name>Duergar Mine-Captain</name>
    <text>{1}{RW}, {untap}: Attacking creatures get +1/+0 until end of turn. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>Duergars are prodigious workers with long memories. Some still fulfill intricately detailed orders given decades, if not centuries, before.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0139</id>
    <name>Figure of Destiny</name>
    <text>{RW}: Figure of Destiny becomes a 2/2 Kithkin Spirit.
(r/w)(r/w){RW}: If Figure of Destiny is a Spirit, it becomes a 4/4 Kithkin Spirit Warrior.
(r/w)(r/w)(r/w)(r/w)(r/w){RW}: If Figure of Destiny is a Warrior, it becomes an 8/8 Kithkin Spirit Warrior Avatar with flying and first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0140</id>
    <name>Fire at Will</name>
    <text>Fire at Will deals 3 damage divided as you choose among one, two, or three target attacking or blocking creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"Make these shots count. The more foes we drop now, the fewer we'll have trying to kill us later."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0141</id>
    <name>Hearthfire Hobgoblin</name>
    <text>Double strike</text>
    <flavorText>Hobgoblins are best left alone. They sharpen their farm implements far more than is necessary for their work in the fields.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0142</id>
    <name>Hobgoblin Dragoon</name>
    <text>Flying, first strike</text>
    <flavorText>The faeries snickered at first. A common hob in Oona's skies? But his lance ended their mockery, and now the sound of a cicada's wings brings a shudder to the faerie heart.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0143</id>
    <name>Moonhold</name>
    <text>Target player can't play land cards this turn if {R} was spent to cast Moonhold and can't play creature cards this turn if {W} was spent to cast it. (Do both if {R}{W} was spent.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0144</id>
    <name>Nobilis of War</name>
    <text>Flying
Attacking creatures you control get +2/+0.</text>
    <flavorText>"A great siege is a banquet to him; a long and terrible battle, the most exquisite delicacy."
—The Seer's Parables</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0145</id>
    <name>Rise of the Hobgoblins</name>
    <text>When Rise of the Hobgoblins enters the battlefield, you may pay {X}. If you do, put X 1/1 red and white Goblin Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield.
{RW}: Red creatures and white creatures you control gain first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A river even the merrow dare not cross.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0146</id>
    <name>Scourge of the Nobilis</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As long as enchanted creature is red, it gets +1/+1 and has "{RW}: This creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn."
As long as enchanted creature is white, it gets +1/+1 and has lifelink. (Damage dealt by the creature also causes its controller to gain that much life.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0147</id>
    <name>Spitemare</name>
    <text>Whenever Spitemare is dealt damage, it deals that much damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"I knew a creature carved from a dream of wild freedom. Any attempt to leash or exploit it failed, and at terrible cost."
—Ashling</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0148</id>
    <name>Waves of Aggression</name>
    <text>Untap all creatures that attacked this turn. After this main phase, there is an additional combat phase followed by an additional main phase.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0149</id>
    <name>Cold-Eyed Selkie</name>
    <text>Islandwalk
Whenever Cold-Eyed Selkie deals combat damage to a player, you may draw that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>She follows the old tributaries built when merrows still shaped the tides.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0150</id>
    <name>Fable of Wolf and Owl</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a green spell, you may put a 2/2 green Wolf creature token onto the battlefield.
Whenever you cast a blue spell, you may put a 1/1 blue Bird creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The forest grew fangs. The sky spread its wings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0151</id>
    <name>Favor of the Overbeing</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As long as enchanted creature is green, it gets +1/+1 and has vigilance.
As long as enchanted creature is blue, it gets +1/+1 and has flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Enlightenment is the mundane seen from the vantage point of the divine.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0152</id>
    <name>Gilder Bairn</name>
    <text>{2}{GU}, {untap}: For each counter on target permanent, put another of those counters on that permanent. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>Do the glowing trinkets show it the way home, or do they set a twisted path for someone else to follow?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0153</id>
    <name>Grazing Kelpie</name>
    <text>{GU}, Sacrifice Grazing Kelpie: Put target card from a graveyard on the bottom of its owner's library.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0154</id>
    <name>Groundling Pouncer</name>
    <text>{GU}: Groundling Pouncer gets +1/+3 and gains flying until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn and only if an opponent controls a creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Endry was determined to teach his groundlings a few winged-faerie tricks.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0155</id>
    <name>Invert the Skies</name>
    <text>Creatures your opponents control lose flying until end of turn if {G} was spent to cast Invert the Skies, and creatures you control gain flying until end of turn if {U} was spent to cast it. (Do both if {G}{U} was spent.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0156</id>
    <name>Murkfiend Liege</name>
    <text>Other green creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other blue creatures you control get +1/+1.
Untap all green and/or blue creatures you control during each other player's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0157</id>
    <name>Overbeing of Myth</name>
    <text>Overbeing of Myth's power and toughness are each equal to the number of cards in your hand.
At the beginning of your draw step, draw an additional card.</text>
    <flavorText>"She walks among us unseen, learning from our imperfections."
—The Seer's Parables</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0158</id>
    <name>Selkie Hedge-Mage</name>
    <text>When Selkie Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Forests, you may gain 3 life.
When Selkie Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Islands, you may return target tapped creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0159</id>
    <name>Shorecrasher Mimic</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a spell that's both green and blue, Shorecrasher Mimic becomes 5/3 and gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Aurora replaced the changelings' innocence with malice and their curiosity with hunger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0160</id>
    <name>Slippery Bogle</name>
    <text>Slippery Bogle can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.</text>
    <flavorText>Bogles are very tasty if you can get the skin off. It's getting a blade on them that's the problem.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0161</id>
    <name>Snakeform</name>
    <text>Target creature loses all abilities and becomes a 1/1 green Snake until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Losing his possessions distressed him, but the lack of limbs was strangely liberating.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0162</id>
    <name>Spitting Image</name>
    <text>Put a token that's a copy of target creature onto the battlefield.
Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)</text>
    <flavorText>Spitting is the customary greeting between a creature and its magical impostor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0163</id>
    <name>Sturdy Hatchling</name>
    <text>Sturdy Hatchling enters the battlefield with four -1/-1 counters on it.
{GU}: Sturdy Hatchling gains shroud until end of turn.
Whenever you cast a green spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Sturdy Hatchling.
Whenever you cast a blue spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Sturdy Hatchling.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0164</id>
    <name>Trapjaw Kelpie</name>
    <text>Flash
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>Travelers in these waters leave a bit of themselves behind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0165</id>
    <name>Wistful Selkie</name>
    <text>When Wistful Selkie enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Selkies call to a sea they never swam, in a tongue they never spoke, with a song they never learned.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0166</id>
    <name>Altar Golem</name>
    <text>Trample
Altar Golem's power and toughness are each equal to the number of creatures on the battlefield.
Altar Golem doesn't untap during your untap step.
Tap five untapped creatures you control: Untap Altar Golem.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0167</id>
    <name>Antler Skulkin</name>
    <text>{2}: Target white creature gains persist until end of turn. (When it's put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>Every skull has a tale to tell, and a skulkin is many dire tales cobbled together.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0168</id>
    <name>Fang Skulkin</name>
    <text>{2}: Target black creature gains wither until end of turn. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Everything falls apart. But living things fall apart in the most fascinating ways."
—Mowagh the Gwyllion</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0169</id>
    <name>Hoof Skulkin</name>
    <text>{3}: Target green creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It hunts with the memory of a long lost herd.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0170</id>
    <name>Jawbone Skulkin</name>
    <text>{2}: Target red creature gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Ah, skull of shrew—a very potent substance. In powdered form, it gives thrice the zing of noggle hoof pulp."
—Boghald, Barrenton medic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0171</id>
    <name>Leering Emblem</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a spell, equipped creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>The banner was not a symbol of victory, but a herald of the carnage to come.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0172</id>
    <name>Scarecrone</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice a Scarecrow: Draw a card.
{4}, {T}: Return target artifact creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Her poppets bring joy to the truly depraved.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0173</id>
    <name>Shell Skulkin</name>
    <text>{3}: Target blue creature gains shroud until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Skulkins confer strange benefits on unsuspecting patrons.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0174</id>
    <name>Ward of Bones</name>
    <text>Each opponent who controls more creatures than you can't play creature cards. The same is true for artifacts, enchantments, and lands.</text>
    <flavorText>Mages dare not attempt magic in its grotesque presence.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0175</id>
    <name>Cascade Bluffs</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{UR}, {T}: Add {U}{U}, {U}{R}, or {R}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Travelers bathe in the falls to wash away curses from the pucas who lurk nearby.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0176</id>
    <name>Fetid Heath</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{WB}, {T}: Add {W}{W}, {W}{B}, or {B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Do not linger in such places, child. There the gwyllions dance. If they find you, you will join in their revels for eternity."
—Talara, elvish safewright</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0177</id>
    <name>Flooded Grove</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{GU}, {T}: Add {G}{G}, {G}{U}, or {U}{U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>At full moon, the river seeps over its banks and crawls through the woods like a blanket of serpents.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0178</id>
    <name>Rugged Prairie</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{RW}, {T}: Add {R}{R}, {R}{W}, or {W}{W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Hobs bury their kin far from home. They believe the dry, open ground keeps hags from stealing the bones and gwyllions from stealing the spirits.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0179</id>
    <name>Springjack Pasture</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{4}, {T}: Put a 0/1 white Goat creature token onto the battlefield.
{T}, Sacrifice X Goats: Add X mana of any one color to your mana pool. You gain X life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>EVE0180</id>
    <name>Twilight Mire</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{BG}, {T}: Add {B}{B}, {B}{G}, or {G}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>As their roots soaked in a weak tea of bogwater and decay, the trees absorbed the essence of death into their living tissue.</flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>