<cards name="Duel Decks: Garruk vs. Liliana">
  <item>
    <id>GVL0001</id>
    <name>Garruk Wildspeaker</name>
    <text>+1: Untap two target lands.
-1: Put a 3/3 green Beast creature token onto the battlefield.
-4: Creatures you control get +3/+3 and gain trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0002</id>
    <name>Basking Rootwalla</name>
    <text>{1}{G}: Basking Rootwalla gets +2/+2 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.
Madness {0} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0003</id>
    <name>Beast</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0004</id>
    <name>Beast</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0005</id>
    <name>Albino Troll</name>
    <text>Echo {1}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
{1}{G}: Regenerate Albino Troll.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0006</id>
    <name>Elephant</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0007</id>
    <name>Vine Trellis</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Nature twists knots stronger than any rope.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0008</id>
    <name>Wild Mongrel</name>
    <text>Discard a card: Wild Mongrel gets +1/+1 and becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It teaches you to play dead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0009</id>
    <name>Wirewood Savage</name>
    <text>Whenever a Beast enters the battlefield, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"She is truly Wirewood's child now."
—Elvish refugee</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0010</id>
    <name>Blastoderm</name>
    <text>Shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)
Fading 3 (This creature enters the battlefield with three fade counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a fade counter from it. If you can't, sacrifice it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0011</id>
    <name>Ravenous Baloth</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a Beast: You gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"All we know about the Krosan Forest we have learned from those few who made it out alive."
—Elvish refugee</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0012</id>
    <name>Stampeding Wildebeests</name>
    <text>Trample (If this creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, return a green creature you control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The most violent and destructive storms in Femeref occur on cloudless days.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0013</id>
    <name>Indrik Stomphowler</name>
    <text>When Indrik Stomphowler enters the battlefield, destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>An indrik's howl has destructive power much subtler than that of its crushing foot.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0014</id>
    <name>Krosan Tusker</name>
    <text>Cycling {2}{G} ({2}{G}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
When you cycle Krosan Tusker, you may search your library for a basic land card, reveal that card, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0015</id>
    <name>Plated Slagwurm</name>
    <text>Plated Slagwurm can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.</text>
    <flavorText>Beneath the Tangle, the wurm tunnels stretch . . . wide as a stone's throw, long as forever, deep as you dare.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0016</id>
    <name>Genju of the Cedars</name>
    <text>Enchant Forest
{2}: Enchanted Forest becomes a 4/4 green Spirit creature until end of turn. It's still a land.
When enchanted Forest is put into a graveyard, you may return Genju of the Cedars from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0017</id>
    <name>Giant Growth</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0018</id>
    <name>Rancor</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+0 and has trample.
When Rancor is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Rancor to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Hatred outlives the hateful.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0019</id>
    <name>Lignify</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature is a 0/4 Treefolk with no abilities.</text>
    <flavorText>Bulgo paused, puzzled. What was that rustling sound, and why did he feel so stiff? And how could his feet be so thirsty?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0020</id>
    <name>Nature's Lore</name>
    <text>Search your library for a Forest card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Nature's secrets can be read on every tree, every branch, every leaf.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0021</id>
    <name>Elephant Guide</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, put a 3/3 green Elephant creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Nature's strength outlives the strong.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0022</id>
    <name>Invigorate</name>
    <text>If you control a Forest, you may have an opponent gain 3 life rather than pay Invigorate's mana cost.

Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0023</id>
    <name>Serrated Arrows</name>
    <text>Serrated Arrows enters the battlefield with three arrowhead counters on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, if there are no arrowhead counters on Serrated Arrows, sacrifice it.
{T}, Remove an arrowhead counter from Serrated Arrows: Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0024</id>
    <name>Harmonize</name>
    <text>Draw three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Words lie. People lie. The land tells the truth."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0025</id>
    <name>Rude Awakening</name>
    <text>Choose one — Untap all lands you control; or until end of turn, lands you control become 2/2 creatures that are still lands.
Entwine {2}{G} (Choose both if you pay the entwine cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0026</id>
    <name>Beast Attack</name>
    <text>Put a 4/4 green Beast creature token onto the battlefield.
Flashback {2}{G}{G}{G} (You may cast this card from your graveyard for its flashback cost. Then exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0027</id>
    <name>Overrun</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +3/+3 and gain trample until end of turn. (If a creature you control would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)</text>
    <flavorText>Nature doesn't walk.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0028</id>
    <name>Windstorm</name>
    <text>Windstorm deals X damage to each creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"We don't like interlopers and thieves cluttering our skies."
—Dionus, elvish archdruid</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0029</id>
    <name>Slippery Karst</name>
    <text>Slippery Karst enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0030</id>
    <name>Treetop Village</name>
    <text>Treetop Village enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{1}{G}: Treetop Village becomes a 3/3 green Ape creature with trample until end of turn. It's still a land. (If it would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0031</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0032</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0033</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0034</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0035</id>
    <name>Liliana Vess</name>
    <text>+1: Target player discards a card.
-2: Search your library for a card, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.
-8: Put all creature cards from all graveyards onto the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0036</id>
    <name>Deathgreeter</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The bones of allies grant wisdom. The bones of enemies grant strength. The bones of dragons grant life eternal."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0037</id>
    <name>Ghost-Lit Stalker</name>
    <text>{4}{B}, {T}: Target player discards two cards. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.
Channel — {5}{B}{B}, Discard Ghost-Lit Stalker: Target player discards four cards. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0038</id>
    <name>Vampire Bats</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
{B}: Vampire Bats gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Activate this ability no more than twice each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0039</id>
    <name>Drudge Skeletons</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Drudge Skeletons. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The dead make good soldiers. They can't disobey orders, never surrender, and don't stop fighting when a random body part falls off."
—Nevinyrral, Necromancer's Handbook</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0040</id>
    <name>Ravenous Rats</name>
    <text>When Ravenous Rats enters the battlefield, target opponent discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Nothing is sacred to rats. Everything is simply another meal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0041</id>
    <name>Fleshbag Marauder</name>
    <text>When Fleshbag Marauder enters the battlefield, each player sacrifices a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Grixis is a world where the only things found in abundance are death and decay. Corpses, whole or in part, are the standard currency among necromancers and demons.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0042</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Rager</name>
    <text>When Phyrexian Rager enters the battlefield, you draw a card and you lose 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>It takes no prisoners, but it keeps the choicest bits for Phyrexia.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0043</id>
    <name>Urborg Syphon-Mage</name>
    <text>{2}{B}, {T}, Discard a card: Each other player loses 2 life. You gain life equal to the life lost this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have become a gourmet of sorts. Each soul has its own distinctive flavor. The art is in inviting the right company to the feast."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0044</id>
    <name>Wall of Bone</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{B}: Regenerate Wall of Bone. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Graveyards are sacrilege! A waste of perfectly good bones."
—Keren-Dur, necromancer lord</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0045</id>
    <name>Faerie Macabre</name>
    <text>Flying
Discard Faerie Macabre: Exile up to two target cards from graveyards.</text>
    <flavorText>The line between dream and death is gauzy and fragile. She leads those too near it from one side to the other.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0046</id>
    <name>Howling Banshee</name>
    <text>Flying
When Howling Banshee enters the battlefield, each player loses 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Villagers cloaked the town in magical silence, but their ears still bled.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0047</id>
    <name>Keening Banshee</name>
    <text>Flying
When Keening Banshee enters the battlefield, target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Her cold wail echoes in the alleys and under-eaves, finding the unfortunate and turning their blood to ice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0048</id>
    <name>Twisted Abomination</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Twisted Abomination.
Swampcycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Search your library for a Swamp card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0049</id>
    <name>Skeletal Vampire</name>
    <text>Flying
When Skeletal Vampire enters the battlefield, put two 1/1 black Bat creature tokens with flying onto the battlefield.
{3}{B}{B}, Sacrifice a Bat: Put two 1/1 black Bat creature tokens with flying onto the battlefield.
Sacrifice a Bat: Regenerate Skeletal Vampire.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0050</id>
    <name>Genju of the Fens</name>
    <text>Enchant Swamp
{2}: Until end of turn, enchanted Swamp becomes a 2/2 black Spirit creature with "{B}: This creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn." It's still a land.
When enchanted Swamp is put into a graveyard, you may return Genju of the Fens from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0051</id>
    <name>Bad Moon</name>
    <text>Black creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0052</id>
    <name>Sign in Blood</name>
    <text>Target player draws two cards and loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"You know I accept only one currency here, and yet you have sought me out. Why now do you hesitate?"
—Xathrid demon</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0053</id>
    <name>Vicious Hunger</name>
    <text>Vicious Hunger deals 2 damage to target creature and you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Only the most ravenous soul feeds on the health of the weak.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0054</id>
    <name>Ichor Slick</name>
    <text>Target creature gets -3/-3 until end of turn.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)
Madness {3}{B} (If you discard this card, you may cast it for its madness cost instead of putting it into your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0055</id>
    <name>Hideous End</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. Its controller loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"A little dark magic won't stop me. The worse the curse, the better the prize."
—Radavi, Joraga relic hunter, last words</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0056</id>
    <name>Snuff Out</name>
    <text>If you control a Swamp, you may pay 4 life rather than pay Snuff Out's mana cost.

Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"The bigger they are, the faster they rot."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0057</id>
    <name>Tendrils of Corruption</name>
    <text>Tendrils of Corruption deals X damage to target creature and you gain X life, where X is the number of Swamps you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Darkness doesn't always send its minions to do its dirty work.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0058</id>
    <name>Mutilate</name>
    <text>All creatures get -1/-1 until end of turn for each Swamp you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Liliana developed a fondness for the moment when roaring becomes squealing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0059</id>
    <name>Rise from the Grave</name>
    <text>Put target creature card from a graveyard onto the battlefield under your control. That creature is a black Zombie in addition to its other colors and types.</text>
    <flavorText>"Death is no excuse for disobedience."
—Liliana Vess</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0060</id>
    <name>Corrupt</name>
    <text>Corrupt deals damage equal to the number of Swamps you control to target creature or player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt this way.</text>
    <flavorText>There are things beneath the murk for whom the bog is a stew, a thin broth in need of meat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0061</id>
    <name>Enslave</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
You control enchanted creature.
At the beginning of your upkeep, enchanted creature deals 1 damage to its owner.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0062</id>
    <name>Polluted Mire</name>
    <text>Polluted Mire enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0063</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0064</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0065</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>GVL0066</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>