<cards name="Planechase">
  <item>
    <id>HOP0001</id>
    <name>Akroma's Vengeance</name>
    <text>Destroy all artifacts, creatures, and enchantments.
Cycling {3} ({3}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>Ixidor had only to imagine their ruin and Akroma made it so.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0002</id>
    <name>Congregate</name>
    <text>Target player gains 2 life for each creature on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"In the gathering there is strength for all who founder, renewal for all who languish, love for all who sing."
—Song of All, canto 642</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0003</id>
    <name>Kor Sanctifiers</name>
    <text>Kicker {W} (You may pay an additional {W} as you cast this spell.)
When Kor Sanctifiers enters the battlefield, if it was kicked, destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why keep such trinkets? They only add weight to your travels."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0004</id>
    <name>Oblivion Ring</name>
    <text>When Oblivion Ring enters the battlefield, exile another target nonland permanent.
When Oblivion Ring leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to the battlefield under its owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0005</id>
    <name>Orim's Thunder</name>
    <text>Kicker {R} (You may pay an additional {R} as you cast this spell.)
Destroy target artifact or enchantment. If Orim's Thunder was kicked, it deals damage equal to that permanent's converted mana cost to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0006</id>
    <name>Prison Term</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block and its activated abilities can't be activated.
Whenever a creature enters the battlefield under an opponent's control, you may attach Prison Term to that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0007</id>
    <name>Soul Warden</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"One does not question the size or shape of the grains of sand in an hourglass. Nor do I question the temperament of the souls under my guidance."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0008</id>
    <name>Broodstar</name>
    <text>Affinity for artifacts (This spell costs {1} less to cast for each artifact you control.)
Flying
Broodstar's power and toughness are each equal to the number of artifacts you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0009</id>
    <name>Fabricate</name>
    <text>Search your library for an artifact card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"The secret to invention is to see something in your mind, then find where it hides in the world."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0010</id>
    <name>Keep Watch</name>
    <text>Draw a card for each attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"I see their moral dilemmas. I see their raw courage. I see their self-sacrifice. I see our victory."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0011</id>
    <name>Master of Etherium</name>
    <text>Master of Etherium's power and toughness are each equal to the number of artifacts you control.
Other artifact creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>"Only a mind unfettered with the concerns of the flesh can see the world as it truly is."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0012</id>
    <name>Qumulox</name>
    <text>Affinity for artifacts (This spell costs {1} less to cast for each artifact you control.)
Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Even the clouds bend themselves to Memnarch's will, eager to swallow those who oppose him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0013</id>
    <name>Sarcomite Myr</name>
    <text>{2}: Sarcomite Myr gains flying until end of turn.
{2}, Sacrifice Sarcomite Myr: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"A horrible sight, yes, but the sounds . . . Its twanging tendons and grinding gears are almost musical."
—Brudiclad, Telchor engineer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0014</id>
    <name>Thirst for Knowledge</name>
    <text>Draw three cards. Then discard two cards unless you discard an artifact card.</text>
    <flavorText>Lymph, the fluid essence of blinkmoths, is prized by wizards for the rush of intellect it provides.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0015</id>
    <name>Vedalken Engineer</name>
    <text>{T}: Add two mana of any one color to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast artifact spells or activate abilities of artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>Art is unknown to the vedalken—for them, all creations must serve a purpose.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0016</id>
    <name>Whiplash Trap</name>
    <text>If an opponent had two or more creatures enter the battlefield under his or her control this turn, you may pay {U} rather than pay Whiplash Trap's mana cost.
Return two target creatures to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0017</id>
    <name>Ascendant Evincar</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Other black creatures get +1/+1.
Nonblack creatures get -1/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>His soul snared by an angel's curse, Crovax twisted heroism into its purest shadow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0018</id>
    <name>Beacon of Unrest</name>
    <text>Put target artifact or creature card from a graveyard onto the battlefield under your control. Shuffle Beacon of Unrest into its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>A vertical scream pierces the night air and echoes doom through the clouds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0019</id>
    <name>Beseech the Queen</name>
    <text>({2B} can be paid with any two mana or with {B}. This card's converted mana cost is 6.)
Search your library for a card with converted mana cost less than or equal to the number of lands you control, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Those who hear her go mad with inspiration.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0020</id>
    <name>Cadaverous Knight</name>
    <text>Flanking (Whenever a creature without flanking blocks this creature, the blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.)
{1}{B}{B}: Regenerate Cadaverous Knight.</text>
    <flavorText>Grieve for the soul in death dishonored.
—Shadow Guild saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0021</id>
    <name>Consume Spirit</name>
    <text>Spend only black mana on X.
Consume Spirit deals X damage to target creature or player and you gain X life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0022</id>
    <name>Corpse Harvester</name>
    <text>{1}{B}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Search your library for a Zombie card and a Swamp card, reveal them, and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0023</id>
    <name>Cruel Revival</name>
    <text>Destroy target non-Zombie creature. It can't be regenerated. Return up to one target Zombie card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Few Cabal fighters fear death. They fear what follows it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0024</id>
    <name>Dark Ritual</name>
    <text>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"If there is such a thing as too much power, I have not discovered it."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0025</id>
    <name>Death Baron</name>
    <text>Skeleton creatures you control and other Zombie creatures you control get +1/+1 and have deathtouch.</text>
    <flavorText>For the necromancer barons, killing and recruitment are one and the same.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0026</id>
    <name>Dregscape Zombie</name>
    <text>Unearth {B} ({B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>The undead of Grixis are fueled by their hatred of the living.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0027</id>
    <name>Festering Goblin</name>
    <text>When Festering Goblin is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>In life, it was a fetid, disease-ridden thing. In death, not much changed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0028</id>
    <name>Grave Pact</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, each other player sacrifices a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The bonds of loyalty can tie one to the grave."
—Crovax, ascendant evincar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0029</id>
    <name>Gravedigger</name>
    <text>When Gravedigger enters the battlefield, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Oddly, no one questioned the Cabal's wisdom in hiring a zombie to work at the cemetery.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0030</id>
    <name>Helldozer</name>
    <text>{B}{B}{B}, {T}: Destroy target land. If that land was nonbasic, untap Helldozer.</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes you go to hell, and sometimes hell comes to you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0031</id>
    <name>Hideous End</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. Its controller loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"A little dark magic won't stop me. The worse the curse, the better the prize."
—Radavi, Joraga relic hunter, last words</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0032</id>
    <name>Incremental Blight</name>
    <text>Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature, two -1/-1 counters on another target creature, and three -1/-1 counters on a third target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Shadowmoor's main crops are rot, slime, and despair.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0033</id>
    <name>Innocent Blood</name>
    <text>Each player sacrifices a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Zombies mourn for the living and celebrate those who will soon be given the gift of death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0034</id>
    <name>Nefashu</name>
    <text>Whenever Nefashu attacks, up to five target creatures each get -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Where the nefashu pass, blood rolls like a silk carpet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0035</id>
    <name>Noxious Ghoul</name>
    <text>Whenever Noxious Ghoul or another Zombie enters the battlefield, all non-Zombie creatures get -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Plague and death wrapped in one convenient package.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0036</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Arena</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you draw a card and you lose 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>A drop of humanity for a sea of power.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0037</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Ghoul</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: Phyrexian Ghoul gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Phyrexia wastes nothing. Its food chain is a spiraling cycle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0038</id>
    <name>Profane Command</name>
    <text>Choose two — Target player loses X life; or return target creature card with converted mana cost X or less from your graveyard to the battlefield; or target creature gets -X/-X until end of turn; or up to X target creatures gain fear until end of turn. (They can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0039</id>
    <name>Rotting Rats</name>
    <text>When Rotting Rats enters the battlefield, each player discards a card.
Unearth {1}{B} ({1}{B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0040</id>
    <name>Shepherd of Rot</name>
    <text>{T}: Each player loses 1 life for each Zombie on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"My priests swore loyalty to the Cabal not until death, but beyond it."
—Cabal Patriarch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0041</id>
    <name>Soulless One</name>
    <text>Soulless One's power and toughness are each equal to the number of Zombies on the battlefield plus the number of Zombie cards in all graveyards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Surrender your soul to me."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0042</id>
    <name>Syphon Mind</name>
    <text>Each other player discards a card. You draw a card for each card discarded this way.</text>
    <flavorText>When tempers run high, it's easy to lose your head.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0043</id>
    <name>Syphon Soul</name>
    <text>Syphon Soul deals 2 damage to each other player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt this way.</text>
    <flavorText>As Phage drank their energy, a vague memory of Jeska stirred. Then she lost herself again in the joy of her victims' suffering.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0044</id>
    <name>Undead Warchief</name>
    <text>Zombie spells you cast cost {1} less to cast.
Zombie creatures you control get +2/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>It has the strength of seven men. In fact, it used to be seven men.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0045</id>
    <name>Withered Wretch</name>
    <text>{1}: Exile target card from a graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Once it consecrated the dead. Now it desecrates them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0046</id>
    <name>Arc Lightning</name>
    <text>Arc Lightning deals 3 damage divided as you choose among one, two, or three target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>Rainclouds don't last long in Shiv, but that doesn't stop the lightning.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0047</id>
    <name>Blaze</name>
    <text>Blaze deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Fire never dies alone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0048</id>
    <name>Bogardan Firefiend</name>
    <text>When Bogardan Firefiend is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, it deals 2 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The next one who tells me to relax and curl up by a fire is dead."
—Mirri of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0049</id>
    <name>Bogardan Rager</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
When Bogardan Rager enters the battlefield, target creature gets +4/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>In the erupting heart of Bogardan, it's hard to tell hurtling volcanic rocks from pouncing volcanic beasts.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0050</id>
    <name>Browbeat</name>
    <text>Any player may have Browbeat deal 5 damage to him or her. If no one does, target player draws three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Even the threat of power has power."
—Jeska, warrior adept</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0051</id>
    <name>Cinder Elemental</name>
    <text>{X}{R}, {T}, Sacrifice Cinder Elemental: Cinder Elemental deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Their rage can grow to such proportions that they explode in a cloud of fire.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0052</id>
    <name>Cone of Flame</name>
    <text>Cone of Flame deals 1 damage to target creature or player, 2 damage to another target creature or player, and 3 damage to a third target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0053</id>
    <name>Flamekin Harbinger</name>
    <text>When Flamekin Harbinger enters the battlefield, you may search your library for an Elemental card, reveal it, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0054</id>
    <name>Flametongue Kavu</name>
    <text>When Flametongue Kavu enters the battlefield, it deals 4 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"For dim-witted, thick-skulled genetic mutants, they have pretty good aim."
—Sisay, captain of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0055</id>
    <name>Furnace of Rath</name>
    <text>If a source would deal damage to a creature or player, it deals double that damage to that creature or player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>The furnace awaits the next master who would stoke the fires of apocalypse.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0056</id>
    <name>Goblin Offensive</name>
    <text>Put X 1/1 red Goblin creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>They certainly are.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0057</id>
    <name>Insurrection</name>
    <text>Untap all creatures and gain control of them until end of turn. They gain haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Maybe they wanted to be on the winning side for once."
—Matoc, lavamancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0058</id>
    <name>Keldon Champion</name>
    <text>Haste
Echo {2}{R}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Keldon Champion enters the battlefield, it deals 3 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0059</id>
    <name>Menacing Ogre</name>
    <text>Trample, haste
When Menacing Ogre enters the battlefield, each player secretly chooses a number. Then those numbers are revealed. Each player with the highest number loses that much life. If you are one of those players, put two +1/+1 counters on Menacing Ogre.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0060</id>
    <name>Pyrotechnics</name>
    <text>Pyrotechnics deals 4 damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>"Who says lightning never strikes twice?"
—Storm shaman</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0061</id>
    <name>Reckless Charge</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+0 and gains haste until end of turn.
Flashback {2}{R} (You may cast this card from your graveyard for its flashback cost. Then exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0062</id>
    <name>Relentless Assault</name>
    <text>Untap all creatures that attacked this turn. After this main phase, there is an additional combat phase followed by an additional main phase.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mercy? Mercy is for the playground, not the battleground."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0063</id>
    <name>Rockslide Elemental</name>
    <text>First strike
Whenever another creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Rockslide Elemental.</text>
    <flavorText>On Jund, even the landscape is a deadly hunter. Volcanoes, tar pits, and rock slides seem to prey upon the living.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0064</id>
    <name>Rolling Thunder</name>
    <text>Rolling Thunder deals X damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>"Such rage," thought Vhati, gazing up at the thunderhead from the Predator. "It is Greven's mind manifest."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0065</id>
    <name>Rorix Bladewing</name>
    <text>Flying, haste</text>
    <flavorText>In the smoldering ashes of Shiv, a few dragons strive to rebuild their native land. The rest seek any opportunity to restore the broken pride of their race.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0066</id>
    <name>Smokebraider</name>
    <text>{T}: Add two mana in any combination of colors to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast Elemental spells or activate abilities of Elementals.</text>
    <flavorText>"Be silent and listen to your inner fire. Only then can you walk the Path of Flame."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0067</id>
    <name>Taurean Mauler</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
Whenever an opponent casts a spell, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Taurean Mauler.</text>
    <flavorText>The power of a waterfall. The fury of an avalanche. The intellect of a gale-force wind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0068</id>
    <name>Beast Hunt</name>
    <text>Reveal the top three cards of your library. Put all creature cards revealed this way into your hand and the rest into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"Surely we could tame something besides hurdas and pillarfield oxen!"
—Sheyda, Ondu gamekeeper</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0069</id>
    <name>Briarhorn</name>
    <text>Flash
When Briarhorn enters the battlefield, target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.
Evoke {1}{G} (You may cast this spell for its evoke cost. If you do, it's sacrificed when it enters the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0070</id>
    <name>Explosive Vegetation</name>
    <text>Search your library for up to two basic land cards and put them onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Torching Krosa would be pointless. It grows faster than it burns.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0071</id>
    <name>Fertile Ground</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds one mana of any color to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0072</id>
    <name>Fertilid</name>
    <text>Fertilid enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it.
{1}{G}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Fertilid: Target player searches his or her library for a basic land card and puts it onto the battlefield tapped. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0073</id>
    <name>Forgotten Ancient</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a spell, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Forgotten Ancient.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may move any number of +1/+1 counters from Forgotten Ancient onto other creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Its blood is life. Its body is growth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0074</id>
    <name>Ivy Elemental</name>
    <text>Ivy Elemental enters the battlefield with X +1/+1 counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>In the gardens of the centaurs, many travelers have mysteriously vanished while admiring the elaborate topiaries.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0075</id>
    <name>Living Hive</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Living Hive deals combat damage to a player, put that many 1/1 green Insect creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>In its center is a single red ant, a queen that regulates the hive's movements.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0076</id>
    <name>Rampant Growth</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Nature grows solutions to its problems.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0077</id>
    <name>Search for Tomorrow</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.
Suspend 2—{G} (Rather than cast this card from your hand, you may pay {G} and exile it with two time counters on it. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a time counter. When the last is removed, cast it without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0078</id>
    <name>Silverglade Elemental</name>
    <text>When Silverglade Elemental enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a Forest card and put that card onto the battlefield. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0079</id>
    <name>Tornado Elemental</name>
    <text>When Tornado Elemental enters the battlefield, it deals 6 damage to each creature with flying.
You may have Tornado Elemental assign its combat damage as though it weren't blocked.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0080</id>
    <name>Tribal Unity</name>
    <text>Creatures of the creature type of your choice get +X/+X until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Kamahl left the violence of his former life behind him, but he still believes in the power of muscle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0081</id>
    <name>Verdant Force</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each upkeep, put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Left to itself, nature overflows any container, overthrows any restriction, and overreaches any boundary.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0082</id>
    <name>Boros Swiftblade</name>
    <text>Double strike</text>
    <flavorText>When the Boros Legion attacks, swiftblades enter the fray first. They pick off the archers and mages, softening the enemy front before the flame-kin and giants go in.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0083</id>
    <name>Branching Bolt</name>
    <text>Choose one or both — Branching Bolt deals 3 damage to target creature with flying; and/or Branching Bolt deals 3 damage to target creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Lightning lives in everything, in living flesh and growing things. It must be set free."
—Rakka Mar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0084</id>
    <name>Bull Cerodon</name>
    <text>Vigilance, haste</text>
    <flavorText>It holds motionless vigil, watching Naya in silence through the screen of the whitecover. When it senses anything amiss, it launches forward with the uncanny sound of torn fog.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0085</id>
    <name>Captain's Maneuver</name>
    <text>The next X damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn is dealt to another target creature or player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Sisay discovered that the mirrored hull of the Weatherlight could be used as a defensive weapon.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0086</id>
    <name>Cerodon Yearling</name>
    <text>Vigilance, haste</text>
    <flavorText>The unit of measurement used to chart a cerodon's growth is "persons consumed."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0087</id>
    <name>Fires of Yavimaya</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have haste.
Sacrifice Fires of Yavimaya: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0088</id>
    <name>Glory of Warfare</name>
    <text>As long as it's your turn, creatures you control get +2/+0.
As long as it's not your turn, creatures you control get +0/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>"Their hopes dashed on our shields! Their victory slashed by our swords!"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0089</id>
    <name>Hull Breach</name>
    <text>Choose one — Destroy target artifact; or destroy target enchantment; or destroy target artifact and target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"Crovax knows we're coming now," said a grinning Sisay. "I just sent the Predator crashing into his stronghold."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0090</id>
    <name>Lightning Helix</name>
    <text>Lightning Helix deals 3 damage to target creature or player and you gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Though less well-known than its army of soldiers, the Boros Legion's mage-priests are as respected by the innocent as they are hated by the ghosts of the guilty.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0091</id>
    <name>Mage Slayer</name>
    <text>Whenever equipped creature attacks, it deals damage equal to its power to defending player.
Equip {3}</text>
    <flavorText>"When the wielder is strong enough, any sword will do."
—Kresh the Bloodbraided</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0092</id>
    <name>Razia, Boros Archangel</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance, haste
{T}: The next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature you control this turn is dealt to another target creature instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Her sword burns with such brightness that foes avert their eyes and arrows divert their paths.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0093</id>
    <name>Rumbling Slum</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Rumbling Slum deals 1 damage to each player.</text>
    <flavorText>The Orzhov contract the Izzet to animate slum districts and banish them to the wastes. The Gruul adopt them and send them back to the city for vengeance.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0094</id>
    <name>Savage Twister</name>
    <text>Savage Twister deals X damage to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Frozen, we watched the funnel pluck up three of the goats—pook! pook! pook!—before we ran for the wadi."
—Travelogue of Najat</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0095</id>
    <name>Sludge Strider</name>
    <text>Whenever another artifact enters the battlefield under your control or another artifact you control leaves the battlefield, you may pay {1}. If you do, target player loses 1 life and you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Underneath the cities of Esper are cycles of life unseen by those who feed them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0096</id>
    <name>Arsenal Thresher</name>
    <text>As Arsenal Thresher enters the battlefield, you may reveal any number of other artifact cards from your hand. Arsenal Thresher enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it for each card revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0097</id>
    <name>Balefire Liege</name>
    <text>Other red creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other white creatures you control get +1/+1.
Whenever you cast a red spell, Balefire Liege deals 3 damage to target player.
Whenever you cast a white spell, you gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0098</id>
    <name>Battlegate Mimic</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a spell that's both red and white, Battlegate Mimic becomes 4/2 and gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Mimics don't need perfect disguises. They need only the perfect victims: the naive, the young, or the poor of sight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0099</id>
    <name>Boros Guildmage</name>
    <text>({RW} can be paid with either {R} or {W}.)
{1}{R}: Target creature gains haste until end of turn.
{1}{W}: Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0100</id>
    <name>Double Cleave</name>
    <text>Target creature gains double strike until end of turn. (It deals both first-strike and regular combat damage.)</text>
    <flavorText>"When in doubt, kill 'em twice."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0101</id>
    <name>Duergar Hedge-Mage</name>
    <text>When Duergar Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Mountains, you may destroy target artifact.
When Duergar Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Plains, you may destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0102</id>
    <name>Hearthfire Hobgoblin</name>
    <text>Double strike</text>
    <flavorText>Hobgoblins are best left alone. They sharpen their farm implements far more than is necessary for their work in the fields.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0103</id>
    <name>Assault</name>
    <text>Put a 3/3 green Elephant creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0104</id>
    <name>Battery</name>
    <text>Put a 3/3 green Elephant creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0105</id>
    <name>Chaos</name>
    <text>Creatures can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0106</id>
    <name>Order</name>
    <text>Creatures can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0107</id>
    <name>Arcbound Crusher</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever another artifact enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on Arcbound Crusher.
Modular 1 (This enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it. When it's put into a graveyard, you may put its +1/+1 counters on target artifact creature.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0108</id>
    <name>Arcbound Slith</name>
    <text>Whenever Arcbound Slith deals combat damage to a player, put a +1/+1 counter on it.
Modular 1 (This enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it. When it's put into a graveyard, you may put its +1/+1 counters on target artifact creature.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0109</id>
    <name>Boros Signet</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Add {R}{W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Have you ever held a Boros signet? There's a weight to it that belies its size—a weight of strength and of pride."
—Agrus Kos</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0110</id>
    <name>Bosh, Iron Golem</name>
    <text>Trample
{3}{R}, Sacrifice an artifact: Bosh, Iron Golem deals damage equal to the sacrificed artifact's converted mana cost to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>As Glissa searches for the truth about Memnarch, Bosh searches to unearth the secrets of his past.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0111</id>
    <name>Copper Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The elves thought of the myr as minor threats, just as the myr thought of the elves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0112</id>
    <name>Cranial Plating</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +1/+0 for each artifact you control.
{B}{B}: Attach Cranial Plating to target creature you control.
Equip {1} ({1}: Attach to target creature you control. Equip only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0113</id>
    <name>Darksteel Forge</name>
    <text>Artifacts you control are indestructible. ("Destroy" effects and lethal damage don't destroy them.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Did it have this shape upon Mirrodin's creation, or did some inconceivable force shape the unshapable?"
—Pontifex, elder researcher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0114</id>
    <name>Door to Nothingness</name>
    <text>Door to Nothingness enters the battlefield tapped.
{W}{W}{U}{U}{B}{B}{R}{R}{G}{G}, {T}, Sacrifice Door to Nothingness: Target player loses the game.</text>
    <flavorText>"All memory of your existence will be wiped from reality. You will die, and no one will mourn."
—Memnarch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0115</id>
    <name>Etched Oracle</name>
    <text>Sunburst (This enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it for each color of mana spent to cast it.)
{1}, Remove four +1/+1 counters from Etched Oracle: Target player draws three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0116</id>
    <name>Gold Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The leonin thought of the myr as omens, never imagining the sinister fate they foretold.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0117</id>
    <name>Iron Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The goblins didn't think of the myr at all, which allowed the myr to observe everywhere unhindered.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0118</id>
    <name>Leaden Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The Moriok saw the myr as fellow scavengers, never knowing just who the myr were scavenging for.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0119</id>
    <name>Lodestone Myr</name>
    <text>Trample
Tap an untapped artifact you control: Lodestone Myr gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>When necessary, myr can override and control any artificial object, as can their creator.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0120</id>
    <name>Loxodon Warhammer</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +3/+0 and has trample and lifelink. (If the creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker. Damage dealt by the creature also causes its controller to gain that much life.)
Equip {3} ({3}: Attach to target creature you control. Equip only as a sorcery.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0121</id>
    <name>Mask of Memory</name>
    <text>Whenever equipped creature deals combat damage to a player, you may draw two cards. If you do, discard a card.
Equip {1} ({1}: Attach to target creature you control. Equip only as a sorcery. This card enters the battlefield unattached and stays on the battlefield if the creature leaves.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0122</id>
    <name>Myr Enforcer</name>
    <text>Affinity for artifacts (This spell costs {1} less to cast for each artifact you control.)</text>
    <flavorText>Most myr monitor other species. Some myr monitor other myr.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0123</id>
    <name>Nuisance Engine</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Put a 0/1 colorless Pest artifact creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>All Auriok children know the tale, "Bolgri and the Long Day of Squashing."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0124</id>
    <name>Pentad Prism</name>
    <text>Sunburst (This enters the battlefield with a charge counter on it for each color of mana spent to cast it.)
Remove a charge counter from Pentad Prism: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0125</id>
    <name>Pentavus</name>
    <text>Pentavus enters the battlefield with five +1/+1 counters on it.
{1}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Pentavus: Put a 1/1 colorless Pentavite artifact creature token with flying onto the battlefield.
{1}, Sacrifice a Pentavite: Put a +1/+1 counter on Pentavus.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0126</id>
    <name>Relic of Progenitus</name>
    <text>{T}: Target player exiles a card from his or her graveyard.
{1}, Exile Relic of Progenitus: Exile all cards from all graveyards. Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Elves believe the hydra-god Progenitus sleeps beneath Naya, feeding on forgotten magics.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0127</id>
    <name>Serum Tank</name>
    <text>Whenever Serum Tank or another artifact enters the battlefield, put a charge counter on Serum Tank.
{3}, {T}, Remove a charge counter from Serum Tank: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0128</id>
    <name>Silver Myr</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The vedalken saw the myr as toys, unaware of the intelligence lurking behind their empty eyes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0129</id>
    <name>Skeleton Shard</name>
    <text>{3}, {T} or {B}, {T}: Return target artifact creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Metal permeates the marrow of every bone in Mephidross—except one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0130</id>
    <name>Suntouched Myr</name>
    <text>Sunburst (This enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it for each color of mana spent to cast it.)</text>
    <flavorText>As the fifth sun joins the other four, new abilities awaken in the creatures of Mirrodin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0131</id>
    <name>Wizard Replica</name>
    <text>Flying
{U}, Sacrifice Wizard Replica: Counter target spell unless its controller pays {2}.</text>
    <flavorText>It responds with unnatural precision.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0132</id>
    <name>Ancient Den</name>
    <text>(Ancient Den isn't a spell.)
{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Taj-Nar, throne of Raksha Golden Cub, destined leader of the leonin prides.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0133</id>
    <name>Boros Garrison</name>
    <text>Boros Garrison enters the battlefield tapped.
When Boros Garrison enters the battlefield, return a land you control to its owner's hand.
{T}: Add {R}{W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0134</id>
    <name>Cabal Coffers</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Add {B} to your mana pool for each Swamp you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Deep within the Cabal's vault, the Mirari pulsed like a dead sun—and its darkness radiated across Otaria.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0135</id>
    <name>Great Furnace</name>
    <text>(Great Furnace isn't a spell.)
{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Kuldotha, wellspring of molten metal, temple of the goblin horde.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0136</id>
    <name>Gruul Turf</name>
    <text>Gruul Turf enters the battlefield tapped.
When Gruul Turf enters the battlefield, return a land you control to its owner's hand.
{T}: Add {R}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0137</id>
    <name>Leechridden Swamp</name>
    <text>({T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.)
Leechridden Swamp enters the battlefield tapped.
{B}, {T}: Each opponent loses 1 life. Activate this ability only if you control two or more black permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0138</id>
    <name>Seat of the Synod</name>
    <text>(Seat of the Synod isn't a spell.)
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Lumengrid, site of the Knowledge Pool, source of vedalken arcana.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0139</id>
    <name>Shivan Oasis</name>
    <text>Shivan Oasis enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Only the hardiest explorers survive to eat the fruit.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0140</id>
    <name>Sunhome, Fortress of the Legion</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{2}{R}{W}, {T}: Target creature gains double strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Sunhome—the stalwart shield, the towering sentinel, the seat of justice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0141</id>
    <name>Terramorphic Expanse</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Terramorphic Expanse: Search your library for a basic land card and put it onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0142</id>
    <name>Tree of Tales</name>
    <text>(Tree of Tales isn't a spell.)
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Tel-Jilad, sanctum of the ancient trolls, keepers of the secret of Mirrodin's origin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0143</id>
    <name>Vault of Whispers</name>
    <text>(Vault of Whispers isn't a spell.)
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Ish Sah, den of the warlord Geth, commander of countless nim.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0144</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0145</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0146</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0147</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0148</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0149</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0150</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0151</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0152</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0153</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0154</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0155</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0156</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0157</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0158</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0159</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0160</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0161</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0162</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0163</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0164</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0165</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0166</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0167</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0168</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0169</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0170</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>HOP0171</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>