<cards name="Masters Edition III">
  <item>
    <id>ME30001</id>
    <name>Akron Legionnaire</name>
    <text>Except for creatures named Akron Legionnaire and artifact creatures, creatures you control can't attack.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30002</id>
    <name>Alabaster Potion</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target player gains X life; or prevent the next X damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Healing is a matter of time, but it is sometimes also a matter of opportunity."
—D'Avenant proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30003</id>
    <name>Amrou Kithkin</name>
    <text>Amrou Kithkin can't be blocked by creatures with power 3 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>Quick and agile, Amrou Kithkin can usually escape from even the most fearsome opponents.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30004</id>
    <name>Call to Arms</name>
    <text>As Call to Arms enters the battlefield, choose a color and an opponent.
White creatures get +1/+1 as long as the chosen color is the most common color among nontoken permanents the chosen player controls but isn't tied for most common.
When the chosen color isn't the most common color among nontoken permanents the chosen player controls or is tied for most common, sacrifice Call to Arms.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30005</id>
    <name>Cleanse</name>
    <text>Destroy all black creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>The clouds broke and the sun's rays burst forth; each foul beast in its turn faltered, and was gone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30006</id>
    <name>D'Avenant Archer</name>
    <text>{T}: D'Avenant Archer deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Avenant's archers are also trained as poets, so that each arrow is guided by a fragment of verse.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30007</id>
    <name>Divine Intervention</name>
    <text>Divine Intervention enters the battlefield with two intervention counters on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, remove an intervention counter from Divine Intervention.
When you remove the last intervention counter from Divine Intervention, the game is a draw.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30008</id>
    <name>Eightfold Maze</name>
    <text>Cast Eightfold Maze only during the declare attackers step and only if you've been attacked this step.
Destroy target attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30009</id>
    <name>Disenchant</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30010</id>
    <name>Disenchant</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30011</id>
    <name>Exorcist</name>
    <text>{1}{W}, {T}: Destroy target black creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Though they often bore little greater charm than the demons they battled, exorcists were always welcome in Scarwood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30012</id>
    <name>False Defeat</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"All warfare is based on deception."
—Sun Tzu, Art of War (trans. Giles)</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30013</id>
    <name>Guan Yu, Sainted Warrior</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)
When Guan Yu, Sainted Warrior is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, you may shuffle Guan Yu into your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30014</id>
    <name>Guan Yu's 1,000-Li March</name>
    <text>Destroy all tapped creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"He Guan Yu covered the ground on a thousand-li horse;/ With dragon blade he took each pass by force."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30015</id>
    <name>Heal</name>
    <text>Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"Sometimes even the smallest boon can save a life."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30016</id>
    <name>Ivory Guardians</name>
    <text>Protection from red
Creatures named Ivory Guardians get +1/+1 as long as an opponent controls a nontoken red permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>The elite guard of the Mesa High Priests, the Ivory Guardians, were created to protect the innocent and faithful. Some say their actions are above the law.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30017</id>
    <name>Kongming, "Sleeping Dragon"</name>
    <text>Other creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>"Such a lord as this—all virtues' height—Had never been, nor ever was again."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30018</id>
    <name>Land Tax</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if an opponent controls more lands than you, you may search your library for up to three basic land cards, reveal them, and put them into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30019</id>
    <name>Lightning Blow</name>
    <text>Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you do it right, they'll never know what hit them."
—General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30020</id>
    <name>Liu Bei, Lord of Shu</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)
Liu Bei, Lord of Shu gets +2/+2 as long as you control a permanent named Guan Yu, Sainted Warrior or a permanent named Zhang Fei, Fierce Warrior.</text>
    <flavorText>"Only wisdom and virtue can truly win men's devotion."
—Liu Bei</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30021</id>
    <name>Loyal Retainers</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Loyal Retainers: Return target legendary creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield. Activate this ability only during your turn, before attackers are declared.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30022</id>
    <name>Misfortune's Gain</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature. Its owner gains 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The mourning families of commanders and generals were often given land, valuables, or money to compensate for their losses.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30023</id>
    <name>Peach Garden Oath</name>
    <text>You gain 2 life for each creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"We three, though of separate ancestry, join in brotherhood. . . . We dare not hope to be together always but hereby vow to die the selfsame day."
—Peach Garden Oath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30024</id>
    <name>Shu Cavalry</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)</text>
    <flavorText>In establishing the Shu kingdom, Liu Bei's forces fought against Ma Chao at Chengdu. Eventually, Ma Chao surrendered and became one of Liu Bei's Tiger Generals.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30025</id>
    <name>Shu Elite Companions</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)</text>
    <flavorText>Throughout the three kingdoms, important generals were often guarded by small groups of expert soldiers known as "elite companions."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30026</id>
    <name>Shu General</name>
    <text>Vigilance; horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30027</id>
    <name>Shu Soldier-Farmers</name>
    <text>When Shu Soldier-Farmers enters the battlefield, you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>During Kongming's campaigns against the Wei, his Shu troops rotated from the battlefront to the fields every hundred days.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30028</id>
    <name>Wall of Light</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Protection from black</text>
    <flavorText>As many attackers were dazzled by the wall's beauty as were halted by its force.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30029</id>
    <name>Zhang Fei, Fierce Warrior</name>
    <text>Vigilance; horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)</text>
    <flavorText>Zhang Fei's uncharacteristic alliance with a defeated Riverlands general, Yan Yan, allowed Shu forces to advance through forty-five Riverlands strongpoints with no casualties.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30030</id>
    <name>Benthic Explorers</name>
    <text>{T}, Untap a tapped land an opponent controls: Add one mana of any type that land could produce to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The rising oceans brought new lakes—and new terrors—to Terisiare. The Explorers found their ancient enemies spawning everywhere.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30031</id>
    <name>Boomerang</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"O! call back yesterday, bid time return."
—William Shakespeare, King Richard the Second</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30032</id>
    <name>Borrowing 100,000 Arrows</name>
    <text>Draw a card for each tapped creature target opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Kongming and Lu Su tricked Wei troops into shooting over 100,000 arrows at them to later use against the Wei at Red Cliffs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30033</id>
    <name>Brilliant Plan</name>
    <text>Draw three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>At Red Cliffs, Kongming and Zhou Yu each wrote his plan for defeating Wei on the palm of his hand. They laughed as they both revealed the same word, "Fire."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30034</id>
    <name>Capture of Jingzhou</name>
    <text>Take an extra turn after this one.</text>
    <flavorText>The province of Jingzhou was the fulcrum of the three kingdoms. At separate times it was coveted and controlled by the Wu, the Shu, and the Wei.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30035</id>
    <name>Dance of Many</name>
    <text>When Dance of Many enters the battlefield, put a token that's a copy of target nontoken creature onto the battlefield.
When Dance of Many leaves the battlefield, exile the token.
When the token leaves the battlefield, sacrifice Dance of Many.
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Dance of Many unless you pay {U}{U}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30036</id>
    <name>Flash Flood</name>
    <text>Choose one — Destroy target red permanent; or return target Mountain to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Many people say that no power can bring the mountains low. Many people are fools.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30037</id>
    <name>Force Spike</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30038</id>
    <name>Forced Retreat</name>
    <text>Put target creature on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Leadership, not numbers, determines victory."
—A Wu commander, before his 5,000 troops forced 15,000 Wei troops to retreat from Ruxu</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30039</id>
    <name>Infuse</name>
    <text>Untap target artifact, creature, or land.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"The potential for change lies in all things. Know a thing's nature, know its possibilities, and know it anew."
—Gustha Ebbasdotter, Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30040</id>
    <name>Labyrinth Minotaur</name>
    <text>Whenever Labyrinth Minotaur blocks a creature, that creature doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>"I doubt any labyrinth minotaurs still live—but then again, we minotaurs are stubborn beings."
—Onatah, Anaba Shaman</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30041</id>
    <name>Land Equilibrium</name>
    <text>If an opponent who controls at least as many lands as you do would put a land onto the battlefield, that player instead puts that land onto the battlefield then sacrifices a land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30042</id>
    <name>Lu Meng, Wu General</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)</text>
    <flavorText>As the Wu chief commander, Lu Meng conquered Shu-held Jingzhou in 219 by disguising soldiers as merchants on boats filled with hiding troops.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30043</id>
    <name>Lu Xun, Scholar General</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)
Whenever Lu Xun, Scholar General deals damage to an opponent, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30044</id>
    <name>Mana Drain</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. At the beginning of your next main phase, add {X} to your mana pool, where X is that spell's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30045</id>
    <name>Mana Vortex</name>
    <text>When you cast Mana Vortex, you may sacrifice a land. If you don't, counter Mana Vortex.
At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player sacrifices a land.
When there are no lands on the battlefield, sacrifice Mana Vortex.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30046</id>
    <name>Old Man of the Sea</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Old Man of the Sea during your untap step.
{T}: Gain control of target creature with power less than or equal to Old Man of the Sea's power for as long as Old Man of the Sea remains tapped and that creature's power remains less than or equal to Old Man of the Sea's power.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30047</id>
    <name>Recall</name>
    <text>Discard X cards, then return a card from your graveyard to your hand for each card discarded this way. Exile Recall.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30048</id>
    <name>Remove Soul</name>
    <text>Counter target creature spell.</text>
    <flavorText>Nethya stiffened suddenly, head cocked as if straining to hear some distant sound, then felt lifeless to the ground.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30049</id>
    <name>Reset</name>
    <text>Cast Reset only during an opponent's turn after his or her upkeep step.
Untap all lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30050</id>
    <name>Reveka, Wizard Savant</name>
    <text>{T}: Reveka, Wizard Savant deals 2 damage to target creature or player and doesn't untap during your next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's nice to see a sister Dwarf in a position of such power, but why'd it have to be one of those seafaring muleheads?"
—Halina, Dwarven Trader</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30051</id>
    <name>Spiny Starfish</name>
    <text>{U}: Regenerate Spiny Starfish.
At the beginning of each end step, if Spiny Starfish regenerated this turn, put a 0/1 blue Starfish creature token onto the battlefield for each time it regenerated this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30052</id>
    <name>Strategic Planning</name>
    <text>Look at the top three cards of your library. Put one of them into your hand and the rest into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"Plans evolved within the tent decide a victory 1,000 li away."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30053</id>
    <name>Sun Ce, Young Conquerer</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)
When Sun Ce, Young Conquerer enters the battlefield, you may return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30054</id>
    <name>Sun Quan, Lord of Wu</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have horsemanship. (They can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)</text>
    <flavorText>"One score and four he reigned, the Southland king: / A dragon coiled, a tiger poised below the mighty Yangtze."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30055</id>
    <name>Wu Elite Cavalry</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)</text>
    <flavorText>At the second battle of Ruxu, the brave Wu general Gan Ning raided Cao Cao's camp of 400,000 men with only 100 cavalry. Not a single man or horse was lost.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30056</id>
    <name>Wu Longbowman</name>
    <text>{T}: Wu Longbowman deals 1 damage to target creature or player. Activate this ability only during your turn, before attackers are declared.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30057</id>
    <name>Wu Warship</name>
    <text>Wu Warship can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.</text>
    <flavorText>Both Wu and Wei warships patrolled the Yangtze River, the natural border between the two kingdoms.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30058</id>
    <name>All Hallow's Eve</name>
    <text>Exile All Hallow's Eve with two scream counters on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, if All Hallow's Eve is exiled with a scream counter on it, remove a scream counter from it. If there are no more scream counters on it, put it into your graveyard and each player returns all creature cards from his or her graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30059</id>
    <name>Ashes to Ashes</name>
    <text>Exile two target nonartifact creatures. Ashes to Ashes deals 5 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"All rivers eventually run to the sea. My job is to sort out who goes first."
—Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30060</id>
    <name>Banshee</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: Banshee deals half X damage, rounded down, to target creature or player, and half X damage, rounded up, to you.</text>
    <flavorText>Some say Banshees are the hounds of Death, baying to herd their prey into the arms of their master.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30061</id>
    <name>Carrion Ants</name>
    <text>{1}: Carrion Ants gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"‘War is no picnic,' my father liked to say. But the ants seemed to disagree."
—General Chanek Valteroth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30062</id>
    <name>Cosmic Horror</name>
    <text>First strike
At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy Cosmic Horror unless you pay {3}{B}{B}{B}. If Cosmic Horror is destroyed this way, it deals 7 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"Then flashed the living lightning from her eyes,/ And screams of horror rend th' affrighted skies."
—Alexander Pope, The Rape of the Lock</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30063</id>
    <name>Demonic Torment</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack.
Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30064</id>
    <name>Desperate Charge</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Lieutenants dishonored, corpses carted home; The general raises troops again to take revenge."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30065</id>
    <name>Evil Presence</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Enchanted land is a Swamp.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30066</id>
    <name>Famine</name>
    <text>Famine deals 3 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>"But it was a year of dearth. People were reduced to eating leaves of jujube trees. Corpses were seen everywhere in the countryside."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30067</id>
    <name>Fevered Strength</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +2/+0 until end of turn.

Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>"The burst of strength brought on by this plague should not be mistaken for a sign of renewed health."
—Kolbjörn, High Honored Druid</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30068</id>
    <name>Ghostly Visit</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Cao Cao was haunted to death by the ghosts of the empresses and other high courtiers he had murdered.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30069</id>
    <name>Ghosts of the Damned</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets -1/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The voices of the dead ring in the heart long after they have faded from the ears.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30070</id>
    <name>Grim Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for a card and put that card into your hand, then shuffle your library. You lose 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>One who goes unpunished never learns.
—Greek proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30071</id>
    <name>Hellfire</name>
    <text>Destroy all nonblack creatures. Hellfire deals X plus 3 damage to you, where X is the number of creatures put into all graveyards this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"High on a throne of royal state . . . insatiate to pursue vain war with heav'n." —John Milton, Paradise Lost</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30072</id>
    <name>Lesser Werewolf</name>
    <text>{B}: If Lesser Werewolf's power is 1 or more, it gets -1/-0 until end of turn and put a -0/-1 counter on target creature blocking or blocked by Lesser Werewolf. Activate this ability only during the declare blockers step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30073</id>
    <name>Mind Twist</name>
    <text>Target player discards X cards at random.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30074</id>
    <name>Nether Void</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a spell, counter it unless its controller pays {3}.</text>
    <flavorText>These days, some wizards are finding that they have a little too much spell left at the end of their mana.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30075</id>
    <name>Spirit Shackle</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature becomes tapped, put a -0/-2 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30076</id>
    <name>Stolen Grain</name>
    <text>Stolen Grain deals 5 damage to target opponent. You gain 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>At the battle of Guandu, Cao Cao defeated Yuan Shao by raiding his grain depot, leaving him with no way to feed his troops.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30077</id>
    <name>Takklemaggot</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, put a -0/-1 counter on that creature.
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, that creature's controller chooses a creature that Takklemaggot could enchant. If he or she does, return Takklemaggot to the battlefield under your control attached to that creature. If he or she doesn't, return Takklemaggot to the battlefield under your control as a non-Aura enchantment. It loses "enchant creature" and gains "At the beginning of that player's upkeep, Takklemaggot deals 1 damage to him or her."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30078</id>
    <name>The Abyss</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, destroy target nonartifact creature that player controls of his or her choice. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"An immense river of oblivion is sweeping us away into a nameless abyss." —Ernest Renan, Souvenirs d'Enfance et de Jeunesse</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30079</id>
    <name>The Wretched</name>
    <text>At end of combat, gain control of all creatures blocking The Wretched for as long as you control The Wretched.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30080</id>
    <name>Wei Elite Companions</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)</text>
    <flavorText>Cao Cao was more concerned with capabilities than lineage. He excelled at recruiting and retaining men of talent to serve him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30081</id>
    <name>Wei Infantry</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Wei won the battle of Hefei when Zhang Liao defeated Sun Quan and then foiled a Wu scheme to incite rebellion.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30082</id>
    <name>Wei Night Raiders</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)
Whenever Wei Night Raiders deals damage to an opponent, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30083</id>
    <name>Wei Strike Force</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)</text>
    <flavorText>At the battle of Chang'an, Ma Chao defeated the two generals Cao Cao sent to guard the pass but was forced to flee when Cao Cao's trickery turned his own ally against him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30084</id>
    <name>Xiahou Dun, the One-Eyed</name>
    <text>Horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)
Sacrifice Xiahou Dun, the One-Eyed: Return target black card from your graveyard to your hand. Activate this ability only during your turn, before attackers are declared.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30085</id>
    <name>Young Wei Recruits</name>
    <text>Young Wei Recruits can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>"To send the common people to war untrained is to throw them away."
—Confucius, The Analects (trans. Lau)</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30086</id>
    <name>Active Volcano</name>
    <text>Choose one — Destroy target blue permanent; or return target Island to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30087</id>
    <name>Anaba Ancestor</name>
    <text>{T}: Another target Minotaur creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Ancestors are the wisdom of the tribe and the soul of the Homelands. I am eternally in their debt."
—Taysir</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30088</id>
    <name>Anaba Spirit Crafter</name>
    <text>Minotaur creatures get +1/+0.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Spirit Crafters sing of all our people. They sing of those lost, of those found, and of those who are yet to be."
—Onatah, Anaba Shaman</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30089</id>
    <name>Blood Lust</name>
    <text>If target creature has toughness 5 or greater, it gets +4/-4 until end of turn. Otherwise, it gets +4/-X until end of turn, where X is its toughness minus 1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30090</id>
    <name>Burning of Xinye</name>
    <text>You destroy four lands you control, then target opponent destroys four lands he or she controls. Then Burning of Xinye deals 4 damage to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30091</id>
    <name>Chain Lightning</name>
    <text>Chain Lightning deals 3 damage to target creature or player. Then that player or that creature's controller may pay {R}{R}. If the player does, he or she may copy this spell and may choose a new target for that copy.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30092</id>
    <name>Cinder Storm</name>
    <text>Cinder Storm deals 7 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>When the sky's rain has turned to fire, what will put it out?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30093</id>
    <name>Corrupt Eunuchs</name>
    <text>When Corrupt Eunuchs enters the battlefield, it deals 2 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30094</id>
    <name>Crimson Kobolds</name>
    <text>Crimson Kobolds is red.</text>
    <flavorText>"Kobolds are harmless."
—Bearand the Bold, epitaph</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30095</id>
    <name>Crimson Manticore</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}, {T}: Crimson Manticore deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Noted neither for their good looks nor their charm, manticores can be fearsome allies. As dinner companions, however, they are best left alone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30096</id>
    <name>Disharmony</name>
    <text>Cast Disharmony only during combat before blockers are declared.
Untap target attacking creature and remove it from combat. Gain control of that creature until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30097</id>
    <name>Dong Zhou, the Tyrant</name>
    <text>When Dong Zhou, the Tyrant enters the battlefield, target creature an opponent controls deals damage equal to its power to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30098</id>
    <name>Fire Ambush</name>
    <text>Fire Ambush deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"With fire he broke the battle at Bowang . . . . Striking fear deep into Cao Cao's soul, thus Kongming scored a coup at his debut."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30099</id>
    <name>Fire Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}: Fire Drake gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Brimstone marks this drake's territory. Unfortunately for travelers, all of the Burning Isles smell likewise.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30100</id>
    <name>Firestorm Phoenix</name>
    <text>Flying
If Firestorm Phoenix would be put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Firestorm Phoenix to its owner's hand instead. Until that player's next turn, that player plays with that card revealed in his or her hand and can't play it.</text>
    <flavorText>"The bird of wonder dies, the maiden phoenix,/ Her ashes new-create another heir/ As great in admiration as herself."
—William Shakespeare, King Henry the Eighth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30101</id>
    <name>Forked Lightning</name>
    <text>Forked Lightning deals 4 damage divided as you choose among one, two, or three target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30102</id>
    <name>Frost Giant</name>
    <text>Rampage 2 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</text>
    <flavorText>The frost giants have been out in the cold a long, long time, but they have their rage to keep them warm.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30103</id>
    <name>Hurloon Minotaur</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The minotaurs of the Hurloon Mountains are known for their love of battle. They are also known for their hymns to the dead, sung for friend and foe alike. These hymns can last for days, filling the mountain valleys with their low, haunting sounds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30104</id>
    <name>Immolation</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/-2.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30105</id>
    <name>Kobold Drill Sergeant</name>
    <text>Other Kobold creatures you control get +0/+1 and have trample.</text>
    <flavorText>"Joining this army is easy, boy. Just survive your first battle."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30106</id>
    <name>Kobold Overlord</name>
    <text>First strike
Other Kobold creatures you control have first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>"One for all, all for one; we strike first, and then you're done!" —Oath of the Kobold Musketeers</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30107</id>
    <name>Kobold Taskmaster</name>
    <text>Other Kobold creatures you control get +1/+0.</text>
    <flavorText>The Taskmaster knows that there is no cure for the common Kobold.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30108</id>
    <name>Kobolds of Kher Keep</name>
    <text>Kobolds of Kher Keep is red.</text>
    <flavorText>Kher Keep is unique among fortresses: impervious to aerial assault but defenseless from the ground.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30109</id>
    <name>Lu Bu, Master-at-Arms</name>
    <text>Haste; horsemanship (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Dong Zhuo's man, Lu Bu, warrior without peer,/ Far surpassed the champions of his sphere."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30110</id>
    <name>Raging Minotaur</name>
    <text>Haste</text>
    <flavorText>The only thing worse than a minotaur with an axe is an angry minotaur with an axe.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30111</id>
    <name>Rolling Earthquake</name>
    <text>Rolling Earthquake deals X damage to each creature without horsemanship and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30112</id>
    <name>Storm World</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Storm World deals X damage to that player, where X is 4 minus the number of cards in his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30113</id>
    <name>Zodiac Dragon</name>
    <text>When Zodiac Dragon is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, you may return it to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>". . . The kingdoms three are now the stuff of dream,/ For men to ponder, past all praise or blame."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30114</id>
    <name>Arboria</name>
    <text>Creatures can't attack a player unless that player cast a spell or put a nontoken permanent onto the battlefield during his or her last turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30115</id>
    <name>Concordant Crossroads</name>
    <text>All creatures have haste.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30116</id>
    <name>Desert Twister</name>
    <text>Destroy target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30117</id>
    <name>Elves of Deep Shadow</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool. Elves of Deep Shadow deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>They are aberrations who have turned on everything we hold sacred. Let them be cast out."
—Ailheen, Speaker of the Council</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30118</id>
    <name>Faerie Noble</name>
    <text>Flying
Other Faerie creatures you control get +0/+1.
{T}: Other Faerie creatures you control get +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Faeries talk all in riddles and tricky bits, ‘cept the Nobles. Now, there's some straight talkers."
—Joskun, An-Havva Constable</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30119</id>
    <name>Fire Sprites</name>
    <text>Flying
{G}, {T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30120</id>
    <name>Freyalise's Winds</name>
    <text>Whenever a permanent becomes tapped, put a wind counter on it.
If a permanent with a wind counter on it would untap during its controller's untap step, remove all wind counters from it instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30121</id>
    <name>Gaea's Touch</name>
    <text>You may play an additional land during your turn if that land is a basic Forest.

Sacrifice Gaea's Touch: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30122</id>
    <name>Heavy Fog</name>
    <text>Cast Heavy Fog only during the declare attackers step and only if you've been attacked this step.
Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you this turn by attacking creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30123</id>
    <name>Hua Tuo, Honored Physician</name>
    <text>{T}: Put target creature card from your graveyard on top of your library. Activate this ability only during your turn, before attackers are declared.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30124</id>
    <name>Hunting Cheetah</name>
    <text>Whenever Hunting Cheetah deals damage to an opponent, you may search your library for a Forest card, reveal that card, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30125</id>
    <name>Jungle Lion</name>
    <text>Jungle Lion can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>The lion's only loyalty is to its hunger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30126</id>
    <name>Killer Bees</name>
    <text>Flying
{G}: Killer Bees gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The communal mind produces a savage strategy, yet no one could predict that this vicious crossbreed would unravel the secret of steel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30127</id>
    <name>Living Plane</name>
    <text>All lands are 1/1 creatures that are still lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30128</id>
    <name>Meng Huo, Barbarian King</name>
    <text>Other green creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>The stubborn Meng Huo was captured and released by Kongming seven times before finally surrendering.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30129</id>
    <name>Scryb Sprites</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>The only sound was the gentle clicking of the faeries' wings. Then those intruders who were still standing turned and fled. One thing was certain: they didn't think the scryb were very funny anymore.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30130</id>
    <name>Scryb Sprites</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>The only sound was the gentle clicking of the faeries' wings. Then those intruders who were still standing turned and fled. One thing was certain: they didn't think the scryb were very funny anymore.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30131</id>
    <name>Meng Huo's Horde</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Through his allies, Meng Huo commanded several hundred thousand troops composed of cavalry, rattan-armored warriors, infantry, naked men with swords, and wild animals.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30132</id>
    <name>Reincarnation</name>
    <text>Choose target creature. When that creature is put into a graveyard this turn, return a creature card from that graveyard to the battlefield under the control of that creature's owner.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30133</id>
    <name>Riding the Dilu Horse</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +2/+2 and gains horsemanship. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship. This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>"All men have their appointed time; that's something no horse can change."
—Liu Bei, after being told that the Dilu brings its master ill fortune</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30134</id>
    <name>Slashing Tiger</name>
    <text>Whenever Slashing Tiger becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Unless you enter the tiger's lair, you cannot get hold of the tiger's cubs."
—Sun Tzu, Art of War (trans. Giles)</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30135</id>
    <name>Spoils of Victory</name>
    <text>Search your library for a Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, or Forest card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30136</id>
    <name>Three Visits</name>
    <text>Search your library for a Forest card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Trying to meet a worthy man in the wrong way is as bad as closing the door on an invited guest."
—Mencius, a Chinese philosopher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30137</id>
    <name>Tracker</name>
    <text>{G}{G}, {T}: Tracker deals damage equal to its power to target creature. That creature deals damage equal to its power to Tracker.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30138</id>
    <name>Trip Wire</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature with horsemanship.</text>
    <flavorText>Trip wire, hooked poles, and sunken pits were commonly used to unhorse riders during the Three Kingdoms period.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30139</id>
    <name>Willow Priestess</name>
    <text>{T}: You may put a Faerie permanent card from your hand onto the battlefield.
{2}{G}: Target green creature gains protection from black until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those of faith are those of strength."
—Autumn Willow</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30140</id>
    <name>Willow Satyr</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Willow Satyr during your untap step.
{T}: Gain control of target legendary creature for as long as you control Willow Satyr and Willow Satyr remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30141</id>
    <name>Wormwood Treefolk</name>
    <text>{G}{G}: Wormwood Treefolk gains forestwalk until end of turn and deals 2 damage to you.
{B}{B}: Wormwood Treefolk gains swampwalk until end of turn and deals 2 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30142</id>
    <name>Angus Mackenzie</name>
    <text>{G}{W}{U}, {T}: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn. Activate this ability only before the combat damage step.</text>
    <flavorText>"Battles no longer served a purpose in Karakas." —Angus Mackenzie, Diary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30143</id>
    <name>Arcades Sabboth</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Arcades Sabboth unless you pay {G}{W}{U}.
Each untapped creature you control gets +0/+2 as long as it's not attacking.
{W}: Arcades Sabboth gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30144</id>
    <name>Axelrod Gunnarson</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever a creature dealt damage by Axelrod Gunnarson this turn is put into a graveyard, you gain 1 life and Axelrod deals 1 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30145</id>
    <name>Barktooth Warbeard</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>He is devious and cunning, in both appearance and deed. Beware the Warbeard, for this brute bites as well as he barks!</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30146</id>
    <name>Bartel Runeaxe</name>
    <text>Vigilance
Bartel Runeaxe can't be the target of Aura spells.</text>
    <flavorText>Thundering down from Hammerheim, no foe could slow Bartel's charge.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30147</id>
    <name>Boris Devilboon</name>
    <text>{2}{B}{R}, {T}: Put a 1/1 black and red Demon creature token named Minor Demon onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30148</id>
    <name>Chromium</name>
    <text>Flying
Rampage 2 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Chromium unless you pay {W}{U}{B}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30149</id>
    <name>Gabriel Angelfire</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, choose flying, first strike, trample, or rampage 3. Gabriel Angelfire gains that ability until your next upkeep. (Whenever a creature with rampage 3 becomes blocked, it gets +3/+3 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30150</id>
    <name>Gwendlyn Di Corci</name>
    <text>{T}: Target player discards a card at random. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Urborg became the final resting place of many swordsmen of renown, their steel outmatched by the wiles of Gwendlyn.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30151</id>
    <name>Halfdane</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Halfdane's power and toughness become equal to the power and toughness of target creature other than Halfdane until the end of your next upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>Hail from Tolaria the ever changing 'Dane.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30152</id>
    <name>Hazezon Tamar</name>
    <text>When Hazezon Tamar enters the battlefield, put X 1/1 Sand Warrior creature tokens that are red, green, and white onto the battlefield at the beginning of your next upkeep, where X is the number of lands you control at that time.
When Hazezon leaves the battlefield, exile all Sand Warriors.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30153</id>
    <name>Hunding Gjornersen</name>
    <text>Rampage 1 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</text>
    <flavorText>"You would never guess, at the terrifying sight of the man, that Hunding was as charming a companion as one could wish for."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30154</id>
    <name>Jedit Ojanen</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Mightiest of the cat warriors, Jedit Ojanen forsook the forests of his tribe and took service with the Robaran Mercenaries, rising through their ranks to lead them in the battle for Efrava.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30155</id>
    <name>Jerrard of the Closed Fist</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Once, the order of the Closed Fist reached throughout the Kb'Briann Highlands. Now, Jerrard alone remains to uphold their standard.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30156</id>
    <name>Kei Takahashi</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30157</id>
    <name>Kjeldoran Frostbeast</name>
    <text>At end of combat, destroy all creatures blocking or blocked by Kjeldoran Frostbeast.</text>
    <flavorText>"Two of my Warriors found that the creature was dangerous not only in combat, but also in simple proximity."
—Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30158</id>
    <name>Lady Caleria</name>
    <text>{T}: Lady Caleria deals 3 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30159</id>
    <name>Lady Evangela</name>
    <text>{W}{B}, {T}: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"When milady was young, the sight of a rainbow would fill her soul with peace. As she grew, she learned to share her rapture with others."
—Lady Gabriella</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30160</id>
    <name>Lady Orca</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"I do not remember what he said to her. I remember her fiery eyes, fixed upon him for an instant. I remember a flash, and the hot breath of sudden flames made me turn away. When I looked again, Angus was gone."
—A Wayfarer, on meeting Lady Orca</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30161</id>
    <name>Livonya Silone</name>
    <text>First strike, legendary landwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Livonya's own nature is a matter of mystery. Nothing is known for sure, merely rumors of unearthly stealth, and unholy alliances.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30162</id>
    <name>Marhault Elsdragon</name>
    <text>Rampage 1 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</text>
    <flavorText>Marhault Elsdragon follows a strict philosophy, never letting emotions cloud his thoughts. No chance observer could imagine the rage in his heart.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30163</id>
    <name>Nebuchadnezzar</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: Name a card. Target opponent reveals X cards at random from his or her hand. Then that player discards all cards with that name revealed this way. Activate this ability only during your turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30164</id>
    <name>Nicol Bolas</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Nicol Bolas unless you pay {U}{B}{R}.
Whenever Nicol Bolas deals damage to an opponent, that player discards his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30165</id>
    <name>Palladia-Mors</name>
    <text>Flying, trample
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Palladia-Mors unless you pay {R}{G}{W}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30166</id>
    <name>Pavel Maliki</name>
    <text>{B}{R}: Pavel Maliki gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>We all know the legend: Pavel wanders the realms, helping those in greatest need. But is this a measure of his generosity, or of his obligation to atone?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30167</id>
    <name>Princess Lucrezia</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30168</id>
    <name>Giant Growth</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30169</id>
    <name>Giant Growth</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30170</id>
    <name>Ragnar</name>
    <text>{G}{W}{U}, {T}: Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"On the field of honor, a soldier need have no fear."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30171</id>
    <name>Ramirez DePietro</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>Ramirez DePietro is a most flamboyant pirate. Be careful not to believe his tall tales, especially when you ask his age.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30172</id>
    <name>Ramses Overdark</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30173</id>
    <name>Rasputin Dreamweaver</name>
    <text>Rasputin Dreamweaver enters the battlefield with seven dream counters on it.
Remove a dream counter from Rasputin: Add {1} to your mana pool.
Remove a dream counter from Rasputin: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to Rasputin this turn.
At the beginning of your upkeep, if Rasputin started the turn untapped, put a dream counter on it.
Rasputin can't have more than seven dream counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30174</id>
    <name>Riven Turnbull</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Political violence is a perfectly legitimate answer to the persecution handed down by dignitaries of the state."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30175</id>
    <name>Rohgahh of Kher Keep</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {R}{R}{R}. If you don't, tap Rohgahh of Kher Keep and all creatures named Kobolds of Kher Keep, then an opponent gains control of them.
Creatures you control named Kobolds of Kher Keep get +2/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30176</id>
    <name>Rubinia Soulsinger</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Rubinia Soulsinger during your untap step.
{T}: Gain control of target creature for as long as you control Rubinia and Rubinia remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30177</id>
    <name>Sir Shandlar of Eberyn</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Remember Sir Shandlar! Remember and stand firm!"
—rallying cry of the Eberyn militia</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30178</id>
    <name>Sivitri Scarzam</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Even the brave have cause to tremble at the sight of Sivitri Scarzam. Who else has tamed Scarzam's Dragon?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30179</id>
    <name>Spectral Shield</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +0/+2 and can't be the target of spells.</text>
    <flavorText>"What can be a stronger shield than concealment? Have you ever defeated an enemy you didn't know existed?"
—Gerda Äagesdotter, Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30180</id>
    <name>Stangg</name>
    <text>When Stangg enters the battlefield, put a legendary 3/4 red and green Human Warrior creature token named Stangg Twin onto the battlefield. When Stangg leaves the battlefield, exile that token. When that token leaves the battlefield, sacrifice Stangg.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30181</id>
    <name>Sunastian Falconer</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {2} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Sunastian has roots in both sorcery and swordplay; he has learned never to depend too heavily on the latter.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30182</id>
    <name>Tetsuo Umezawa</name>
    <text>Tetsuo Umezawa can't be the target of Aura spells.
{U}{B}{B}{R}, {T}: Destroy target tapped or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30183</id>
    <name>The Lady of the Mountain</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Her given name has been lost in the mists of time. Legend says that her silent vigil will one day be ended by the one who, pure of heart and spirit, calls out that name again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30184</id>
    <name>Tobias Andrion</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Administrator of the military state of Sheoltun, Tobias is the military right arm of the empire and the figurehead of its freedom.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30185</id>
    <name>Tor Wauki</name>
    <text>{T}: Tor Wauki deals 2 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30186</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30187</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30188</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30189</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30190</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30191</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30192</id>
    <name>Torsten Von Ursus</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"How can you accuse me of evil? Though these deeds be unsavory, no one will argue: good shall follow from them."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30193</id>
    <name>Tuknir Deathlock</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}{G}, {T}: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>An explorer of the Æther, Tuknir often discovers himself in the most unusual physical realms.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30194</id>
    <name>Vaevictis Asmadi</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Vaevictis Asmadi unless you pay {B}{R}{G}.
{B}: Vaevictis Asmadi gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
{R}: Vaevictis Asmadi gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
{G}: Vaevictis Asmadi gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30195</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30196</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30197</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30198</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30199</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30200</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30201</id>
    <name>Wandering Mage</name>
    <text>{W}, Pay 1 life: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.
{U}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target Cleric or Wizard creature this turn.
{B}, Put a -1/-1 counter on a creature you control: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to target player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30202</id>
    <name>Xira Arien</name>
    <text>Flying
{B}{R}{G}, {T}: Target player draws a card.</text>
    <flavorText>A regular guest at the Royal Masquerade, Arien is the envy of the Court. She appears in a new costume every hour.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30203</id>
    <name>Arena of the Ancients</name>
    <text>Legendary creatures don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.
When Arena of the Ancients enters the battlefield, tap all legendary creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30204</id>
    <name>Astrolabe</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Astrolabe: Add two mana of any one color to your mana pool. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30205</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30206</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30207</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30208</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30209</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30210</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30211</id>
    <name>Barl's Cage</name>
    <text>{3}: Target creature doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>For a dozen years the Cage had held Lord Ith, but as the Pretender Mairsil's power weakened, so did the bars.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30212</id>
    <name>Black Vise</name>
    <text>As Black Vise enters the battlefield, choose an opponent.
At the beginning of the chosen player's upkeep, Black Vise deals X damage to that player, where X is the number of cards in his or her hand minus 4.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30213</id>
    <name>Bone Flute</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: All creatures get -1/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>After the Battle of Pitdown, Lady Ursnell fashioned the first such instrument out of Lord Ursnell's left leg.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30214</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30215</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30216</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30217</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30218</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30219</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30220</id>
    <name>Coal Golem</name>
    <text>{3}, Sacrifice Coal Golem: Add {R}{R}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Three such creatures stood burning at the crest of the hill. Only seconds later, the fireball struck our front line."
—Lydia, Countess Brellis</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30221</id>
    <name>Didgeridoo</name>
    <text>{3}: You may put a Minotaur permanent card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Play the song of he who delivered us. Play the song of Feroz."
—Onatah, Anaba Shaman</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30222</id>
    <name>Fellwar Stone</name>
    <text>{T}: Add to your mana pool one mana of any color that a land an opponent controls could produce.</text>
    <flavorText>"What do you have that I cannot obtain?"
—Mairsil, called the Pretender</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30223</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30224</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30225</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30226</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30227</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30228</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30229</id>
    <name>Gauntlets of Chaos</name>
    <text>{5}, Sacrifice Gauntlets of Chaos: Exchange control of target artifact, creature, or land you control and target permanent an opponent controls that shares one of those types with it. If those permanents are exchanged this way, destroy all Auras attached to them.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30230</id>
    <name>Illusionary Mask</name>
    <text>{X}: You may choose a creature card in your hand whose mana cost could be paid by some amount of, or all of, the mana you spent on {X}. If you do, you may cast that card face down as a 2/2 creature spell without paying its mana cost. If the creature that spell becomes as it resolves has not been turned face up and would assign or deal damage, be dealt damage, or become tapped, instead it's turned face up and assigns or deals damage, is dealt damage, or becomes tapped. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30231</id>
    <name>Knowledge Vault</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Exile the top card of your library face down.
{0}: Sacrifice Knowledge Vault. If you do, discard your hand, then put all cards exiled with Knowledge Vault into their owner's hand.
When Knowledge Vault leaves the battlefield, put all cards exiled with Knowledge Vault into their owner's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30232</id>
    <name>Life Chisel</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: You gain life equal to the sacrificed creature's toughness. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30233</id>
    <name>Nova Pentacle</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, that damage is dealt to target creature of an opponent's choice instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30234</id>
    <name>Sol Grail</name>
    <text>As Sol Grail enters the battlefield, choose a color.
{T}: Add one mana of the chosen color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Look deep into the Grail, and see there what you desire most."
—Gerda Äagesdotter, Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30235</id>
    <name>Sword of the Ages</name>
    <text>Sword of the Ages enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}, Exile Sword of the Ages and any number of creatures you control: Sword of the Ages deals X damage to target creature or player, where X is the total power of the creatures exiled this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30236</id>
    <name>Voodoo Doll</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a pin counter on Voodoo Doll.
At the beginning of your end step, if Voodoo Doll is untapped, it deals damage to you equal to the number of pin counters on it. If Voodoo Doll deals damage to you this way, destroy it.
{X}{X}, {T}: Voodoo Doll deals X damage to target creature or player. X is the number of pin counters on Voodoo Doll.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30237</id>
    <name>Bayou</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30238</id>
    <name>Bazaar of Baghdad</name>
    <text>{T}: Draw two cards, then discard three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30239</id>
    <name>City of Shadows</name>
    <text>{T}, Exile a creature you control: Put a storage counter on City of Shadows.
{T}: Add {X} to your mana pool, where X is the number of storage counters on City of Shadows.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30240</id>
    <name>Hammerheim</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.

{T}: Target creature loses all landwalk abilities until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"‘Tis distance lends enchantment to the view,/ And robes the mountain in its azure hue." —Thomas Campbell, "Pleasures of Hope"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30241</id>
    <name>Karakas</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.
{T}: Return target legendary creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"To make a prairie it takes a clover and one bee,/ One clover, and a bee,/ And revery."
—Emily Dickinson</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30242</id>
    <name>Plateau</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30243</id>
    <name>Scrubland</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30244</id>
    <name>Sorrow's Path</name>
    <text>{T}: Choose two target blocking creatures an opponent controls. If each of those creatures could block all creatures that the other is blocking, remove both of them from combat. Each one then blocks all creatures the other was blocking.
Whenever Sorrow's Path becomes tapped, it deals 2 damage to you and each creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30245</id>
    <name>The Tabernacle at Pendrell Vale</name>
    <text>All creatures have "At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy this creature unless you pay {1}."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30246</id>
    <name>Tropical Island</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30247</id>
    <name>Urborg</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.

{T}: Target creature loses first strike or swampwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Resignedly beneath the sky/The melancholy waters lie./So blend the turrets and shadows there/That all seem pendulous in air,/While from a proud tower in town/Death looks gigantically down."
—Edgar Allan Poe, "The City in the Sea"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ME30248</id>
    <name>Volcanic Island</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>