<cards name="Masters Edition">
  <item>
    <id>MED0001</id>
    <name>Angry Mob</name>
    <text>Trample
As long as it's your turn, Angry Mob's power and toughness are each equal to 2 plus the number of Swamps your opponents control. As long as it's not your turn, Angry Mob's power and toughness are each 2.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0002</id>
    <name>Animate Wall</name>
    <text>Enchant Wall
Enchanted Wall can attack as though it didn't have defender.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0003</id>
    <name>Argivian Archaeologist</name>
    <text>{W}{W}, {T}: Return target artifact card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Fascinated by the lore of ancient struggles, the archaeologist searches incessantly for remnants of an earlier, more powerful era.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0004</id>
    <name>Armageddon</name>
    <text>Destroy all lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0005</id>
    <name>Benalish Hero</name>
    <text>Banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>Benalia has a complex caste system that changes with the lunar year. No matter what the season, the only caste that cannot be attained by either heredity or money is that of the hero.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0006</id>
    <name>Crusade</name>
    <text>White creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0007</id>
    <name>Death Speakers</name>
    <text>Protection from black</text>
    <flavorText>"Such innocent little birds. They sing a sweet song, sitting on their fragile branch."
—Grandmother Sengir</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0008</id>
    <name>Death Ward</name>
    <text>Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0009</id>
    <name>Divine Transformation</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.</text>
    <flavorText>Glory surged through her and radiance surrounded her. All things were possible with the blessing of the Divine.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0010</id>
    <name>Dust to Dust</name>
    <text>Exile two target artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>Tervish never noticed that the amulet had vanished. It had disappeared not only from his possession, but from his memory as well.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0011</id>
    <name>Elder Land Wurm</name>
    <text>Defender, trample
When Elder Land Wurm blocks, it loses defender.</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes it's best to let sleeping dragons lie.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0012</id>
    <name>Exile</name>
    <text>Exile target nonwhite attacking creature. You gain life equal to its toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0013</id>
    <name>Greater Realm of Preservation</name>
    <text>{1}{W}: The next time a black or red source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0014</id>
    <name>Hallowed Ground</name>
    <text>{W}{W}: Return target nonsnow land you control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"On this site where Kjeld's blood was spilled, let none raise a fist or deny a beggar."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0015</id>
    <name>Hand of Justice</name>
    <text>{T}, Tap three untapped white creatures you control: Destroy target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Hand of Justice will come to cleanse the world if we are true."
—Oliver Farrel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0016</id>
    <name>Holy Light</name>
    <text>Nonwhite creatures get -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Bathed in hallowed light, the infidels looked upon the impurities of their souls and despaired."
—The Book of Tal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0017</id>
    <name>Icatian Lieutenant</name>
    <text>{1}{W}: Target Soldier creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>To become an officer, an Icatian soldier had to pass a series of tests. These evaluated not only fighting and leadership skills, but also integrity, honor, and moral strength.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0018</id>
    <name>Icatian Town</name>
    <text>Put four 1/1 white Citizen creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Icatia's once peaceful towns faced increasing attacks from orcs and goblins as the climate cooled. By the time the empire fell, they were little more than armed camps.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0019</id>
    <name>Knights of Thorn</name>
    <text>Protection from red; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>"With a great cry, the goblin host broke and ran as the first wave of knights penetrated its ranks."
—Tivadar of Thorn,
History of the Goblin Wars</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0020</id>
    <name>Mesa Pegasus</name>
    <text>Flying; banding (Any creatures with banding, and up to one without, can attack in a band. Bands are blocked as a group. If any creatures with banding you control are blocking or being blocked by a creature, you divide that creature's combat damage, not its controller, among any of the creatures it's being blocked by or is blocking.)</text>
    <flavorText>Before a woman marries in the village of Sursi, she must visit the land of the mesa pegasus. Legend has it that if the woman is pure of heart and her love is true, a mesa pegasus will appear, blessing her family with long life and good fortune.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0021</id>
    <name>Moat</name>
    <text>Creatures without flying can't attack.</text>
    <flavorText>The purpose of any moat is to impede attack. Some are filled with water, some with thistles. Some are filled with things best left unseen.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0022</id>
    <name>Order of Leitbur</name>
    <text>Protection from black
{W}: Order of Leitbur gains first strike until end of turn.
{W}{W}: Order of Leitbur gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Trained to battle the followers of Tourach, the Order of Leitbur was not as successful in later conflicts with orcish and goblin raiders."
—Sarpadian Empires, vol. I</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0023</id>
    <name>Petra Sphinx</name>
    <text>{T}: Target player names a card, then reveals the top card of his or her library. If that card is the named card, that player puts it into his or her hand. If it isn't, the player puts it into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>What walks on four legs in the morning, two legs in the afternoon, and three legs in the evening?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0024</id>
    <name>Preacher</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Preacher during your untap step.
{T}: Gain control of target creature of an opponent's choice that he or she controls for as long as Preacher remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0025</id>
    <name>Righteous Avengers</name>
    <text>Plainswalk</text>
    <flavorText>Few can withstand the wrath of the righteous.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0026</id>
    <name>Seraph</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever a creature dealt damage by Seraph this turn is put into a graveyard, put that card onto the battlefield under your control at the beginning of the next end step. Sacrifice the creature when you lose control of Seraph.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0027</id>
    <name>Thunder Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying, first strike</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0028</id>
    <name>Tivadar's Crusade</name>
    <text>Destroy all Goblins.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0029</id>
    <name>Amnesia</name>
    <text>Target player reveals his or her hand and discards all nonland cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"When one has witnessed the unspeakable, 'tis sometimes better to forget."
—Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0030</id>
    <name>Apprentice Wizard</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}: Add {3} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0031</id>
    <name>Arcane Denial</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. Its controller may draw up to two cards at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.
You draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0032</id>
    <name>Diminishing Returns</name>
    <text>Each player shuffles his or her hand and graveyard into his or her library. You exile the top ten cards of your library. Then each player draws up to seven cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0033</id>
    <name>Force of Will</name>
    <text>You may pay 1 life and exile a blue card from your hand rather than pay Force of Will's mana cost.
Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0034</id>
    <name>Giant Tortoise</name>
    <text>Giant Tortoise gets +0/+3 as long as it's untapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0035</id>
    <name>High Tide</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, whenever a player taps an Island for mana, that player adds {U} to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>"May Svyelun and her tides favor you."
—Traditional merfolk blessing</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0036</id>
    <name>Homarid Spawning Bed</name>
    <text>{1}{U}{U}, Sacrifice a blue creature: Put X 1/1 blue Camarid creature tokens onto the battlefield, where X is the sacrificed creature's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0037</id>
    <name>Hydroblast</name>
    <text>Choose one — Counter target spell if it's red; or destroy target permanent if it's red.</text>
    <flavorText>"Heed the lessons of our time: the forms of water may move the land itself and hold captive the fires within."
—Gustha Ebbasdotter,
Kjeldoran royal mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0038</id>
    <name>Illusionary Forces</name>
    <text>Flying
Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"This school was founded in secret, operates in secret, and exists for the teaching of secrets. Those who would alter reality must first escape it."
—Gerda Äagesdotter,
Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0039</id>
    <name>Illusionary Wall</name>
    <text>Defender, flying, first strike
Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Let them see what is not there and feel what does not touch them. When they no longer trust their senses, that is the time to strike."
—Gerda Äagesdotter,
Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0040</id>
    <name>Illusions of Grandeur</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
When Illusions of Grandeur enters the battlefield, you gain 20 life.
When Illusions of Grandeur leaves the battlefield, you lose 20 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0041</id>
    <name>Juxtapose</name>
    <text>You and target player exchange control of the creature you each control with the highest converted mana cost. Then exchange control of artifacts the same way. If two or more permanents a player controls are tied for highest cost, their controller chooses one of them.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0042</id>
    <name>Mystic Remora</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Whenever an opponent casts a noncreature spell, you may draw a card unless that player pays {4}.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0043</id>
    <name>Phantom Monster</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"While, like a ghastly rapid river,
Through the pale door
A hideous throng rush out forever,
And laugh—but smile no more."
—Edgar Allan Poe, "The Haunted Palace"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0044</id>
    <name>Polar Kraken</name>
    <text>Trample
Polar Kraken enters the battlefield tapped.
Cumulative upkeep—Sacrifice a land. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"It was big. Really, really, big. No, bigger than that. It was big!"
—Arna Kennerüd, skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0045</id>
    <name>Psychic Purge</name>
    <text>Psychic Purge deals 1 damage to target creature or player.
When a spell or ability an opponent controls causes you to discard Psychic Purge, that player loses 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0046</id>
    <name>Psychic Venom</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land becomes tapped, Psychic Venom deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0047</id>
    <name>River Merfolk</name>
    <text>{U}: River Merfolk gains mountainwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Dwelling in icy mountain streams near goblin and orcish foes, the river merfolk were known for their stoicism."
—Sarpadian Empires, vol. V</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0048</id>
    <name>Sea Sprite</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from red</text>
    <flavorText>"No one can catch what won't be caught."
—Kakra, sea troll</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0049</id>
    <name>Seasinger</name>
    <text>When you control no Islands, sacrifice Seasinger.
You may choose not to untap Seasinger during your untap step.
{T}: Gain control of target creature whose controller controls an Island for as long as you control Seasinger and Seasinger remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0050</id>
    <name>Serendib Efreet</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, Serendib Efreet deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0051</id>
    <name>Sunken City</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Sunken City unless you pay {U}{U}.
Blue creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0052</id>
    <name>Telekinesis</name>
    <text>Tap target creature. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by that creature this turn. It doesn't untap during its controller's next two untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0053</id>
    <name>Time Elemental</name>
    <text>When Time Elemental attacks or blocks, at end of combat, sacrifice it and it deals 5 damage to you.
{2}{U}{U}, {T}: Return target permanent that isn't enchanted to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0054</id>
    <name>Vesuvan Doppelganger</name>
    <text>You may have Vesuvan Doppelganger enter the battlefield as a copy of any creature on the battlefield except it doesn't copy that creature's color and it gains "At the beginning of your upkeep, you may have this creature become a copy of target creature except it doesn't copy that creature's color. If you do, this creature gains this ability."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0055</id>
    <name>Vodalian Knights</name>
    <text>First strike
Vodalian Knights can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.
When you control no Islands, sacrifice Vodalian Knights.
{U}: Vodalian Knights gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Fear the knight leaping from the water into the air, weapon ready.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0056</id>
    <name>Word of Undoing</name>
    <text>Return target creature and all white Auras you own attached to it to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>"It was in Urza's journals that I finally found the secret at the core of the summonings."
—Journal, author unknown</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0057</id>
    <name>Animate Dead</name>
    <text>Enchant creature card in a graveyard
When Animate Dead enters the battlefield, if it's on the battlefield, it loses "enchant creature card in a graveyard" and gains "enchant creature put onto the battlefield with Animate Dead." Return enchanted creature card to the battlefield under your control and attach Animate Dead to it. When Animate Dead leaves the battlefield, that creature's controller sacrifices it.
Enchanted creature gets -1/-0.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0058</id>
    <name>Baron Sengir</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever a creature dealt damage by Baron Sengir this turn is put into a graveyard, put a +2/+2 counter on Baron Sengir.
{T}: Regenerate another target Vampire.</text>
    <flavorText>"Beast. Defiler. The source of all my pain."
—Ihsan's Shade</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0059</id>
    <name>Basal Thrull</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Basal Thrull: Add {B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Initially bred for sacrifice, the thrulls eventually turned on their masters, the Order of the Ebon Hand, with gruesome results.
—Sarpadian Empires, vol. II</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0060</id>
    <name>Black Knight</name>
    <text>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)
Protection from white (This creature can't be blocked, targeted, dealt damage, or enchanted by anything white.)</text>
    <flavorText>Battle doesn't need a purpose; the battle is its own purpose. You don't ask why a plague spreads or a field burns. Don't ask why I fight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0061</id>
    <name>Blight</name>
    <text>Enchant land
When enchanted land becomes tapped, destroy it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0062</id>
    <name>Breeding Pit</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Breeding Pit unless you pay {B}{B}.
At the beginning of your end step, put a 0/1 black Thrull creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The thrulls bred at a terrifying pace. In the end, they overwhelmed the Order of the Ebon Hand.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0063</id>
    <name>Chains of Mephistopheles</name>
    <text>If a player would draw a card except the first one he or she draws in his or her draw step each turn, that player discards a card instead. If the player discards a card this way, he or she draws a card. If the player doesn't discard a card this way, he or she puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0064</id>
    <name>Contagion</name>
    <text>You may pay 1 life and exile a black card from your hand rather than pay Contagion's mana cost.
Distribute two -2/-1 counters among one or two target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0065</id>
    <name>Cuombajj Witches</name>
    <text>{T}: Cuombajj Witches deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to target creature or player of an opponent's choice.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0066</id>
    <name>Derelor</name>
    <text>Black spells you cast cost {B} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>"Strength it has, but at the cost of a continuous supply of energy. Such failure can bear only one result."
—Execution order of Endrek Sahr,
master breeder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0067</id>
    <name>Eater of the Dead</name>
    <text>{0}: If Eater of the Dead is tapped, exile target creature card from a graveyard and untap Eater of the Dead.</text>
    <flavorText>Even the putrid muscles of the dead can provide strength to those loathsome enough to consume them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0068</id>
    <name>Erg Raiders</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your end step, if Erg Raiders didn't attack this turn, Erg Raiders deals 2 damage to you unless it came under your control this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0069</id>
    <name>The Fallen</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, The Fallen deals 1 damage to each opponent it has dealt damage to this game.</text>
    <flavorText>Magic often masters those who cannot master it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0070</id>
    <name>Feast or Famine</name>
    <text>Choose one — Put a 2/2 black Zombie creature token onto the battlefield; or destroy target nonblack, nonartifact creature and it can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"We are not yet free of Lim-Dûl's terrors."
—Halvor Arensson, Kjeldoran priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0071</id>
    <name>Hecatomb</name>
    <text>When Hecatomb enters the battlefield, sacrifice Hecatomb unless you sacrifice four creatures.
Tap an untapped Swamp you control: Hecatomb deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0072</id>
    <name>Hyalopterous Lemure</name>
    <text>{0}: Hyalopterous Lemure gets -1/-0 and gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The lemures looked harmless, until they descended on my troops. Within moments, only bones remained."
—Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0073</id>
    <name>Hymn to Tourach</name>
    <text>Target player discards two cards at random.</text>
    <flavorText>Knowing the hymn's power, the followers of Leitbur carefully guarded their pillaged transciptions.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0074</id>
    <name>Juzám Djinn</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Juzám Djinn deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"Expect my visit when the darkness comes. The night I think is best for hiding all."
—Ouallada</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0075</id>
    <name>Khabál Ghoul</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each end step, put a +1/+1 counter on Khabál Ghoul for each creature put into a graveyard from the battlefield this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0076</id>
    <name>Mindstab Thrull</name>
    <text>Whenever Mindstab Thrull attacks and isn't blocked, you may sacrifice it. If you do, defending player discards three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0077</id>
    <name>Nether Shadow</name>
    <text>Haste
At the beginning of your upkeep, if Nether Shadow is in your graveyard with three or more creature cards above it, you may put Nether Shadow onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0078</id>
    <name>Order of the Ebon Hand</name>
    <text>Protection from white
{B}: Order of the Ebon Hand gains first strike until end of turn.
{B}{B}: Order of the Ebon Hand gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0079</id>
    <name>Oubliette</name>
    <text>When Oubliette enters the battlefield, exile target creature and all Auras attached to it. Note the number and kind of counters that were on that creature.
When Oubliette leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to the battlefield under its owner's control tapped with the noted number and kind of counters on it. If you do, return the exiled Aura cards to the battlefield under their owner's control attached to that permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0080</id>
    <name>Paralyze</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Paralyze enters the battlefield, tap enchanted creature.
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, that player may pay {4}. If he or she does, untap the creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0081</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Boon</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+1 as long as it's black. Otherwise, it gets -1/-2.</text>
    <flavorText>"Phyrexia's touch is painful to all but the blackest of hearts."
—Gerda Äagesdotter,
Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0082</id>
    <name>Pox</name>
    <text>Each player loses a third of his or her life, then discards a third of the cards in his or her hand, then sacrifices a third of the creatures he or she controls, then sacrifices a third of the lands he or she controls. Round up each time.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0083</id>
    <name>Thrull Champion</name>
    <text>Thrull creatures get +1/+1.
{T}: Gain control of target Thrull for as long as you control Thrull Champion.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those idiots should never have bred thrulls for combat!"
—Jherana Rure</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0084</id>
    <name>Thrull Retainer</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1.
Sacrifice Thrull Retainer: Regenerate enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Until the Rebellion, thrulls served their masters faithfully—even at the cost of their own lives."
—Sarpadian Empires, vol. II</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0085</id>
    <name>Artifact Blast</name>
    <text>Counter target artifact spell.</text>
    <flavorText>The first line of defense against Urza and Mishra, the artifact blast achieved widespread fame until an unlucky mage discovered it was useless on the devices the brothers had already created.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0086</id>
    <name>Balduvian Horde</name>
    <text>When Balduvian Horde enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you discard a card at random.</text>
    <flavorText>"Peace will come only when we have taken Varchild's head."
—Lovisa Coldeyes, Balduvian chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0087</id>
    <name>Ball Lightning</name>
    <text>Trample (If this creature would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)
Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)
At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice Ball Lightning.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0088</id>
    <name>Bestial Fury</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Bestial Fury enters the battlefield, draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.
Whenever enchanted creature becomes blocked, it gets +4/+0 and gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0089</id>
    <name>Brothers of Fire</name>
    <text>{1}{R}{R}: Brothers of Fire deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>Fire is never a gentle master.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0090</id>
    <name>Crookshank Kobolds</name>
    <text>Crookshank Kobolds is red.</text>
    <flavorText>The Crookshank military boasts a standing army of nearly twenty-four million, give or take twenty-two million.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0091</id>
    <name>Dwarven Catapult</name>
    <text>Dwarven Catapult deals X damage divided evenly, rounded down, among all creatures target opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"Often greatly outnumbered in battle, dwarves relied on catapults as one means of damaging a large army."
—Sarpadian Empires, vol. IV</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0092</id>
    <name>Dwarven Soldier</name>
    <text>Whenever Dwarven Soldier blocks or becomes blocked by one or more Orcs, Dwarven Soldier gets +0/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let no one say we did not fight until the last . . . ."
—Headstone fragment from a mass grave found in the Crimson Peaks</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0093</id>
    <name>Fissure</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature or land. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Must not all things at the last be swallowed up in death?"
—Plato, Phædo, trans. Jowett</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0094</id>
    <name>Goblin Chirurgeon</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a Goblin: Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Perhaps goblins are good for something after all."
—General Khurzog</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0095</id>
    <name>Goblin Grenade</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Goblin Grenade, sacrifice a Goblin.
Goblin Grenade deals 5 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"According to accepted theory, the grenade held some kind of flammable mixture and was carried to its target by a hapless goblin."
—Sarpadian Empires, vol. IV</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0096</id>
    <name>Goblin Mutant</name>
    <text>Trample
Goblin Mutant can't attack if defending player controls an untapped creature with power 3 or greater.
Goblin Mutant can't block creatures with power 3 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>If only it had three brains, too.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0097</id>
    <name>Goblin Wizard</name>
    <text>{T}: You may put a Goblin permanent card from your hand onto the battlefield.
{R}: Target Goblin gains protection from white until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0098</id>
    <name>Goblins of the Flarg</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk
When you control a Dwarf, sacrifice Goblins of the Flarg.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0099</id>
    <name>Granite Gargoyle</name>
    <text>Flying
{R}: Granite Gargoyle gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"While most overworlders fortunately don't realize this, gargoyles can be most delicious, providing you have the appropriate tools to carve them."
—Asmoranomardicadaistinaculdacar,
The Underworld Cookbook</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0100</id>
    <name>Jokulhaups</name>
    <text>Destroy all artifacts, creatures, and lands. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"I was shocked when I first saw the aftermath of the Yavimaya Valley disaster. The raging waters had swept away trees, bridges, and even houses. My healers had much work to do."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0101</id>
    <name>Keldon Warlord</name>
    <text>Keldon Warlord's power and toughness are each equal to the number of non-Wall creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0102</id>
    <name>Lightning Bolt</name>
    <text>Lightning Bolt deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0103</id>
    <name>Mana Flare</name>
    <text>Whenever a player taps a land for mana, that player adds one mana to his or her mana pool of any type that land produced.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0104</id>
    <name>Márton Stromgald</name>
    <text>Whenever Márton Stromgald attacks, other attacking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn for each attacking creature other than Márton Stromgald.
Whenever Márton Stromgald blocks, other blocking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn for each blocking creature other than Márton Stromgald.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0105</id>
    <name>Mountain Yeti</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk, protection from white</text>
    <flavorText>The Yeti's single greatest asset is its unnerving ability to blend in with its surroundings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0106</id>
    <name>Orcish Mechanics</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice an artifact: Orcish Mechanics deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0107</id>
    <name>Pyroblast</name>
    <text>Choose one — Counter target spell if it's blue; or destroy target permanent if it's blue.</text>
    <flavorText>"Just the thing for those pesky water mages."
—Jaya Ballard, task mage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0108</id>
    <name>Spinal Villain</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target blue creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Striking silent as a dream,
Cutting short the strangled scream . . ."
—Tobrian, "Watchdragon"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0109</id>
    <name>Stone Giant</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature you control with toughness less than Stone Giant's power gains flying until end of turn. Destroy that creature at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>What goes up, must come down.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0110</id>
    <name>Varchild's War-Riders</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep—Put a 1/1 red Survivor creature token onto the battlefield under an opponent's control. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
Trample; rampage 1 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</text>
    <flavorText>"What tries to crush our spirit only strengthens our resolve."
—Lovisa Coldeyes, Balduvian chieftain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0111</id>
    <name>Winds of Change</name>
    <text>Each player shuffles the cards from his or her hand into his or her library, then draws that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"'Tis the set of sails and not the gales
Which tells us the way to go."
—Ella Wheeler Wilcox, "Winds of Fate"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0112</id>
    <name>Ydwen Efreet</name>
    <text>Whenever Ydwen Efreet blocks, flip a coin. If you lose the flip, remove Ydwen Efreet from combat and it can't block this turn. Creatures it was blocking that had become blocked by only Ydwen Efreet this combat become unblocked.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0113</id>
    <name>Autumn Willow</name>
    <text>Shroud
{G}: Until end of turn, Autumn Willow can be the target of spells and abilities controlled by target player as though it didn't have shroud.</text>
    <flavorText>"We must shake her limbs and rattle her brains."
—Grandmother Sengir</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0114</id>
    <name>Berserk</name>
    <text>Cast Berserk only before the combat damage step.
Target creature gains trample and gets +X/+0 until end of turn, where X is its power. At the beginning of the next end step, destroy that creature if it attacked this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0115</id>
    <name>Carnivorous Plant</name>
    <text>Defender</text>
    <flavorText>"It had a mouth like that of a great beast, and gnashed its teeth as it strained to reach us. I am thankful it possessed no means of locomotion."
—Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0116</id>
    <name>Chub Toad</name>
    <text>Whenever Chub Toad blocks or becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Chub toad, chub toad
At the door.
Run away quick
Or you'll run no more."
—Traditional children's rhyme</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0117</id>
    <name>Eureka</name>
    <text>Starting with you, each player may put a permanent card from his or her hand onto the battlefield. Repeat this process until no one puts a card onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0118</id>
    <name>Fyndhorn Elves</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Living side by side with the elves for so long leaves me with no doubt that we serve the same goddess."
—Kolbjörn, elder druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0119</id>
    <name>Gargantuan Gorilla</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Gargantuan Gorilla unless you sacrifice a Forest. If you sacrifice Gargantuan Gorilla this way, it deals 7 damage to you. If you sacrifice a snow Forest this way, Gargantuan Gorilla gains trample until end of turn.
{T}: Gargantuan Gorilla deals damage equal to its power to target creature. That creature deals damage equal to its power to Gargantuan Gorilla.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0120</id>
    <name>Ghazbán Ogre</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if a player has more life than each other player, the player with the most life gains control of Ghazbán Ogre.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0121</id>
    <name>Hungry Mist</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Hungry Mist unless you pay {G}{G}.</text>
    <flavorText>"If the air must feed, let it take the self-righteous."
—Murat, death speaker</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0122</id>
    <name>Ice Storm</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0123</id>
    <name>Ifh-Bíff Efreet</name>
    <text>Flying
{G}: Ifh-Bíff Efreet deals 1 damage to each creature with flying and each player. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0124</id>
    <name>Nature's Lore</name>
    <text>Search your library for a Forest card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Fyndhorn is our home."
—Kolbjörn, elder druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0125</id>
    <name>Primal Order</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Primal Order deals damage to that player equal to the number of nonbasic lands he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's strange, but I can feel it when the land is corrupted. I understand why the Autumn Willow is so protective."
—Daria</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0126</id>
    <name>Rabid Wombat</name>
    <text>Vigilance
Rabid Wombat gets +2/+2 for each Aura attached to it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0127</id>
    <name>Roots</name>
    <text>Enchant creature without flying
When Roots enters the battlefield, tap enchanted creature.
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>"That which nourishes can also bind."
—Gemma, Willow Priestess</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0128</id>
    <name>Scryb Sprites</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>The only sound was the gentle clicking of the faeries' wings. Then those intruders who were still standing turned and fled. One thing was certain: they didn't think the Scryb were very funny anymore.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0129</id>
    <name>Shambling Strider</name>
    <text>{R}{G}: Shambling Strider gets +1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Freyalise forbid that any stranger should wander into the striders' territory.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0130</id>
    <name>Singing Tree</name>
    <text>{T}: Target attacking creature's power becomes 0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0131</id>
    <name>Spectral Bears</name>
    <text>Whenever Spectral Bears attacks, if defending player controls no black nontoken permanents, it doesn't untap during your next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>"I hear there are bears—or spirits—that guard caravans passing through the forest."
—Gulsen, abbey matron</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0132</id>
    <name>Storm Seeker</name>
    <text>Storm Seeker deals damage equal to the number of cards in target player's hand to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0133</id>
    <name>Sylvan Library</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your draw step, you may draw two additional cards. If you do, choose two cards in your hand drawn this turn. For each of those cards, pay 4 life or put the card on top of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0134</id>
    <name>Thicket Basilisk</name>
    <text>Whenever Thicket Basilisk blocks or becomes blocked by a non-Wall creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>Moss-covered statues littered the area, a macabre monument to the basilisk's power.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0135</id>
    <name>Thorn Thallid</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a spore counter on Thorn Thallid.
Remove three spore counters from Thorn Thallid: Thorn Thallid deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"The danger in cultivating massive plants caught the elves by surprise."
—Sarpadian Empires, vol. III</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0136</id>
    <name>Tornado</name>
    <text>Cumulative upkeep {G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)
{2}{G}, Pay 3 life for each velocity counter on Tornado: Destroy target permanent and put a velocity counter on Tornado. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0137</id>
    <name>Wanderlust</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, Wanderlust deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0138</id>
    <name>Winter Blast</name>
    <text>Tap X target creatures. Winter Blast deals 2 damage to each of those creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Blow, winds, and crack your cheeks! rage! blow!"William Shakespeare, King Lear</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0139</id>
    <name>Wyluli Wolf</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"When one wolf calls, others follow. Who wants to fight creatures that eat scorpions?"
—Maimun al-Wyluli, diary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0140</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Ants</name>
    <text>Trample, haste
Cumulative upkeep {G}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Few natural forces are as devastating as hunger."
—Kaysa, elder druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0141</id>
    <name>Adun Oakenshield</name>
    <text>{B}{R}{G}, {T}: Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>". . . And at his passing, the bodies of the world's great warriors shall rise from their graves and follow him to battle."
—The Anvilonian Grimoire</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0142</id>
    <name>Centaur Archer</name>
    <text>{T}: Centaur Archer deals 1 damage to target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Centaurs will kill our aesthir if they can; they've always been enemies. Destroy the horse-people on sight."
—Arna Kennerüd, Skyknight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0143</id>
    <name>Dakkon Blackblade</name>
    <text>Dakkon Blackblade's power and toughness are each equal to the number of lands you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"My power is as vast as the plains, my strength is that of mountains. Each wave that crashes upon the shore thunders like blood in my veins."
—Dakkon Blackblade, Memoirs</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0144</id>
    <name>Energy Arc</name>
    <text>Untap any number of target creatures. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by those creatures this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Relent, and you may transcend your situation."
—Gerda Äagesdotter,
Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0145</id>
    <name>Fire Covenant</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Fire Covenant, pay X life.
Fire Covenant deals X damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0146</id>
    <name>Hymn of Rebirth</name>
    <text>Put target creature card from a graveyard onto the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>"There will come soft rains, and spring shall be amongst us, a welcome friend."
—Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0147</id>
    <name>Jacques le Vert</name>
    <text>Green creatures you control get +0/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>Abandoning his sword to return to the lush forest of Pendelhaven, Jacques le Vert devoted his life to protecting the creatures of his homeland.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0148</id>
    <name>Lim-Dûl's Vault</name>
    <text>Look at the top five cards of your library. As many times as you choose, you may pay 1 life, put those cards on the bottom of your library, then look at the top five cards of your library. Then shuffle your library and put the last cards you looked at this way on top of it in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0149</id>
    <name>Lord of Tresserhorn</name>
    <text>When Lord of Tresserhorn enters the battlefield, you lose 2 life, you sacrifice two creatures, and target opponent draws two cards.
{B}: Regenerate Lord of Tresserhorn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0150</id>
    <name>Phelddagrif</name>
    <text>{G}: Phelddagrif gains trample until end of turn. Target opponent puts a 1/1 green Hippo creature token onto the battlefield.
{W}: Phelddagrif gains flying until end of turn. Target opponent gains 2 life.
{U}: Return Phelddagrif to its owner's hand. Target opponent may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0151</id>
    <name>Ankh of Mishra</name>
    <text>Whenever a land enters the battlefield, Ankh of Mishra deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0152</id>
    <name>Ashnod's Transmogrant</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Ashnod's Transmogrant: Put a +1/+1 counter on target nonartifact creature. That creature becomes an artifact in addition to its other types.</text>
    <flavorText>Ashnod found few willing to trade their humanity for the power she offered them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0153</id>
    <name>Clockwork Beast</name>
    <text>Clockwork Beast enters the battlefield with seven +1/+0 counters on it.
At end of combat, if Clockwork Beast attacked or blocked this combat, remove a +1/+0 counter from it.
{X}, {T}: Put up to X +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Beast. This ability can't cause the total number of +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Beast to be greater than seven. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0154</id>
    <name>Copper Tablet</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Copper Tablet deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0155</id>
    <name>Cursed Rack</name>
    <text>As Cursed Rack enters the battlefield, choose an opponent.
The chosen player's maximum hand size is four.</text>
    <flavorText>Ashnod invented several torture techniques that could make victims even miles away beg for mercy as if the End had come.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0156</id>
    <name>Dragon Engine</name>
    <text>{2}: Dragon Engine gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Those who believed the city of Kroog would never fall to Mishra's forces severely underestimated the might of his war machines.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0157</id>
    <name>Forcefield</name>
    <text>{1}: The next time an unblocked creature of your choice would deal combat damage to you this turn, prevent all but 1 of that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0158</id>
    <name>Ivory Tower</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you gain X life, where X is the number of cards in your hand minus four.</text>
    <flavorText>Valuing scholarship above all else, the inhabitants of the Ivory Tower reward those who sacrifice power for knowledge.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0159</id>
    <name>Mirror Universe</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Mirror Universe: Exchange life totals with target opponent. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0160</id>
    <name>Nevinyrral's Disk</name>
    <text>Nevinyrral's Disk enters the battlefield tapped.
{1}, {T}: Destroy all artifacts, creatures, and enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0161</id>
    <name>Onulet</name>
    <text>When Onulet is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>An early inspiration for Urza, Tocasia's onulets contained magical essences that could be cannibalized after they stopped functioning.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0162</id>
    <name>Phyrexian War Beast</name>
    <text>When Phyrexian War Beast leaves the battlefield, sacrifice a land and Phyrexian War Beast deals 1 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>"Knowing its origins, how could they have thought they could control it?"
—Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi heretic</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0163</id>
    <name>Ring of Ma'rûf</name>
    <text>{5}, {T}, Exile Ring of Ma'rûf: The next time you would draw a card this turn, instead choose a card you own from outside the game and put it into your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0164</id>
    <name>Serpent Generator</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Put a 1/1 colorless Snake artifact creature token onto the battlefield. This creature has "Whenever this creature deals damage to a player, that player gets a poison counter." (A player with ten or more poison counters loses the game.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0165</id>
    <name>Shield of the Ages</name>
    <text>{2}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to you this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"This shield is a true rarity: an artifact whose purpose is obvious."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0166</id>
    <name>Shield Sphere</name>
    <text>Defender
Whenever Shield Sphere blocks, put a -0/-1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"My soldiers know that they need never fear for their protection."
—King Darien of Kjeldor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0167</id>
    <name>Stone Calendar</name>
    <text>Spells you cast cost up to {1} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>The Pretender Mairsil ordered a great calendar drawn up to show when the paths to the Dark Lands were strongest.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0168</id>
    <name>Su-Chi</name>
    <text>When Su-Chi is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, add {4} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Flawed copies of relics from the Thran Empire, the su-chi were inherently unstable but provided useful knowledge for Tocasia's students.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0169</id>
    <name>Tawnos's Coffin</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Tawnos's Coffin during your untap step.
{3}, {T}: Exile target creature and all Auras attached to it. Note the number and kind of counters that were on that creature. When Tawnos's Coffin leaves the battlefield or becomes untapped, return the exiled card to the battlefield under its owner's control tapped with the noted number and kind of counters on it, and if you do, return the exiled Aura cards to the battlefield under their owner's control attached to that permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0170</id>
    <name>Urza's Bauble</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Urza's Bauble: Look at a card at random in target player's hand. You draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0171</id>
    <name>Urza's Chalice</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts an artifact spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>When sorely wounded or tired, Urza would often retreat to the workshops of his apprentices. They were greatly amazed at how much better he looked each time he took a sip of water.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0172</id>
    <name>Walking Wall</name>
    <text>Defender
{3}: Walking Wall gets +3/-1 until end of turn and can attack this turn as though it didn't have defender. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The fortress is not what it seems."
—Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi machinist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0173</id>
    <name>Winter Orb</name>
    <text>As long as Winter Orb is untapped, players can't untap more than one land during their untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0174</id>
    <name>Zuran Orb</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a land: You gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"I will go to any length to achieve my goal. Eternal life is worth any sacrifice."
—Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0175</id>
    <name>Diamond Valley</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a creature: You gain life equal to the sacrificed creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0176</id>
    <name>Island of Wak-Wak</name>
    <text>{T}: The power of target creature with flying becomes 0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Isle of Wak-Wak, home to a tribe of winged folk, is named for a peculiar fruit that grows there. The fruit looks like a woman's head, and when ripe speaks the word "Wak."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0177</id>
    <name>Lake of the Dead</name>
    <text>If Lake of the Dead would enter the battlefield, sacrifice a Swamp instead. If you do, put Lake of the Dead onto the battlefield. If you don't, put it into its owner's graveyard.
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice a Swamp: Add {B}{B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0178</id>
    <name>Mishra's Factory</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{1}: Mishra's Factory becomes a 2/2 Assembly-Worker artifact creature until end of turn. It's still a land.
{T}: Target Assembly-Worker creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0179</id>
    <name>Rainbow Vale</name>
    <text>{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. An opponent gains control of Rainbow Vale at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>In the feudal days of Icatia, finding the Rainbow Vale was often the goal of knights' quests.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0180</id>
    <name>Thawing Glaciers</name>
    <text>Thawing Glaciers enters the battlefield tapped.
{1}, {T}: Search your library for a basic land card, put that card onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle your library. Return Thawing Glaciers to its owner's hand at the beginning of the next cleanup step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0181</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0182</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0183</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0184</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0185</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0186</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0187</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0188</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0189</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0190</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0191</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0192</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0193</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0194</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MED0195</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>