<cards name="Mercadian Masques">
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0001</id>
    <name>Afterlife</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature. It can't be regenerated. Its controller puts a 1/1 white Spirit creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0002</id>
    <name>Alabaster Wall</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Its mortar is mixed with waters straight from the Fountain of Cho.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0003</id>
    <name>Armistice</name>
    <text>{3}{W}{W}: You draw a card and target opponent gains 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>We all must profit for peace to last.
—Mercadian saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0004</id>
    <name>Arrest</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block, and its activated abilities can't be activated.</text>
    <flavorText>Orim had no memory of the previous night—the first thing she could remember was waking up with the dead guard's blood on her hands.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0005</id>
    <name>Ballista Squad</name>
    <text>{X}{W}, {T}: Ballista Squad deals X damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The perfect antidote for a tightly packed formation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0006</id>
    <name>Charm Peddler</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}, Discard a card: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to target creature this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0007</id>
    <name>Charmed Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying
When Charmed Griffin enters the battlefield, each other player may put an artifact or enchantment card onto the battlefield from his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Are you sure you can afford such a luxury?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0008</id>
    <name>Cho-Arrim Alchemist</name>
    <text>{1}{W}{W}, {T}, Discard a card: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage. You gain life equal to the damage prevented this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0009</id>
    <name>Cho-Arrim Bruiser</name>
    <text>Whenever Cho-Arrim Bruiser attacks, you may tap up to two target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>He doesn't know why the Cho-Arrim fight the Mercadians, but he's happy to bash heads for them anyway.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0010</id>
    <name>Cho-Arrim Legate</name>
    <text>Protection from black
If an opponent controls a Swamp and you control a Plains, you may cast Cho-Arrim Legate without paying its mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0011</id>
    <name>Cho-Manno, Revolutionary</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt to Cho-Manno, Revolutionary.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mercadia's masks can no longer hide the truth. Our day has come at last."
—Cho-Manno</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0012</id>
    <name>Cho-Manno's Blessing</name>
    <text>Flash
Enchant creature
As Cho-Manno's Blessing enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Enchanted creature has protection from the chosen color. This effect doesn't remove Cho-Manno's Blessing.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0013</id>
    <name>Common Cause</name>
    <text>Nonartifact creatures get +2/+2 as long as they all share a color.</text>
    <flavorText>Mercadia City's troops are at their best when they have no enemy to fight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0014</id>
    <name>Cornered Market</name>
    <text>Players can't cast spells with the same name as a nontoken permanent.
Players can't play nonbasic lands with the same name as a nontoken permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>Don't step on the livelihood of other vendors, or they may step on you.
—Mercadian saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0015</id>
    <name>Crackdown</name>
    <text>Nonwhite creatures with power 3 or greater don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is no place for mercy in defense of our lives."
—Ta-Spon, Cho-Arrim executioner</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0016</id>
    <name>Crossbow Infantry</name>
    <text>{T}: Crossbow Infantry deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The crossbow is the ideal weapon for the lazy Mercadians: just point and shoot.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0017</id>
    <name>Devout Witness</name>
    <text>{1}{W}, {T}, Discard a card: Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>The Cho-Arrim fought Mercadia's decadence with more than just swords.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0018</id>
    <name>Disenchant</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>The scepter of power is fragile in a calloused hand.
—Cho-Arrim saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0019</id>
    <name>Fountain Watch</name>
    <text>Artifacts and enchantments you control have shroud. (They can't be the targets of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>The Cho-Arrim didn't rely only on a secret location to protect their Fountain.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0020</id>
    <name>Fresh Volunteers</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Every Cho-Arrim villager is a potential warrior; when they are called, they abandon their peaceful way of life and take up arms to defend it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0021</id>
    <name>Honor the Fallen</name>
    <text>Exile all creature cards from all graveyards. You gain 1 life for each card exiled this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"May the River claim Cho-Manno's body, wherever it lies."
—Ta-Karnst, Cho-Arrim healer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0022</id>
    <name>Ignoble Soldier</name>
    <text>Whenever Ignoble Soldier becomes blocked, prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by it this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Cowardice is a term invented by those with no cunning.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0023</id>
    <name>Inviolability</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Prevent all damage that would be dealt to enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>A soldier's faith is magic strong enough to protect against any blade.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0024</id>
    <name>Ivory Mask</name>
    <text>You have shroud. (You can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I did not choose my role, Orim," said Cho-Manno patiently, "and I suspect Gerrard did not choose his."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0025</id>
    <name>Jhovall Queen</name>
    <text>Vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>War-trained jhovalls eat twice their weight in war-trained soldiers daily.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0026</id>
    <name>Jhovall Rider</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>Don't be fooled by the riders' fluid grace—it takes years of practice to ride these beasts.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0027</id>
    <name>Last Breath</name>
    <text>Exile target creature with power 2 or less. Its controller gains 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The River flows. My soul returns."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0028</id>
    <name>Moment of Silence</name>
    <text>Target player skips his or her next combat phase this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The silence commemorates not those who've died, but those about to.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0029</id>
    <name>Moonlit Wake</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"As long as Rushwood glows, no life is ever truly lost."
—Ta-Karnst, Cho-Arrim healer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0030</id>
    <name>Muzzle</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Prevent all damage that would be dealt by enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Clenched teeth do not bite.
—Cho-Arrim saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0031</id>
    <name>Nightwind Glider</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from black</text>
    <flavorText>Once you learn to float on the shadows, you'll never fear them again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0032</id>
    <name>Noble Purpose</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control deals combat damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>Fighting for the right reason is itself a source of strength.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0033</id>
    <name>Orim's Cure</name>
    <text>If you control a Plains, you may tap an untapped creature you control rather than pay the mana cost of Orim's Cure.

Prevent the next 4 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0034</id>
    <name>Pious Warrior</name>
    <text>Whenever Pious Warrior is dealt combat damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>The Cho-Arrim make no distinction between healers and soldiers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0035</id>
    <name>Ramosian Captain</name>
    <text>First strike
{5}, {T}: Search your library for a Rebel permanent card with converted mana cost 4 or less and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The Cho-Arrim believe in leading by example.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0036</id>
    <name>Ramosian Commander</name>
    <text>{6}, {T}: Search your library for a Rebel permanent card with converted mana cost 5 or less and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Cho-Manno guides your spirit. I guide your sword."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0037</id>
    <name>Ramosian Lieutenant</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Search your library for a Rebel permanent card with converted mana cost 3 or less and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Give me your hand and I will give you victory."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0038</id>
    <name>Ramosian Rally</name>
    <text>If you control a Plains, you may tap an untapped creature you control rather than pay Ramosian Rally's mana cost.

Creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0039</id>
    <name>Ramosian Sergeant</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Search your library for a Rebel permanent card with converted mana cost 2 or less and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Her commands are part rallying cry, part sermon, and wholly undeniable.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0040</id>
    <name>Ramosian Sky Marshal</name>
    <text>Flying
{7}, {T}: Search your library for a Rebel permanent card with converted mana cost 6 or less and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The Cho-Arrim fell from the sky onto Mercadia City like a vengeful rain.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0041</id>
    <name>Rappelling Scouts</name>
    <text>Flying
{2}{W}: Rappelling Scouts gains protection from the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0042</id>
    <name>Renounce</name>
    <text>Sacrifice any number of permanents. You gain 2 life for each one sacrificed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard offered no defense to Orim's condemnation; the mission was under his command, and he was responsible.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0043</id>
    <name>Revered Elder</name>
    <text>{1}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to Revered Elder this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Cho-Arrim worship life and revere those who've experienced it longest.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0044</id>
    <name>Reverent Mantra</name>
    <text>You may exile a white card from your hand rather than pay Reverent Mantra's mana cost.
All creatures gain protection from the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0045</id>
    <name>Righteous Aura</name>
    <text>{W}, Pay 2 life: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>"There is a great difference between pain and injury."
—Cho-Manno</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0046</id>
    <name>Righteous Indignation</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature blocks a black or red creature, the blocking creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"You are the disease that plagues Mercadia. I am the healer's knife that will cut you out."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0047</id>
    <name>Security Detail</name>
    <text>{W}{W}: Put a 1/1 white Soldier creature token onto the battlefield. Activate this ability only if you control no creatures and only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0048</id>
    <name>Soothing Balm</name>
    <text>Target player gains 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Orim taught Ta-Karnst and the other Cho-Arrim healers a far less invasive method of healing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0049</id>
    <name>Spiritual Focus</name>
    <text>Whenever a spell or ability an opponent controls causes you to discard a card, you gain 2 life and you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0050</id>
    <name>Steadfast Guard</name>
    <text>Vigilance (Attacking doesn't cause this creature to tap.)</text>
    <flavorText>The Mercadians were prepared for the guard, but the guard was even more prepared for the Mercadians.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0051</id>
    <name>Story Circle</name>
    <text>As Story Circle enters the battlefield, choose a color.
{W}: The next time a source of your choice of the chosen color would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0052</id>
    <name>Task Force</name>
    <text>Whenever Task Force becomes the target of a spell or ability, it gets +0/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>They are the reflection of Rushwood's glow on the edge of a wooden sword.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0053</id>
    <name>Thermal Glider</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from red</text>
    <flavorText>"The Mercadians are too busy looking down on us to see us coming."
—Cho-Arrim rebel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0054</id>
    <name>Tonic Peddler</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}, Discard a card: Target player gains 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The price is written at the bottom of the cup."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0055</id>
    <name>Trap Runner</name>
    <text>{T}: Target attacking unblocked creature becomes blocked. Activate this ability only during the declare blockers step. (This ability works on unblockable creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>"How could I catch her when the trees conspired to stop me?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0056</id>
    <name>Wave of Reckoning</name>
    <text>Each creature deals damage to itself equal to its power.</text>
    <flavorText>Inner conflict can defeat a soldier more quickly than any army.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0057</id>
    <name>Wishmonger</name>
    <text>{2}: Target creature gains protection from the color of its controller's choice until end of turn. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's not what you ask for, but how you ask for it."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0058</id>
    <name>Aerial Caravan</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{U}{U}: Exile the top card of your library. Until end of turn, you may play that card. (Reveal the card as you exile it.)</text>
    <flavorText>Successful delivery is not guaranteed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0059</id>
    <name>Balloon Peddler</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}, Discard a card: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The market festival turned out to be the high point of Jaffy's visit.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0060</id>
    <name>Blockade Runner</name>
    <text>{U}: Blockade Runner is unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I need to get back to Mercadia City," said Sisay. "We can get you there," the vizier answered. "Easily."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0061</id>
    <name>Brainstorm</name>
    <text>Draw three cards, then put two cards from your hand on top of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>"I see more than others do because I know where to look."
—Saprazzan vizier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0062</id>
    <name>Bribery</name>
    <text>Search target opponent's library for a creature card and put that card onto the battlefield under your control. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>In Mercadia City, loyalties extend only as far as your purse can stretch.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0063</id>
    <name>Buoyancy</name>
    <text>Flash
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Saprazzan merfolk become legged on land, but some find it quicker to bring the water with them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0064</id>
    <name>Chambered Nautilus</name>
    <text>Whenever Chambered Nautilus becomes blocked, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>What's merely a home for the nautilus can become exquisite jewelry in the hands of Saprazzan artisans.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0065</id>
    <name>Chameleon Spirit</name>
    <text>As Chameleon Spirit enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Chameleon Spirit's power and toughness are each equal to the number of permanents of the chosen color your opponents control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0066</id>
    <name>Charisma</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage to a creature, gain control of the second creature for as long as Charisma remains on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>It was Gerrard's nature to lead and the Mercadians' to follow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0067</id>
    <name>Cloud Sprite</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Cloud Sprite can block only creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>The delicate sprites carry messages for Saprazzans, but they refuse to land in Mercadia City's filthy markets.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0068</id>
    <name>Coastal Piracy</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control deals combat damage to an opponent, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I don't like to think of myself as a pirate. I'm more like a stimulator of the local economy."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0069</id>
    <name>Counterspell</name>
    <text>Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your attack has been rendered harmless. It is, however, quite pretty."
—Saprazzan vizier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0070</id>
    <name>Cowardice</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature becomes the target of a spell or ability, return that creature to its owner's hand. (It won't be affected by the spell or ability.)</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard was the Mercadian soldiers' greatest hero; they followed him blindly. When he left, they stumbled around blindly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0071</id>
    <name>Customs Depot</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a creature spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, draw a card, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>A bribe is always faster than filling out paperwork.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0072</id>
    <name>Darting Merfolk</name>
    <text>{U}: Return Darting Merfolk to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>You might as well try to catch water with a net.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0073</id>
    <name>Dehydration</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>"You say Saprazzo is a city built on water? I hope they have enough to wash the dust from my throat."
—Sisay</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0074</id>
    <name>Diplomatic Escort</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}, Discard a card: Counter target spell or ability that targets a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0075</id>
    <name>Diplomatic Immunity</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)
Enchanted creature has shroud.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0076</id>
    <name>Drake Hatchling</name>
    <text>Flying
{U}: Drake Hatchling gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>There is beauty in the space between learning to fly and taking it for granted.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0077</id>
    <name>Embargo</name>
    <text>Nonland permanents don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.

At the beginning of your upkeep, you lose 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0078</id>
    <name>Energy Flux</name>
    <text>All artifacts have "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice this artifact unless you pay {2}."</text>
    <flavorText>Karn said nothing—he just grasped the powerstone and squeezed tightly. The wild flashing ceased.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0079</id>
    <name>Extravagant Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Extravagant Spirit unless you pay {1} for each card in your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The fewer your possessions, the fewer your worries.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0080</id>
    <name>False Demise</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, return that card to the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Go down there and fish him out. Maybe his hide will fetch a price."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0081</id>
    <name>Glowing Anemone</name>
    <text>When Glowing Anemone enters the battlefield, you may return target land to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Beautiful to behold, terrible to be held.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0082</id>
    <name>Gush</name>
    <text>You may return two Islands you control to their owner's hand rather than pay Gush's mana cost.

Draw two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Don't trust your secrets to the sea.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0083</id>
    <name>High Seas</name>
    <text>Red creature spells and green creature spells cost {1} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>Bend as the wave breaks or it will break you as well.
—Saprazzan saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0084</id>
    <name>Hoodwink</name>
    <text>Return target artifact, enchantment, or land to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The youths of Rishada's marketplace are always ready for a quick footrace.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0085</id>
    <name>Indentured Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying
When Indentured Djinn enters the battlefield, each other player may draw up to three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>It's not always clear who's the master and who's the servant.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0086</id>
    <name>Karn's Touch</name>
    <text>Target noncreature artifact becomes an artifact creature with power and toughness each equal to its converted mana cost until end of turn. (It retains its abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0087</id>
    <name>Misdirection</name>
    <text>You may exile a blue card from your hand rather than pay Misdirection's mana cost.
Change the target of target spell with a single target.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0088</id>
    <name>Misstep</name>
    <text>Creatures target player controls don't untap during that player's next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>The feet have no eyes.
—Saprazzan saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0089</id>
    <name>Overtaker</name>
    <text>{3}{U}, {T}, Discard a card: Untap target creature and gain control of it until end of turn. That creature gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's no challenge to master a Mercadian."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0090</id>
    <name>Port Inspector</name>
    <text>Whenever Port Inspector becomes blocked, you may look at defending player's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"There may be a few minor additional fees, levies, duties, surtaxes, tariffs, imposts, tolls . . . ."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0091</id>
    <name>Rishadan Airship</name>
    <text>Flying
Rishadan Airship can block only creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>The view is truly spectacular—as long as you don't look at Rishada itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0092</id>
    <name>Rishadan Brigand</name>
    <text>Flying
When Rishadan Brigand enters the battlefield, each opponent sacrifices a permanent unless he or she pays {3}.
Rishadan Brigand can block only creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0093</id>
    <name>Rishadan Cutpurse</name>
    <text>When Rishadan Cutpurse enters the battlefield, each opponent sacrifices a permanent unless he or she pays {1}.</text>
    <flavorText>The bigger the purse, the greater the fool.
—Rishadan saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0094</id>
    <name>Rishadan Footpad</name>
    <text>When Rishadan Footpad enters the battlefield, each opponent sacrifices a permanent unless he or she pays {2}.</text>
    <flavorText>"The best things in life are free. Money, for instance."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0095</id>
    <name>Sailmonger</name>
    <text>{2}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>Clients who cheat the sailmonger make an impact on the rest.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0096</id>
    <name>Sand Squid</name>
    <text>Islandwalk
You may choose not to untap Sand Squid during your untap step.
{T}: Tap target creature. That creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step for as long as Sand Squid remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0097</id>
    <name>Saprazzan Bailiff</name>
    <text>When Saprazzan Bailiff enters the battlefield, exile all artifact and enchantment cards from all graveyards.
When Saprazzan Bailiff leaves the battlefield, return all artifact and enchantment cards from all graveyards to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0098</id>
    <name>Saprazzan Breaker</name>
    <text>{U}: Put the top card of your library into your graveyard. If that card is a land card, Saprazzan Breaker is unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0099</id>
    <name>Saprazzan Heir</name>
    <text>Whenever Saprazzan Heir becomes blocked, you may draw three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Within the walls of the floating city, Saprazzan wealth is like Saprazzan water: abundant, free-flowing, and accessible to all.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0100</id>
    <name>Saprazzan Legate</name>
    <text>Flying
If an opponent controls a Mountain and you control an Island, you may cast Saprazzan Legate without paying its mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0101</id>
    <name>Saprazzan Outrigger</name>
    <text>When Saprazzan Outrigger attacks or blocks, put it on top of its owner's library at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>The Saprazzans excel at both tactics: hit and run.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0102</id>
    <name>Saprazzan Raider</name>
    <text>When Saprazzan Raider becomes blocked, return it to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Some quick dagger work and then back to the sea—that's the Saprazzan way.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0103</id>
    <name>Shoving Match</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, all creatures gain "{T}: Tap target creature."</text>
    <flavorText>Rishadan barkeeps know something the Mercadians have yet to learn: if you keep pushing, someone will eventually push back.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0104</id>
    <name>Soothsaying</name>
    <text>{3}{U}{U}: Shuffle your library.

{X}: Look at the top X cards of your library and put them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>The vizier's wisdom proved invaluable in untangling the Mercadian knot of lies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0105</id>
    <name>Squeeze</name>
    <text>Sorcery spells cost {3} more to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>Any pirate would prefer Rishada's swift and cruel justice to Saprazzo's patient punishments.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0106</id>
    <name>Statecraft</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Inside these walls, peace; outside, sharks. You choose."
—Saprazzan vizier</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0107</id>
    <name>Stinging Barrier</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{U}, {T}: Stinging Barrier deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0108</id>
    <name>Thwart</name>
    <text>You may return three Islands you control to their owner's hand rather than pay Thwart's mana cost.

Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0109</id>
    <name>Tidal Bore</name>
    <text>You may return an Island you control to its owner's hand rather than pay Tidal Bore's mana cost.
You may tap or untap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The dry riverbed became a raging torrent, and the Cho-Arrim claimed their prize.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0110</id>
    <name>Tidal Kraken</name>
    <text>Tidal Kraken is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>To merfolk, pirates are a nuisance. To pirates, merfolk are a threat. To the kraken, they're both appetizers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0111</id>
    <name>Timid Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
When another creature enters the battlefield, return Timid Drake to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>It flees from anything that isn't shaped like a cloud.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0112</id>
    <name>Trade Routes</name>
    <text>{1}: Return target land you control to its owner's hand.
{1}, Discard a land card: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Like the price of goods, the value of the routes was renegotiated daily.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0113</id>
    <name>War Tax</name>
    <text>{X}{U}: Creatures can't attack this turn unless their controller pays {X} for each attacking creature he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>The worst thing about being a depraved pirate is having to work with a bunch of depraved pirates.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0114</id>
    <name>Waterfront Bouncer</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}, Discard a card: Return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Closing time comes earlier to some than to others.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0115</id>
    <name>Alley Grifters</name>
    <text>Whenever Alley Grifters becomes blocked, defending player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>One distracts the victim, the other extracts the valuables.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0116</id>
    <name>Black Market</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a charge counter on Black Market.
At the beginning of your precombat main phase, add {B} to your mana pool for each charge counter on Black Market.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0117</id>
    <name>Bog Smugglers</name>
    <text>Swampwalk</text>
    <flavorText>They slide over the bog like oil across glass.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0118</id>
    <name>Bog Witch</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}, Discard a card: Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The world is the body. The mana is the blood. The witch is the surgeon.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0119</id>
    <name>Cackling Witch</name>
    <text>{X}{B}, {T}, Discard a card: Target creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The touch of his madness can drive anyone into a killing frenzy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0120</id>
    <name>Cateran Brute</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Search your library for a Mercenary permanent card with converted mana cost 2 or less and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The Cateran guild prefers to call them "public relations."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0121</id>
    <name>Cateran Enforcer</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
{4}, {T}: Search your library for a Mercenary permanent card with converted mana cost 4 or less and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0122</id>
    <name>Cateran Kidnappers</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Search your library for a Mercenary permanent card with converted mana cost 3 or less and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Recruits aren't always volunteers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0123</id>
    <name>Cateran Overlord</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: Regenerate Cateran Overlord.
{6}, {T}: Search your library for a Mercenary permanent card with converted mana cost 6 or less and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0124</id>
    <name>Cateran Persuader</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Search your library for a Mercenary permanent card with converted mana cost 1 or less and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0125</id>
    <name>Cateran Slaver</name>
    <text>Swampwalk
{5}, {T}: Search your library for a Mercenary permanent card with converted mana cost 5 or less and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0126</id>
    <name>Cateran Summons</name>
    <text>Search your library for a Mercenary card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Even when recruitment is slow, the guild can always cook something up.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0127</id>
    <name>Conspiracy</name>
    <text>As Conspiracy enters the battlefield, choose a creature type.
Creature cards you own that aren't on the battlefield, creature spells you control, and creatures you control are the chosen type.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0128</id>
    <name>Corrupt Official</name>
    <text>{2}{B}: Regenerate Corrupt Official.
Whenever Corrupt Official becomes blocked, defending player discards a card at random.</text>
    <flavorText>His favor comes at a high price.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0129</id>
    <name>Dark Ritual</name>
    <text>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Eye of twilight, give us sight.
Take our offer, give us might.
Make our power tears of night."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0130</id>
    <name>Deathgazer</name>
    <text>Whenever Deathgazer blocks or becomes blocked by a nonblack creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0131</id>
    <name>Deepwood Ghoul</name>
    <text>Pay 2 life: Regenerate Deepwood Ghoul.</text>
    <flavorText>They feed on the living to stay undead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0132</id>
    <name>Deepwood Legate</name>
    <text>If an opponent controls a Forest and you control a Swamp, you may cast Deepwood Legate without paying its mana cost.
{B}: Deepwood Legate gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0133</id>
    <name>Delraich</name>
    <text>Trample
You may sacrifice three black creatures rather than pay Delraich's mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>It wears the souls of its victims like jewels on a chain.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0134</id>
    <name>Enslaved Horror</name>
    <text>When Enslaved Horror enters the battlefield, each other player may return a creature card from his or her graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0135</id>
    <name>Extortion</name>
    <text>Look at target player's hand and choose up to two cards from it. That player discards those cards.</text>
    <flavorText>The enforcers make no effort to distinguish gold from flesh.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0136</id>
    <name>Forced March</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures with converted mana cost X or less.</text>
    <flavorText>The Caterans call it a screening process. The dead are in no condition to argue.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0137</id>
    <name>Ghoul's Feast</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn, where X is the number of creature cards in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Mercadians not wealthy enough to buy a tomb are thrown into a bog called "the Ghoul's Larder."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0138</id>
    <name>Haunted Crossroads</name>
    <text>{B}: Put target creature card from your graveyard on top of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>It seemed as if no one wanted them to reach the Henge of Ramos—not even the dead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0139</id>
    <name>Highway Robber</name>
    <text>When Highway Robber enters the battlefield, target opponent loses 2 life and you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Tonight, madam, it's your money and your life."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0140</id>
    <name>Instigator</name>
    <text>{1}{B}{B}, {T}, Discard a card: Creatures target player controls attack this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>The desecration of their dead makes even the Saprazzans careless.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0141</id>
    <name>Insubordination</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of the end step of enchanted creature's controller, Insubordination deals 2 damage to that player unless that creature attacked this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0142</id>
    <name>Intimidation</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have fear. (They can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>"If they move, kill them. In fact, kill one now to make sure the other understands."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0143</id>
    <name>Larceny</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control deals combat damage to a player, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0144</id>
    <name>Liability</name>
    <text>Whenever a nontoken permanent is put into a player's graveyard from the battlefield, that player loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard realized that the helpless woman they'd rescued from Rath was nothing of the sort.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0145</id>
    <name>Maggot Therapy</name>
    <text>Flash
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/-2.</text>
    <flavorText>"If this is the cure, I'd hate to see the disease."
—Orim</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0146</id>
    <name>Midnight Ritual</name>
    <text>Exile X target creature cards from your graveyard. For each creature card exiled this way, put a 2/2 black Zombie creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Bury old friends deeply, lest they return bearing worms.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0147</id>
    <name>Misshapen Fiend</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>You'd scarcely believe they could fly until they drop out of the sky onto you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0148</id>
    <name>Molting Harpy</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Molting Harpy unless you pay {2}.</text>
    <flavorText>Shed harpy feathers leave painful wounds—which explains the harpies' mood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0149</id>
    <name>Nether Spirit</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if Nether Spirit is the only creature card in your graveyard, you may return Nether Spirit to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>It roams in both the worlds of the living and the dead but belongs to neither.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0150</id>
    <name>Notorious Assassin</name>
    <text>{2}{B}, {T}, Discard a card: Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>He wears his infamy like a fine silk shirt.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0151</id>
    <name>Pretender's Claim</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature becomes blocked, tap all lands defending player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>The surest way to lose your holdings is to plead for them in Mercadia City's courts.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0152</id>
    <name>Primeval Shambler</name>
    <text>{B}: Primeval Shambler gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>His mind, like his body, is made up of the swamp's flotsam.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0153</id>
    <name>Putrefaction</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a green or white spell, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Do you want to be alive or whole?"
—Ta-Karnst, Cho-Arrim healer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0154</id>
    <name>Quagmire Lamprey</name>
    <text>Whenever Quagmire Lamprey becomes blocked by a creature, put a -1/-1 counter on that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0155</id>
    <name>Rain of Tears</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>Mercadian elitism is reinforced daily by physical position: their neighbors are literally beneath them and are treated accordingly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0156</id>
    <name>Rampart Crawler</name>
    <text>Rampart Crawler can't be blocked by Walls.</text>
    <flavorText>"Not even the magistrate in his lofty tower is out of our reach."
—Cateran overlord</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0157</id>
    <name>Rouse</name>
    <text>If you control a Swamp, you may pay 2 life rather than pay Rouse's mana cost.

Target creature gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0158</id>
    <name>Scandalmonger</name>
    <text>{2}: Target player discards a card. Any player may activate this ability but only any time he or she could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>Silence costs extra. Breaking it costs extra still.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0159</id>
    <name>Sever Soul</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated. You gain life equal to its toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>"With the proper tools, even the Great River can be dammed."
—Ta-Spon, Cho-Arrim executioner</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0160</id>
    <name>Silent Assassin</name>
    <text>{3}{B}: Destroy target blocking creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>She feels no need to disturb her victim's slumber.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0161</id>
    <name>Skulking Fugitive</name>
    <text>When Skulking Fugitive becomes the target of a spell or ability, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>In the Cateran guild, being caught is a capital offense.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0162</id>
    <name>Snuff Out</name>
    <text>If you control a Swamp, you may pay 4 life rather than pay Snuff Out's mana cost.

Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>Squee watched his Kyren cousins fall with a mixture of sympathy and relief.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0163</id>
    <name>Soul Channeling</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Pay 2 life: Regenerate enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Driven by masters more terrible than the Mercadians could imagine, the dark overseers would pay any price to keep their shipwrights working.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0164</id>
    <name>Specter's Wail</name>
    <text>Target player discards a card at random.</text>
    <flavorText>As he gritted his teeth to focus through the pain, Tahngarth glanced at Takara. She seemed completely unaffected.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0165</id>
    <name>Strongarm Thug</name>
    <text>When Strongarm Thug enters the battlefield, you may return target Mercenary card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"No, I insist—let me carry all that heavy jewelry."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0166</id>
    <name>Thrashing Wumpus</name>
    <text>{B}: Thrashing Wumpus deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>Young wumpuses are malevolent and vicious—but they grow out of it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0167</id>
    <name>Undertaker</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}, Discard a card: Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The weight of death is heavy but not immovable.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0168</id>
    <name>Unmask</name>
    <text>You may exile a black card from your hand rather than pay Unmask's mana cost.
Target player reveals his or her hand. You choose a nonland card from it. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0169</id>
    <name>Unnatural Hunger</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, Unnatural Hunger deals damage to that player equal to that creature's power unless he or she sacrifices another creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0170</id>
    <name>Vendetta</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated. You lose life equal to that creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>Starke knew the voice was Takara's, but the venom was Volrath's.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0171</id>
    <name>Wall of Distortion</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{2}{B}, {T}: Target player discards a card. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>It reflects only nightmares.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0172</id>
    <name>Arms Dealer</name>
    <text>{1}{R}, Sacrifice a Goblin: Arms Dealer deals 4 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>He has the weapons, he has the connections, and he knows the hangar's dark secret.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0173</id>
    <name>Battle Rampart</name>
    <text>Defender
{T}: Target creature gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0174</id>
    <name>Battle Squadron</name>
    <text>Flying
Battle Squadron's power and toughness are each equal to the number of creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The goblins made an unruly pile with military precision.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0175</id>
    <name>Blaster Mage</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}, Discard a card: Destroy target Wall.</text>
    <flavorText>"Don't get up. I'll show myself out."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0176</id>
    <name>Blood Hound</name>
    <text>Whenever you're dealt damage, you may put that many +1/+1 counters on Blood Hound.
At the beginning of your end step, remove all +1/+1 counters from Blood Hound.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0177</id>
    <name>Blood Oath</name>
    <text>Choose a card type. Target opponent reveals his or her hand. Blood Oath deals 3 damage to that player for each card of the chosen type revealed this way. (The card types are artifact, creature, enchantment, instant, land, planeswalker, sorcery, and tribal.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0178</id>
    <name>Brawl</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, all creatures gain "{T}: This creature deals damage equal to its power to target creature."</text>
    <flavorText>Anything can happen when patience is scarce and wine is abundant.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0179</id>
    <name>Cave Sense</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has mountainwalk.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0180</id>
    <name>Cave-In</name>
    <text>You may exile a red card from your hand rather than pay Cave-In's mana cost.
Cave-In deals 2 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>One fleet was gone; others were poised.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0181</id>
    <name>Cavern Crawler</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk
{R}: Cavern Crawler gets +1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0182</id>
    <name>Ceremonial Guard</name>
    <text>When Ceremonial Guard attacks or blocks, destroy it at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"These guards are the most disciplined military unit in the city. They couldn't fight their way out of a broom closet, but they've got discipline."
—Gerrard, to Sisay</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0183</id>
    <name>Cinder Elemental</name>
    <text>{X}{R}, {T}, Sacrifice Cinder Elemental: Cinder Elemental deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Their rage can grow to such proportions that they explode in a cloud of fire.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0184</id>
    <name>Close Quarters</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control becomes blocked, Close Quarters deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>The Mercadians' ineptitude in close combat sometimes accidentally pays off.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0185</id>
    <name>Crag Saurian</name>
    <text>Whenever a source deals damage to Crag Saurian, that source's controller gains control of Crag Saurian.</text>
    <flavorText>It follows the strongest leader—the one with the longest whip.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0186</id>
    <name>Crash</name>
    <text>You may sacrifice a Mountain rather than pay Crash's mana cost.

Destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard shook his head as the ground rushed to meet him. "This," he thought, "is not the start I was hoping for."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0187</id>
    <name>Flailing Manticore</name>
    <text>Flying, first strike
{1}: Flailing Manticore gets +1/+1 until end of turn. Any player may activate this ability.
{1}: Flailing Manticore gets -1/-1 until end of turn. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0188</id>
    <name>Flailing Ogre</name>
    <text>{1}: Flailing Ogre gets +1/+1 until end of turn. Any player may activate this ability.
{1}: Flailing Ogre gets -1/-1 until end of turn. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0189</id>
    <name>Flailing Soldier</name>
    <text>{1}: Flailing Soldier gets +1/+1 until end of turn. Any player may activate this ability.
{1}: Flailing Soldier gets -1/-1 until end of turn. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0190</id>
    <name>Flaming Sword</name>
    <text>Flash
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 and has first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's not Talruum crystal, but I must admit—it gets the job done."
—Tahngarth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0191</id>
    <name>Furious Assault</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a creature spell, Furious Assault deals 1 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Does it burn, Saprazzan? Do you wish you had never raised arms against us?"
—Kyren overseer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0192</id>
    <name>Gerrard's Irregulars</name>
    <text>Trample, haste</text>
    <flavorText>Had Gerrard realized he'd end up fighting against them, he might not have trained them so well.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0193</id>
    <name>Hammer Mage</name>
    <text>{X}{R}, {T}, Discard a card: Destroy all artifacts with converted mana cost X or less.</text>
    <flavorText>When he's holding the hammers, everything looks like a nail.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0194</id>
    <name>Hired Giant</name>
    <text>When Hired Giant enters the battlefield, each other player may search his or her library for a land card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then each player who searched his or her library this way shuffles it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0195</id>
    <name>Kris Mage</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}, Discard a card: Kris Mage deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Her blade draws blood without ever touching its target.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0196</id>
    <name>Kyren Glider</name>
    <text>Flying
Kyren Glider can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>Mercadia's Kyren goblins are the opposite of Dominarian goblins: they're smart and cowardly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0197</id>
    <name>Kyren Legate</name>
    <text>Haste
If an opponent controls a Plains and you control a Mountain, you may cast Kyren Legate without paying its mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0198</id>
    <name>Kyren Negotiations</name>
    <text>Tap an untapped creature you control: Kyren Negotiations deals 1 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Kyren goblins always speak in questions and never allow wrong answers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0199</id>
    <name>Kyren Sniper</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may have Kyren Sniper deal 1 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Kyren goblins always act behind the scenes—even in battle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0200</id>
    <name>Lava Runner</name>
    <text>Haste
Whenever Lava Runner becomes the target of a spell or ability, that spell or ability's controller sacrifices a land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0201</id>
    <name>Lightning Hounds</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>Quick enough to avoid jhovalls when alone and fierce enough to attack them in packs, the hounds were as at home in the mountains as the Mercadians were atop theirs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0202</id>
    <name>Lithophage</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Lithophage unless you sacrifice a Mountain.</text>
    <flavorText>It's viciously territorial, destroying every creature on the mountain it has chosen to consume.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0203</id>
    <name>Lunge</name>
    <text>Lunge deals 2 damage to target creature and 2 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Cho-Arrim righteousness was no match for Benalish combat training.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0204</id>
    <name>Magistrate's Veto</name>
    <text>White creatures and blue creatures can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>The magistrate had been the goblins' puppet for so long that he made the right decisions with little prompting.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0205</id>
    <name>Mercadia's Downfall</name>
    <text>Each attacking creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn for each nonbasic land defending player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>With an explosion that shook the foundation of the city, the Weatherlight burst from the underground hangar.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0206</id>
    <name>Ogre Taskmaster</name>
    <text>Ogre Taskmaster can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>He doesn't have to be smart—his masters only ever give him one command.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0207</id>
    <name>Pulverize</name>
    <text>You may sacrifice two Mountains rather than pay Pulverize's mana cost.

Destroy all artifacts.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0208</id>
    <name>Puppet's Verdict</name>
    <text>Flip a coin. If you win the flip, destroy all creatures with power 2 or less. If you lose the flip, destroy all creatures with power 3 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>"What was heads again?"
—Mercadian magistrate</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0209</id>
    <name>Robber Fly</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Robber Fly becomes blocked, defending player discards all the cards in his or her hand, then draws that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>In pursuit of the juicy fly, Squee stumbled on the hidden hangar.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0210</id>
    <name>Rock Badger</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Mountain.)</text>
    <flavorText>The Kyren goblins created most of the inverted mountain's tunnels simply by driving the beast before them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0211</id>
    <name>Seismic Mage</name>
    <text>{2}{R}, {T}, Discard a card: Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>The ground shakes when he walks. His customers shake if they're late with his fee.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0212</id>
    <name>Shock Troops</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Shock Troops: Shock Troops deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>When goblins blow themselves up, it's called stupidity. When humans do, it's called heroism.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0213</id>
    <name>Sizzle</name>
    <text>Sizzle deals 3 damage to each opponent.</text>
    <flavorText>Explosions ripped through the ship overhead, and those unfortunate enough to be directly below scrambled to find cover.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0214</id>
    <name>Squee, Goblin Nabob</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may return Squee, Goblin Nabob from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"General?" Tahngarth roared. "General nuisance, maybe."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0215</id>
    <name>Stone Rain</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>The return of Ramos was foretold by devastating natural disasters and unnatural storms.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0216</id>
    <name>Tectonic Break</name>
    <text>Each player sacrifices X lands.</text>
    <flavorText>Only the foolish and the rich build their houses where the land is thin and the ocean is near.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0217</id>
    <name>Territorial Dispute</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Territorial Dispute unless you sacrifice a land.
Players can't play lands.</text>
    <flavorText>Bit by bit, Mercadia City had forced the Cho-Arrim from their ancestral lands. They would be pushed no further.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0218</id>
    <name>Thieves' Auction</name>
    <text>Exile all nontoken permanents. Starting with you, each player chooses one of the exiled cards and puts it onto the battlefield tapped under his or her control. Repeat this process until all those cards have been chosen.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0219</id>
    <name>Thunderclap</name>
    <text>You may sacrifice a Mountain rather than pay Thunderclap's mana cost.

Thunderclap deals 3 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0220</id>
    <name>Tremor</name>
    <text>Tremor deals 1 damage to each creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Without a word, Gerrard and Sisay ran deeper into the mountain. Neither of them intended to leave Mercadia without the Weatherlight and its crew.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0221</id>
    <name>Two-Headed Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{R}: Two-Headed Dragon gets +2/+0 until end of turn.
Two-Headed Dragon can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.
Two-Headed Dragon can block an additional creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0222</id>
    <name>Uphill Battle</name>
    <text>Creatures your opponents play enter the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>Cho-Manno knew he had no choice but to ally with Gerrard. If that's what it took to free his people, he'd pay the price.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0223</id>
    <name>Volcanic Wind</name>
    <text>Volcanic Wind deals X damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures, where X is the number of creatures on the battlefield as you cast Volcanic Wind.</text>
    <flavorText>The Cho-Arrim call it "the fury of Ramos."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0224</id>
    <name>War Cadence</name>
    <text>{X}{R}: Creatures can't block this turn unless their controller pays {X} for each blocking creature he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>The rhythm isn't a call to arms, but a signal that the goblins have made a new enemy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0225</id>
    <name>Warmonger</name>
    <text>{2}: Warmonger deals 1 damage to each creature without flying and each player. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>Funny how money and war travel so well together.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0226</id>
    <name>Warpath</name>
    <text>Warpath deals 3 damage to each blocking creature and each blocked creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Cho-Manno had never seen Mercadia City's forces fight so well. The magistrate must have hired a new hero.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0227</id>
    <name>Wild Jhovall</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Jhovalls sharpen their claws on trees—or on Mercadians, if no trees are handy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0228</id>
    <name>Word of Blasting</name>
    <text>Destroy target Wall. It can't be regenerated. Word of Blasting deals damage equal to that Wall's converted mana cost to the Wall's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0229</id>
    <name>Ancestral Mask</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 for each other enchantment on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>The masks, like the ancient trees they're grown from, lend strength to the dryads.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0230</id>
    <name>Bifurcate</name>
    <text>Search your library for a permanent card with the same name as target nontoken creature and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0231</id>
    <name>Boa Constrictor</name>
    <text>{T}: Boa Constrictor gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Its eyes are bigger than its stomach, but its mouth is larger still.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0232</id>
    <name>Briar Patch</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature attacks you, it gets -1/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>As easily as the dryads could close a fist, so could the branches and underbrush entangle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0233</id>
    <name>Caller of the Hunt</name>
    <text>As Caller of the Hunt enters the battlefield, choose a creature type.
Caller of the Hunt's power and toughness are each equal to the number of creatures of the chosen type on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0234</id>
    <name>Caustic Wasps</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Caustic Wasps deals combat damage to a player, you may destroy target artifact that player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Even the wasp knows how to pay the magistrate his due respect.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0235</id>
    <name>Clear the Land</name>
    <text>Each player reveals the top five cards of his or her library, puts all land cards revealed this way onto the battlefield tapped, and exiles the rest.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0236</id>
    <name>Collective Unconscious</name>
    <text>Draw a card for each creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard knew little of Ramos, the sky god they worshiped. But he felt the power of the chant.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0237</id>
    <name>Dawnstrider</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}, Discard a card: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Morning's mists can hide many things.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0238</id>
    <name>Deadly Insect</name>
    <text>Shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>With his newfound sense of self-importance, Squee set his sights on ever-bigger bugs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0239</id>
    <name>Deepwood Drummer</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}, Discard a card: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>His drums echo Deepwood's heartbeat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0240</id>
    <name>Deepwood Elder</name>
    <text>{X}{G}{G}, {T}, Discard a card: X target lands become Forests until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>They'd guarded the Henge so long that they were as attuned to the powerstones as they were to the trees.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0241</id>
    <name>Deepwood Tantiv</name>
    <text>Whenever Deepwood Tantiv becomes blocked, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>A single tantiv is just as dangerous as a herd.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0242</id>
    <name>Deepwood Wolverine</name>
    <text>Whenever Deepwood Wolverine becomes blocked, it gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The jhovalls are depleting its food sources, the Mercadians are eroding its home, and you're wondering why it's angry?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0243</id>
    <name>Desert Twister</name>
    <text>Destroy target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>The magical dust clouds Mercadian mages use to traverse the plane generate storms that devastate the surrounding terrain. But as long as the storms don't touch the mountain, the nobles simply don't care.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0244</id>
    <name>Erithizon</name>
    <text>Whenever Erithizon attacks, put a +1/+1 counter on target creature of defending player's choice.</text>
    <flavorText>Unlike scorpions, the erithizon isn't immune to its own weaponry.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0245</id>
    <name>Ferocity</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature blocks or becomes blocked, you may put a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"You lot go on ahead. I'll keep killing them until it sticks."
—Tahngarth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0246</id>
    <name>Food Chain</name>
    <text>Exile a creature you control: Add X mana of any one color to your mana pool, where X is the exiled creature's converted mana cost plus one. Spend this mana only to cast creature spells.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0247</id>
    <name>Foster</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {1}. If you do, reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal a creature card. Put that card into your hand and the rest into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0248</id>
    <name>Game Preserve</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, each player reveals the top card of his or her library. If all cards revealed this way are creature cards, put those cards onto the battlefield under their owners' control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0249</id>
    <name>Giant Caterpillar</name>
    <text>{G}, Sacrifice Giant Caterpillar: Put a 1/1 green Insect creature token with flying named Butterfly onto the battlefield at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0250</id>
    <name>Groundskeeper</name>
    <text>{1}{G}: Return target basic land card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Whereas the rebels fight to defend the land, they work to renew it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0251</id>
    <name>Horned Troll</name>
    <text>{G}: Regenerate Horned Troll.</text>
    <flavorText>"If I says it's a troll, it's a troll. Goblins is always right in Mercadia."
—Squee</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0252</id>
    <name>Howling Wolf</name>
    <text>When Howling Wolf enters the battlefield, you may search your library for up to three cards named Howling Wolf, reveal them, and put them into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0253</id>
    <name>Hunted Wumpus</name>
    <text>When Hunted Wumpus enters the battlefield, each other player may put a creature card from his or her hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Just one can feed a dozen people for a month.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0254</id>
    <name>Invigorate</name>
    <text>If you control a Forest, you may have an opponent gain 3 life rather than pay Invigorate's mana cost.

Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0255</id>
    <name>Land Grant</name>
    <text>If you have no land cards in hand, you may reveal your hand rather than pay Land Grant's mana cost.

Search your library for a Forest card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0256</id>
    <name>Ley Line</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player may put a +1/+1 counter on target creature of his or her choice.</text>
    <flavorText>"I can feel the strength of the entire forest."
—Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0257</id>
    <name>Lumbering Satyr</name>
    <text>All creatures have forestwalk.</text>
    <flavorText>The satyr carves the path that all of Rushwood follows.
—Cho-Arrim saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0258</id>
    <name>Lure</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
All creatures able to block enchanted creature do so.</text>
    <flavorText>Deepwood's reach is not long, so it invites its enemies in.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0259</id>
    <name>Megatherium</name>
    <text>Trample
When Megatherium enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you pay {1} for each card in your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0260</id>
    <name>Natural Affinity</name>
    <text>All lands become 2/2 creatures until end of turn. They're still lands.</text>
    <flavorText>As long as the dryads are a part of the forest, the forest is a part of the army.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0261</id>
    <name>Pangosaur</name>
    <text>Whenever a player plays a land, return Pangosaur to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Only Rushwood is vast enough to swallow this creature whole.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0262</id>
    <name>Revive</name>
    <text>Return target green card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard's heart ached, recalling the living wreath Mirri laid for her dead kin. No such memorial was left for her in Rath.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0263</id>
    <name>Rushwood Dryad</name>
    <text>Forestwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Forest.)</text>
    <flavorText>Rushwood is a living jewel that reflects its dwellers' hearts.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0264</id>
    <name>Rushwood Elemental</name>
    <text>Trample
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Rushwood Elemental.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0265</id>
    <name>Rushwood Herbalist</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}, Discard a card: Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>When generals gather their armies, healers gather their herbs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0266</id>
    <name>Rushwood Legate</name>
    <text>If an opponent controls an Island and you control a Forest, you may cast Rushwood Legate without paying its mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0267</id>
    <name>Saber Ants</name>
    <text>Whenever Saber Ants is dealt damage, you may put that many 1/1 green Insect creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>They stay on the battlefield only long enough to consume the losers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0268</id>
    <name>Sacred Prey</name>
    <text>Whenever Sacred Prey becomes blocked, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>To see one is a good omen to the Cho-Arrim.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0269</id>
    <name>Silverglade Elemental</name>
    <text>When Silverglade Elemental enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a Forest card and put that card onto the battlefield. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0270</id>
    <name>Silverglade Pathfinder</name>
    <text>{1}{G}, {T}, Discard a card: Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0271</id>
    <name>Snake Pit</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a blue or black spell, you may put a 1/1 green Snake creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>If the ground is smooth, the way will be rough.
—Deepwood saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0272</id>
    <name>Snorting Gahr</name>
    <text>Whenever Snorting Gahr becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>There's little advantage to surprising the gahr.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0273</id>
    <name>Spidersilk Armor</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +0/+1 and have reach. (They can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>It hardly weighs anything, but it takes all day to remove.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0274</id>
    <name>Spontaneous Generation</name>
    <text>Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield for each card in your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Saprolings always thrive on the ruins of others, and Mercadia ruins more than most.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0275</id>
    <name>Squall</name>
    <text>Squall deals 2 damage to each creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>The air that holds them aloft can just as easily put them down.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0276</id>
    <name>Squallmonger</name>
    <text>{2}: Squallmonger deals 1 damage to each creature with flying and each player. Any player may activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>"Squall, gale, hurricane—it's all a matter of size . . . and price."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0277</id>
    <name>Stamina</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has vigilance.
Sacrifice Stamina: Regenerate enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0278</id>
    <name>Sustenance</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice a land: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Like the dryads, the forest itself willingly gives up some of its life for the sake of the future.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0279</id>
    <name>Tiger Claws</name>
    <text>Flash
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has trample.</text>
    <flavorText>Cho-Arrim martial artists emulate the beasts of their home.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0280</id>
    <name>Tranquility</name>
    <text>Destroy all enchantments.</text>
    <flavorText>Sisay had been restored to her place on the ship, the Legacy had been recovered, and the Weatherlight was sailing home to Dominaria. Gerrard focused on the debts he'd settled . . . and on those he'd soon collect.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0281</id>
    <name>Venomous Breath</name>
    <text>At end of combat, destroy all creatures that blocked or were blocked by target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The dryads need neither size nor strength to defeat their enemies in battle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0282</id>
    <name>Venomous Dragonfly</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Venomous Dragonfly blocks or becomes blocked by a creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>A pretty little death is still death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0283</id>
    <name>Vernal Equinox</name>
    <text>Any player may play creature and enchantment cards as though they had flash.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0284</id>
    <name>Vine Dryad</name>
    <text>Flash
Forestwalk
You may exile a green card from your hand rather than pay Vine Dryad's mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0285</id>
    <name>Vine Trellis</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"We protect our own with our own."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0286</id>
    <name>Assembly Hall</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Reveal a creature card in your hand. Search your library for a card with the same name as that card, reveal the card, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0287</id>
    <name>Barbed Wire</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Barbed Wire deals 1 damage to that player.

{2}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt by Barbed Wire this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A steel snake with ten thousand teeth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0288</id>
    <name>Bargaining Table</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: Draw a card. X is the number of cards in an opponent's hand as you activate this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>Although it looks like a game, business around the table is deadly serious.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0289</id>
    <name>Credit Voucher</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Credit Voucher: Shuffle any number of cards from your hand into your library, then draw that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0290</id>
    <name>Crenellated Wall</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{T}: Target creature gets +0/+4 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Mercadian soldiers excel at finding things to stand behind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0291</id>
    <name>Crooked Scales</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Flip a coin. If you win the flip, destroy target creature an opponent controls. If you lose the flip, destroy target creature you control unless you pay {3} and repeat this process.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0292</id>
    <name>Crumbling Sanctuary</name>
    <text>For each 1 damage that would be dealt to a player, that player exiles the top card of his or her library instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0293</id>
    <name>Distorting Lens</name>
    <text>{T}: Target permanent becomes the color of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The magistrate seems to prefer a distorted perspective of reality.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0294</id>
    <name>Eye of Ramos</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.

Sacrifice Eye of Ramos: Add {U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Ramos wept, and there were seas.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0295</id>
    <name>General's Regalia</name>
    <text>{3}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, that damage is dealt to target creature you control instead.</text>
    <flavorText>A uniform fit for a goblin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0296</id>
    <name>Heart of Ramos</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.

Sacrifice Heart of Ramos: Add {R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Ramos bled, and there was fire.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0297</id>
    <name>Henge Guardian</name>
    <text>{2}: Henge Guardian gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Like so many Thran relics, the wurm engine kept operating long after its creators were gone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0298</id>
    <name>Horn of Plenty</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a spell, he or she may pay {1}. If that player does, he or she draws a card at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>"This horn is an exact replica of the fabled Horn of Ramos, except mine is more lavish."
—Mercadian magistrate</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0299</id>
    <name>Horn of Ramos</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.

Sacrifice Horn of Ramos: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Ramos touched, and there was life.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0300</id>
    <name>Iron Lance</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The only way to get Mercadians to fight on the front lines is to give them really long weapons."
—Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0301</id>
    <name>Jeweled Torque</name>
    <text>As Jeweled Torque enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Whenever a player casts a spell of the chosen color, you may pay {2}. If you do, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0302</id>
    <name>Kyren Archive</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may exile the top card of your library face down.
{5}, Discard your hand, Sacrifice Kyren Archive: Put all cards exiled with Kyren Archive into their owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0303</id>
    <name>Kyren Toy</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Kyren Toy.
{T}, Remove X charge counters from Kyren Toy: Add {X}{1} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0304</id>
    <name>Magistrate's Scepter</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Magistrate's Scepter.
{T}, Remove three charge counters from Magistrate's Scepter: Take an extra turn after this one.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0305</id>
    <name>Mercadian Atlas</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your end step, if you didn't play a land this turn, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>One may as well chart the clouds as try to map Mercadia.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0306</id>
    <name>Mercadian Lift</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Put a winch counter on Mercadian Lift.
{T}, Remove X winch counters from Mercadian Lift: You may put a creature card with converted mana cost X from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0307</id>
    <name>Monkey Cage</name>
    <text>When a creature enters the battlefield, sacrifice Monkey Cage and put X 2/2 green Ape creature tokens onto the battlefield, where X is that creature's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0308</id>
    <name>Panacea</name>
    <text>{X}{X}, {T}: Prevent the next X damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A drop numbs the tongue. A sip sends the heart racing. A draught reforges the body.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0309</id>
    <name>Power Matrix</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 and gains flying, first strike, and trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>As he repaired the ship's planeswalking engine, Karn saw for the first time how he could catalyze the Weatherlight's evolution.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0310</id>
    <name>Puffer Extract</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: Target creature you control gets +X/+X until end of turn. Destroy it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>The puffer's flesh is the deadliest in the sea—and therefore the most useful.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0311</id>
    <name>Rishadan Pawnshop</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Shuffle target nontoken permanent you control into its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>Everything comes to the waterfront eventually, on the tide or on credit.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0312</id>
    <name>Skull of Ramos</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.

Sacrifice Skull of Ramos: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Ramos fell, and there was night.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0313</id>
    <name>Tooth of Ramos</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.

Sacrifice Tooth of Ramos: Add {W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Ramos smiled, and there was day.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0314</id>
    <name>Toymaker</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Discard a card: Target noncreature artifact becomes an artifact creature with power and toughness each equal to its converted mana cost until end of turn. (It retains its abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0315</id>
    <name>Worry Beads</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0316</id>
    <name>Dust Bowl</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{3}, {T}, Sacrifice a land: Destroy target nonbasic land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0317</id>
    <name>Fountain of Cho</name>
    <text>Fountain of Cho enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Put a storage counter on Fountain of Cho.
{T}, Remove any number of storage counters from Fountain of Cho: Add {W} to your mana pool for each storage counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0318</id>
    <name>Henge of Ramos</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{2}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>It is the hub. We are the wheel.
—Dryad saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0319</id>
    <name>Hickory Woodlot</name>
    <text>Hickory Woodlot enters the battlefield tapped with two depletion counters on it.
{T}, Remove a depletion counter from Hickory Woodlot: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool. If there are no depletion counters on Hickory Woodlot, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0320</id>
    <name>High Market</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{T}, Sacrifice a creature: You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>If it can't be had here, it can't be had on any world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0321</id>
    <name>Mercadian Bazaar</name>
    <text>Mercadian Bazaar enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Put a storage counter on Mercadian Bazaar.
{T}, Remove any number of storage counters from Mercadian Bazaar: Add {R} to your mana pool for each storage counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0322</id>
    <name>Peat Bog</name>
    <text>Peat Bog enters the battlefield tapped with two depletion counters on it.
{T}, Remove a depletion counter from Peat Bog: Add {B}{B} to your mana pool. If there are no depletion counters on Peat Bog, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0323</id>
    <name>Remote Farm</name>
    <text>Remote Farm enters the battlefield tapped with two depletion counters on it.
{T}, Remove a depletion counter from Remote Farm: Add {W}{W} to your mana pool. If there are no depletion counters on Remote Farm, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0324</id>
    <name>Rishadan Port</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{1}, {T}: Tap target land.</text>
    <flavorText>Rishada is the gateway to free trade—but the key will cost you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0325</id>
    <name>Rushwood Grove</name>
    <text>Rushwood Grove enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Put a storage counter on Rushwood Grove.
{T}, Remove any number of storage counters from Rushwood Grove: Add {G} to your mana pool for each storage counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0326</id>
    <name>Sandstone Needle</name>
    <text>Sandstone Needle enters the battlefield tapped with two depletion counters on it.
{T}, Remove a depletion counter from Sandstone Needle: Add {R}{R} to your mana pool. If there are no depletion counters on Sandstone Needle, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0327</id>
    <name>Saprazzan Cove</name>
    <text>Saprazzan Cove enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Put a storage counter on Saprazzan Cove.
{T}, Remove any number of storage counters from Saprazzan Cove: Add {U} to your mana pool for each storage counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0328</id>
    <name>Saprazzan Skerry</name>
    <text>Saprazzan Skerry enters the battlefield tapped with two depletion counters on it.
{T}, Remove a depletion counter from Saprazzan Skerry: Add {U}{U} to your mana pool. If there are no depletion counters on Saprazzan Skerry, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0329</id>
    <name>Subterranean Hangar</name>
    <text>Subterranean Hangar enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Put a storage counter on Subterranean Hangar.
{T}, Remove any number of storage counters from Subterranean Hangar: Add {B} to your mana pool for each storage counter removed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0330</id>
    <name>Tower of the Magistrate</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{1}, {T}: Target creature gains protection from artifacts until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Like the city, weakest at its foundation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0331</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0332</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0333</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0334</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0335</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0336</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0337</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0338</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0339</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0340</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0341</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0342</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0343</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0344</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0345</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0346</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0347</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0348</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0349</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>MMQ0350</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>