<cards name="Premium Deck Series: Slivers">
  <item>
    <id>PDS0001</id>
    <name>Metallic Sliver</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>When the clever counterfeit was accepted by the hive, Volrath's influence upon the slivers grew even stronger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0002</id>
    <name>Virulent Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have poisonous 1. (Whenever a Sliver deals combat damage to a player, that player gets a poison counter. A player with ten or more poison counters loses the game.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0003</id>
    <name>Amoeboid Changeling</name>
    <text>Changeling (This card is every creature type at all times.)
{T}: Target creature gains all creature types until end of turn.
{T}: Target creature loses all creature types until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0004</id>
    <name>Winged Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Everything around here has cut a deal with gravity."
—Gerrard of the Weatherlight</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0005</id>
    <name>Clot Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{2}: Regenerate this permanent."</text>
    <flavorText>"One would think I would be accustomed to unexpected returns."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0006</id>
    <name>Frenzy Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have frenzy 1. (Whenever a Sliver attacks and isn't blocked, it gets +1/+0 until end of turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>The Arturan conjurers took the strange, alien fossil and patterned their own twisted creations in its image.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0007</id>
    <name>Heart Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have haste.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard looked all around for the source of the mysterious pulse, and at that moment the slivers boiled forth from the crevasses.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0008</id>
    <name>Gemhide Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>"The land is weary. Even Skyshroud is depleted. We must find another source of mana—one that is growing despite our withering world."
—Freyalise</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0009</id>
    <name>Muscle Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>The air was filled with the cracks and snaps of flesh hardening as the new sliver joined the battle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0010</id>
    <name>Quick Sliver</name>
    <text>Flash
Any player may play Sliver cards as though they had flash.</text>
    <flavorText>The directors of the Riptide Project wanted instant results on the sliver experiments. They got their wish.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0011</id>
    <name>Crystalline Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have shroud. (They can't be the targets of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>Bred as living shields, these slivers have proven unruly—they know they cannot be caught.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0012</id>
    <name>Hibernation Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "Pay 2 life: Return this permanent to its owner's hand."</text>
    <flavorText>Mogglings have been known to play ball with hibernating slivers, completely unaware of their true nature.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0013</id>
    <name>Acidic Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{2}, Sacrifice this permanent: This permanent deals 2 damage to target creature or player."</text>
    <flavorText>The first sliver burst against the cave wall, and others piled in behind to deepen the new tunnel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0014</id>
    <name>Spined Sliver</name>
    <text>Whenever a Sliver becomes blocked, that Sliver gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Slivers are evil and slivers are sly;
And if you get eaten, then no one will cry."
—Mogg children's rhyme</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0015</id>
    <name>Victual Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{2}, Sacrifice this permanent: You gain 4 life."</text>
    <flavorText>"We are kinfolk," explained Karn to the sliver queen. "Just as you need your progeny to complete you, so do I need the pieces of the Legacy to make me whole."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0016</id>
    <name>Armor Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have "{2}: This creature gets +0/+1 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>Hanna: "We must learn how they protect each other."
Mirri: "After they're done trying to kill us, all right?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0017</id>
    <name>Spectral Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have "{2}: This creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>"Sure, I've seen agents of the Cabal here and there. Well, not here, and certainly not in any of the sliver labs. Oh dear, I've said too much."
—Apprentice researcher</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0018</id>
    <name>Barbed Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have "{2}: This creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>Spans of spines leapt from one sliver to the next, forming a deadly hedge around the Weatherlight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0019</id>
    <name>Homing Sliver</name>
    <text>Each Sliver card in each player's hand has slivercycling {3}.
Slivercycling {3} ({3}, Discard this card: Search your library for a Sliver card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0020</id>
    <name>Necrotic Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{3}, Sacrifice this permanent: Destroy target permanent."</text>
    <flavorText>Though Volrath is long dead, the slivers have become everything he wanted them to be: mindless instruments of destruction and despair.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0021</id>
    <name>Fungus Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have "Whenever this creature is dealt damage, put a +1/+1 counter on it." (The damage is dealt before the counter is put on.)</text>
    <flavorText>"When a sliver of this breed enters the hive, the others claw each other in frenzied fits, thereby ensuring their rapid growth."
—Rukarumel, field journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0022</id>
    <name>Brood Sliver</name>
    <text>Whenever a Sliver deals combat damage to a player, its controller may put a 1/1 colorless Sliver creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Within weeks, more slivers nested in Otaria than ever existed on Rath.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0023</id>
    <name>Might Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures get +2/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>"The colossal thing rumbled over the ridge, tree husks crumbling before it. The ones we were already fighting howled as it came, their muscles suddenly surging, and we knew it was time to flee."
—Llanach, Skyshroud ranger</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0024</id>
    <name>Sliver Overlord</name>
    <text>{3}: Search your library for a Sliver card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.
{3}: Gain control of target Sliver. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>The end of evolution.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0025</id>
    <name>Fury Sliver</name>
    <text>All Sliver creatures have double strike.</text>
    <flavorText>"A rift opened, and our arrows were abruptly stilled. To move was to push the world. But the sliver's claw still twitched, red wounds appeared in Thed's chest, and ribbons of blood hung in the air."
—Adom Capashen, Benalish hero</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0026</id>
    <name>Heartstone</name>
    <text>Activated abilities of creatures cost {1} less to activate. This effect can't reduce the amount of mana an ability costs to activate to less than one mana.</text>
    <flavorText>"Finding a true heartstone is even harder than finding a true heart."
—Hanna, Weatherlight navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0027</id>
    <name>Distant Melody</name>
    <text>Choose a creature type. Draw a card for each permanent you control of that type.</text>
    <flavorText>Oona's song is like a twisted dinner chime. All the faeries return home, but it is Oona who feasts—on the stolen dreams and rumors they serve her.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0028</id>
    <name>Aphetto Dredging</name>
    <text>Return up to three target creature cards of the creature type of your choice from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Phage became both executioner and savior, helping others to the same rebirth she had found.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0029</id>
    <name>Coat of Arms</name>
    <text>Each creature gets +1/+1 for each other creature on the battlefield that shares at least one creature type with it. (For example, if two Goblin Warriors and a Goblin Shaman are on the battlefield, each gets +2/+2.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Hup, two, three, four,
Dunno how to count no more."
—Mogg march</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0030</id>
    <name>Wild Pair</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature enters the battlefield, if you cast it from your hand, you may search your library for a creature card with the same total power and toughness and put it onto the battlefield. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0031</id>
    <name>Ancient Ziggurat</name>
    <text>{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast creature spells.</text>
    <flavorText>Built in honor of Alara's creatures, the ziggurat vanished long ago. When Progenitus awakened, the temple emerged again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0032</id>
    <name>Rootbound Crag</name>
    <text>Rootbound Crag enters the battlefield tapped unless you control a Mountain or a Forest.
{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0033</id>
    <name>Rupture Spire</name>
    <text>Rupture Spire enters the battlefield tapped.
When Rupture Spire enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you pay {1}.
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0034</id>
    <name>Terramorphic Expanse</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Terramorphic Expanse: Search your library for a basic land card and put it onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0035</id>
    <name>Vivid Creek</name>
    <text>Vivid Creek enters the battlefield tapped with two charge counters on it.
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.
{T}, Remove a charge counter from Vivid Creek: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0036</id>
    <name>Vivid Grove</name>
    <text>Vivid Grove enters the battlefield tapped with two charge counters on it.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{T}, Remove a charge counter from Vivid Grove: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0037</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0038</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0039</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0040</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>PDS0041</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>