<cards name="Portal">
  <item>
    <id>POR0001</id>
    <name>Alabaster Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
When Alabaster Dragon is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, shuffle Alabaster Dragon into its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0002</id>
    <name>Alluring Scent</name>
    <text>All creatures able to block target creature this turn do so.</text>
    <flavorText>Doom rarely smells this sweet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0003</id>
    <name>Anaconda</name>
    <text>Swampwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Swamp.)</text>
    <flavorText>Something soft bumped against the rowboat, then was gone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0004</id>
    <name>Anaconda</name>
    <text>Swampwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Swamp.)</text>
    <flavorText>Something soft bumped against the rowboat, then was gone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0005</id>
    <name>Ancestral Memories</name>
    <text>Look at the top seven cards of your library. Put two of them into your hand and the rest into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0006</id>
    <name>Angelic Blessing</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +3/+3 and gains flying until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>A peasant can do more by faith than a king by proclamation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0007</id>
    <name>Archangel</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0008</id>
    <name>Ardent Militia</name>
    <text>Vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>Some fight for honor and some for gold, but the militia fights for hearth and home.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0009</id>
    <name>Armageddon</name>
    <text>Destroy all lands.</text>
    <flavorText>"‘O miserable of happy Is this the end
Of this new glorious world . . . ?'"
—John Milton, Paradise Lost</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0010</id>
    <name>Armored Pegasus</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Asked how it survived a run-in with a bog imp, the pegasus just shook its mane and burped.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0011</id>
    <name>Arrogant Vampire</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Charm and grace may hide a foul heart.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0012</id>
    <name>Assassin's Blade</name>
    <text>Cast Assassin's Blade only during the declare attackers step and only if you've been attacked this step.
Destroy target nonblack attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0013</id>
    <name>Balance of Power</name>
    <text>If target opponent has more cards in hand than you, draw cards equal to the difference.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0014</id>
    <name>Baleful Stare</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You draw a card for each Mountain and red card in it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0015</id>
    <name>Bee Sting</name>
    <text>Bee Sting deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>There are few things as motivating as a swarm of bees.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0016</id>
    <name>Blaze</name>
    <text>Blaze deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0017</id>
    <name>Blaze</name>
    <text>Blaze deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0018</id>
    <name>Blessed Reversal</name>
    <text>You gain 3 life for each creature attacking you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0019</id>
    <name>Blinding Light</name>
    <text>Tap all nonwhite creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Let the unjust avert their faces and contemplate their peril.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0020</id>
    <name>Bog Imp</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Don't be fooled by their looks. Think of them as little knives with wings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0021</id>
    <name>Bog Raiders</name>
    <text>Swampwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Those who live amid decay must expect scavengers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0022</id>
    <name>Bog Wraith</name>
    <text>Swampwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Swamp.)</text>
    <flavorText>It moved through the troops leaving no footprints, save on their souls.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0023</id>
    <name>Boiling Seas</name>
    <text>Destroy all Islands.</text>
    <flavorText>What burns the land, boils the seas.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0024</id>
    <name>Border Guard</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Join the army, see foreign countries" they'd said.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0025</id>
    <name>Breath of Life</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0026</id>
    <name>Bull Hippo</name>
    <text>Islandwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Stay alert: his lumbering may shake the ground itself, but in water, he glides.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0027</id>
    <name>Burning Cloak</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +2/+0 until end of turn. Burning Cloak deals 2 damage to that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0028</id>
    <name>Capricious Sorcerer</name>
    <text>{T}: Capricious Sorcerer deals 1 damage to target creature or player. Activate this ability only during your turn, before attackers are declared.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0029</id>
    <name>Charging Bandits</name>
    <text>Whenever Charging Bandits attacks, it gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The fear in their victims' eyes is their most cherished reward.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0030</id>
    <name>Charging Paladin</name>
    <text>Whenever Charging Paladin attacks, it gets +0/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A true warrior's thoughts are of victory, not death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0031</id>
    <name>Charging Rhino</name>
    <text>Charging Rhino can't be blocked by more than one creature.</text>
    <flavorText>A rhino rarely uses its horn to announce its charge, only to end it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0032</id>
    <name>Cloak of Feathers</name>
    <text>Target creature gains flying until end of turn.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>A thousand feathers from a thousand birds, sewn with magic and song.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0033</id>
    <name>Cloud Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
Cloud Dragon can block only creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0034</id>
    <name>Cloud Pirates</name>
    <text>Flying
Cloud Pirates can block only creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0035</id>
    <name>Cloud Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying
Cloud Spirit can block only creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0036</id>
    <name>Command of Unsummoning</name>
    <text>Cast Command of Unsummoning only during the declare attackers step and only if you've been attacked this step.
Return one or two target attacking creatures to their owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0037</id>
    <name>Coral Eel</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Some fishers like to eat eels, and some eels like to eat fishers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0038</id>
    <name>Craven Giant</name>
    <text>Craven Giant can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>"The best armor is to keep out of range."
—Italian proverb</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0039</id>
    <name>Craven Knight</name>
    <text>Craven Knight can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>"I say victory is better than honor."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0040</id>
    <name>Cruel Bargain</name>
    <text>Draw four cards. You lose half your life, rounded up.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0041</id>
    <name>Cruel Fate</name>
    <text>Look at the top five cards of target opponent's library. Put one of those cards into that player's graveyard, and the rest on top of his or her library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0042</id>
    <name>Cruel Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for a card, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it. You lose 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The more you pay for the lesson, the better you'll remember it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0043</id>
    <name>Deep Wood</name>
    <text>Cast Deep Wood only during the declare attackers step and only if you've been attacked this step.
Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you this turn by attacking creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0044</id>
    <name>Deep-Sea Serpent</name>
    <text>Deep-Sea Serpent can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.</text>
    <flavorText>Sailors fear the deep-sea serpent; others thank the gods it has no legs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0045</id>
    <name>Defiant Stand</name>
    <text>Cast Defiant Stand only during the declare attackers step and only if you've been attacked this step.
Target creature gets +1/+3 until end of turn. If that creature is tapped, untap it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0046</id>
    <name>Déjà Vu</name>
    <text>Return target sorcery card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The past is a mirror of the future.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0047</id>
    <name>Desert Drake</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Never doubt a dragon just because of its size.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0048</id>
    <name>Devastation</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures and lands.</text>
    <flavorText>There is much talk about the art of creation. What about the art of destruction?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0049</id>
    <name>Devoted Hero</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The heart's courage is the soul's guardian.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0050</id>
    <name>Djinn of the Lamp</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Once they learn the trick of carrying their own lamps, they never touch the ground again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0051</id>
    <name>Dread Charge</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, black creatures you control can be blocked only by black creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"As equal were their souls, so equal was their fate."John Dryden, "Ode to Mrs. Anne Killigrew"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0052</id>
    <name>Dread Reaper</name>
    <text>Flying
When Dread Reaper enters the battlefield, you lose 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0053</id>
    <name>Dry Spell</name>
    <text>Dry Spell deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>A fist of dust to line your throat, a bowl of sand to fill your belly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0054</id>
    <name>Earthquake</name>
    <text>Earthquake deals X damage to each creature without flying and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0055</id>
    <name>Ebon Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
When Ebon Dragon enters the battlefield, you may have target opponent discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0056</id>
    <name>Elite Cat Warrior</name>
    <text>Forestwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Hear that? No? That's a cat warrior."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0057</id>
    <name>Elite Cat Warrior</name>
    <text>Forestwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Hear that? No? That's a cat warrior."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0058</id>
    <name>Elven Cache</name>
    <text>Return target card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Elves know where to harvest the best of the forest, for they planted it themselves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0059</id>
    <name>Elvish Ranger</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>It's up to you if you enter their woods—and up to them if you leave.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0060</id>
    <name>Endless Cockroaches</name>
    <text>When Endless Cockroaches is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Endless Cockroaches to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0061</id>
    <name>Exhaustion</name>
    <text>Creatures and lands target opponent controls don't untap during his or her next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0062</id>
    <name>False Peace</name>
    <text>Target player skips all combat phases of his or her next turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Mutual consent is not required for war.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0063</id>
    <name>Feral Shadow</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Not all shadows are cast by light—some are cast by darkness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0064</id>
    <name>Final Strike</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Final Strike, sacrifice a creature.
Final Strike deals damage to target opponent equal to the sacrificed creature's power.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0065</id>
    <name>Fire Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
When Fire Dragon enters the battlefield, it deals damage equal to the number of Mountains you control to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0066</id>
    <name>Fire Imp</name>
    <text>When Fire Imp enters the battlefield, it deals 2 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0067</id>
    <name>Fire Snake</name>
    <text>When Fire Snake is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>The snake's final thrashings only spread the fire within it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0068</id>
    <name>Fire Tempest</name>
    <text>Fire Tempest deals 6 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0069</id>
    <name>Flashfires</name>
    <text>Destroy all Plains.</text>
    <flavorText>Dry grass is tinder before the spark.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0070</id>
    <name>Fleet-Footed Monk</name>
    <text>Fleet-Footed Monk can't be blocked by creatures with power 2 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>"Hesitation is for the faithless. My belief lends me speed."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0071</id>
    <name>Flux</name>
    <text>Each player discards any number of cards, then draws that many cards.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0072</id>
    <name>Foot Soldiers</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Infantry deployment is the art of putting your troops in the wrong place at the right time.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0073</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0074</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0075</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0076</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0077</id>
    <name>Forked Lightning</name>
    <text>Forked Lightning deals 4 damage divided as you choose among one, two, or three target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0078</id>
    <name>Fruition</name>
    <text>You gain 1 life for each Forest on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Come to these woods and suffer no pain; you've burdens to lose and new life to gain.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0079</id>
    <name>Giant Octopus</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>At the sight of the thing the calamari vendor's eyes went wide, but from fear or avarice none could tell.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0080</id>
    <name>Giant Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>It's not far into the trap, as the crow flies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0081</id>
    <name>Gift of Estates</name>
    <text>If an opponent controls more lands than you, search your library for up to three Plains cards, reveal them, and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0082</id>
    <name>Goblin Bully</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>It's easy to stand head and shoulders over those with no backbone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0083</id>
    <name>Gorilla Warrior</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>They were formidable even before they learned the use of weapons.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0084</id>
    <name>Gravedigger</name>
    <text>When Gravedigger enters the battlefield, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0085</id>
    <name>Grizzly Bears</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Don't worry about provoking grizzly bears; they come that way.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0086</id>
    <name>Hand of Death</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Death claims all but the darkest souls.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0087</id>
    <name>Hand of Death</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Death claims all but the darkest souls.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0088</id>
    <name>Harsh Justice</name>
    <text>Cast Harsh Justice only during the declare attackers step and only if you've been attacked this step.
This turn, whenever an attacking creature deals combat damage to you, it deals that much damage to its controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0089</id>
    <name>Highland Giant</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Though slow-witted and slow-moving, they are quick to anger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0090</id>
    <name>Hill Giant</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Hill giants are mostly just big. Of course, that does count for a lot</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0091</id>
    <name>Horned Turtle</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Its spear has no shaft, its shield no handle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0092</id>
    <name>Howling Fury</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +4/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>I howl my soul to the moon, and the moon howls with me.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0093</id>
    <name>Hulking Cyclops</name>
    <text>Hulking Cyclops can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>Anyone can get around a cyclops, but few can stand in its way.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0094</id>
    <name>Hulking Goblin</name>
    <text>Hulking Goblin can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>The bigger they are, the harder they avoid work.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0095</id>
    <name>Hurricane</name>
    <text>Hurricane deals X damage to each creature with flying and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0096</id>
    <name>Ingenious Thief</name>
    <text>Flying
When Ingenious Thief enters the battlefield, look at target player's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0097</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0098</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0099</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0100</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0101</id>
    <name>Jungle Lion</name>
    <text>Jungle Lion can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>The lion's only loyalty is to its hunger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0102</id>
    <name>Keen-Eyed Archers</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>"If it has wings, shoot it. If it doesn't, shoot it anyway."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0103</id>
    <name>King's Assassin</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target tapped creature. Activate this ability only during your turn, before attackers are declared.</text>
    <flavorText>Fear is as effective a weapon as the blade.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0104</id>
    <name>Knight Errant</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>". . . Before honor is humility."
—The Bible, Proverbs 15:33</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0105</id>
    <name>Last Chance</name>
    <text>Take an extra turn after this one. At the beginning of that turn's end step, you lose the game.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0106</id>
    <name>Lava Axe</name>
    <text>Lava Axe deals 5 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Swing your axe as a broom, to sweep away the foe.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0107</id>
    <name>Lava Flow</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature or land.</text>
    <flavorText>People ran as never before at the thought of being buried and cremated at the same time.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0108</id>
    <name>Lizard Warrior</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Don't let its appearance frighten you. Let its claws and teeth do that.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0109</id>
    <name>Man-o'-War</name>
    <text>When Man-o'-War enters the battlefield, return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0110</id>
    <name>Mercenary Knight</name>
    <text>When Mercenary Knight enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you discard a creature card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0111</id>
    <name>Merfolk of the Pearl Trident</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Are merfolk humans with fins, or are humans merfolk with feet?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0112</id>
    <name>Mind Knives</name>
    <text>Target opponent discards a card at random.</text>
    <flavorText>To dodge the unerring knife, one must be free of thought.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0113</id>
    <name>Mind Rot</name>
    <text>Target player discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0114</id>
    <name>Minotaur Warrior</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The herd's patience, the stampede's fury.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0115</id>
    <name>Mobilize</name>
    <text>Untap all creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>A rested mind is the sharpest weapon.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0116</id>
    <name>Monstrous Growth</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Some cats are born fighters; others need a little persuading.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0117</id>
    <name>Monstrous Growth</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Some cats are born fighters; others need a little persuading.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0118</id>
    <name>Moon Sprite</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"I am that merry wanderer of the night."
—William Shakespeare,
A Midsummer Night's Dream</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0119</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0120</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0121</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0122</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0123</id>
    <name>Mountain Goat</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Only the heroic and the mad follow mountain goat trails.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0124</id>
    <name>Muck Rats</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The difference between a nuisance and a threat is often merely a matter of numbers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0125</id>
    <name>Mystic Denial</name>
    <text>Counter target creature or sorcery spell.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0126</id>
    <name>Natural Order</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Natural Order, sacrifice a green creature.
Search your library for a green creature card and put it onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0127</id>
    <name>Natural Spring</name>
    <text>Target player gains 8 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Though many have come to this place to wash their wounds, the water has never turned red.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0128</id>
    <name>Nature's Cloak</name>
    <text>Green creatures you control gain forestwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0129</id>
    <name>Nature's Lore</name>
    <text>Search your library for a Forest card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Nature's secrets can be read on every tree, every branch, every leaf.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0130</id>
    <name>Nature's Ruin</name>
    <text>Destroy all green creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>One chill blast—the exhalation of the grave.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0131</id>
    <name>Needle Storm</name>
    <text>Needle Storm deals 4 damage to each creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0132</id>
    <name>Noxious Toad</name>
    <text>When Noxious Toad is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, each opponent discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0133</id>
    <name>Omen</name>
    <text>Look at the top three cards of your library, then put them back in any order. You may shuffle your library.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0134</id>
    <name>Owl Familiar</name>
    <text>Flying
When Owl Familiar enters the battlefield, draw a card, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0135</id>
    <name>Panther Warriors</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The dogs of war are nothing compared to the cats.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0136</id>
    <name>Path of Peace</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature. Its owner gains 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The soldier reaped the profits of peace.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0137</id>
    <name>Personal Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for a sorcery card and reveal that card. Shuffle your library, then put the card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0138</id>
    <name>Phantom Warrior</name>
    <text>Phantom Warrior is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>The phantom warrior comes from nowhere and returns there just as quickly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0139</id>
    <name>Pillaging Horde</name>
    <text>When Pillaging Horde enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you discard a card at random.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0140</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0141</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0142</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0143</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0144</id>
    <name>Plant Elemental</name>
    <text>When Plant Elemental enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you sacrifice a Forest.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0145</id>
    <name>Primeval Force</name>
    <text>When Primeval Force enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you sacrifice three Forests.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0146</id>
    <name>Prosperity</name>
    <text>Each player draws X cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"Life can never be too good."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0147</id>
    <name>Pyroclasm</name>
    <text>Pyroclasm deals 2 damage to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Chaos does not choose its enemies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0148</id>
    <name>Python</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>What could it have swallowed to grow so large?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0149</id>
    <name>Raging Cougar</name>
    <text>Haste</text>
    <flavorText>Mountaineers quickly learn to travel with their spears always pointed up.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0150</id>
    <name>Raging Goblin</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)</text>
    <flavorText>Charging alone takes uncommon daring or uncommon stupidity. Or both.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0151</id>
    <name>Raging Goblin</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)</text>
    <flavorText>Charging alone takes uncommon daring or uncommon stupidity. Or both.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0152</id>
    <name>Raging Minotaur</name>
    <text>Haste</text>
    <flavorText>The only thing worse than a minotaur with an axe is an angry minotaur with an axe.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0153</id>
    <name>Rain of Salt</name>
    <text>Destroy two target lands.</text>
    <flavorText>It pelts the land with its fury,
spoiling what was once sweet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0154</id>
    <name>Rain of Tears</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>When emotions rain down, what rivers will be born?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0155</id>
    <name>Raise Dead</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The earth cannot hold that which magic commands.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0156</id>
    <name>Redwood Treefolk</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The soldiers chopped and chopped, and still the great tree stood, frowning down at them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0157</id>
    <name>Regal Unicorn</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Unicorns don't care if you believe in them any more than you care if they believe in you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0158</id>
    <name>Renewing Dawn</name>
    <text>You gain 2 life for each Mountain target opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Dawn brings a new day, and a new day brings hope.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0159</id>
    <name>Rowan Treefolk</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>One of the forest's best protectors is the forest itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0160</id>
    <name>Sacred Knight</name>
    <text>Sacred Knight can't be blocked by black and/or red creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"No flame, no horror can sway me from my cause."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0161</id>
    <name>Sacred Nectar</name>
    <text>You gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"For he on honey-dew hath fed,
And drunk the milk of Paradise."
—Samuel Taylor Coleridge, "Kubla Khan"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0162</id>
    <name>Scorching Spear</name>
    <text>Scorching Spear deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Lift your spear as you might lift your glass, and toast your enemy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0163</id>
    <name>Scorching Winds</name>
    <text>Cast Scorching Winds only during the declare attackers step and only if you've been attacked this step.
Scorching Winds deals 1 damage to each attacking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0164</id>
    <name>Seasoned Marshal</name>
    <text>Whenever Seasoned Marshal attacks, you may tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0165</id>
    <name>Serpent Assassin</name>
    <text>When Serpent Assassin enters the battlefield, you may destroy target nonblack creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0166</id>
    <name>Serpent Warrior</name>
    <text>When Serpent Warrior enters the battlefield, you lose 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0167</id>
    <name>Skeletal Crocodile</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The less flesh there is, the more teeth there seem to be.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0168</id>
    <name>Skeletal Snake</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>They watched as the snake shed layer after layer until only cold bone remained.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0169</id>
    <name>Snapping Drake</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Drakes claim to be dragons—until the dragons show up.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0170</id>
    <name>Sorcerous Sight</name>
    <text>Look at target opponent's hand.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Do not react; anticipate.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0171</id>
    <name>Soul Shred</name>
    <text>Soul Shred deals 3 damage to target nonblack creature. You gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>It would be a shame to let life slip away to nothing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0172</id>
    <name>Spined Wurm</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>It has more teeth than fit in its mouth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0173</id>
    <name>Spiritual Guardian</name>
    <text>When Spiritual Guardian enters the battlefield, you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Hope is born within.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0174</id>
    <name>Spitting Earth</name>
    <text>Spitting Earth deals damage equal to the number of Mountains you control to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0175</id>
    <name>Spotted Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>When the cat flies and the bird stalks, guard your horses carefully.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0176</id>
    <name>Stalking Tiger</name>
    <text>Stalking Tiger can't be blocked by more than one creature.</text>
    <flavorText>No one is happy when they notice a tiger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0177</id>
    <name>Starlight</name>
    <text>You gain 3 life for each black creature target opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Stars are like coins dropped into the night: their light buys safe passage.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0178</id>
    <name>Starlit Angel</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>To soar as high as hope, to dive as swift as justice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0179</id>
    <name>Steadfastness</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +0/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Brute force wins the battles. Conviction wins the wars.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0180</id>
    <name>Stern Marshal</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn. Activate this ability only during your turn, before attackers are declared.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0181</id>
    <name>Stone Rain</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>I cast a thousand tiny suns—
Beware my many dawns.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0182</id>
    <name>Storm Crow</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</text>
    <flavorText>Storm crow descending, winter unending.  Storm crow departing, summer is starting.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0183</id>
    <name>Summer Bloom</name>
    <text>You may play up to three additional lands this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Summer sends its kiss with warmth and blooming life.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0184</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0185</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0186</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0187</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0188</id>
    <name>Sylvan Tutor</name>
    <text>Search your library for a creature card and reveal that card. Shuffle your library, then put the card on top of it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0189</id>
    <name>Symbol of Unsummoning</name>
    <text>Return target creature to its owner's hand.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>". . . inviting the soul to wander for a spell in abysses of solitude . . . ."
—Kate Chopin, The Awakening</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0190</id>
    <name>Taunt</name>
    <text>During target player's next turn, creatures that player controls attack you if able.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0191</id>
    <name>Temporary Truce</name>
    <text>Each player may draw up to two cards. For each card less than two a player draws this way, that player gains 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0192</id>
    <name>Theft of Dreams</name>
    <text>Draw a card for each tapped creature target opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Energy is never lost, only transformed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0193</id>
    <name>Thing from the Deep</name>
    <text>Whenever Thing from the Deep attacks, sacrifice it unless you sacrifice an Island.</text>
    <flavorText>Seafarers fear sailing off the world's edge not so much as down its gullet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0194</id>
    <name>Thundering Wurm</name>
    <text>When Thundering Wurm enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you discard a land card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0195</id>
    <name>Thundermare</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack the turn it comes under your control.)
When Thundermare enters the battlefield, tap all other creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0196</id>
    <name>Tidal Surge</name>
    <text>Tap up to three target creatures without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"'Twas  when the seas were roaring
With hollow blasts of wind . . . ."
—John Gay, "The What D'Ye Call It"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0197</id>
    <name>Time Ebb</name>
    <text>Put target creature on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>Like the tide, time both ebbs and flows.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0198</id>
    <name>Touch of Brilliance</name>
    <text>Draw two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Acting on one good idea is better than hoarding all the world's knowledge.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0199</id>
    <name>Treetop Defense</name>
    <text>Cast Treetop Defense only during the declare attackers step and only if you've been attacked this step.
Creatures you control gain reach until end of turn. (They can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0200</id>
    <name>Undying Beast</name>
    <text>When Undying Beast is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put Undying Beast on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0201</id>
    <name>Untamed Wilds</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0202</id>
    <name>Valorous Charge</name>
    <text>White creatures get +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Stand in the way of truth at your peril.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0203</id>
    <name>Vampiric Feast</name>
    <text>Vampiric Feast deals 4 damage to target creature or player and you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>It's not always gold the thief is after.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0204</id>
    <name>Vampiric Touch</name>
    <text>Vampiric Touch deals 2 damage to target opponent and you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>A touch, not comforting, but of death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0205</id>
    <name>Venerable Monk</name>
    <text>When Venerable Monk enters the battlefield, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>His presence brings not only a strong arm but also renewed hope.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0206</id>
    <name>Vengeance</name>
    <text>Destroy target tapped creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Bitter as wormwood, sweet as mulled wine.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0207</id>
    <name>Virtue's Ruin</name>
    <text>Destroy all white creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>All must fall, and those who stand highest fall hardest.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0208</id>
    <name>Volcanic Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying, haste</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0209</id>
    <name>Volcanic Hammer</name>
    <text>Volcanic Hammer deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Cast the weight as though it were a die, to see a rival's fate.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0210</id>
    <name>Wall of Granite</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</text>
    <flavorText>The wisest man builds his house behind the rock.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0211</id>
    <name>Wall of Swords</name>
    <text>Defender, flying (This creature can't attack, and it can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>Sharper than wind, lighter than air.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0212</id>
    <name>Warrior's Charge</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It is not the absence of fear that makes a warrior, but its domination.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0213</id>
    <name>Warrior's Charge</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It is not the absence of fear that makes a warrior, but its domination.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0214</id>
    <name>Whiptail Wurm</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>It's hard to say for certain which end is more dangerous.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0215</id>
    <name>Wicked Pact</name>
    <text>Destroy two target nonblack creatures. You lose 5 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0216</id>
    <name>Willow Dryad</name>
    <text>Forestwalk</text>
    <flavorText>Some think that dryads are the dreams of trees.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0217</id>
    <name>Wind Drake</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"No bird soars too high, if he soars with his own wings."—William Blake, The Marriage of Heaven and Hell</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0218</id>
    <name>Winds of Change</name>
    <text>Each player shuffles the cards from his or her hand into his or her library, then draws that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0219</id>
    <name>Winter's Grasp</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>Winter settles on the land, and the land prays it will wake.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0220</id>
    <name>Withering Gaze</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You draw a card for each Forest and green card in it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0221</id>
    <name>Wood Elves</name>
    <text>When Wood Elves enters the battlefield, search your library for a Forest card and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>POR0222</id>
    <name>Wrath of God</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"As flies to wanton boys, are we to the gods. They kill us for their sport."
—William Shakespeare, King Lear</flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>