<cards name="Rise of the Eldrazi">
  <item>
    <id>ROE0001</id>
    <name>All Is Dust</name>
    <text>Each player sacrifices all colored permanents he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"The emergence of the Eldrazi isn't necessarily a bad thing, as long as you've already lived a fulfilling and complete life without regrets."
—Javad Nasrin, Ondu relic hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0002</id>
    <name>Artisan of Kozilek</name>
    <text>When you cast Artisan of Kozilek, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.
Annihilator 2 (Whenever this creature attacks, defending player sacrifices two permanents.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0003</id>
    <name>Eldrazi Conscription</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +10/+10 and has trample and annihilator 2. (Whenever it attacks, defending player sacrifices two permanents.)</text>
    <flavorText>The barest taste of Eldrazi power shatters both realms and identities.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0004</id>
    <name>Emrakul, the Aeons Torn</name>
    <text>Emrakul, the Aeons Torn can't be countered.
When you cast Emrakul, take an extra turn after this one.
Flying, protection from colored spells, annihilator 6
When Emrakul is put into a graveyard from anywhere, its owner shuffles his or her graveyard into his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0005</id>
    <name>Hand of Emrakul</name>
    <text>You may sacrifice four Eldrazi Spawn rather than pay Hand of Emrakul's mana cost.
Annihilator 1 (Whenever this creature attacks, defending player sacrifices a permanent.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I believed in a beautiful god. But this is the true face of the divine."
—Ayli, Kamsa cleric</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0006</id>
    <name>Kozilek, Butcher of Truth</name>
    <text>When you cast Kozilek, Butcher of Truth, draw four cards.
Annihilator 4 (Whenever this creature attacks, defending player sacrifices four permanents.)
When Kozilek is put into a graveyard from anywhere, its owner shuffles his or her graveyard into his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0007</id>
    <name>It That Betrays</name>
    <text>Annihilator 2 (Whenever this creature attacks, defending player sacrifices two permanents.)
Whenever an opponent sacrifices a nontoken permanent, put that card onto the battlefield under your control.</text>
    <flavorText>Your pleas for death shall go unheard.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0008</id>
    <name>Not of This World</name>
    <text>Counter target spell or ability that targets a permanent you control.
Not of This World costs {7} less to cast if it targets a spell or ability that targets a creature you control with power 7 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0009</id>
    <name>Pathrazer of Ulamog</name>
    <text>Annihilator 3 (Whenever this creature attacks, defending player sacrifices three permanents.)
Pathrazer of Ulamog can't be blocked except by three or more creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>No thought but hunger. No strategy but destruction.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0010</id>
    <name>Skittering Invasion</name>
    <text>Put five 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature tokens onto the battlefield. They have "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>"The brood spread far faster than we could kill it. I fear the worst is yet to come."
—The War Diaries</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0011</id>
    <name>Spawnsire of Ulamog</name>
    <text>Annihilator 1 (Whenever this creature attacks, defending player sacrifices a permanent.)
{4}: Put two 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature tokens onto the battlefield. They have "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."
{2}0: Cast any number of Eldrazi cards you own from outside the game without paying their mana costs.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0012</id>
    <name>Ulamog, the Infinite Gyre</name>
    <text>When you cast Ulamog, the Infinite Gyre, destroy target permanent.
Annihilator 4 (Whenever this creature attacks, defending player sacrifices four permanents.)
Ulamog is indestructible.
When Ulamog is put into a graveyard from anywhere, its owner shuffles his or her graveyard into his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0013</id>
    <name>Ulamog's Crusher</name>
    <text>Annihilator 2 (Whenever this creature attacks, defending player sacrifices two permanents.)
Ulamog's Crusher attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>"Whatever the Eldrazi's purpose is, it has nothing to do with something so insignificant as us."
—Nirthu, lone missionary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0014</id>
    <name>Affa Guard Hound</name>
    <text>Flash
When Affa Guard Hound enters the battlefield, target creature gets +0/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Once a welcoming hub for explorers, Affa became a place of guarded tongues and quick defenses.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0015</id>
    <name>Caravan Escort</name>
    <text>Level up {2} ({2}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-4
2/2

LEVEL 5+
5/5
First strike</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0016</id>
    <name>Dawnglare Invoker</name>
    <text>Flying
{8}: Tap all creatures target player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"What we knew as Emeria, Ula, and Cosi were not divine beings at all, but a cruel trick, and a grave error."
—The Invokers' Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0017</id>
    <name>Deathless Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
{W}{W}: Target creature is indestructible this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I should have died that day, but I suffered not a scratch. I awoke in a lake of blood, none of it apparently my own."
—The War Diaries</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0018</id>
    <name>Demystify</name>
    <text>Destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>The Singing City was silent, the pathway stones were still, and the winds of the Howling Spire ceased.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0019</id>
    <name>Eland Umbra</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +0/+4.
Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0020</id>
    <name>Emerge Unscathed</name>
    <text>Target creature you control gains protection from the color of your choice until end of turn.
Rebound (If you cast this spell from your hand, exile it as it resolves. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast this card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0021</id>
    <name>Gideon Jura</name>
    <text>+2: During target opponent's next turn, creatures that player controls attack Gideon Jura if able.
-2: Destroy target tapped creature.
0: Until end of turn, Gideon Jura becomes a 6/6 Human Soldier creature that's still a planeswalker. Prevent all damage that would be dealt to him this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0022</id>
    <name>Glory Seeker</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"There's no contract to sign, no oath to swear. The enlistment procedure is to unsheathe your sword and point it at the enemy."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0023</id>
    <name>Guard Duty</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has defender.</text>
    <flavorText>"I was told these were standard issue. Do I look standard to you?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0024</id>
    <name>Harmless Assault</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn by attacking creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>After encasing it in a paralyzing beam of light, the angel studied the Eldrazi as a child would study a bug, curiously and without fear.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0025</id>
    <name>Hedron-Field Purists</name>
    <text>Level up {2}{W} ({2}{W}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-4
1/4
If a source would deal damage to you or a creature you control, prevent 1 of that damage.
LEVEL 5+
2/5
If a source would deal damage to you or a creature you control, prevent 2 of that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0026</id>
    <name>Hyena Umbra</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has first strike.
Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0027</id>
    <name>Ikiral Outrider</name>
    <text>Level up {4} ({4}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-3
2/6
Vigilance
LEVEL 4+
3/10
Vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0028</id>
    <name>Kabira Vindicator</name>
    <text>Level up {2}{W} ({2}{W}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 2-4
3/6
Other creatures you control get +1/+1.
LEVEL 5+
4/8
Other creatures you control get +2/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0029</id>
    <name>Knight of Cliffhaven</name>
    <text>Level up {3} ({3}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-3
2/3
Flying
LEVEL 4+
4/4
Flying, vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0030</id>
    <name>Kor Line-Slinger</name>
    <text>{T}: Tap target creature with power 3 or less.</text>
    <flavorText>"I tried to tell her to stay behind, that this fight was too dangerous. I spent the next hour tied to the rafters."
—Zahr Gada, Halimar expedition leader</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0031</id>
    <name>Kor Spiritdancer</name>
    <text>Kor Spiritdancer gets +2/+2 for each Aura attached to it.
Whenever you cast an Aura spell, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>She reaches beyond the physical realm, touching the ideals from which all creatures draw their power.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0032</id>
    <name>Lightmine Field</name>
    <text>Whenever one or more creatures attack, Lightmine Field deals damage to each of those creatures equal to the number of attacking creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>If you want to kill a lot of goblins, just make sure your defenses look like fun.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0033</id>
    <name>Linvala, Keeper of Silence</name>
    <text>Flying
Activated abilities of creatures your opponents control can't be activated.</text>
    <flavorText>Those who seek to disturb the harmony of life will see their instruments taken from them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0034</id>
    <name>Lone Missionary</name>
    <text>When Lone Missionary enters the battlefield, you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>His mission has become a grim pilgrimage, a tour of the Eldrazi-stricken outposts across Zendikar. But he marches on alone, stubborn as the daily dawn.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0035</id>
    <name>Luminous Wake</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature attacks or blocks, you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"If destiny's champions have arisen to fight the Ancient Ones, then let me, too, do my part."
—Ravuel of Graypelt</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0036</id>
    <name>Makindi Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>As the hedrons began to coalesce into colossal Eldrazi superstructures, the griffins were forced to seek new territory lest their aeries be crushed between the massive stone monoliths.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0037</id>
    <name>Mammoth Umbra</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3 and has vigilance.
Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0038</id>
    <name>Near-Death Experience</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you have exactly 1 life, you win the game.</text>
    <flavorText>Lands ravaged, cities in ruins, so many lives sacrificed, and yet there was no other word for it but victory.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0039</id>
    <name>Nomads' Assembly</name>
    <text>Put a 1/1 white Kor Soldier creature token onto the battlefield for each creature you control.
Rebound (If you cast this spell from your hand, exile it as it resolves. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast this card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0040</id>
    <name>Oust</name>
    <text>Put target creature into its owner's library second from the top. Its controller gains 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"‘Invincible' is just a word."
—Gideon Jura</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0041</id>
    <name>Puncturing Light</name>
    <text>Destroy target attacking or blocking creature with power 3 or less.</text>
    <flavorText>"The vampires knew what was coming. I know it. And they did nothing. They deserve to feel the same agony they've caused all of us."
—Anitan, Ondu cleric</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0042</id>
    <name>Repel the Darkness</name>
    <text>Tap up to two target creatures.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>A boon to those who cannot see in the dark. A bane to those who live in it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0043</id>
    <name>Smite</name>
    <text>Destroy target blocked creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The mighty rely solely on their strength. They are shocked when we do the same."
—Tars Olan, kor world-gift</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0044</id>
    <name>Soul's Attendant</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature enters the battlefield, you may gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>In truth, her own faith was gone, trodden in Ulamog's wake. She pantomimed the blessing in the hope that it would inspire others to continue to struggle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0045</id>
    <name>Soulbound Guardians</name>
    <text>Defender, flying</text>
    <flavorText>The kor's most righteous dead are given the greatest reward: an eternity tied to the land they so cherish.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0046</id>
    <name>Stalwart Shield-Bearers</name>
    <text>Defender
Other creatures you control with defender get +0/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>"Hold fast the line! Either we stop them here or we wake up in their guts!"
—Tala Vertan, Makindi shieldmate</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0047</id>
    <name>Student of Warfare</name>
    <text>Level up {W} ({W}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 2-6
3/3
First strike
LEVEL 7+
4/4
Double strike</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0048</id>
    <name>Survival Cache</name>
    <text>You gain 2 life. Then if you have more life than an opponent, draw a card.
Rebound (If you cast this spell from your hand, exile it as it resolves. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast this card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0049</id>
    <name>Time of Heroes</name>
    <text>Each creature you control with a level counter on it gets +2/+2.</text>
    <flavorText>No one spoke. There was no need. The threat of the Eldrazi presented a simple choice: lay down your weapons and die for nothing, or hold them fast and die for something.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0050</id>
    <name>Totem-Guide Hartebeest</name>
    <text>When Totem-Guide Hartebeest enters the battlefield, you may search your library for an Aura card, reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The kor track hartebeests in hopes of finding magic to help fight the Eldrazi.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0051</id>
    <name>Transcendent Master</name>
    <text>Level up {1} ({1}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 6-11
6/6
Lifelink
LEVEL 12+
9/9
Lifelink
Transcendent Master is indestructible.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0052</id>
    <name>Umbra Mystic</name>
    <text>Auras attached to permanents you control have totem armor. (If an enchanted permanent you control would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy an Aura attached to it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I have found the courage to face death—twice, if I must."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0053</id>
    <name>Wall of Omens</name>
    <text>Defender
When Wall of Omens enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"I search for a vision of Zendikar that does not include the Eldrazi."
—Expedition journal entry</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0054</id>
    <name>Aura Finesse</name>
    <text>Attach target Aura you control to target creature.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Although armor and auras can be similar, the brains required to use them are worlds apart."
—Zilan, Makindi auramancer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0055</id>
    <name>Cast Through Time</name>
    <text>Instant and sorcery spells you control have rebound. (Exile the spell as it resolves if you cast it from your hand. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast that card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0056</id>
    <name>Champion's Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
Champion's Drake gets +3/+3 as long as you control a creature with three or more level counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"'Fraid of heights? Ride a horse. 'Fraid of missing out? Rein up a drake."
—Trinda, Hada spy patrol</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0057</id>
    <name>Coralhelm Commander</name>
    <text>Level up {1} ({1}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 2-3
3/3
Flying
LEVEL 4+
4/4
Flying
Other Merfolk creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0058</id>
    <name>Crab Umbra</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{2}{U}: Untap enchanted creature.
Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0059</id>
    <name>Deprive</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Deprive, return a land you control to its owner's hand.
Counter target spell.</text>
    <flavorText>"That would have brought shame to you as a mage. Tell you what—I'll keep your secret."
—Noyan Dar, Tazeem lullmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0060</id>
    <name>Distortion Strike</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn and is unblockable this turn.
Rebound (If you cast this spell from your hand, exile it as it resolves. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast this card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0061</id>
    <name>Domestication</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
You control enchanted creature.
At the beginning of your end step, if enchanted creature's power is 4 or greater, sacrifice Domestication.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0062</id>
    <name>Dormant Gomazoa</name>
    <text>Flying
Dormant Gomazoa enters the battlefield tapped.
Dormant Gomazoa doesn't untap during your untap step.
Whenever you become the target of a spell, you may untap Dormant Gomazoa.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0063</id>
    <name>Drake Umbra</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3 and has flying.
Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0064</id>
    <name>Echo Mage</name>
    <text>Level up {1}{U} ({1}{U}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 2-3
2/4
{U}{U}, {T}: Copy target instant or sorcery spell. You may choose new targets for the copy.
LEVEL 4+
2/5
{U}{U}, {T}: Copy target instant or sorcery spell twice. You may choose new targets for the copies.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0065</id>
    <name>Eel Umbra</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1.
Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0066</id>
    <name>Enclave Cryptologist</name>
    <text>Level up {1}{U} ({1}{U}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-2
0/1
{T}: Draw a card, then discard a card.
LEVEL 3+
0/1
{T}: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0067</id>
    <name>Fleeting Distraction</name>
    <text>Target creature gets -1/-0 until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"To distract an archmage would take incredible power. But for a simpleton, something sparkly will do."
—Noyan Dar, Tazeem lullmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0068</id>
    <name>Frostwind Invoker</name>
    <text>Flying
{8}: Creatures you control gain flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"We thought Zendikar's rage was kindled by its explorers and plunderers. But the world had sensed the stirrings of the Eldrazi."
—The Invokers' Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0069</id>
    <name>Gravitational Shift</name>
    <text>Creatures with flying get +2/+0.
Creatures without flying get -2/-0.</text>
    <flavorText>As they awakened, the Eldrazi reasserted their mastery over all of Zendikar's natural forces.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0070</id>
    <name>Guard Gomazoa</name>
    <text>Defender, flying
Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to Guard Gomazoa.</text>
    <flavorText>It lingers near the outposts of the Makindi Trenches, inadvertently granting another layer of defense.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0071</id>
    <name>Hada Spy Patrol</name>
    <text>Level up {2}{U} ({2}{U}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-2
2/2
Hada Spy Patrol is unblockable.
LEVEL 3+
3/3
Shroud
Hada Spy Patrol is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0072</id>
    <name>Halimar Wavewatch</name>
    <text>Level up {2} ({2}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-4
0/6

LEVEL 5+
6/6
Islandwalk</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0073</id>
    <name>Jwari Scuttler</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Yeah, they've got a lot of meat. The only downside to eating 'em is that you often find human bones and body parts inside."
—Jaby, Silundi Sea nomad</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0074</id>
    <name>Lay Bare</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. Look at its controller's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's good to learn from your failures, but I prefer to learn from the failures of others."
—Jace Beleren</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0075</id>
    <name>Lighthouse Chronologist</name>
    <text>Level up {U} ({U}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 4-6
2/4

LEVEL 7+
3/5
At the beginning of each end step, if it's not your turn, take an extra turn after this one.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0076</id>
    <name>Merfolk Observer</name>
    <text>When Merfolk Observer enters the battlefield, look at the top card of target player's library.</text>
    <flavorText>"The structure gets bigger every hour, with hedrons coalescing even deep under the surface. If I could only get inside . . . ."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0077</id>
    <name>Merfolk Skyscout</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Merfolk Skyscout attacks or blocks, untap target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"Emeria is a pleasant lie, a figment to hide Emrakul's hideous face. I can only hope to uncover a truth that lies deeper still."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0078</id>
    <name>Mnemonic Wall</name>
    <text>Defender
When Mnemonic Wall enters the battlefield, you may return target instant or sorcery card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'd build an entire fortress of them if I could."
—Mzali, Lighthouse archmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0079</id>
    <name>Narcolepsy</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of each upkeep, if enchanted creature is untapped, tap it.</text>
    <flavorText>"It's so cute when it's sleeping, isn't it? Actually, it's still as abhorrent as ever, but at least it's not trying to kill us."
—Noyan Dar, Tazeem lullmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0080</id>
    <name>Phantasmal Abomination</name>
    <text>Defender
When Phantasmal Abomination becomes the target of a spell or ability, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>Create an illusion so strong that it becomes another's reality, and you can become the master of all.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0081</id>
    <name>Reality Spasm</name>
    <text>Choose one — Tap X target permanents; or untap X target permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>From the moment the first Eldrazi spawn squirmed free, everything on Zendikar took on an adjusted meaning, a new slant toward or away from the waking giants.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0082</id>
    <name>Recurring Insight</name>
    <text>Draw cards equal to the number of cards in target opponent's hand.
Rebound (If you cast this spell from your hand, exile it as it resolves. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast this card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0083</id>
    <name>Regress</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Never look too deep, where the waters turn dark. What the sea has hidden there may not stay down forever."
—Jaby, Silundi Sea nomad</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0084</id>
    <name>Renegade Doppelganger</name>
    <text>Whenever another creature enters the battlefield under your control, you may have Renegade Doppelganger become a copy of that creature until end of turn. (If it does, it loses this ability for the rest of the turn.)</text>
    <flavorText>To truly know a creature, slither a mile in its tentacles.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0085</id>
    <name>Sea Gate Oracle</name>
    <text>When Sea Gate Oracle enters the battlefield, look at the top two cards of your library. Put one of them into your hand and the other on the bottom of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"The secret entrance should be near."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0086</id>
    <name>See Beyond</name>
    <text>Draw two cards, then shuffle a card from your hand into your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Ancient lore locked in a mind driven mad is just as safe as when it was locked deep underground.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0087</id>
    <name>Shared Discovery</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Shared Discovery, tap four untapped creatures you control.
Draw three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Riches must be divided, but real wealth can be shared.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0088</id>
    <name>Skywatcher Adept</name>
    <text>Level up {3} ({3}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-2
2/2
Flying
LEVEL 3+
4/2
Flying</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0089</id>
    <name>Sphinx of Magosi</name>
    <text>Flying
{2}{U}: Draw a card, then put a +1/+1 counter on Sphinx of Magosi.</text>
    <flavorText>"A riddle is nothing more than a trap for small minds, baited with the promise of understanding."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0090</id>
    <name>Surrakar Spellblade</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an instant or sorcery spell, you may put a charge counter on Surrakar Spellblade.
Whenever Surrakar Spellblade deals combat damage to a player, you may draw X cards, where X is the number of charge counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0091</id>
    <name>Training Grounds</name>
    <text>Activated abilities of creatures you control cost up to {2} less to activate. This effect can't reduce the amount of mana an ability costs to activate to less than one mana.</text>
    <flavorText>Under the master's eye, skills are honed sharper and spells cut deeper.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0092</id>
    <name>Unified Will</name>
    <text>Counter target spell if you control more creatures than that spell's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>"We're glad to be of service—to be an audience to your failure."
—Maizah Shere, Tazeem lullmage</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0093</id>
    <name>Venerated Teacher</name>
    <text>When Venerated Teacher enters the battlefield, put two level counters on each creature you control with level up.</text>
    <flavorText>"The unfathomable is upon us, students. I have no doubt you will rise to the occasion."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0094</id>
    <name>Arrogant Bloodlord</name>
    <text>Whenever Arrogant Bloodlord blocks or becomes blocked by a creature with power 1 or less, destroy Arrogant Bloodlord at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"I would rather take my own head than be thwarted by a presumptuous wretch with a shield and a dream."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0095</id>
    <name>Bala Ged Scorpion</name>
    <text>When Bala Ged Scorpion enters the battlefield, you may destroy target creature with power 1 or less.</text>
    <flavorText>Fast and lethal, with a penchant for the weak and infirm.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0096</id>
    <name>Baneful Omen</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your end step, you may reveal the top card of your library. If you do, each opponent loses life equal to that card's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"Ah, again it does not bode well for you."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0097</id>
    <name>Bloodrite Invoker</name>
    <text>{8}: Target player loses 3 life and you gain 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The brood lineages unfolded across the world, each patterned after one of three progenitors, each a study in mindless consumption."
—The Invokers' Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0098</id>
    <name>Bloodthrone Vampire</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: Bloodthrone Vampire gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Some humans willingly offered up their blood, hoping it would grant the vampire families the strength to stave off the Eldrazi.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0099</id>
    <name>Cadaver Imp</name>
    <text>Flying
When Cadaver Imp enters the battlefield, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>The mouth must be pried open before rigor mortis sets in. Otherwise the returning soul can find no ingress.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0100</id>
    <name>Consume the Meek</name>
    <text>Destroy each creature with converted mana cost 3 or less. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why does it destroy? It does, and to talk of reasons wastes time and breath."
—Nirthu, lone missionary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0101</id>
    <name>Consuming Vapors</name>
    <text>Target player sacrifices a creature. You gain life equal to that creature's toughness.
Rebound (If you cast this spell from your hand, exile it as it resolves. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast this card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0102</id>
    <name>Contaminated Ground</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Enchanted land is a Swamp.
Whenever enchanted land becomes tapped, its controller loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Na Plateau is lost. Do not ask what happened, and never return there."
—Nirthu, lone missionary</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0103</id>
    <name>Corpsehatch</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. Put two 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature tokens onto the battlefield. They have "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0104</id>
    <name>Curse of Wizardry</name>
    <text>As Curse of Wizardry enters the battlefield, choose a color.
Whenever a player casts a spell of the chosen color, that player loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"We must all push through the pain to heal our world."
—Ayli, Kamsa cleric</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0105</id>
    <name>Death Cultist</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Death Cultist: Target player loses 1 life and you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Death inevitably seduces all who study it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0106</id>
    <name>Demonic Appetite</name>
    <text>Enchant creature you control
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Morality is just shorthand for the constraints of being powerless."
—Ob Nixilis</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0107</id>
    <name>Drana, Kalastria Bloodchief</name>
    <text>Flying
{X}{B}{B}: Target creature gets -0/-X until end of turn and Drana, Kalastria Bloodchief gets +X/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"If our former masters would have us kneel again, they shall feel our defiance slashed across their membranes."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0108</id>
    <name>Dread Drone</name>
    <text>When Dread Drone enters the battlefield, put two 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature tokens onto the battlefield. They have "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>Each Eldrazi ancient spawned a lineage of horrors in unfathomable shapes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0109</id>
    <name>Escaped Null</name>
    <text>Lifelink
Whenever Escaped Null blocks or becomes blocked, it gets +5/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Left masterless by Kozilek, it wandered the wilds, raving in its ceaseless hunger.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0110</id>
    <name>Essence Feed</name>
    <text>Target player loses 3 life. You gain 3 life and put three 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature tokens onto the battlefield. They have "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>Eldrazi grow wherever something else dies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0111</id>
    <name>Gloomhunter</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Scavengers both mundane and magical follow in its wake, feeding on the scraps of flesh and spirit it leaves behind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0112</id>
    <name>Guul Draz Assassin</name>
    <text>Level up {1}{B} ({1}{B}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 2-3
2/2
{B}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn.
LEVEL 4+
4/4
{B}, {T}: Target creature gets -4/-4 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0113</id>
    <name>Hellcarver Demon</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Hellcarver Demon deals combat damage to a player, sacrifice all other permanents you control and discard your hand. Exile the top six cards of your library. You may cast any number of nonland cards exiled this way without paying their mana costs.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0114</id>
    <name>Induce Despair</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Induce Despair, reveal a creature card from your hand.
Target creature gets -X/-X until end of turn, where X is the revealed card's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>All the angel saw was her doom.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0115</id>
    <name>Inquisition of Kozilek</name>
    <text>Target player reveals his or her hand. You choose a nonland card from it with converted mana cost 3 or less. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>You will scream out your innermost secrets just to make it stop.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0116</id>
    <name>Last Kiss</name>
    <text>Last Kiss deals 2 damage to target creature and you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Romanticize it, glamorize it, call it what you will. To me, it will always be carnal, bloody murder."
—Ayli, Kamsa cleric</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0117</id>
    <name>Mortician Beetle</name>
    <text>Whenever a player sacrifices a creature, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Mortician Beetle.</text>
    <flavorText>To the soldier, war is famine; to the scavenger, a feast.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0118</id>
    <name>Nighthaze</name>
    <text>Target creature gains swampwalk until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"To evade the brood lineages, one must be made dark to all the senses."
—Traga, Zulaport runner</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0119</id>
    <name>Nirkana Cutthroat</name>
    <text>Level up {2}{B} ({2}{B}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-2
4/3
Deathtouch
LEVEL 3+
5/4
First strike, deathtouch</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0120</id>
    <name>Nirkana Revenant</name>
    <text>Whenever you tap a Swamp for mana, add {B} to your mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).
{B}: Nirkana Revenant gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Hate is an everlasting wellspring from which it is eternally sustained.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0121</id>
    <name>Null Champion</name>
    <text>Level up {3} ({3}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-3
4/2

LEVEL 4+
7/3
{B}: Regenerate Null Champion.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0122</id>
    <name>Pawn of Ulamog</name>
    <text>Whenever Pawn of Ulamog or another nontoken creature you control is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may put a 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature token onto the battlefield. It has "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0123</id>
    <name>Perish the Thought</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You choose a card from it. That player shuffles that card into his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>It removed only one idea from her mind: defiance.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0124</id>
    <name>Pestilence Demon</name>
    <text>Flying
{B}: Pestilence Demon deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have schemed too long to be supplanted by dead gods. If I cannot have this world, no one can."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0125</id>
    <name>Repay in Kind</name>
    <text>Each player's life total becomes the lowest life total among all players.</text>
    <flavorText>Sorin has gathered grudges for centuries, patiently awaiting the day he can exact the perfect vengeance.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0126</id>
    <name>Shrivel</name>
    <text>All creatures get -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Have you ever killed insects nibbling at your crops? I think that's what the Eldrazi believe they're doing to us."
—Sheyda, Ondu gamekeeper</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0127</id>
    <name>Skeletal Wurm</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Skeletal Wurm.</text>
    <flavorText>Necromancers are judged by the most powerful undead they've ever created. There are those who have animated just a single being, yet are considered the pinnacle of their dark craft.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0128</id>
    <name>Suffer the Past</name>
    <text>Exile X target cards from target player's graveyard. For each card exiled this way, that player loses 1 life and you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Ulamog's tentacles, their touch like burning ice, rummaged through his soul and stung his memories one by one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0129</id>
    <name>Thought Gorger</name>
    <text>Trample
When Thought Gorger enters the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on it for each card in your hand. If you do, discard your hand.
When Thought Gorger leaves the battlefield, draw a card for each +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0130</id>
    <name>Vendetta</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated. You lose life equal to that creature's toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>"Consider my debt to your kin paid in full."
—Idrol, Guul Draz assassin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0131</id>
    <name>Virulent Swipe</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +2/+0 and gains deathtouch until end of turn.
Rebound (If you cast this spell from your hand, exile it as it resolves. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast this card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0132</id>
    <name>Zof Shade</name>
    <text>{2}{B}: Zof Shade gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It haunts the remnants of the Helix of Zof, leeching strength from the vast Eldrazi ruin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0133</id>
    <name>Zulaport Enforcer</name>
    <text>Level up {4} ({4}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-2
3/3

LEVEL 3+
5/5
Zulaport Enforcer can't be blocked except by black creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0134</id>
    <name>Akoum Boulderfoot</name>
    <text>When Akoum Boulderfoot enters the battlefield, it deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you're in Akoum and you glimpse a shadow overhead, the worst thing you can do is duck."
—Chadir the Navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0135</id>
    <name>Battle Rampart</name>
    <text>Defender
{T}: Target creature gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I will build no sanctuaries. The safety you seek can be won only by the sword."
—Yannash, outpost builder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0136</id>
    <name>Battle-Rattle Shaman</name>
    <text>At the beginning of combat on your turn, you may have target creature get +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The shaman rattles not to inspire a battle fury but to drown out the shrieks of those fleeing the Eldrazi.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0137</id>
    <name>Brimstone Mage</name>
    <text>Level up {3}{R} ({3}{R}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-2
2/3
{T}: Brimstone Mage deals 1 damage to target creature or player.
LEVEL 3+
2/4
{T}: Brimstone Mage deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0138</id>
    <name>Brood Birthing</name>
    <text>If you control an Eldrazi Spawn, put three 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature tokens onto the battlefield. They have "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool." Otherwise, put one of those tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0139</id>
    <name>Conquering Manticore</name>
    <text>Flying
When Conquering Manticore enters the battlefield, gain control of target creature an opponent controls until end of turn. Untap that creature. It gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It speaks no commands but is always obeyed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0140</id>
    <name>Devastating Summons</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Devastating Summons, sacrifice X lands.
Put two X/X red Elemental creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Things born in magma are always angry.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0141</id>
    <name>Disaster Radius</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Disaster Radius, reveal a creature card from your hand.
Disaster Radius deals X damage to each creature your opponents control, where X is the revealed card's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0142</id>
    <name>Emrakul's Hatcher</name>
    <text>When Emrakul's Hatcher enters the battlefield, put three 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature tokens onto the battlefield. They have "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>Wordlessly it leads its abhorrent brood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0143</id>
    <name>Explosive Revelation</name>
    <text>Choose target creature or player. Reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal a nonland card. Explosive Revelation deals damage equal to that card's converted mana cost to that creature or player. Put the nonland card into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0144</id>
    <name>Fissure Vent</name>
    <text>Choose one or both — Destroy target artifact; and/or destroy target nonbasic land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Something down there has an appetite for what we're standing on. Let's hope it doesn't want seconds."
—Samila, Murasa Expeditionary House</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0145</id>
    <name>Flame Slash</name>
    <text>Flame Slash deals 4 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>After millennia asleep, the Eldrazi had forgotten about Zendikar's fiery temper and dislike of strangers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0146</id>
    <name>Forked Bolt</name>
    <text>Forked Bolt deals 2 damage divided as you choose among one or two target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>"Play no favorites. Everybody dies."
—Sparkmage saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0147</id>
    <name>Goblin Arsonist</name>
    <text>When Goblin Arsonist is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may have it deal 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>With great power comes great risk of getting yourself killed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0148</id>
    <name>Goblin Tunneler</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature with power 2 or less is unblockable this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"You never know what's going to be in goblin tunnels. Even in the best case, there will still be goblins."
—Sachir, Akoum Expeditionary House</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0149</id>
    <name>Grotag Siege-Runner</name>
    <text>{R}, Sacrifice Grotag Siege-Runner: Destroy target creature with defender. Grotag Siege-Runner deals 2 damage to that creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>"I don't think he's bringing in the mail . . . ."
—Nundari, Sea Gate militia captain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0150</id>
    <name>Heat Ray</name>
    <text>Heat Ray deals X damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"There was clearly a scream. I'm not sure if there was a mouth."
—Sachir, Akoum Expeditionary House</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0151</id>
    <name>Hellion Eruption</name>
    <text>Sacrifice all creatures you control, then put that many 4/4 red Hellion creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Just when you thought you'd be safe, in the middle of an open field with no Eldrazi around for miles.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0152</id>
    <name>Kargan Dragonlord</name>
    <text>Level up {R} ({R}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 4-7
4/4
Flying
LEVEL 8+
8/8
Flying, trample
{R}: Kargan Dragonlord gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0153</id>
    <name>Kiln Fiend</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an instant or sorcery spell, Kiln Fiend gets +3/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It traps an explosion within its stony skin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0154</id>
    <name>Lagac Lizard</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Tracing their ancestry back to Zendikar's earliest forms of life, lagac lizards have seen the comings and goings of planeswalkers and the Eldrazi, and the rise of the vampire clans, none of which has changed them one bit.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0155</id>
    <name>Lavafume Invoker</name>
    <text>{8}: Creatures you control get +3/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Then the ancient masters themselves, towers of rapacity, rose and began their calamitous feast."
—The Invokers' Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0156</id>
    <name>Lord of Shatterskull Pass</name>
    <text>Level up {1}{R} ({1}{R}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-5
6/6

LEVEL 6+
6/6
Whenever Lord of Shatterskull Pass attacks, it deals 6 damage to each creature defending player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0157</id>
    <name>Lust for War</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature becomes tapped, Lust for War deals 3 damage to that creature's controller.
Enchanted creature attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0158</id>
    <name>Magmaw</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice a nonland permanent: Magmaw deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>"The purpose of existence is simple: everything is fuel for the magmaw."
—Jaji, magmaw worshipper</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0159</id>
    <name>Ogre Sentry</name>
    <text>Defender</text>
    <flavorText>"You have to appreciate the genius of it. Why bother building defenses when you can just fill the pass with angry ogres?"
—Javad Nasrin, Ondu relic hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0160</id>
    <name>Rage Nimbus</name>
    <text>Defender, flying
{1}{R}: Target creature attacks this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>The settlement knew there was something strange about the cloud when the old priest Mandli suddenly grabbed an axe and ran screaming into the hills.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0161</id>
    <name>Raid Bombardment</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control with power 2 or less attacks, Raid Bombardment deals 1 damage to defending player.</text>
    <flavorText>Goblins in the first wave of a fire raid always bemoan the aim of everyone else.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0162</id>
    <name>Rapacious One</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Rapacious One deals combat damage to a player, put that many 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature tokens onto the battlefield. They have "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0163</id>
    <name>Soulsurge Elemental</name>
    <text>First strike
Soulsurge Elemental's power is equal to the number of creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>It draws its strength from those around it, but the pleasure of destruction is all its own.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0164</id>
    <name>Spawning Breath</name>
    <text>Spawning Breath deals 1 damage to target creature or player. Put a 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature token onto the battlefield. It has "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>Death by death, Kozilek's lineage spread.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0165</id>
    <name>Splinter Twin</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has "{T}: Put a token that's a copy of this creature onto the battlefield. That token has haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step."</text>
    <flavorText>"I know just the person for that job."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0166</id>
    <name>Staggershock</name>
    <text>Staggershock deals 2 damage to target creature or player.
Rebound (If you cast this spell from your hand, exile it as it resolves. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast this card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0167</id>
    <name>Surreal Memoir</name>
    <text>Return an instant card at random from your graveyard to your hand.
Rebound (If you cast this spell from your hand, exile it as it resolves. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast this card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0168</id>
    <name>Traitorous Instinct</name>
    <text>Gain control of target creature until end of turn. Untap that creature. Until end of turn, it gets +2/+0 and gains haste.</text>
    <flavorText>The horror lurched about like a puppet from a madman's nightmare, squeezing the life from its own kind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0169</id>
    <name>Tuktuk the Explorer</name>
    <text>Haste
When Tuktuk the Explorer is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a legendary 5/5 colorless Goblin Golem artifact creature token named Tuktuk the Returned onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Remade by Eldrazi magic, Tuktuk inspired an entire clan of misguided goblins.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0170</id>
    <name>Valakut Fireboar</name>
    <text>Whenever Valakut Fireboar attacks, switch its power and toughness until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Just move very slowly, and for the love of Ula, do not get it mad."
—Chadir the Navigator</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0171</id>
    <name>Vent Sentinel</name>
    <text>Defender
{1}{R}, {T}: Vent Sentinel deals damage to target player equal to the number of creatures with defender you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Zendikar fortifies itself against the Great Threat, making sentries of sky, sea, and stone."
—The War Diaries</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0172</id>
    <name>World at War</name>
    <text>After the first postcombat main phase this turn, there's an additional combat phase followed by an additional main phase. At the beginning of that combat, untap all creatures that attacked this turn.
Rebound (If you cast this spell from your hand, exile it as it resolves. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast this card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0173</id>
    <name>Wrap in Flames</name>
    <text>Wrap in Flames deals 1 damage to each of up to three target creatures. Those creatures can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our pyromancer's flames may not have killed them, but they bought us the time we needed."
—The War Diaries</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0174</id>
    <name>Ancient Stirrings</name>
    <text>Look at the top five cards of your library. You may reveal a colorless card from among them and put it into your hand. Then put the rest on the bottom of your library in any order. (Cards with no colored mana in their mana costs are colorless. Lands are also colorless.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0175</id>
    <name>Aura Gnarlid</name>
    <text>Creatures with power less than Aura Gnarlid's power can't block it.
Aura Gnarlid gets +1/+1 for each Aura on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Kill a gnarlid with your first blow, or it'll cheerfully show you how it's done.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0176</id>
    <name>Awakening Zone</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature token onto the battlefield. It has "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>The ground erupted in time with the hedron's thrum, a dirge of the last days.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0177</id>
    <name>Bear Umbra</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and has "Whenever this creature attacks, untap all lands you control."
Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0178</id>
    <name>Beastbreaker of Bala Ged</name>
    <text>Level up {2}{G} ({2}{G}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-3
4/4

LEVEL 4+
6/6
Trample</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0179</id>
    <name>Boar Umbra</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.
Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)</text>
    <flavorText>"From in here, everything looks like dinner."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0180</id>
    <name>Bramblesnap</name>
    <text>Trample
Tap an untapped creature you control: Bramblesnap gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A bramblesnap is formed by grafting together thirteen different plants that already hunger for meat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0181</id>
    <name>Broodwarden</name>
    <text>Eldrazi Spawn creatures you control get +2/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>"The least of gods shall tower over the mightiest of mortals, and death shall reign over all."
—Crypt of Agadeem inscription</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0182</id>
    <name>Daggerback Basilisk</name>
    <text>Deathtouch</text>
    <flavorText>"Petrifying gaze, deadly fangs, knifelike dorsal spines, venomous saliva . . . Am I missing anything? . . . Toxic bones? Seriously?"
—Samila, Murasa Expeditionary House</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0183</id>
    <name>Gelatinous Genesis</name>
    <text>Put X X/X green Ooze creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Even as the world was left cracked and gory by the marauding Eldrazi, new life began to drip from its wounds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0184</id>
    <name>Gigantomancer</name>
    <text>{1}: Target creature you control becomes 7/7 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"All life is driven by an indomitable will to survive. I simply turn that into something more . . . tangible."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0185</id>
    <name>Gravity Well</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature with flying attacks, it loses flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Storms spread throughout Oran-Rief, ripping the skies with wind and rain. Airborne creatures sought shelter where they could.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0186</id>
    <name>Growth Spasm</name>
    <text>Search your library for a basic land card, put it onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle your library. Put a 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature token onto the battlefield. It has "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0187</id>
    <name>Haze Frog</name>
    <text>Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)
When Haze Frog enters the battlefield, prevent all combat damage that other creatures would deal this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Its breath leaves its prey too drowsy to struggle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0188</id>
    <name>Irresistible Prey</name>
    <text>Target creature must be blocked this turn if able.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The baloth's instincts boiled, its muscles pulled taut, and its razor-spines bristled, as it turned to face—a runt meepling.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0189</id>
    <name>Jaddi Lifestrider</name>
    <text>When Jaddi Lifestrider enters the battlefield, you may tap any number of untapped creatures you control. You gain 2 life for each creature tapped this way.</text>
    <flavorText>Nature's arms encircle all who are willing to draw close.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0190</id>
    <name>Joraga Treespeaker</name>
    <text>Level up {1}{G} ({1}{G}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 1-4
1/2
{T}: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool.
LEVEL 5+
1/4
Elves you control have "{T}: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0191</id>
    <name>Kazandu Tuskcaller</name>
    <text>Level up {1}{G} ({1}{G}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)
LEVEL 2-5
1/1
{T}: Put a 3/3 green Elephant creature token onto the battlefield.
LEVEL 6+
1/1
{T}: Put two 3/3 green Elephant creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0192</id>
    <name>Khalni Hydra</name>
    <text>Khalni Hydra costs {G} less to cast for each green creature you control.
Trample</text>
    <flavorText>"In ages past, bargains were struck and promises were made. Now we must collect on our debt. Begin the hymns."
—Moruul, Khalni druid</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0193</id>
    <name>Kozilek's Predator</name>
    <text>When Kozilek's Predator enters the battlefield, put two 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature tokens onto the battlefield. They have "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>It's difficult to outwit something that doesn't speak, strategize, or even think.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0194</id>
    <name>Leaf Arrow</name>
    <text>Leaf Arrow deals 3 damage to target creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those who think the trees shall remain bystanders throughout this conflict shall be sorely mistaken."
—Sutina, Speaker of the Tajuru</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0195</id>
    <name>Living Destiny</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Living Destiny, reveal a creature card from your hand.
You gain life equal to the revealed card's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"That our enemies are great only brings us greater hope."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0196</id>
    <name>Might of the Masses</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The Joraga elves never need ask a troll to leave their territory. They merely grant it their combined strength, and it can't resist embarking on a merry rampage.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0197</id>
    <name>Momentous Fall</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Momentous Fall, sacrifice a creature.
You draw cards equal to the sacrificed creature's power, then you gain life equal to its toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>It wasn't long until the elves had developed a use for every part of the Eldrazi.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0198</id>
    <name>Mul Daya Channelers</name>
    <text>Play with the top card of your library revealed.
As long as the top card of your library is a creature card, Mul Daya Channelers gets +3/+3.
As long as the top card of your library is a land card, Mul Daya Channelers has "{T}: Add two mana of any one color to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0199</id>
    <name>Naturalize</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"The scholars wept when we destroyed the hedron. I had no such pity. What would this world be like had we done so sooner?"
—The War Diaries</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0200</id>
    <name>Nema Siltlurker</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>In one gargantuan bite, it will swallow not only you but also the riverbank you were standing on.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0201</id>
    <name>Nest Invader</name>
    <text>When Nest Invader enters the battlefield, put a 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature token onto the battlefield. It has "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>It nurtures its masters' glorious future.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0202</id>
    <name>Ondu Giant</name>
    <text>When Ondu Giant enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a basic land card, put it onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Some druids nurture gardens. Others nurture continents.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0203</id>
    <name>Overgrown Battlement</name>
    <text>Defender
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool for each creature with defender you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Our enemy is nothing less than the end of all life. We shall not want for allies."
—The War Diaries</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0204</id>
    <name>Pelakka Wurm</name>
    <text>Trample
When Pelakka Wurm enters the battlefield, you gain 7 life.
When Pelakka Wurm is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>It eats what it wants to eat—which is anything that moves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0205</id>
    <name>Prey's Vengeance</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.
Rebound (If you cast this spell from your hand, exile it as it resolves. At the beginning of your next upkeep, you may cast this card from exile without paying its mana cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0206</id>
    <name>Realms Uncharted</name>
    <text>Search your library for four land cards with different names and reveal them. An opponent chooses two of those cards. Put the chosen cards into your graveyard and the rest into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0207</id>
    <name>Snake Umbra</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has "Whenever this creature deals damage to an opponent, you may draw a card."
Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0208</id>
    <name>Spider Umbra</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has reach. (It can block creatures with flying.)
Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0209</id>
    <name>Sporecap Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>"They don't move much, but then again, if you get caught in its web, it has all the time in the world to get to you."
—Saidah, Joraga hunter</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0210</id>
    <name>Stomper Cub</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>"This one is only a yearling, but it would be wise to move away before we provide it with excellent hunting practice."
—Samila, Murasa Expeditionary House</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0211</id>
    <name>Tajuru Preserver</name>
    <text>Spells and abilities your opponents control can't cause you to sacrifice permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>"No more blood shall be spilled to satisfy another's deluded lust for power."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0212</id>
    <name>Vengevine</name>
    <text>Haste
Whenever you cast a spell, if it's the second creature spell you cast this turn, you may return Vengevine from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Leave but a shred of root and it will return, bursting with vigor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0213</id>
    <name>Wildheart Invoker</name>
    <text>{8}: Target creature gets +5/+5 and gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Life as we know it dangles on the brink of extinction. We must show the strength they would steal from us."
—The Invokers' Tales</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0214</id>
    <name>Sarkhan the Mad</name>
    <text>0: Reveal the top card of your library and put it into your hand. Sarkhan the Mad deals damage to himself equal to that card's converted mana cost.
-2: Target creature's controller sacrifices it, then that player puts a 5/5 red Dragon creature token with flying onto the battlefield.
-4: Each Dragon creature you control deals damage equal to its power to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0215</id>
    <name>Angelheart Vial</name>
    <text>Whenever you're dealt damage, you may put that many charge counters on Angelheart Vial.
{2}, {T}, Remove four charge counters from Angelheart Vial: You gain 2 life and draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>It holds a whisper from Iona: "Persevere."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0216</id>
    <name>Dreamstone Hedron</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {3} to your mana pool.
{3}, {T}, Sacrifice Dreamstone Hedron: Draw three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Only the Eldrazi mind thinks in the warped paths required to open the hedrons and tap the power within.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0217</id>
    <name>Enatu Golem</name>
    <text>When Enatu Golem is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Golems conjured from the debris of Enatu Temple provided a sturdy but expendable first line of defense against the Eldrazi.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0218</id>
    <name>Hedron Matrix</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +X/+X, where X is its converted mana cost.
Equip {4}</text>
    <flavorText>The hedrons awoke along with the Eldrazi, forming superstructures that radiated overwhelming magic.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0219</id>
    <name>Keening Stone</name>
    <text>{5}, {T}: Target player puts the top X cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard, where X is the number of cards in that player's graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>As it spins, dead voices shriek in an ever-increasing cacophony, rending the mind asunder.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0220</id>
    <name>Ogre's Cleaver</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +5/+0.
Equip {5}</text>
    <flavorText>She adopted the weapon of the slave-lord Kazuul, and with it, all his cruelty.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0221</id>
    <name>Pennon Blade</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +1/+1 for each creature you control.
Equip {4}</text>
    <flavorText>Draped with the pennon of a fallen outpost, the sword came to symbolize the peoples of Zendikar becoming one.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0222</id>
    <name>Prophetic Prism</name>
    <text>When Prophetic Prism enters the battlefield, draw a card.
{1}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"The explorer who found it got a bad deal when he sold it. He merely got rich."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0223</id>
    <name>Reinforced Bulwark</name>
    <text>Defender
{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to you this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Built of wood and iron. Held together by hope and prayer.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0224</id>
    <name>Runed Servitor</name>
    <text>When Runed Servitor is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, each player draws a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Scholars had puzzled for centuries over the ruins at Tal Terig. Its secrets had always lived within one rune-carved head.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0225</id>
    <name>Sphinx-Bone Wand</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast an instant or sorcery spell, you may put a charge counter on Sphinx-Bone Wand. If you do, Sphinx-Bone Wand deals damage equal to the number of charge counters on it to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Its host's final curse lies captured within.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0226</id>
    <name>Warmonger's Chariot</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +2/+2.
As long as equipped creature has defender, it can attack as though it didn't have defender.
Equip {3}</text>
    <flavorText>The best defense is a good offense.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0227</id>
    <name>Eldrazi Temple</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}: Add {2} to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast colorless Eldrazi spells or activate abilities of colorless Eldrazi.</text>
    <flavorText>Each temple is a door to a horrible future.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0228</id>
    <name>Evolving Wilds</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice Evolving Wilds: Search your library for a basic land card and put it onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Every world is an organism, able to grow new lands. Some just do it faster than others.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0229</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0230</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0231</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0232</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0233</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0234</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0235</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0236</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0237</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0238</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0239</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0240</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0241</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0242</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0243</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0244</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0245</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0246</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0247</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>ROE0248</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>