<cards name="Shadowmoor">
  <item>
    <id>SHM0001</id>
    <name>Apothecary Initiate</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a white spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Kithkin jealously hoard their knowledge of poultices and remedies so that no outside threat can benefit from their wisdom.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0002</id>
    <name>Armored Ascension</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 for each Plains you control and has flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why enchant feathers to make them sturdy when we can enchant shields to make them fly?"
—Braenna, cobblesmith</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0003</id>
    <name>Ballynock Cohort</name>
    <text>First strike
Ballynock Cohort gets +1/+1 as long as you control another white creature.</text>
    <flavorText>A kithkin's worst enemy is solitude.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0004</id>
    <name>Barrenton Medic</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.
Put a -1/-1 counter on Barrenton Medic: Untap Barrenton Medic.</text>
    <flavorText>His dreams are filled with noxious powders and clinking vials.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0005</id>
    <name>Boon Reflection</name>
    <text>If you would gain life, you gain twice that much life instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Kithkin healers chant the clan songs of both their parents over the broth to double its curative effect.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0006</id>
    <name>Goldenglow Moth</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Goldenglow Moth blocks, you may gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Ordinary moths follow it, drawn to its light.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0007</id>
    <name>Greater Auramancy</name>
    <text>Other enchantments you control have shroud.
Enchanted creatures you control have shroud.</text>
    <flavorText>A delicate veil of glamers can prove as sturdy as iron.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0008</id>
    <name>Inquisitor's Snare</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage target attacking or blocking creature would deal this turn. If that creature is black or red, destroy it.</text>
    <flavorText>Driven by their paranoia, kithkin inflict on their foes all the agonies they believe would have been inflicted on them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0009</id>
    <name>Kithkin Rabble</name>
    <text>Vigilance
Kithkin Rabble's power and toughness are each equal to the number of white permanents you control.</text>
    <flavorText>If even the slightest hint of panic enters the thoughtweft, bakers, potters, and even medics drop their spoons and salves to take up arms.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0010</id>
    <name>Kithkin Shielddare</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Target blocking creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The nova glyph is a potent symbol. A shield embossed with it can resist the force of even the most determined giant.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0011</id>
    <name>Last Breath</name>
    <text>Exile target creature with power 2 or less. Its controller gains 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Tsk. You'd think those nasty merrows would know how to hold their breath."
—Olka, mistmeadow witch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0012</id>
    <name>Mass Calcify</name>
    <text>Destroy all nonwhite creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>The dead serve as their own tombstones.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0013</id>
    <name>Mine Excavation</name>
    <text>Return target artifact or enchantment card from a graveyard to its owner's hand.
Conspire (As you cast this spell, you may tap two untapped creatures you control that share a color with it. When you do, copy it and you may choose a new target for the copy.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0014</id>
    <name>Mistmeadow Skulk</name>
    <text>Lifelink, protection from converted mana cost 3 or greater</text>
    <flavorText>Doyo suspected the boggarts of brewing a plot against his crop, so he scythed away his grain to clear the sightlines.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0015</id>
    <name>Niveous Wisps</name>
    <text>Target creature becomes white until end of turn. Tap that creature.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>In a world devoid of sun, illumination comes from cheerless fires or the wandering spirits of the dead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0016</id>
    <name>Order of Whiteclay</name>
    <text>{1}{W}{W}, {untap}: Return target creature card with converted mana cost 3 or less from your graveyard to the battlefield. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>Made from the clay of burial mounds, the face paint of the priests is a sign of their respect for those whose rest they interrupt.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0017</id>
    <name>Pale Wayfarer</name>
    <text>{2}{W}{W}, {untap}: Target creature gains protection from the color of its controller's choice until end of turn. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>As it wandered Shadowmoor, it did not remember its crime—only its shame.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0018</id>
    <name>Prison Term</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block and its activated abilities can't be activated.
Whenever a creature enters the battlefield under an opponent's control, you may attach Prison Term to that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Clear out the cell. Bring in the next prisoner.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0019</id>
    <name>Resplendent Mentor</name>
    <text>White creatures you control have "{T}: You gain 1 life."</text>
    <flavorText>Thoughtweft gives new meaning to the phrase "common knowledge."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0020</id>
    <name>Rune-Cervin Rider</name>
    <text>Flying
{GW}{GW}: Rune-Cervin Rider gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Things of beauty are in constant peril. The riders whisk them to safety, ahead of the encroaching darkness.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0021</id>
    <name>Runed Halo</name>
    <text>As Runed Halo enters the battlefield, name a card.
You have protection from the chosen name. (You can't be targeted, dealt damage, or enchanted by anything with that name.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0022</id>
    <name>Safehold Sentry</name>
    <text>{2}{W}, {untap}: Safehold Sentry gets +0/+2 until end of turn. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>"These bracers were worn by my father and by his mother before him. Boggart fangs have shattered on them. Cinder flames have withered at their touch. While I wear them, the safehold will not fall."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0023</id>
    <name>Spectral Procession</name>
    <text>({2W} can be paid with any two mana or with {W}. This card's converted mana cost is 6.)
Put three 1/1 white Spirit creature tokens with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"The dead have it easy. They suffer no more. If breaking their rest helps the living, so be it."
—Olka, mistmeadow witch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0024</id>
    <name>Strip Bare</name>
    <text>Destroy all Auras and Equipment attached to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"All glamers lifted, all lies revealed, all flesh exposed."
—Awylla, elvish safewright</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0025</id>
    <name>Twilight Shepherd</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance
When Twilight Shepherd enters the battlefield, return to your hand all cards in your graveyard that were put there from the battlefield this turn.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0026</id>
    <name>Windbrisk Raptor</name>
    <text>Flying
Attacking creatures you control have lifelink.</text>
    <flavorText>It awakened to gloom-fouled skies and responded with a righteous rage that shook the heavens.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0027</id>
    <name>Woeleecher</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Remove a -1/-1 counter from target creature. If you do, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>One head senses the curse. The second loosens it from the soul. The third drinks it as an invigorating mist.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0028</id>
    <name>Advice from the Fae</name>
    <text>({2U} can be paid with any two mana or with {U}. This card's converted mana cost is 6.)
Look at the top five cards of your library. If you control more creatures than each other player, put two of those cards into your hand. Otherwise, put one of them into your hand. Then put the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0029</id>
    <name>Biting Tether</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
You control enchanted creature.
At the beginning of your upkeep, put a -1/-1 counter on enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>A chain of lies as strong as steel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0030</id>
    <name>Briarberry Cohort</name>
    <text>Flying
Briarberry Cohort gets +1/+1 as long as you control another blue creature.</text>
    <flavorText>A clique can cause far more mischief than one faerie on its own.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0031</id>
    <name>Cerulean Wisps</name>
    <text>Target creature becomes blue until end of turn. Untap that creature.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you see ghostly lights by the river, eat three twigs of marshroot to ward off kelpies."
—Kithkin superstition</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0032</id>
    <name>Consign to Dream</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand. If that permanent is red or green, put it on top of its owner's library instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"Dreams are fleeting. Reality even more so."
—Oona, queen of the fae</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0033</id>
    <name>Counterbore</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. Search its controller's graveyard, hand, and library for all cards with the same name as that spell and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0034</id>
    <name>Cursecatcher</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Cursecatcher: Counter target instant or sorcery spell unless its controller pays {1}.</text>
    <flavorText>"Of all the things that can be stolen, opportunity is the most valuable."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0035</id>
    <name>Deepchannel Mentor</name>
    <text>Blue creatures you control are unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>The rivers can no longer provide safe passage for travelers and commerce. They serve only as highways for raiders and channels for blood and woe.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0036</id>
    <name>Drowner Initiate</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a blue spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, target player puts the top two cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Nothing satisfies a merrow as much as drowning what it cannot have.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0037</id>
    <name>Faerie Swarm</name>
    <text>Flying
Faerie Swarm's power and toughness are each equal to the number of blue permanents you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Untouched by the Aurora, Oona's faeries greeted the night like any other day.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0038</id>
    <name>Flow of Ideas</name>
    <text>Draw a card for each Island you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Beware the merrows, whose envy and covetousness surpasses even that of the ravenous whirlpools where they dwell."
—The Book of Other Folk</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0039</id>
    <name>Ghastly Discovery</name>
    <text>Draw two cards, then discard a card.
Conspire (As you cast this spell, you may tap two untapped creatures you control that share a color with it. When you do, copy it.)</text>
    <flavorText>Korrigans, spirits bound to sources of water, shriek when they come upon their own drowned corpses.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0040</id>
    <name>Isleback Spawn</name>
    <text>Shroud
Isleback Spawn gets +4/+8 as long as a library has twenty or fewer cards in it.</text>
    <flavorText>The more deadly the lake monster, the shorter the tale.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0041</id>
    <name>Kinscaer Harpoonist</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Kinscaer Harpoonist attacks, you may have target creature lose flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The suspicious kithkin of Kinscaer patrol the skies, their eyes attuned to the shapes of outsiders.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0042</id>
    <name>Knacksaw Clique</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{U}, {untap}: Target opponent exiles the top card of his or her library. Until end of turn, you may play that card. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>Most of the Knacksaw clique's skills were hewn from the minds of others.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0043</id>
    <name>Leech Bonder</name>
    <text>Leech Bonder enters the battlefield with two -1/-1 counters on it.
{U}, {untap}: Move a counter from target creature onto another target creature. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>Some don't know his face, but his pets are a dead giveaway.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0044</id>
    <name>Merrow Wavebreakers</name>
    <text>{1}{U}, {untap}: Merrow Wavebreakers gains flying until end of turn. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>The merrows' prey have retreated from the shore, so they have learned to follow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0045</id>
    <name>Parapet Watchers</name>
    <text>{WU}: Parapet Watchers gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A kithkin doun is not so much a town as a fortress, built to withstand the constantly besieging darkness. Only those most watchful and trustworthy are tasked with guarding its walls.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0046</id>
    <name>Prismwake Merrow</name>
    <text>Flash
When Prismwake Merrow enters the battlefield, target permanent becomes the color or colors of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Seeing is believing" is a fact the merrows ruthlessly exploit in their dealings with the other residents of Shadowmoor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0047</id>
    <name>Puca's Mischief</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may exchange control of target nonland permanent you control and target nonland permanent an opponent controls with an equal or lesser converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0048</id>
    <name>Put Away</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. You may shuffle up to one target card from your graveyard into your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Kithkin spellbottlers spend half their time preserving old memories and the other half punishing the new.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0049</id>
    <name>River Kelpie</name>
    <text>Whenever River Kelpie or another permanent is put onto the battlefield from a graveyard, draw a card.
Whenever a player casts a spell from a graveyard, draw a card.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0050</id>
    <name>Savor the Moment</name>
    <text>Take an extra turn after this one. Skip the untap step of that turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The merrow took a moment for herself. She never gave it back.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0051</id>
    <name>Sinking Feeling</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.
Enchanted creature has "{1}, Put a -1/-1 counter on this creature: Untap this creature."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0052</id>
    <name>Spell Syphon</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1} for each blue permanent you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Warrik Brutehexer felt betrayed that his aura favored the depths of the Wanderbrine River over its rightful place, hovering around him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0053</id>
    <name>Thought Reflection</name>
    <text>If you would draw a card, draw two cards instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Knowledge fills the mind of a fool and opens the mind of the sage.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0054</id>
    <name>Whimwader</name>
    <text>Whimwader can't attack unless defending player controls a blue permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"Thought? Deceit? Progress? Now you're just making it hungry."
—Abral, kithkin alchemist</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0055</id>
    <name>Aphotic Wisps</name>
    <text>Target creature becomes black and gains fear until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Merrows skulk the silty bogs around the Wanderbrine, their very thoughts stained with evil.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0056</id>
    <name>Ashenmoor Cohort</name>
    <text>Ashenmoor Cohort gets +1/+1 as long as you control another black creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"None will concede a place for us in this world. If it is not for us, neither shall it be for them. We rest not until they choke in its cold ashes."
—Illulia of Nighthearth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0057</id>
    <name>Beseech the Queen</name>
    <text>({2B} can be paid with any two mana or with {B}. This card's converted mana cost is 6.)
Search your library for a card with converted mana cost less than or equal to the number of lands you control, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Those who hear her go mad with inspiration.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0058</id>
    <name>Blowfly Infestation</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had a -1/-1 counter on it, put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>When the giant Tollek Worldslayer fell, a corruption erupted from his corpse to carry on his name.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0059</id>
    <name>Cinderbones</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
{1}{B}: Regenerate Cinderbones.</text>
    <flavorText>Not all coals lie quietly in their beds of cold ash.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0060</id>
    <name>Cinderhaze Wretch</name>
    <text>{T}: Target player discards a card. Activate this ability only during your turn.
Put a -1/-1 counter on Cinderhaze Wretch: Untap Cinderhaze Wretch.</text>
    <flavorText>Thick smoke billows and twists to form disturbing faces that cackle and click their teeth to the popping embers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0061</id>
    <name>Corrosive Mentor</name>
    <text>Black creatures you control have wither. (They deal damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>Guttering cinders stoke their dying flames by snuffing out the lights of others.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0062</id>
    <name>Corrupt</name>
    <text>Corrupt deals damage equal to the number of Swamps you control to target creature or player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt this way.</text>
    <flavorText>There are things beneath the murk for whom the bog is a stew, a thin broth in need of meat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0063</id>
    <name>Crowd of Cinders</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
Crowd of Cinders's power and toughness are each equal to the number of black permanents you control.</text>
    <flavorText>They envy the life-giving heat so much that they tear it from those who still possess it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0064</id>
    <name>Disturbing Plot</name>
    <text>Return target creature card from a graveyard to its owner's hand.
Conspire (As you cast this spell, you may tap two untapped creatures you control that share a color with it. When you do, copy it and you may choose a new target for the copy.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0065</id>
    <name>Dusk Urchins</name>
    <text>Whenever Dusk Urchins attacks or blocks, put a -1/-1 counter on it.
When Dusk Urchins is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, draw a card for each -1/-1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>They spawn from shadow, wreaking chaos until shadow claims them again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0066</id>
    <name>Faerie Macabre</name>
    <text>Flying
Discard Faerie Macabre: Exile up to two target cards from graveyards.</text>
    <flavorText>The line between dream and death is gauzy and fragile. She leads those too near it from one side to the other.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0067</id>
    <name>Gloomlance</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature. If that creature was green or white, its controller discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Death stings the victim only once, but those left behind feel the pain of loss with every passing memory.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0068</id>
    <name>Hollowborn Barghest</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you have no cards in hand, each opponent loses 2 life.
At the beginning of each opponent's upkeep, if that player has no cards in hand, he or she loses 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>It leaves a trail of crumpled trees and dashed dreams.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0069</id>
    <name>Hollowsage</name>
    <text>Whenever Hollowsage becomes untapped, you may have target player discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Dreams of dark nights to come are said to stir in the minds of scheming hollowsages.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0070</id>
    <name>Incremental Blight</name>
    <text>Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature, two -1/-1 counters on another target creature, and three -1/-1 counters on a third target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Shadowmoor's main crops are rot, slime, and despair.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0071</id>
    <name>Loch Korrigan</name>
    <text>{UB}: Loch Korrigan gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Don't look upon still waters without first breaking the surface. The korrigan will catch you with her gaze and drag you to your death."
—Kithkin superstition</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0072</id>
    <name>Midnight Banshee</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
At the beginning of your upkeep, put a -1/-1 counter on each nonblack creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Many have heard the beginning of its low, sustained shriek but few the end.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0073</id>
    <name>Plague of Vermin</name>
    <text>Starting with you, each player may pay any amount of life. Repeat this process until no one pays life. Each player puts a 1/1 black Rat creature token onto the battlefield for each 1 life he or she paid this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0074</id>
    <name>Polluted Bonds</name>
    <text>Whenever a land enters the battlefield under an opponent's control, that player loses 2 life and you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The mystic bond between spellcasters and the land is just as vulnerable to attack as the casters themselves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0075</id>
    <name>Puppeteer Clique</name>
    <text>Flying
When Puppeteer Clique enters the battlefield, put target creature card from an opponent's graveyard onto the battlefield under your control. It has haste. At the beginning of your next end step, exile it.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0076</id>
    <name>Rite of Consumption</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Rite of Consumption, sacrifice a creature.
Rite of Consumption deals damage equal to the sacrificed creature's power to target player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0077</id>
    <name>Sickle Ripper</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>His sickle was forged in the heat of another cinder's funeral pyre.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0078</id>
    <name>Smolder Initiate</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a black spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, target player loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Life is a circle. Death is a vicious circle."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0079</id>
    <name>Splitting Headache</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target player discards two cards; or target player reveals his or her hand, you choose a card from it, then that player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>All faeries delve for dreams. But not all wait for their victims to fall asleep.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0080</id>
    <name>Torture</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{1}{B}: Put a -1/-1 counter on enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>What the vigor of life builds up, agony tears down again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0081</id>
    <name>Wound Reflection</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each end step, each opponent loses life equal to the life he or she lost this turn. (Damage causes loss of life.)</text>
    <flavorText>The mission of the Nighthearth, Illulia's cult of murderous cinders, is to intensify every pain suffered in Shadowmoor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0082</id>
    <name>Blistering Dieflyn</name>
    <text>Flying
{BR}: Blistering Dieflyn gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Any kithkin smith would love to catch a dieflyn for her kiln, relieving her of ever having to gather fuel again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0083</id>
    <name>Bloodmark Mentor</name>
    <text>Red creatures you control have first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>Boggarts divide the world into two categories: things you can eat, and things you have to chase down and pummel before you can eat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0084</id>
    <name>Bloodshed Fever</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>Cinder mages enjoy seeing their victims in the throes of bloodlust—and seeing the regret that inevitably follows.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0085</id>
    <name>Boggart Arsonists</name>
    <text>Plainswalk
{2}{R}, Sacrifice Boggart Arsonists: Destroy target Scarecrow or Plains.</text>
    <flavorText>The Aurora transformed Nibb and Gyik from mischief-makers into feral marauders. They still don't know much about tool safety.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0086</id>
    <name>Burn Trail</name>
    <text>Burn Trail deals 3 damage to target creature or player.
Conspire (As you cast this spell, you may tap two untapped creatures you control that share a color with it. When you do, copy it and you may choose a new target for the copy.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0087</id>
    <name>Cragganwick Cremator</name>
    <text>When Cragganwick Cremator enters the battlefield, discard a card at random. If you discard a creature card this way, Cragganwick Cremator deals damage equal to that card's power to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Each night that his bowl fills, a village mourns.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0088</id>
    <name>Crimson Wisps</name>
    <text>Target creature becomes red and gains haste until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The whispers are incomprehensible, yet cinders always hear a message of urgency.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0089</id>
    <name>Deep-Slumber Titan</name>
    <text>Deep-Slumber Titan enters the battlefield tapped.
Deep-Slumber Titan doesn't untap during your untap step.
Whenever Deep-Slumber Titan is dealt damage, untap it.</text>
    <flavorText>Do not disturb.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0090</id>
    <name>Elemental Mastery</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has "{T}: Put X 1/1 red Elemental creature tokens with haste onto the battlefield, where X is this creature's power. Exile them at the beginning of the next end step."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0091</id>
    <name>Ember Gale</name>
    <text>Creatures target player controls can't block this turn. Ember Gale deals 1 damage to each white and/or blue creature that player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"Terrible wind. It whipped sparks into our skin, then stoked them even hotter"
—Bowen, Barrenton guardcaptain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0092</id>
    <name>Flame Javelin</name>
    <text>({2R} can be paid with any two mana or with {R}. This card's converted mana cost is 6.)
Flame Javelin deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Gyara Spearhurler would have been renowned for her deadly accuracy, if it weren't for her deadly accuracy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0093</id>
    <name>Furystoke Giant</name>
    <text>When Furystoke Giant enters the battlefield, other creatures you control gain "{T}: This creature deals 2 damage to target creature or player" until end of turn.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0094</id>
    <name>Horde of Boggarts</name>
    <text>Horde of Boggarts's power and toughness are each equal to the number of red permanents you control.
Horde of Boggarts can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Strategies don't come easily to the boggarts' feral minds, but full-on assault hasn't failed them yet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0095</id>
    <name>Inescapable Brute</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Inescapable Brute must be blocked if able.</text>
    <flavorText>If you think you made it past him alive, he's just teasing you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0096</id>
    <name>Intimidator Initiate</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a red spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, target creature can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Don't stand in his way, for his way is full of pointy things and fire.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0097</id>
    <name>Jaws of Stone</name>
    <text>Jaws of Stone deals X damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players, where X is the number of Mountains you control as you cast Jaws of Stone.</text>
    <flavorText>When giants find their mountain homes infested, they have a whole range of solutions.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0098</id>
    <name>Knollspine Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
When Knollspine Dragon enters the battlefield, you may discard your hand and draw cards equal to the damage dealt to target opponent this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It woke to find a vast world in need of a master.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0099</id>
    <name>Knollspine Invocation</name>
    <text>{X}, Discard a card with converted mana cost X: Knollspine Invocation deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Witches tempted by the power of flame gathered to study in the ruins of Spinerock Knoll.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0100</id>
    <name>Mudbrawler Cohort</name>
    <text>Haste
Mudbrawler Cohort gets +1/+1 as long as you control another red creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Before a raid, the members of Wort's gang egg each other on with tales of their hunger and what they'll do to sate it, each outdoing the last.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0101</id>
    <name>Power of Fire</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has "{T}: This creature deals 1 damage to target creature or player."</text>
    <flavorText>The cinders believe their flame was stolen by one they call the Extinguisher. All who now wield fire draw their desperate wrath.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0102</id>
    <name>Puncture Bolt</name>
    <text>Puncture Bolt deals 1 damage to target creature. Put a -1/-1 counter on that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Cinder pyromancers measure their success by counting their enemies' smoking holes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0103</id>
    <name>Pyre Charger</name>
    <text>Haste
{R}: Pyre Charger gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>His blade was forged over coals of moaning treefolk, curved at the optimum angle for severing heads, and heated to volcanic temperatures by his touch.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0104</id>
    <name>Rage Reflection</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have double strike.</text>
    <flavorText>Vengeance is a dish best served twice.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0105</id>
    <name>Rustrazor Butcher</name>
    <text>First strike
Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>A Bloodwort's blade is salted with blood and peppered with rust, seasoning and slaughtering in a single swipe.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0106</id>
    <name>Slinking Giant</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Whenever Slinking Giant blocks or becomes blocked, it gets -3/-0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"I need a better hiding place."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0107</id>
    <name>Smash to Smithereens</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact. Smash to Smithereens deals 3 damage to that artifact's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>The giant Tarvik dreamed that trinkets and machines caused all the world's woe. When he awoke from his troubled sleep, he took the name Tarvik Relicsmasher.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0108</id>
    <name>Wild Swing</name>
    <text>Choose three target nonenchantment permanents. Destroy one of them at random.</text>
    <flavorText>Though the shaman rarely got what she wanted, she was never disappointed in the result.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0109</id>
    <name>Crabapple Cohort</name>
    <text>Crabapple Cohort gets +1/+1 as long as you control another green creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Seven wives made seven pies from seven apples, each plucked from its branches. Now bare and bitter, it comes to exact its price: one apple, one bone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0110</id>
    <name>Devoted Druid</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
Put a -1/-1 counter on Devoted Druid: Untap Devoted Druid.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mana lurks in all things, even in the depths of one's own heart."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0111</id>
    <name>Dramatic Entrance</name>
    <text>You may put a green creature card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Some things aren't worth waiting for.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0112</id>
    <name>Drove of Elves</name>
    <text>Drove of Elves's power and toughness are each equal to the number of green permanents you control.
Drove of Elves can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.</text>
    <flavorText>"The light of beauty protects our journeys through darkness."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0113</id>
    <name>Farhaven Elf</name>
    <text>When Farhaven Elf enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a basic land card and put it onto the battlefield tapped. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Verdant bloom does exist. It merely hides for its own safety."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0114</id>
    <name>Flourishing Defenses</name>
    <text>Whenever a -1/-1 counter is placed on a creature, you may put a 1/1 green Elf Warrior creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Many horrors take the bait of brave elf volunteers walking alone, only to fall to the blades of rescuers lurking nearby.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0115</id>
    <name>Foxfire Oak</name>
    <text>{RG}{RG}{RG}: Foxfire Oak gets +3/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The brethren shall blaze with unnatural fire, and the flame shall consume and purify our rage."
—Treefolk catastrophe myth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0116</id>
    <name>Gleeful Sabotage</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.
Conspire (As you cast this spell, you may tap two untapped creatures you control that share a color with it. When you do, copy it and you may choose a new target for the copy.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0117</id>
    <name>Gloomwidow</name>
    <text>Reach
Gloomwidow can't block creatures without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>When gloomwidows mature, they abandon venom in favor of massive webs that span the eaves of cliffs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0118</id>
    <name>Gloomwidow's Feast</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature with flying. If that creature was blue or black, put a 1/2 green Spider creature token with reach onto the battlefield. (It can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>Each night, gloomwidows cull fresh prey for their ravenous hatchlings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0119</id>
    <name>Howl of the Night Pack</name>
    <text>Put a 2/2 green Wolf creature token onto the battlefield for each Forest you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The murderous horrors of Raven's Run are legendary, but even that haunted place goes quiet when the night wolves howl.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0120</id>
    <name>Hungry Spriggan</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Hungry Spriggan attacks, it gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>If a spriggan's eyes are larger than its stomach, it has ways to remedy the situation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0121</id>
    <name>Juvenile Gloomwidow</name>
    <text>Reach (This can block creatures with flying.)
Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>Gloomwidow venom is particularly virulent during the spider's first years, when it does most of its hunting near the forest floor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0122</id>
    <name>Mana Reflection</name>
    <text>If you tap a permanent for mana, it produces twice as much of that mana instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Despite its darkness, Shadowmoor doesn't want for growth. Legions of creeping things thrive in the shade.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0123</id>
    <name>Mossbridge Troll</name>
    <text>If Mossbridge Troll would be destroyed, regenerate it.
Tap any number of untapped creatures you control other than Mossbridge Troll with total power 10 or greater: Mossbridge Troll gets +20/+20 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0124</id>
    <name>Nurturer Initiate</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a green spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The elves alone preserve the few shreds of beauty left. There is no one else who cares.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0125</id>
    <name>Presence of Gond</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has "{T}: Put a 1/1 green Elf Warrior creature token onto the battlefield."</text>
    <flavorText>"Here lies Gond, hero of Safehold Taldwen. May he ever guide our quest."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0126</id>
    <name>Prismatic Omen</name>
    <text>Lands you control are every basic land type in addition to their other types.</text>
    <flavorText>In times of portent, the land sculpts itself in accordance with the sigils burned on the sky.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0127</id>
    <name>Raking Canopy</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature with flying attacks you, Raking Canopy deals 4 damage to it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Raven's Run has awoken, and ravens will no longer cry in its branches."
—Roon Ghastbark</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0128</id>
    <name>Roughshod Mentor</name>
    <text>Green creatures you control have trample.</text>
    <flavorText>He didn't hear the cries of the treefolk whose branches he snapped or of the elves caught underfoot. He had eyes only for the path ahead.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0129</id>
    <name>Spawnwrithe</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Spawnwrithe deals combat damage to a player, put a token that's a copy of Spawnwrithe onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Its victims feel only an itchy, wriggling feeling just under their skin. By then, it's far too late.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0130</id>
    <name>Toil to Renown</name>
    <text>You gain 1 life for each tapped artifact, creature, and land you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The last survivor of her patrol, the warrior returned expecting disappointment and scorn. Instead she found gratitude. "You are alive. That is reason to celebrate."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0131</id>
    <name>Tower Above</name>
    <text>({2G} can be paid with any two mana or with {G}. This card's converted mana cost is 6.)
Until end of turn, target creature gets +4/+4 and gains trample, wither, and "When this creature attacks, target creature blocks it this turn if able." (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0132</id>
    <name>Viridescent Wisps</name>
    <text>Target creature becomes green and gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>In the wisps that night, the once timid boggart saw all the terrible, bloody things he was capable of. And it was glorious.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0133</id>
    <name>Wildslayer Elves</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>Some elves battled too long in the deep shadow, their swords dipped too often in tainted flesh and poisoned blood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0134</id>
    <name>Witherscale Wurm</name>
    <text>Whenever Witherscale Wurm blocks or becomes blocked by a creature, that creature gains wither until end of turn. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Whenever Witherscale Wurm deals damage to an opponent, remove all -1/-1 counters from it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0135</id>
    <name>Woodfall Primus</name>
    <text>Trample
When Woodfall Primus enters the battlefield, destroy target noncreature permanent.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0136</id>
    <name>Æthertow</name>
    <text>Put target attacking or blocking creature on top of its owner's library.
Conspire (As you cast this spell, you may tap two untapped creatures you control that share a color with it. When you do, copy it and you may choose a new target for the copy.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0137</id>
    <name>Augury Adept</name>
    <text>Whenever Augury Adept deals combat damage to a player, reveal the top card of your library and put that card into your hand. You gain life equal to its converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>Moonstones grant limited foresight but unlimited advantages.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0138</id>
    <name>Barrenton Cragtreads</name>
    <text>Barrenton Cragtreads can't be blocked by red creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"Boggarts are easy to get around. Just toss some mutton in another direction. Giants are a little harder. You have to be quick to avoid their steps. Cinders are the difficult ones, but even they have fears to be exploited."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0139</id>
    <name>Curse of Chains</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of each upkeep, tap enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The giant's real punishment was the fleeting moment when he was allowed to stand before being dragged down to his knees again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0140</id>
    <name>Enchanted Evening</name>
    <text>All permanents are enchantments in addition to their other types.</text>
    <flavorText>In the reflection, she saw the rough shell of the world sloughing away, revealing the truth shining underneath.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0141</id>
    <name>Glamer Spinners</name>
    <text>Flash
Flying
When Glamer Spinners enters the battlefield, attach all Auras enchanting target permanent to another permanent with the same controller.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0142</id>
    <name>Godhead of Awe</name>
    <text>Flying
Other creatures are 1/1.</text>
    <flavorText>"What she saw crawling upon this world repulsed her. Yet she could not tear her gaze away."
—The Seer's Parables</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0143</id>
    <name>Mirrorweave</name>
    <text>Each other creature becomes a copy of target nonlegendary creature until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Those who are different are untrustworthy, unpredictable. Put your safety in the hands of your own kind."
—Bowen, Barrenton guardcaptain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0144</id>
    <name>Mistmeadow Witch</name>
    <text>{2}{W}{U}: Exile target creature. Return that card to the battlefield under its owner's control at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>Olka collected the evening mist for years, studying its secrets. Once she learned its essence, she could vanish with a thought.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0145</id>
    <name>Plumeveil</name>
    <text>Flash
Defender, flying</text>
    <flavorText>"It was vast, a great sheet of soaring wings, and equally silent. It caught us unawares and blocked our view of the kithkin stronghold."
—Grensch, merrow cutthroat</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0146</id>
    <name>Puresight Merrow</name>
    <text>{WU}, {untap}: Look at the top card of your library. You may exile that card. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>Stripped of his sight, he was free to see only the ideal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0147</id>
    <name>Repel Intruders</name>
    <text>Put two 1/1 white Kithkin Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield if {W} was spent to cast Repel Intruders. Counter up to one target creature spell if {U} was spent to cast Repel Intruders. (Do both if {W}{U} was spent.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0148</id>
    <name>Silkbind Faerie</name>
    <text>Flying
{1}{WU}, {untap}: Tap target creature. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The bigger they are, the more fun it is to watch them fall flat on their faces."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0149</id>
    <name>Somnomancer</name>
    <text>When Somnomancer enters the battlefield, you may tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Are you tired? You look tired."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0150</id>
    <name>Steel of the Godhead</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As long as enchanted creature is white, it gets +1/+1 and has lifelink. (Damage dealt by the creature also causes its controller to gain that much life.)
As long as enchanted creature is blue, it gets +1/+1 and is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0151</id>
    <name>Swans of Bryn Argoll</name>
    <text>Flying
If a source would deal damage to Swans of Bryn Argoll, prevent that damage. The source's controller draws cards equal to the damage prevented this way.</text>
    <flavorText>Any being that harms them quickly learns its lesson.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0152</id>
    <name>Thistledown Duo</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a white spell, Thistledown Duo gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
Whenever you cast a blue spell, Thistledown Duo gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0153</id>
    <name>Thistledown Liege</name>
    <text>Flash
Other white creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other blue creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>The thoughtweft is his informant, and he its devoted guardian.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0154</id>
    <name>Thoughtweft Gambit</name>
    <text>Tap all creatures your opponents control and untap all creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The kithkin mind-bond is even tighter in Shadowmoor, reinforcing the unity of their community to the point of xenophobia.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0155</id>
    <name>Turn to Mist</name>
    <text>Exile target creature. Return that card to the battlefield under its owner's control at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>"Did you expect me to dodge? How quaint."
—Olka, mistmeadow witch</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0156</id>
    <name>Worldpurge</name>
    <text>Return all permanents to their owners' hands. Each player chooses up to seven cards in his or her hand, then shuffles the rest into his or her library. Empty all mana pools.</text>
    <flavorText>The Aurora is not the only magic capable of remaking a world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0157</id>
    <name>Zealous Guardian</name>
    <text>Flash</text>
    <flavorText>Parapet watchers patrol the outer edges of the doun, signaling to others who wait patiently in shadow.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0158</id>
    <name>Cemetery Puca</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may pay {1}. If you do, Cemetery Puca becomes a copy of that creature and gains this ability.</text>
    <flavorText>"'Tis a strange creature indeed that chooses the vanquished over the victor."
—Awylla, elvish safewright</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0159</id>
    <name>Dire Undercurrents</name>
    <text>Whenever a blue creature enters the battlefield under your control, you may have target player draw a card.
Whenever a black creature enters the battlefield under your control, you may have target player discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0160</id>
    <name>Dream Salvage</name>
    <text>Draw cards equal to the number of cards target opponent discarded this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Awylla tried hard to forget the horrors she had seen, but someone else had developed a keen interest in them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0161</id>
    <name>Fate Transfer</name>
    <text>Move all counters from target creature onto another target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The cinders find strength in suffering, the elves in beauty. But if you make an elf suffer, he gets weaker. I wonder what happens if you make a cinder beautiful?"
—Hrugash, leech bonder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0162</id>
    <name>Ghastlord of Fugue</name>
    <text>Ghastlord of Fugue is unblockable.
Whenever Ghastlord of Fugue deals combat damage to a player, that player reveals his or her hand. You choose a card from it. That player exiles that card.</text>
    <flavorText>"He is a ghost that has never known life."
—The Seer's Parables</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0163</id>
    <name>Glen Elendra Liege</name>
    <text>Flying
Other blue creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other black creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>Those who displease Oona soon learn the extent of the armies she commands.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0164</id>
    <name>Gravelgill Axeshark</name>
    <text>Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Their sharp scales would make good armor, if they'd just stay dead."
—Taeryn, cinder armorkeep</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0165</id>
    <name>Gravelgill Duo</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a blue spell, Gravelgill Duo gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
Whenever you cast a black spell, Gravelgill Duo gains fear until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0166</id>
    <name>Helm of the Ghastlord</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As long as enchanted creature is blue, it gets +1/+1 and has "Whenever this creature deals damage to an opponent, draw a card."
As long as enchanted creature is black, it gets +1/+1 and has "Whenever this creature deals damage to an opponent, that player discards a card."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0167</id>
    <name>Inkfathom Infiltrator</name>
    <text>Inkfathom Infiltrator can't block and is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>No one can navigate the dank maze of Shadowmoor's rivers better than the cruel and covetous merrows. They use the currents to steal—and to steal away.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0168</id>
    <name>Inkfathom Witch</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
{2}{U}{B}: Each unblocked creature becomes 4/1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The murk of the Wanderbrine concealed unseemly rituals designed to bring out the worst in merrowkind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0169</id>
    <name>Memory Plunder</name>
    <text>You may cast target instant or sorcery card from an opponent's graveyard without paying its mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>"Vengeance is the echo of the victim's own crime."
—Grensch, merrow cutthroat</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0170</id>
    <name>Memory Sluice</name>
    <text>Target player puts the top four cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.
Conspire (As you cast this spell, you may tap two untapped creatures you control that share a color with it. When you do, copy it and you may choose a new target for the copy.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0171</id>
    <name>Merrow Grimeblotter</name>
    <text>{1}{UB}, {untap}: Target creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>Grimeblotters spend so much time in the Dark Meanders that they're able to bring a piece with them wherever they go.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0172</id>
    <name>Oona, Queen of the Fae</name>
    <text>Flying
{X}{UB}: Choose a color. Target opponent exiles the top X cards of his or her library. For each card of the chosen color exiled this way, put a 1/1 blue and black Faerie Rogue creature token with flying onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0173</id>
    <name>Oona's Gatewarden</name>
    <text>Defender, flying
Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>"So now you've seen Glen Elendra. Take a good look. It will be the last thing you'll ever see."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0174</id>
    <name>River's Grasp</name>
    <text>If {U} was spent to cast River's Grasp, return up to one target creature to its owner's hand. If {B} was spent to cast River's Grasp, target player reveals his or her hand, you choose a nonland card from it, then that player discards that card. (Do both if {U}{B} was spent.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0175</id>
    <name>Scarscale Ritual</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Scarscale Ritual, put a -1/-1 counter on a creature you control.
Draw two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Some words are too important to trust to something as fragile as memory.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0176</id>
    <name>Sygg, River Cutthroat</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each end step, if an opponent lost 3 or more life this turn, you may draw a card. (Damage causes loss of life.)</text>
    <flavorText>"It's not a matter of deserving. It's a matter of strength. The power to hold versus the power to take."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0177</id>
    <name>Torpor Dust</name>
    <text>Flash
Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets -3/-0.</text>
    <flavorText>"Some folk these days are too restless to dream the dreams we need. We need to teach them to stop and catch their breath."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0178</id>
    <name>Wanderbrine Rootcutters</name>
    <text>Wanderbrine Rootcutters can't be blocked by green creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Most dirtwalkers only know of the vicious merrows that dwell in the shallows. They can't begin to fathom the wickedness that skulks in the Dark Meanders.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0179</id>
    <name>Wasp Lancer</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>"I doubt that faeries understand how short their lives are, compared to the rest of us. If they did, would they so readily charge into battle, heedless of the danger before them?"
—Awylla, elvish safewright</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0180</id>
    <name>Ashenmoor Gouger</name>
    <text>Ashenmoor Gouger can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>After his hands had crumbled away, leaving only wickedly sharp points, he decided his only purpose was war.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0181</id>
    <name>Ashenmoor Liege</name>
    <text>Other black creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other red creatures you control get +1/+1.
Whenever Ashenmoor Liege becomes the target of a spell or ability an opponent controls, that player loses 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Cinders carry an ancestral grudge that makes them slow to trust and quick to retaliate.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0182</id>
    <name>Cultbrand Cinder</name>
    <text>When Cultbrand Cinder enters the battlefield, put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your seared flesh will be the first step in your journey to dark enlightenment."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0183</id>
    <name>Demigod of Revenge</name>
    <text>Flying, haste
When you cast Demigod of Revenge, return all cards named Demigod of Revenge from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"His laugh, a bellowing, deathly din, slices through the heavens, making them bleed."
—The Seer's Parables</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0184</id>
    <name>Din of the Fireherd</name>
    <text>Put a 5/5 black and red Elemental creature token onto the battlefield. Target opponent sacrifices a creature for each black creature you control, then sacrifices a land for each red creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Vengeance in stampede form.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0185</id>
    <name>Emberstrike Duo</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a black spell, Emberstrike Duo gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
Whenever you cast a red spell, Emberstrike Duo gains first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0186</id>
    <name>Everlasting Torment</name>
    <text>Players can't gain life.
Damage can't be prevented.
All damage is dealt as though its source had wither. (A source with wither deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>When night fell, the plane itself was scarred.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0187</id>
    <name>Fists of the Demigod</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As long as enchanted creature is black, it gets +1/+1 and has wither. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
As long as enchanted creature is red, it gets +1/+1 and has first strike.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0188</id>
    <name>Fulminator Mage</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Fulminator Mage: Destroy target nonbasic land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Unsafe Terrain Ahead—Turn Back"
—Sign near the former location of Pyrtagh Cairn</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0189</id>
    <name>Grief Tyrant</name>
    <text>Grief Tyrant enters the battlefield with four -1/-1 counters on it.
When Grief Tyrant is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a -1/-1 counter on target creature for each -1/-1 counter on Grief Tyrant.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0190</id>
    <name>Kulrath Knight</name>
    <text>Flying
Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Creatures your opponents control with counters on them can't attack or block.</text>
    <flavorText>Mounted cinders circle the blasted peak at Kulrath, hunting the Extinguisher.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0191</id>
    <name>Manaforge Cinder</name>
    <text>{1}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool. Activate this ability no more than three times each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Cinder mystics set traps for sluaghs and other spirits of flame, seeking to extract the secrets of the fire their own hearts have lost.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0192</id>
    <name>Murderous Redcap</name>
    <text>When Murderous Redcap enters the battlefield, it deals damage equal to its power to target creature or player.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0193</id>
    <name>Poison the Well</name>
    <text>Destroy target land. Poison the Well deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>Wells that provide clean, unhaunted water are rare enough to be worth building an entire town around.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0194</id>
    <name>Scar</name>
    <text>Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"What is a scar? A sign of courage in the face of danger? A mere trick of flesh? Or a constant reminder of agonizing pain, and the follies of war."
—Illulia of Nighthearth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0195</id>
    <name>Sootstoke Kindler</name>
    <text>Haste
{T}: Target black or red creature gains haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Nothing warms my heart better than a spirit kindled with rage."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0196</id>
    <name>Sootwalkers</name>
    <text>Sootwalkers can't be blocked by white creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"Why allow the fires of others to burn, when ours do not? Why leave them content, while we suffer? If there is to be misery, let it be borne by all."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0197</id>
    <name>Spiteflame Witch</name>
    <text>{B}{R}: Each player loses 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Cinder beliefs revolve around the Path of Sorrow, a spiritual descent into oblivion. They don't mind taking others on their journey down.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0198</id>
    <name>Spiteful Visions</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's draw step, that player draws an additional card.
Whenever a player draws a card, Spiteful Visions deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>Knowledge brings the sting of disillusionment, but the pain teaches perspective.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0199</id>
    <name>Torrent of Souls</name>
    <text>Return up to one target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield if {B} was spent to cast Torrent of Souls. Creatures target player controls get +2/+0 and gain haste until end of turn if {R} was spent to cast Torrent of Souls. (Do both if {B}{R} was spent.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0200</id>
    <name>Traitor's Roar</name>
    <text>Tap target untapped creature. It deals damage equal to its power to its controller.
Conspire (As you cast this spell, you may tap two untapped creatures you control that share a color with it. When you do, copy it and you may choose a new target for the copy.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0201</id>
    <name>Tyrannize</name>
    <text>Target player discards his or her hand unless he or she pays 7 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"I can stab you where it hurts, or where you will feel absolutely nothing."
—Illulia of Nighthearth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0202</id>
    <name>Boartusk Liege</name>
    <text>Trample
Other red creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other green creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>The boar leads its rider to victory in battle, but it doesn't know how close it is to becoming the victory feast.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0203</id>
    <name>Boggart Ram-Gang</name>
    <text>Haste
Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>"We're going to need a bigger gate."
—Bowen, Barrenton guardcaptain</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0204</id>
    <name>Deus of Calamity</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Deus of Calamity deals 6 or more damage to an opponent, destroy target land that player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"He bears the marks of ages upon his skin, memories of dreams long dead and best left buried."
—The Seer's Parables</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0205</id>
    <name>Firespout</name>
    <text>Firespout deals 3 damage to each creature without flying if {R} was spent to cast Firespout and 3 damage to each creature with flying if {G} was spent to cast it. (Do both if {R}{G} was spent.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0206</id>
    <name>Fossil Find</name>
    <text>Return a card at random from your graveyard to your hand, then reorder your graveyard as you choose.</text>
    <flavorText>"Some secrets want to be revealed. They burst through the soil of their own accord."
—Dindun of Kulrath Mine</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0207</id>
    <name>Giantbaiting</name>
    <text>Put a 4/4 red and green Giant Warrior creature token with haste onto the battlefield. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step.
Conspire (As you cast this spell, you may tap two untapped creatures you control that share a color with it. When you do, copy it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0208</id>
    <name>Guttural Response</name>
    <text>Counter target blue instant spell.</text>
    <flavorText>Wort had a raiding-bellow that could shatter steel, melt auras, and slice countermagic in half.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0209</id>
    <name>Impromptu Raid</name>
    <text>{2}{RG}: Reveal the top card of your library. If it isn't a creature card, put it into your graveyard. Otherwise, put that card onto the battlefield. That creature has haste. Sacrifice it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>For the Scuzzback gang, it's always "raid o'clock."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0210</id>
    <name>Loamdragger Giant</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>Giants sleep soundly and long, sometimes for long enough that a crust of earth and moss grows over them. But inevitably something disturbs their slumber, and they wake unhappy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0211</id>
    <name>Manamorphose</name>
    <text>Add two mana in any combination of colors to your mana pool.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>For a moment, objects of pure mana glimmered in the wonderstruck boggart's hands. In the next moment, they were in his mouth, as he chewed contentedly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0212</id>
    <name>Morselhoarder</name>
    <text>Morselhoarder enters the battlefield with two -1/-1 counters on it.
Remove a -1/-1 counter from Morselhoarder: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>It scours the hills for living matter, savoring even the tang of poisonous fungi.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0213</id>
    <name>Mudbrawler Raiders</name>
    <text>Mudbrawler Raiders can't be blocked by blue creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>To reach the ravine of the Wanderbrine River, they were told to take the shortcut "through the mountains." They took the directions literally.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0214</id>
    <name>Rosheen Meanderer</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {4} to your mana pool. Spend this mana only on costs that contain {X}.</text>
    <flavorText>Night after night, Rosheen babbled about a bygone sunlit world, her every word dismissed as a madwoman's ravings.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0215</id>
    <name>Runes of the Deus</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As long as enchanted creature is red, it gets +1/+1 and has double strike. (It deals both first-strike and regular combat damage.)
As long as enchanted creature is green, it gets +1/+1 and has trample.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0216</id>
    <name>Scuzzback Marauders</name>
    <text>Trample
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0217</id>
    <name>Scuzzback Scrapper</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>The Scuzzback gang scavenges rusty armor covered in barbed protrusions. No threat is more effective than the threat of infection.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0218</id>
    <name>Tattermunge Duo</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a red spell, Tattermunge Duo gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
Whenever you cast a green spell, Tattermunge Duo gains forestwalk until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0219</id>
    <name>Tattermunge Maniac</name>
    <text>Tattermunge Maniac attacks each turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>It shows up at one meal wearing the carcass of the last.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0220</id>
    <name>Tattermunge Witch</name>
    <text>{R}{G}: Each blocked creature gets +1/+0 and gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The Tattermunge gang has no words for the spell that whips their instinctual rage into a frenzy. They only know they like it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0221</id>
    <name>Valleymaker</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a Mountain: Valleymaker deals 3 damage to target creature.
{T}, Sacrifice a Forest: Choose a player. That player adds {G}{G}{G} to his or her mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Their home uprooted by a giant, the gang of boggarts mourned their old stomping ground.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0222</id>
    <name>Vexing Shusher</name>
    <text>Vexing Shusher can't be countered.
{RG}: Target spell can't be countered by spells or abilities.</text>
    <flavorText>The stench of bloodcap mushrooms on the breath is enough to ward off even the most potent magics, especially when combined with a special chant: "Hushhh."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0223</id>
    <name>Wort, the Raidmother</name>
    <text>When Wort, the Raidmother enters the battlefield, put two 1/1 red and green Goblin Warrior creature tokens onto the battlefield.
Each red or green instant or sorcery spell you cast has conspire. (As you cast the spell, you may tap two untapped creatures you control that share a color with it. When you do, copy it and you may choose new targets for the copy.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0224</id>
    <name>Barkshell Blessing</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.
Conspire (As you cast this spell, you may tap two untapped creatures you control that share a color with it. When you do, copy it and you may choose a new target for the copy.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0225</id>
    <name>Dawnglow Infusion</name>
    <text>You gain X life if {G} was spent to cast Dawnglow Infusion and X life if {W} was spent to cast it. (Do both if {G}{W} was spent.)</text>
    <flavorText>Dawnglove bloom is a potent nostrum, but the dawnglow brewed from its sap is nothing less than life itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0226</id>
    <name>Elvish Hexhunter</name>
    <text>{GW}, {T}, Sacrifice Elvish Hexhunter: Destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"All manner of curses, blights, and luckspoils infect Shadowmoor. We stalk them, one perilous quest at a time."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0227</id>
    <name>Fracturing Gust</name>
    <text>Destroy all artifacts and enchantments. You gain 2 life for each permanent destroyed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>Elvish dawnhands test a relic's worthiness before collecting it for the safehold. If it can't stand up to a stiff breeze, it's left behind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0228</id>
    <name>Heartmender</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a -1/-1 counter from each creature you control.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0229</id>
    <name>Kitchen Finks</name>
    <text>When Kitchen Finks enters the battlefield, you gain 2 life.
Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>Accept one favor from an ouphe, and you're doomed to accept another.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0230</id>
    <name>Medicine Runner</name>
    <text>When Medicine Runner enters the battlefield, you may remove a counter from target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>Elvish healers carry vials of the balm known as dawnglow, reserving it for those wounds that herbs cannot treat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0231</id>
    <name>Mercy Killing</name>
    <text>Target creature's controller sacrifices it, then puts X 1/1 green and white Elf Warrior creature tokens onto the battlefield, where X is that creature's power.</text>
    <flavorText>"We will give you the peace you seek, though you may not yet know you seek it."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0232</id>
    <name>Old Ghastbark</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"Beware of trees that talk. Their words are threats. And mind the ones that sway and creak. They too threaten us, but in a foreign tongue."
—The Book of Other Folk</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0233</id>
    <name>Oracle of Nectars</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: You gain X life.</text>
    <flavorText>When elves find a fount of beauty, they protect it. Where there is beauty, there is hope.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0234</id>
    <name>Oversoul of Dusk</name>
    <text>Protection from blue, from black, and from red</text>
    <flavorText>"Some say she hid the sun herself, a desperate act to save it from its ultimate extinction."
—The Seer's Parables</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0235</id>
    <name>Raven's Run Dragoon</name>
    <text>Raven's Run Dragoon can't be blocked by black creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"I have a gift. The ability to sense encroaching darkness has saved many lives. And yet constantly feeling the force of so much ugliness is a terrible burden."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0236</id>
    <name>Reknit</name>
    <text>Regenerate target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"An axe may break upon a ribbon if the ribbon's will is the stronger."
—Awylla, elvish safewright</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0237</id>
    <name>Rhys the Redeemed</name>
    <text>{2}{GW}, {T}: Put a 1/1 green and white Elf Warrior creature token onto the battlefield.
{4}(g/w){GW}, {T}: For each creature token you control, put a token that's a copy of that creature onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Whole again in honor and horn.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0238</id>
    <name>Safehold Duo</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a green spell, Safehold Duo gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
Whenever you cast a white spell, Safehold Duo gains vigilance until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0239</id>
    <name>Safehold Elite</name>
    <text>Persist (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>"I refuse to die—not at the hands of one such as you."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0240</id>
    <name>Safewright Quest</name>
    <text>Search your library for a Forest or Plains card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>Elves search for sources of beauty in a nighted world. Meanwhile, the nighted world searches for the blood of elves.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0241</id>
    <name>Seedcradle Witch</name>
    <text>{2}{G}{W}: Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn. Untap that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>She whispered a prayer for strength, and her wishes wafted away like seeds on the wind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0242</id>
    <name>Shield of the Oversoul</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
As long as enchanted creature is green, it gets +1/+1 and is indestructible. (Lethal damage and effects that say "destroy" don't destroy it. If its toughness is 0 or less, it's still put into its owner's graveyard.)
As long as enchanted creature is white, it gets +1/+1 and has flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0243</id>
    <name>Wheel of Sun and Moon</name>
    <text>Enchant player
If a card would be put into enchanted player's graveyard from anywhere, instead that card is revealed and put on the bottom of that player's library.</text>
    <flavorText>Every life ends, but life itself never does.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0244</id>
    <name>Wilt-Leaf Cavaliers</name>
    <text>Vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>Every elf in Shadowmoor is charged from birth with a terrible duty: to strike back against the ugliness and darkness, even though they are all around and seemingly without end.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0245</id>
    <name>Wilt-Leaf Liege</name>
    <text>Other green creatures you control get +1/+1.
Other white creatures you control get +1/+1.
If a spell or ability an opponent controls causes you to discard Wilt-Leaf Liege, put it onto the battlefield instead of putting it into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0246</id>
    <name>Blazethorn Scarecrow</name>
    <text>Blazethorn Scarecrow has haste as long as you control a red creature.
Blazethorn Scarecrow has wither as long as you control a green creature. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0247</id>
    <name>Blight Sickle</name>
    <text>Equipped creature gets +1/+0 and has wither. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Equip {2}</text>
    <flavorText>Its scars cut deeper than its blade.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0248</id>
    <name>Cauldron of Souls</name>
    <text>{T}: Choose any number of target creatures. Each of those creatures gains persist until end of turn. (When it's put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0249</id>
    <name>Chainbreaker</name>
    <text>Chainbreaker enters the battlefield with two -1/-1 counters on it.
{3}, {T}: Remove a -1/-1 counter from target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Scarecrows deemed too malevolent to roam free are shackled to boulders or dolmen stones. Their animosity usually outlives the chains.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0250</id>
    <name>Elsewhere Flask</name>
    <text>When Elsewhere Flask enters the battlefield, draw a card.
Sacrifice Elsewhere Flask: Choose a basic land type. Each land you control becomes that type until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>One night Oona bottled the sky. The next night she aligned the stars and released it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0251</id>
    <name>Gnarled Effigy</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}: Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Bits of fallen scarecrow, laces of elfskin leather, teeth of an axeshark merrow . . . An industrious soul can find new uses for the most mundane items."
—Mowagh the Gwyllion</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0252</id>
    <name>Grim Poppet</name>
    <text>Grim Poppet enters the battlefield with three -1/-1 counters on it.
Remove a -1/-1 counter from Grim Poppet: Put a -1/-1 counter on another target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Beware a scarecrow bearing gifts—especially sloshing vessels of acid.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0253</id>
    <name>Heap Doll</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Heap Doll: Exile target card from a graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"I know one night it won't come back. Then I'll know it's truly done its job."
—Braenna, cobblesmith</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0254</id>
    <name>Illuminated Folio</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Reveal two cards from your hand that share a color: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Most such relics remain clasped shut for fear of what ominous truths might be carved into the diptych inside.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0255</id>
    <name>Lockjaw Snapper</name>
    <text>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
When Lockjaw Snapper is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a -1/-1 counter on each creature with a -1/-1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0256</id>
    <name>Lurebound Scarecrow</name>
    <text>As Lurebound Scarecrow enters the battlefield, choose a color.
When you control no permanents of the chosen color, sacrifice Lurebound Scarecrow.</text>
    <flavorText>It's a fool's race to run if all is lost if it be won.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0257</id>
    <name>Painter's Servant</name>
    <text>As Painter's Servant enters the battlefield, choose a color.
All cards that aren't on the battlefield, spells, and permanents are the chosen color in addition to their other colors.</text>
    <flavorText>It gathers hues from the twilight mist so that its master can paint a better world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0258</id>
    <name>Pili-Pala</name>
    <text>Flying
{2}, {untap}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. ({untap} is the untap symbol.)</text>
    <flavorText>It wasn't really expected to fly. Then again, it wasn't expected to move, either.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0259</id>
    <name>Rattleblaze Scarecrow</name>
    <text>Rattleblaze Scarecrow has persist as long as you control a black creature. (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)
Rattleblaze Scarecrow has haste as long as you control a red creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0260</id>
    <name>Reaper King</name>
    <text>({2W} can be paid with any two mana or with {W}. This card's converted mana cost is 10.)
Other Scarecrow creatures you control get +1/+1.
Whenever another Scarecrow enters the battlefield under your control, destroy target permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>It's harvest time.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0261</id>
    <name>Revelsong Horn</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Tap an untapped creature you control: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A deflated sigh breathed into the horn emerges as an inspiring melody.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0262</id>
    <name>Scrapbasket</name>
    <text>{1}: Scrapbasket becomes all colors until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Once a tool of kithkin farmers, scarecrows of all shapes now skitter and lurch across Shadowmoor, animated by residual rustic magics.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0263</id>
    <name>Scuttlemutt</name>
    <text>{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.
{T}: Target creature becomes the color or colors of your choice until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Built to shuttle goods from the river, it took off one day carrying a cauldron of dyes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0264</id>
    <name>Tatterkite</name>
    <text>Flying
Tatterkite can't have counters placed on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"I rigged it together from wicker and scrap, yet somehow I find it unalterably perfect."
—Braenna, cobblesmith</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0265</id>
    <name>Thornwatch Scarecrow</name>
    <text>Thornwatch Scarecrow has wither as long as you control a green creature. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)
Thornwatch Scarecrow has vigilance as long as you control a white creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0266</id>
    <name>Trip Noose</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>A taut slipknot trigger is the only thing standing between you and standing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0267</id>
    <name>Umbral Mantle</name>
    <text>Equipped creature has "{3}, {untap}: This creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn." ({untap} is the untap symbol.)
Equip {0}</text>
    <flavorText>It harnesses the power of night in a land where daylight fears to show itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0268</id>
    <name>Watchwing Scarecrow</name>
    <text>Watchwing Scarecrow has vigilance as long as you control a white creature.
Watchwing Scarecrow has flying as long as you control a blue creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The wings are held in place by wicker rods. The rods are held in place by pure faith.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0269</id>
    <name>Wicker Warcrawler</name>
    <text>Whenever Wicker Warcrawler attacks or blocks, put a -1/-1 counter on it at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>It's the twisted creation of a kithkin diviner who dreamed of very large crows.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0270</id>
    <name>Wingrattle Scarecrow</name>
    <text>Wingrattle Scarecrow has flying as long as you control a blue creature.
Wingrattle Scarecrow has persist as long as you control a black creature. (When this creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0271</id>
    <name>Fire-Lit Thicket</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{RG}, {T}: Add {R}{R}, {R}{G}, or {G}{G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Occupancy of the den changes from night to night as boggart gangs fight for control of a place they aren't willing to simply eat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0272</id>
    <name>Graven Cairns</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{BR}, {T}: Add {B}{B}, {B}{R}, or {R}{R} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Here did the Extinguisher steal the light from the world. Here will we sacrifice her to bring the Great Rekindling to our people."
—Illulia of Nighthearth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0273</id>
    <name>Leechridden Swamp</name>
    <text>({T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.)
Leechridden Swamp enters the battlefield tapped.
{B}, {T}: Each opponent loses 1 life. Activate this ability only if you control two or more black permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0274</id>
    <name>Madblind Mountain</name>
    <text>({T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.)
Madblind Mountain enters the battlefield tapped.
{R}, {T}: Shuffle your library. Activate this ability only if you control two or more red permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0275</id>
    <name>Mistveil Plains</name>
    <text>({T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.)
Mistveil Plains enters the battlefield tapped.
{W}, {T}: Put target card from your graveyard on the bottom of your library. Activate this ability only if you control two or more white permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0276</id>
    <name>Moonring Island</name>
    <text>({T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.)
Moonring Island enters the battlefield tapped.
{U}, {T}: Look at the top card of target player's library. Activate this ability only if you control two or more blue permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0277</id>
    <name>Mystic Gate</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{WU}, {T}: Add {W}{W}, {W}{U}, or {U}{U} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The gate of every kithkin doun is a cunning trap, intended to spill visitors into an oubliette from which there is no escape.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0278</id>
    <name>Reflecting Pool</name>
    <text>{T}: Add to your mana pool one mana of any type that a land you control could produce.</text>
    <flavorText>Does it reflect the future that once was or the past that can never be?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0279</id>
    <name>Sapseep Forest</name>
    <text>({T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.)
Sapseep Forest enters the battlefield tapped.
{G}, {T}: You gain 1 life. Activate this ability only if you control two or more green permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0280</id>
    <name>Sunken Ruins</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{UB}, {T}: Add {U}{U}, {U}{B}, or {B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Without the care of the tideshapers, the Lanes lie neglected. Some have flooded entire towns; others dried to cracked mud.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0281</id>
    <name>Wooded Bastion</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{GW}, {T}: Add {G}{G}, {G}{W}, or {W}{W} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The elves of Wilt-Leaf Wood continually expand the palisade surrounding the sanctuary. They hope to one day enclose the entire forest within its walls.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0282</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0283</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0284</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0285</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0286</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0287</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0288</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0289</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0290</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0291</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0292</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0293</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0294</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0295</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0296</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0297</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0298</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0299</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0300</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>SHM0301</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>