<cards name="Stronghold">
  <item>
    <id>STH0001</id>
    <name>Acidic Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{2}, Sacrifice this permanent: This permanent deals 2 damage to target creature or player."</text>
    <flavorText>The first sliver burst against the cave wall, and others piled in behind to deepen the new tunnel.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0002</id>
    <name>Amok</name>
    <text>{1}, Discard a card at random: Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Crovax's rage was horrifying. Within moments only blood and shreds of flesh remained of the shapeshifter.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0003</id>
    <name>Awakening</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each upkeep, untap all creatures and lands.</text>
    <flavorText>"There are times when destiny calls forth a people and demands an action. Now is the time. We are the people. This is our action. Charge"
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0004</id>
    <name>Bandage</name>
    <text>Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.
Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Takara shook with guilt. She knew the last image her father had seen was her sword flashing toward him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0005</id>
    <name>Bottomless Pit</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player discards a card at random.</text>
    <flavorText>"I'm sure it came with the place. I don't think you build one on purpose."
—Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0006</id>
    <name>Brush with Death</name>
    <text>Buyback {2}{B}{B} (You may pay an additional {2}{B}{B} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Target opponent loses 2 life. You gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0007</id>
    <name>Bullwhip</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}: Bullwhip deals 1 damage to target creature. That creature attacks this turn if able.</text>
    <flavorText>"Pain is a crude way to enforce obedience, but it is cheap and plentiful."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0008</id>
    <name>Burgeoning</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent plays a land, you may put a land card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"The plants said, ‘We will fight the stone with root and stem and seed. We are patient. We will win.'"
—Skyshroud myth of the forest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0009</id>
    <name>Calming Licid</name>
    <text>{W}, {T}: Calming Licid loses this ability and becomes an Aura enchantment with enchant creature. Attach it to target creature. You may pay {W} to end this effect.
Enchanted creature can't attack.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0010</id>
    <name>Cannibalize</name>
    <text>Choose two target creatures controlled by the same player. Exile one of those creatures and put two +1/+1 counters on the other.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mine."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0011</id>
    <name>Carnassid</name>
    <text>Trample

{1}{G}: Regenerate Carnassid.</text>
    <flavorText>The hunter would never forget the time or place where he first met the carnassid, for they buried him there.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0012</id>
    <name>Change of Heart</name>
    <text>Buyback {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Target creature can't attack this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0013</id>
    <name>Cloud Spirit</name>
    <text>Flying
Cloud Spirit can block only creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Clouds are the soil, dreams are the crop.
—Kor saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0014</id>
    <name>Constant Mists</name>
    <text>Buyback—Sacrifice a land. (You may sacrifice a land in addition to any other costs as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0015</id>
    <name>Contemplation</name>
    <text>Whenever you cast a spell, you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"How fascinating it is to watch the machinations of one's own mind play themselves out."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0016</id>
    <name>Contempt</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature attacks, return it and Contempt to their owners' hands at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"Predictable little man. In all these years you taught me so much yet learned so little."
—Volrath, to Starke</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0017</id>
    <name>Conviction</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+3.
{W}: Return Conviction to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>It was not the minotaur's shoulders but his soul that bore the heaviest weight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0018</id>
    <name>Convulsing Licid</name>
    <text>{R}, {T}: Convulsing Licid loses this ability and becomes an Aura enchantment with enchant creature. Attach it to target creature. You may pay {R} to end this effect.
Enchanted creature can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0019</id>
    <name>Corrupting Licid</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}: Corrupting Licid loses this ability and becomes an Aura enchantment with enchant creature. Attach it to target creature. You may pay {B} to end this effect.
Enchanted creature has fear. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0020</id>
    <name>Craven Giant</name>
    <text>Craven Giant can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>What is high as a mountain and low as a snake?
—Dal riddle</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0021</id>
    <name>Crossbow Ambush</name>
    <text>Creatures you control gain reach until end of turn. (They can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>There is no drake that flies faster than a crossbow bolt.
—Vec saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0022</id>
    <name>Crovax the Cursed</name>
    <text>Crovax the Cursed enters the battlefield with four +1/+1 counters on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may sacrifice a creature. If you do, put a +1/+1 counter on Crovax. If you don't, remove a +1/+1 counter from Crovax.
{B}: Crovax gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0023</id>
    <name>Crystalline Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have shroud. (They can't be the targets of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>Bred as living shields, these slivers have proven unruly—they know they cannot be caught.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0024</id>
    <name>Dauthi Trapper</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature gains shadow until end of turn. (It can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)</text>
    <flavorText>Merfolk tell their young of Dandân, humans of Rag Man. Dal tell tales of the Dauthi, and they are far worse.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0025</id>
    <name>Death Stroke</name>
    <text>Destroy target tapped creature.</text>
    <flavorText>For a sharp second, Selenia froze, and Crovax's blade found home. As the angel shattered like glass, Crovax felt his mind collapse—the curse had been fulfilled.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0026</id>
    <name>Dream Halls</name>
    <text>Rather than pay the mana cost for a spell, its controller may discard a card that shares a color with that spell.</text>
    <flavorText>Within without.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0027</id>
    <name>Dream Prowler</name>
    <text>Dream Prowler is unblockable as long as it's attacking alone.</text>
    <flavorText>"To think that some find sleep a restful state."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0028</id>
    <name>Duct Crawler</name>
    <text>{1}{R}: Target creature can't block Duct Crawler this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The mountain's ducts will be like organ pipes, amplifying the glorious roar of the dying."
—Stronghold architect, journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0029</id>
    <name>Dungeon Shade</name>
    <text>Flying
{B}: Dungeon Shade gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A sickness stirs in its eyes, a nightmare born in darkened wails.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0030</id>
    <name>Elven Rite</name>
    <text>Distribute two +1/+1 counters among one or two target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>As the bough stretches, so shall you grow. As the roots spread, so shall you thrive.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0031</id>
    <name>Endangered Armodon</name>
    <text>When you control a creature with toughness 2 or less, sacrifice Endangered Armodon.</text>
    <flavorText>These are its last days. Its doom to be remembered only until the hunters hunger again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0032</id>
    <name>Ensnaring Bridge</name>
    <text>Creatures with power greater than the number of cards in your hand can't attack.</text>
    <flavorText>"I expected a fight, but I didn't expect it from the building itself."
—Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0033</id>
    <name>Evacuation</name>
    <text>Return all creatures to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>The first step of every exodus is from the blood and the fire onto the trail.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0034</id>
    <name>Fanning the Flames</name>
    <text>Buyback {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Fanning the Flames deals X damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0035</id>
    <name>Flame Wave</name>
    <text>Flame Wave deals 4 damage to target player and each creature he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>"I hear the roaring of a wave whose waters are red and whose mists are black."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0036</id>
    <name>Fling</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Fling, sacrifice a creature.
Fling deals damage equal to the sacrificed creature's power to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>It's raining rats and moggs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0037</id>
    <name>Flowstone Blade</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Remember the fable of the elf who came upon a cave of gold. In trying to free the largest piece, she was crushed by its weight."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0038</id>
    <name>Flowstone Hellion</name>
    <text>Haste
{0}: Flowstone Hellion gets +1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Volrath leaves no stone untrained.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0039</id>
    <name>Flowstone Mauler</name>
    <text>Trample
{R}: Flowstone Mauler gets +1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Once these horrifying creatures were perfected, there was no need for armodons.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0040</id>
    <name>Flowstone Shambler</name>
    <text>{R}: Flowstone Shambler gets +1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Flowstone troops are notoriously difficult to keep in formation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0041</id>
    <name>Foul Imp</name>
    <text>Flying
When Foul Imp enters the battlefield, you lose 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>The imp, unaware of its own odor, paused to catch its breath . . . and promptly died.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0042</id>
    <name>Furnace Spirit</name>
    <text>Haste
{R}: Furnace Spirit gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>If it can survive the Furnace, you don't want it near you.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0043</id>
    <name>Gliding Licid</name>
    <text>{U}, {T}: Gliding Licid loses this ability and becomes an Aura enchantment with enchant creature. Attach it to target creature. You may pay {U} to end this effect.
Enchanted creature has flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0044</id>
    <name>Grave Pact</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature you control is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, each other player sacrifices a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The bonds of loyalty can tie one to the grave."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0045</id>
    <name>Hammerhead Shark</name>
    <text>Hammerhead Shark can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.</text>
    <flavorText>Cross the eyes of a hammerhead and you'll dot its teeth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0046</id>
    <name>Heartstone</name>
    <text>Activated abilities of creatures cost {1} less to activate. This effect can't reduce the amount of mana an ability costs to activate to less than one mana.</text>
    <flavorText>"Finding a true heartstone is even harder than finding a true heart."
—Hanna</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0047</id>
    <name>Heat of Battle</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature blocks, Heat of Battle deals 1 damage to that creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>"Takara, it's me" shouted Starke. It was no use—she obeyed Volrath.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0048</id>
    <name>Hermit Druid</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: Reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal a basic land card. Put that card into your hand and all other cards revealed this way into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Seeking the company of plants ensures that your wits will go to seed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0049</id>
    <name>Hesitation</name>
    <text>When a player casts a spell, sacrifice Hesitation. If you do, counter that spell.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard hesitated, looking up at the enemy ship. The future hesitated with him, changed forever by the pause.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0050</id>
    <name>Hibernation Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "Pay 2 life: Return this permanent to its owner's hand."</text>
    <flavorText>Mogglings have been known to play ball with hibernating slivers, completely unaware of their true nature.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0051</id>
    <name>Hidden Retreat</name>
    <text>Put a card from your hand on top of your library: Prevent all damage that would be dealt by target instant or sorcery spell this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>After an hour in the hidey-hole, Squee seriously pondered the advantages of danger over boredom.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0052</id>
    <name>Honor Guard</name>
    <text>{W}: Honor Guard gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is not a choice I make, to have this guard. It is the choice of my people, and my duty to them."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0053</id>
    <name>Horn of Greed</name>
    <text>Whenever a player plays a land, that player draws a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Rath grows, and I am nourished."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0054</id>
    <name>Hornet Cannon</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Put a 1/1 colorless Insect artifact creature token with flying and haste named Hornet onto the battlefield. Destroy it at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0055</id>
    <name>Intruder Alarm</name>
    <text>Creatures don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.
Whenever a creature enters the battlefield, untap all creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Mirri was startled by Volrath's apparition—it had no scent.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0056</id>
    <name>Invasion Plans</name>
    <text>All creatures block each turn if able.
The attacking player chooses how each creature blocks each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Gerrard studied the globe as Mirri kept watch. Suddenly, his eyes widened. "This is Dominaria"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0057</id>
    <name>Jinxed Ring</name>
    <text>Whenever a nontoken permanent is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, Jinxed Ring deals 1 damage to you.
Sacrifice a creature: Target opponent gains control of Jinxed Ring. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0058</id>
    <name>Lab Rats</name>
    <text>Buyback {4} (You may pay an additional {4} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Put a 1/1 black Rat creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0059</id>
    <name>Lancers en-Kor</name>
    <text>Trample
{0}: The next 1 damage that would be dealt to Lancers en-Kor this turn is dealt to target creature you control instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Nearly all sets of Kor twins are trained as lancers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0060</id>
    <name>Leap</name>
    <text>Target creature gains flying until end of turn.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Mirri leapt quickly and silently. The guard died likewise.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0061</id>
    <name>Lowland Basilisk</name>
    <text>Whenever Lowland Basilisk deals damage to a creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>Unlike their cousins, Rathi basilisks turn their victims into puddles of flowstone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0062</id>
    <name>Mana Leak</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {3}.</text>
    <flavorText>"The fatal flaw in every plan is the assumption that you know more than your enemy."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0063</id>
    <name>Mask of the Mimic</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Mask of the Mimic, sacrifice a creature.
Search your library for a card with the same name as target nontoken creature and put that card onto the battlefield. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0064</id>
    <name>Megrim</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent discards a card, Megrim deals 2 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>"You can run from your pain," explained Gerrard to Crovax, "but take it from experience: you will tire before it does."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0065</id>
    <name>Mind Games</name>
    <text>Buyback {2}{U} (You may pay an additional {2}{U} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Tap target artifact, creature, or land.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0066</id>
    <name>Mind Peel</name>
    <text>Buyback {2}{B}{B} (You may pay an additional {2}{B}{B} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Target player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0067</id>
    <name>Mindwarper</name>
    <text>Mindwarper enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it.
{2}{B}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Mindwarper: Target player discards a card. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0068</id>
    <name>Mob Justice</name>
    <text>Mob Justice deals damage to target player equal to the number of creatures you control.</text>
    <flavorText>A single stone can start an avalanche.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0069</id>
    <name>Mogg Bombers</name>
    <text>When another creature enters the battlefield, sacrifice Mogg Bombers. If you do, it deals 3 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Behind every great mogg bomber is another mogg with a shovel and a basket.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0070</id>
    <name>Mogg Flunkies</name>
    <text>Mogg Flunkies can't attack or block alone.</text>
    <flavorText>They'll attack whatever's in front of them—as long as you tell them where that is.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0071</id>
    <name>Mogg Infestation</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures target player controls. For each creature put into a graveyard this way, put two 1/1 red Goblin creature tokens onto the battlefield under that player's control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0072</id>
    <name>Mogg Maniac</name>
    <text>Whenever Mogg Maniac is dealt damage, it deals that much damage to target opponent.</text>
    <flavorText>Stand clear if he gets an itch.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0073</id>
    <name>Morgue Thrull</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Morgue Thrull: Put the top three cards of your library into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>It's so hard to find good help these days.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0074</id>
    <name>Mortuary</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, put that card on top of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>"Think of them not as failures but as works in progress."
—Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0075</id>
    <name>Mox Diamond</name>
    <text>If Mox Diamond would enter the battlefield, you may discard a land card instead. If you do, put Mox Diamond onto the battlefield. If you don't, put it into its owner's graveyard.
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0076</id>
    <name>Mulch</name>
    <text>Reveal the top four cards of your library. Put all land cards revealed this way into your hand and the rest into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>Hope is the one crop that can grow in any climate.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0077</id>
    <name>Nomads en-Kor</name>
    <text>{0}: The next 1 damage that would be dealt to Nomads en-Kor this turn is dealt to target creature you control instead.</text>
    <flavorText>The Kor forsake roots for the winding of the path; forsake voices for the silence of the mind; forsake all else for the poverty of isolation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0078</id>
    <name>Overgrowth</name>
    <text>Enchant land (Target a land as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that land.)
Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds {G}{G} to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>Life needs no encouragement.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0079</id>
    <name>Portcullis</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature enters the battlefield, if there are two or more other creatures on the battlefield, exile that creature. Return that card to the battlefield under its owner's control when Portcullis leaves the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0080</id>
    <name>Primal Rage</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have trample. (If a creature you control would deal enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Charge" A great cry went out, and countless elves and Vec soldiers charged up the mountain. Their fury and passion hid the fact that they were horribly outnumbered.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0081</id>
    <name>Provoke</name>
    <text>Untap target creature you don't control. That creature blocks this turn if able.

Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Mirri did not have time to think, only to react.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0082</id>
    <name>Pursuit of Knowledge</name>
    <text>If you would draw a card, you may put a study counter on Pursuit of Knowledge instead.

Remove three study counters from Pursuit of Knowledge, Sacrifice Pursuit of Knowledge: Draw seven cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0083</id>
    <name>Rabid Rats</name>
    <text>{T}: Target blocking creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Every sentence in Volrath's prisons ends the same way.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0084</id>
    <name>Ransack</name>
    <text>Look at the top five cards of target player's library. Put any number of them on the bottom of that library in any order and the rest on top of the library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0085</id>
    <name>Rebound</name>
    <text>Change the target of target spell that targets only a player. The new target must be a player.</text>
    <flavorText>Insult, like an arrow, is beyond control once loosed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0086</id>
    <name>Reins of Power</name>
    <text>Untap all creatures you control and all creatures target opponent controls. You and that opponent each gain control of all creatures the other controls until end of turn. Those creatures gain haste until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0087</id>
    <name>Revenant</name>
    <text>Flying
Revenant's power and toughness are each equal to the number of creature cards in your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>"Not again."
—Hans</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0088</id>
    <name>Rolling Stones</name>
    <text>Wall creatures can attack as though they didn't have defender.</text>
    <flavorText>Walls collapse and kill people all the time. Some are just more aggressive about it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0089</id>
    <name>Ruination</name>
    <text>Destroy all nonbasic lands.</text>
    <flavorText>"We have built a wall upon sand. The wall will vanish. The sand will remain."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0090</id>
    <name>Sacred Ground</name>
    <text>Whenever a spell or ability an opponent controls causes a land to be put into your graveyard from the battlefield, return that card to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"That which knows itself cannot be shaped to another's will."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0091</id>
    <name>Samite Blessing</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has "{T}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to target creature this turn, prevent that damage."</text>
    <flavorText>Knit bone, darn flesh,
Stitch skin, weave breath.
—Samite healing ritual</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0092</id>
    <name>Scapegoat</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Scapegoat, sacrifice a creature.
Return any number of target creatures you control to their owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Enjoy your deception, Vuel," Gerrard said as Volrath's features melted from the dead shapeshifter. "I'll count this one as practice."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0093</id>
    <name>Seething Anger</name>
    <text>Buyback {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Target creature gets +3/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0094</id>
    <name>Serpent Warrior</name>
    <text>When Serpent Warrior enters the battlefield, you lose 3 life.</text>
    <flavorText>A hiss before dying.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0095</id>
    <name>Shaman en-Kor</name>
    <text>{0}: The next 1 damage that would be dealt to Shaman en-Kor this turn is dealt to target creature you control instead.
{1}{W}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to target creature this turn, that damage is dealt to Shaman en-Kor instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0096</id>
    <name>Shard Phoenix</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Sacrifice Shard Phoenix: Shard Phoenix deals 2 damage to each creature without flying.
{R}{R}{R}: Return Shard Phoenix from your graveyard to your hand. Activate this ability only during your upkeep.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0097</id>
    <name>Shifting Wall</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Shifting Wall enters the battlefield with X +1/+1 counters on it.</text>
    <flavorText>"You'd almost think Volrath doesn't want me here."
—Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0098</id>
    <name>Shock</name>
    <text>Shock deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>Lightning tethers souls to the world.
—Kor saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0099</id>
    <name>Sift</name>
    <text>Draw three cards, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Twice I have let the Legacy slip away. Never again."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0100</id>
    <name>Silver Wyvern</name>
    <text>Flying
{U}: Change the target of target spell or ability that targets only Silver Wyvern. The new target must be a creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0101</id>
    <name>Skeleton Scavengers</name>
    <text>Skeleton Scavengers enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.
Pay {1} for each +1/+1 counter on Skeleton Scavengers: Regenerate Skeleton Scavengers. When it regenerates this way, put a +1/+1 counter on it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0102</id>
    <name>Skyshroud Archer</name>
    <text>{T}: Target creature with flying gets -1/-1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>In Rath, arrows are guided not by virtue but by necessity.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0103</id>
    <name>Skyshroud Falcon</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance</text>
    <flavorText>The falcon slits the sky to let the light drip through.
—Kor saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0104</id>
    <name>Skyshroud Troopers</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"We were not made for war. Like flowstone, Volrath shaped us to it."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0105</id>
    <name>Sliver Queen</name>
    <text>{2}: Put a 1/1 colorless Sliver creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Her children are ever part of her.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0106</id>
    <name>Smite</name>
    <text>Destroy target blocked creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"You've got your childhood wish at last. Now you get to die."
—Gerrard, to Volrath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0107</id>
    <name>Soltari Champion</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
Whenever Soltari Champion attacks, all other creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0108</id>
    <name>Spike Breeder</name>
    <text>Spike Breeder enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it.
{2}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Spike Breeder: Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.
{2}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Spike Breeder: Put a 1/1 green Spike creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0109</id>
    <name>Spike Colony</name>
    <text>Spike Colony enters the battlefield with four +1/+1 counters on it.
{2}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Spike Colony: Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0110</id>
    <name>Spike Feeder</name>
    <text>Spike Feeder enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it.
{2}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Spike Feeder: Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.
Remove a +1/+1 counter from Spike Feeder: You gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0111</id>
    <name>Spike Soldier</name>
    <text>Spike Soldier enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it.
{2}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Spike Soldier: Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.
Remove a +1/+1 counter from Spike Soldier: Spike Soldier gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0112</id>
    <name>Spike Worker</name>
    <text>Spike Worker enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it.
{2}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Spike Worker: Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0113</id>
    <name>Spindrift Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Spindrift Drake unless you pay {U}.</text>
    <flavorText>Sea brine for blood, washing foam for laughter.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0114</id>
    <name>Spined Sliver</name>
    <text>Whenever a Sliver becomes blocked, that Sliver gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Slivers are evil and slivers are sly;
And if you get eaten, then no one will cry."
—Mogg children's rhyme</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0115</id>
    <name>Spined Wurm</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>"As it moved, the wurm's spines gathered up bits of flowstone, which took the shapes of dead villagers' heads. Each head spoke a single sound, but if taken together, they said, ‘Alas for the living.'"
—Dal myth of the wurm</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0116</id>
    <name>Spirit en-Kor</name>
    <text>Flying
{0}: The next 1 damage that would be dealt to Spirit en-Kor this turn is dealt to target creature you control instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Death free throat from thirst, mouth from speech, feet from earth.
—Kor requiem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0117</id>
    <name>Spitting Hydra</name>
    <text>Spitting Hydra enters the battlefield with four +1/+1 counters on it.
{1}{R}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Spitting Hydra: Spitting Hydra deals 1 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0118</id>
    <name>Stronghold Assassin</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a creature: Destroy target nonblack creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The assassin see only throats and hears only heartbeats.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0119</id>
    <name>Stronghold Taskmaster</name>
    <text>Other black creatures get -1/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>"With the completion of each joyous task, we are closer to Yawgmoth's divine vision."
—Stronghold architect, journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0120</id>
    <name>Sword of the Chosen</name>
    <text>{T}: Target legendary creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>One shard of Selenia yet remained.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0121</id>
    <name>Temper</name>
    <text>Prevent the next X damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn. For each 1 damage prevented this way, put a +1/+1 counter on that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"I don't need a plan, just a goal. The rest will follow on its own."
—Gerrard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0122</id>
    <name>Tempting Licid</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: Tempting Licid loses this ability and becomes an Aura enchantment with enchant creature. Attach it to target creature. You may pay {G} to end this effect.
All creatures able to block enchanted creature do so.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0123</id>
    <name>Thalakos Deceiver</name>
    <text>Shadow (This creature can block or be blocked by only creatures with shadow.)
Whenever Thalakos Deceiver attacks and isn't blocked, you may sacrifice it. If you do, gain control of target creature. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0124</id>
    <name>Tidal Surge</name>
    <text>Tap up to three target creatures without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is nature that gives us our boundaries and nature that enforces them."
—Eladamri, Lord of Leaves</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0125</id>
    <name>Tidal Warrior</name>
    <text>{T}: Target land becomes an Island until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The tide of battle favors those who can swim.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0126</id>
    <name>Torment</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets -3/-0.</text>
    <flavorText>"Volrath has killed me. All that remains of me is the scar"
—Tahngarth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0127</id>
    <name>Tortured Existence</name>
    <text>{B}, Discard a creature card: Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"There are terrors lurking in the unseen corners of us all."
—Crovax</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0128</id>
    <name>Venerable Monk</name>
    <text>When Venerable Monk enters the battlefield, you gain 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>Age wears the flesh but galvanizes the soul.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0129</id>
    <name>Verdant Touch</name>
    <text>Buyback {3} (You may pay an additional {3} as you cast this spell. If you do, put this card into your hand as it resolves.)
Target land becomes a 2/2 creature that's still a land. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0130</id>
    <name>Victual Sliver</name>
    <text>All Slivers have "{2}, Sacrifice this permanent: You gain 4 life."</text>
    <flavorText>"We are kinfolk," explained Karn to the sliver queen. "Just as you need your progeny to complete you, so do I need the pieces of the Legacy to make me whole."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0131</id>
    <name>Volrath's Gardens</name>
    <text>{2}, Tap an untapped creature you control: You gain 2 life. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.</text>
    <flavorText>"Watch yourself," warned Starke. "These plants aren't nice when they're hungry."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0132</id>
    <name>Volrath's Laboratory</name>
    <text>As Volrath's Laboratory enters the battlefield, choose a color and a creature type.
{5}, {T}: Put a 2/2 creature token of the chosen color and type onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0133</id>
    <name>Volrath's Shapeshifter</name>
    <text>As long as the top card of your graveyard is a creature card, Volrath's Shapeshifter has the full text of that card and has the text "{2}: Discard a card." (Volrath's Shapeshifter has that card's name, mana cost, color, types, abilities, power, and toughness.)
{2}: Discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0134</id>
    <name>Volrath's Stronghold</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{1}{B}, {T}: Put target creature card from your graveyard on top of your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The seed of a world's evil.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0135</id>
    <name>Walking Dream</name>
    <text>Walking Dream is unblockable.

Walking Dream doesn't untap during your untap step if an opponent controls two or more creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>Dreams, by definition, live shorter lives than those who dream them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0136</id>
    <name>Wall of Blossoms</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
When Wall of Blossoms enters the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Each flower identical, every leaf and petal disturbingly exact.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0137</id>
    <name>Wall of Essence</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Whenever Wall of Essence is dealt combat damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>The ceiling and the floor fell in love, but only the wall knew.
—Dal saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0138</id>
    <name>Wall of Razors</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
First strike</text>
    <flavorText>"In this blessed structure let the very walls baptize themselves in the blood of intruders."
—Stronghold architect, journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0139</id>
    <name>Wall of Souls</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Whenever Wall of Souls is dealt combat damage, it deals that much damage to target opponent.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is the nature of evil to turn you against yourself."
—Starke</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0140</id>
    <name>Wall of Tears</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Whenever Wall of Tears blocks a creature, return that creature to its owner's hand at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>"Many have been lost to pity."
—Karn, silver golem</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0141</id>
    <name>Warrior Angel</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Warrior Angel deals damage, you gain that much life.</text>
    <flavorText>She represents not hope, but hope's desperate fury.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0142</id>
    <name>Warrior en-Kor</name>
    <text>{0}: The next 1 damage that would be dealt to Warrior en-Kor this turn is dealt to target creature you control instead.</text>
    <flavorText>Only a matter as vital as destroying Volrath could bring together the reclusive Kor people.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>STH0143</id>
    <name>Youthful Knight</name>
    <text>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Let no child be without a sword. We will all fight, for if we fail, we will certainly all die."
—Oracle en-Vec</flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>