<cards name="Urza's Destiny">
  <item>
    <id>UDS0001</id>
    <name>Academy Rector</name>
    <text>When Academy Rector is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may exile it. If you do, search your library for an enchantment card, put that card onto the battlefield, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0002</id>
    <name>Archery Training</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put an arrow counter on Archery Training.
Enchanted creature has "{T}: This creature deals X damage to target attacking or blocking creature, where X is the number of arrow counters on Archery Training."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0003</id>
    <name>Capashen Knight</name>
    <text>First strike
{1}{W}: Capashen Knight gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Few warriors dare to challenge a knight of Capashen. Should one do so, there is one fewer.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0004</id>
    <name>Capashen Standard</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1.
{2}, Sacrifice Capashen Standard: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Benalia has no need for peacocks to serve as symbols of vanity. The Capashens strut more proudly than any bird.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0005</id>
    <name>Capashen Templar</name>
    <text>{W}: Capashen Templar gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Their shields are Benalia's outermost battlements.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0006</id>
    <name>False Prophet</name>
    <text>When False Prophet is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, exile all creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"You lived for Serra's love. Will you not die for it?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0007</id>
    <name>Fend Off</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by target creature this turn.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>The best defense is to not get hit.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0008</id>
    <name>Field Surgeon</name>
    <text>Tap an untapped creature you control: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Commanders order soldiers to attack. Field surgeons order them to heal. Both are obeyed without question.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0009</id>
    <name>Flicker</name>
    <text>Exile target nontoken permanent, then return it to the battlefield under its owner's control.</text>
    <flavorText>Who is truer: you who are, or you who are to be?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0010</id>
    <name>Jasmine Seer</name>
    <text>{2}{W}, {T}: Reveal any number of white cards in your hand. You gain 2 life for each card revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0011</id>
    <name>Mask of Law and Grace</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has protection from black and from red.</text>
    <flavorText>The archangels zealously drove Serra's light into every corner of their new home as if their creator still commanded them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0012</id>
    <name>Master Healer</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 4 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Behind his eyes is the pain of every soldier his hands have healed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0013</id>
    <name>Opalescence</name>
    <text>Each other non-Aura enchantment is a creature with power and toughness each equal to its converted mana cost. It's still an enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0014</id>
    <name>Reliquary Monk</name>
    <text>When Reliquary Monk is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>A thing of Serra's realm exists only by the grace of her followers' faith.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0015</id>
    <name>Replenish</name>
    <text>Return all enchantment cards from your graveyard to the battlefield. (Auras with nothing to enchant remain in your graveyard.)</text>
    <flavorText>Treasures, trinkets, trash—the relics of the past are brought forth again.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0016</id>
    <name>Sanctimony</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent taps a Mountain for mana, you may gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"To forgive our enemies is to forgive ourselves."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0017</id>
    <name>Scent of Jasmine</name>
    <text>Reveal any number of white cards in your hand. You gain 2 life for each card revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0018</id>
    <name>Scour</name>
    <text>Exile target enchantment. Search its controller's graveyard, hand, and library for all cards with the same name as that enchantment and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0019</id>
    <name>Serra Advocate</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Target attacking or blocking creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>An angel's touch can prepare a soldier for battle more than a thousand military drills.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0020</id>
    <name>Solidarity</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +0/+5 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Their commitment to Serra is as solid as any shield.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0021</id>
    <name>Tethered Griffin</name>
    <text>Flying

When you control no enchantments, sacrifice Tethered Griffin.</text>
    <flavorText>Poorly trained griffins sometimes attack the noble audiences that gather to watch their progress.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0022</id>
    <name>Tormented Angel</name>
    <text>Flying</text>
    <flavorText>Falling from heaven is not as painful as surviving the impact.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0023</id>
    <name>Voice of Duty</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from green</text>
    <flavorText>"Next to Law is Duty, and Duty must be obeyed. If the frame of Duty is broken, none shall weave life's fabric."
—Song of All, canto 167</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0024</id>
    <name>Voice of Reason</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from blue</text>
    <flavorText>"Next to Grace is Reason, and Reason must be retained. If the web of Reason comes unwoven, madness will escape."
—Song of All, canto 167</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0025</id>
    <name>Wall of Glare</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Wall of Glare can block any number of creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>The blinding barrier served Benalia better than a hundred shields.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0026</id>
    <name>Aura Thief</name>
    <text>Flying
When Aura Thief is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you gain control of all enchantments. (You don't get to move Auras.)</text>
    <flavorText>Illusion steals reality from the unwise.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0027</id>
    <name>Blizzard Elemental</name>
    <text>Flying
{3}{U}: Untap Blizzard Elemental.</text>
    <flavorText>Students who had seen Rayne argue with Urza were certain she had summoned it to make him seem warmer by comparison.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0028</id>
    <name>Brine Seer</name>
    <text>{2}{U}, {T}: Reveal any number of blue cards in your hand. Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1} for each card revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0029</id>
    <name>Bubbling Beebles</name>
    <text>Bubbling Beebles is unblockable as long as defending player controls an enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"Chancellor Rayne canceled the annual beeble roast. I should have married a crueler woman."
—Barrin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0030</id>
    <name>Disappear</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{U}: Return enchanted creature and Disappear to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>If at first you don't succeed, run away and hide.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0031</id>
    <name>Donate</name>
    <text>Target player gains control of target permanent you control.</text>
    <flavorText>Campus pranksters initiate new students with the old "beeble bomb" routine.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0032</id>
    <name>Fatigue</name>
    <text>Target player skips his or her next draw step.</text>
    <flavorText>"Mind if I just lie down right here for a few weeks?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0033</id>
    <name>Fledgling Osprey</name>
    <text>Fledgling Osprey has flying as long as it's enchanted.</text>
    <flavorText>It isn't truly born until its first flight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0034</id>
    <name>Illuminated Wings</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has flying.
{2}, Sacrifice Illuminated Wings: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>For a moment, Urza thought not of war and destruction, but of the freedom of the skies.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0035</id>
    <name>Iridescent Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
When Iridescent Drake enters the battlefield, put target Aura card from a graveyard onto the battlefield under your control attached to Iridescent Drake.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0036</id>
    <name>Kingfisher</name>
    <text>Flying
When Kingfisher is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>It's tastiest when served with the fish it stole.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0037</id>
    <name>Mental Discipline</name>
    <text>{1}{U}, Discard a card: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Barrin drowned his doubts about Urza's project by delving ever deeper into its details.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0038</id>
    <name>Metathran Elite</name>
    <text>Metathran Elite is unblockable as long as it's enchanted.</text>
    <flavorText>If the eyes are windows to the soul, their souls are not of this world.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0039</id>
    <name>Metathran Soldier</name>
    <text>Metathran Soldier is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>Just as Serra crafted angels of light and faith, Urza constructed an army of sorcery and power to resist the coming invasion.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0040</id>
    <name>Opposition</name>
    <text>Tap an untapped creature you control: Tap target artifact, creature, or land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Urza says he's sane. Perhaps, but measures of sanity among planeswalkers are hard to come by."
—Barrin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0041</id>
    <name>Private Research</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a page counter on Private Research.
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, draw a card for each page counter on Private Research.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0042</id>
    <name>Quash</name>
    <text>Counter target instant or sorcery spell. Search its controller's graveyard, hand, and library for all cards with the same name as that spell and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0043</id>
    <name>Rayne, Academy Chancellor</name>
    <text>Whenever you or a permanent you control becomes the target of a spell or ability an opponent controls, you may draw a card. You may draw an additional card if Rayne, Academy Chancellor is enchanted.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0044</id>
    <name>Rescue</name>
    <text>Return target permanent you control to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Urza, I've discovered more promising students than you and my husband have, combined. And I haven't lost a single one."
—Rayne, Academy Chancellor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0045</id>
    <name>Scent of Brine</name>
    <text>Reveal any number of blue cards in your hand. Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1} for each card revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0046</id>
    <name>Sigil of Sleep</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage to a player, return target creature that player controls to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Arrows are only one way to remove an enemy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0047</id>
    <name>Telepathic Spies</name>
    <text>When Telepathic Spies enters the battlefield, look at target opponent's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Do try to keep an open mind, would you?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0048</id>
    <name>Temporal Adept</name>
    <text>{U}{U}{U}, {T}: Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Of course she's at the head of her class. All her classmates have disappeared."
—Gatha, Tolarian renegade</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0049</id>
    <name>Thieving Magpie</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
Whenever Thieving Magpie deals damage to an opponent, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Rayne once made several unkind comparisons between the bird's naked opportunism and Urza's.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0050</id>
    <name>Treachery</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Treachery enters the battlefield, untap up to five lands.
You control enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"The academy educates; I employ. It's a perfect arrangement."
—Gatha, Tolarian renegade</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0051</id>
    <name>Apprentice Necromancer</name>
    <text>{B}, {T}, Sacrifice Apprentice Necromancer: Return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield. That creature gains haste. At the beginning of the next end step, sacrifice it.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0052</id>
    <name>Attrition</name>
    <text>{B}, Sacrifice a creature: Destroy target nonblack creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"I will trade life for life with the insurgents. Our resources, unlike theirs, are limitless."
—Davvol, Evincar of Rath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0053</id>
    <name>Body Snatcher</name>
    <text>When Body Snatcher enters the battlefield, you may discard a creature card. If you don't, exile Body Snatcher.
When Body Snatcher is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, exile Body Snatcher and return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0054</id>
    <name>Bubbling Muck</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, whenever a player taps a Swamp for mana, that player adds {B} to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>The muck claims a hundred living things for each meager treasure it spews forth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0055</id>
    <name>Carnival of Souls</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature enters the battlefield, you lose 1 life and add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"‘Davvol, blast those elves.' ‘Davvol, transport those troops.' No one cares that today is my birthday."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0056</id>
    <name>Chime of Night</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When Chime of Night is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, destroy target nonblack creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Many sent to serve Davvol carried such instruments, as if to remind him who their true masters were.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0057</id>
    <name>Disease Carriers</name>
    <text>When Disease Carriers is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Rath is a disease all its inhabitants carry.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0058</id>
    <name>Dying Wail</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, target player discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>This is a world of spiteful wasps that sting and kill even as they die.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0059</id>
    <name>Encroach</name>
    <text>Target player reveals his or her hand. You choose a nonbasic land card from it. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>"The rate of spread in this region is unacceptable. Start again."
—Davvol, Evincar of Rath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0060</id>
    <name>Eradicate</name>
    <text>Exile target nonblack creature. Search its controller's graveyard, hand, and library for all cards with the same name as that creature and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0061</id>
    <name>Festering Wound</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put an infection counter on Festering Wound.
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, Festering Wound deals X damage to that player, where X is the number of infection counters on Festering Wound.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0062</id>
    <name>Lurking Jackals</name>
    <text>When an opponent has 10 or less life, if Lurking Jackals is an enchantment, it becomes a 3/2 Hound creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Often it's not the hunter or the hunted but the opportunist who thrives in Rath.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0063</id>
    <name>Nightshade Seer</name>
    <text>{2}{B}, {T}: Reveal any number of black cards in your hand. Target creature gets -X/-X until end of turn, where X is the number of cards revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0064</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Monitor</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Phyrexian Monitor.</text>
    <flavorText>Being one would be an honor, if the word "honor" had any meaning in Phyrexia.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0065</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Negator</name>
    <text>Trample
Whenever Phyrexian Negator is dealt damage, sacrifice that many permanents.</text>
    <flavorText>They exist to cease.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0066</id>
    <name>Plague Dogs</name>
    <text>When Plague Dogs is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, all creatures get -1/-1 until end of turn.
{2}, Sacrifice Plague Dogs: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"They're not just retrievers, they're carriers."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0067</id>
    <name>Rapid Decay</name>
    <text>Exile up to three target cards from a single graveyard.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>The grave robbers arrived the day after the burial. They were a day too late.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0068</id>
    <name>Ravenous Rats</name>
    <text>When Ravenous Rats enters the battlefield, target opponent discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"For all the priceless tomes they have destroyed, one would think they would taste better."
—Davvol, Evincar of Rath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0069</id>
    <name>Scent of Nightshade</name>
    <text>Reveal any number of black cards in your hand. Target creature gets -X/-X until end of turn, where X is the number of cards revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0070</id>
    <name>Skittering Horror</name>
    <text>When you cast a creature spell, sacrifice Skittering Horror.</text>
    <flavorText>"This monstrosity will do—for now."
—Davvol, Evincar of Rath</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0071</id>
    <name>Slinking Skirge</name>
    <text>Flying
{2}, Sacrifice Slinking Skirge: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Davvol encouraged the skirges; they made excellent sentries and were quite edible if properly seasoned.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0072</id>
    <name>Soul Feast</name>
    <text>Target player loses 4 life and you gain 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>As no one has ever accepted a second invitation to Davvol's table, the evincar often dines alone.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0073</id>
    <name>Squirming Mass</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>Only the coldest hearts and the strongest stomachs can stand against it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0074</id>
    <name>Twisted Experiment</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/-1.</text>
    <flavorText>Gatha showed remarkable prowess in increasing his subjects' stature. Their lifespans, however, were another matter.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0075</id>
    <name>Yawgmoth's Bargain</name>
    <text>Skip your draw step.

Pay 1 life: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>He craves only one commodity.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0076</id>
    <name>Æther Sting</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a creature spell, Æther Sting deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>When Gatha fell, he was called to account for each abomination he created.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0077</id>
    <name>Bloodshot Cyclops</name>
    <text>{T}, Sacrifice a creature: Bloodshot Cyclops deals damage equal to the sacrificed creature's power to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>After their first encounter, the goblins named him Chuck.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0078</id>
    <name>Cinder Seer</name>
    <text>{2}{R}, {T}: Reveal any number of red cards in your hand. Cinder Seer deals X damage to target creature or player, where X is the number of cards revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0079</id>
    <name>Colos Yearling</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk
{R}: Colos Yearling gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A steed grows with its rider.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0080</id>
    <name>Covetous Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
When you control no artifacts, sacrifice Covetous Dragon.</text>
    <flavorText>Gatha survived as long as he did by giving all Keld's predators exactly what they wanted.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0081</id>
    <name>Flame Jet</name>
    <text>Flame Jet deals 3 damage to target player.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>Did the land make the Keldons? Did the Keldons make the land? Or were they simply meant for each other?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0082</id>
    <name>Goblin Berserker</name>
    <text>First strike, haste</text>
    <flavorText>Goblins don't know the meaning of the word "tactics"—or the word "meaning," for that matter.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0083</id>
    <name>Goblin Festival</name>
    <text>{2}: Goblin Festival deals 1 damage to target creature or player. Flip a coin. If you lose the flip, choose one of your opponents. That player gains control of Goblin Festival.</text>
    <flavorText>"What are we celebratin' again?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0084</id>
    <name>Goblin Gardener</name>
    <text>When Goblin Gardener is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>"Grow food in dirt? Save time—eat dirt."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0085</id>
    <name>Goblin Marshal</name>
    <text>Echo {4}{R}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Goblin Marshal enters the battlefield or is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put two 1/1 red Goblin creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0086</id>
    <name>Goblin Masons</name>
    <text>When Goblin Masons is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, destroy target Wall.</text>
    <flavorText>"Goblins build with true zeal—and anything else within arm's reach."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0087</id>
    <name>Hulking Ogre</name>
    <text>Hulking Ogre can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>"The Keldons' ogre campaign provided more body parts than my meager facility could properly use."
—Gatha, Tolarian renegade</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0088</id>
    <name>Impatience</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's end step, if that player didn't cast a spell this turn, Impatience deals 2 damage to him or her.</text>
    <flavorText>Ask a Keldon to hold his temper and you'll be left holding your guts.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0089</id>
    <name>Incendiary</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a fuse counter on Incendiary.
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, Incendiary deals X damage to target creature or player, where X is the number of fuse counters on Incendiary.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0090</id>
    <name>Keldon Champion</name>
    <text>Haste
Echo {2}{R}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Keldon Champion enters the battlefield, it deals 3 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0091</id>
    <name>Keldon Vandals</name>
    <text>Echo {2}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Keldon Vandals enters the battlefield, destroy target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>Keldons divide all their spoils into two groups: trophies and catapult ammunition.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0092</id>
    <name>Landslide</name>
    <text>Sacrifice any number of Mountains. Landslide deals that much damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes the mountain takes.
—Keldon saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0093</id>
    <name>Mark of Fury</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has haste.
At the beginning of the end step, return Mark of Fury to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Many Keldon warriors bear the mark of intentional insanity.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0094</id>
    <name>Reckless Abandon</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Reckless Abandon, sacrifice a creature.
Reckless Abandon deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>The climax of a warlord's career is always death.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0095</id>
    <name>Repercussion</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is dealt damage, Repercussion deals that much damage to that creature's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>Not all Keld's warriors are found on the battlefield.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0096</id>
    <name>Scent of Cinder</name>
    <text>Reveal any number of red cards in your hand. Scent of Cinder deals X damage to target creature or player, where X is the number of cards revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0097</id>
    <name>Sowing Salt</name>
    <text>Exile target nonbasic land. Search its controller's graveyard, hand, and library for all cards with the same name as that land and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0098</id>
    <name>Trumpet Blast</name>
    <text>Attacking creatures get +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Keldon warriors don't need signals to tell them when to attack, but when to stop.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0099</id>
    <name>Wake of Destruction</name>
    <text>Destroy target land and all other lands with the same name as that land.</text>
    <flavorText>Land charred black, rivers boiled,
Crops and wells alike despoiled,
Mountains leveled, forests felled—
Footprints of the beasts of Keld.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0100</id>
    <name>Wild Colos</name>
    <text>Haste</text>
    <flavorText>You'll never get a Keldon's goat.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0101</id>
    <name>Ancient Silverback</name>
    <text>{G}: Regenerate Ancient Silverback. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>The Phyrexian killing machines couldn't have known the seriousness of their mistake in wounding the ape—they'd never seen it angry.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0102</id>
    <name>Compost</name>
    <text>Whenever a black card is put into an opponent's graveyard from anywhere, you may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>A fruit must rot before its seed can sprout.
—Yavimaya saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0103</id>
    <name>Elvish Lookout</name>
    <text>Shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>Like a masterful quilter, Yavimaya stitches together patches of color to warn its denizens of threats.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0104</id>
    <name>Elvish Piper</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}: You may put a creature card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>From Gaea grew the world, and the world was silent. From Gaea grew the world's elves, and the world was silent no more.
—Elvish teaching</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0105</id>
    <name>Emperor Crocodile</name>
    <text>When you control no other creatures, sacrifice Emperor Crocodile.</text>
    <flavorText>The king of Yavimaya's waters pays constant attention to his subjects . . . and thrives on their adulation.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0106</id>
    <name>Gamekeeper</name>
    <text>When Gamekeeper is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may exile it. If you do, reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal a creature card. Put that card onto the battlefield and put all other cards revealed this way into your graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0107</id>
    <name>Goliath Beetle</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>The balance of nature dictates that one day humans will be stepped on by bugs.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0108</id>
    <name>Heart Warden</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
{2}, Sacrifice Heart Warden: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"In Llanowar, we tend the forest's boughs and branches. In Yavimaya, we are a part of them."
—Rofellos of Llanowar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0109</id>
    <name>Hunting Moa</name>
    <text>Echo {2}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Hunting Moa enters the battlefield or is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0110</id>
    <name>Ivy Seer</name>
    <text>{2}{G}, {T}: Reveal any number of green cards in your hand. Target creature gets +X/+X until end of turn, where X is the number of cards revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0111</id>
    <name>Magnify</name>
    <text>All creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The seed torches' pollen gives off light, but the elves find it heightens their senses as well.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0112</id>
    <name>Marker Beetles</name>
    <text>When Marker Beetles is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.
{2}, Sacrifice Marker Beetles: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>In case of emergency, crush bug.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0113</id>
    <name>Momentum</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a growth counter on Momentum.
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 for each growth counter on Momentum.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0114</id>
    <name>Multani's Decree</name>
    <text>Destroy all enchantments. You gain 2 life for each enchantment destroyed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"This is my place of power. Nothing can take root here unless I allow it."
—Multani, maro-sorcerer</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0115</id>
    <name>Pattern of Rebirth</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, that creature's controller may search his or her library for a creature card and put that card onto the battlefield. If that player does, he or she shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0116</id>
    <name>Plated Spider</name>
    <text>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>Most spiders wait patiently for their prey to arrive. Most spiders aren't forty feet tall.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0117</id>
    <name>Plow Under</name>
    <text>Put two target lands on top of their owners' libraries.</text>
    <flavorText>To renew the land, plow the land. To destroy the land, do nothing.
—Druids' saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0118</id>
    <name>Rofellos, Llanowar Emissary</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool for each Forest you control.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0119</id>
    <name>Rofellos's Gift</name>
    <text>Reveal any number of green cards in your hand. Return an enchantment card from your graveyard to your hand for each card revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"Rise, elf. We are both of Gaea, and thus we are equal."
—Multani, to Rofellos</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0120</id>
    <name>Scent of Ivy</name>
    <text>Reveal any number of green cards in your hand. Target creature gets +X/+X until end of turn, where X is the number of cards revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0121</id>
    <name>Splinter</name>
    <text>Exile target artifact. Search its controller's graveyard, hand, and library for all cards with the same name as that artifact and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0122</id>
    <name>Taunting Elf</name>
    <text>All creatures able to block Taunting Elf do so.</text>
    <flavorText>Much to Multani's chagrin, Rofellos gleefully tutored Yavimaya's elves on the rudest and most vulgar words spoken in Llanowar.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0123</id>
    <name>Thorn Elemental</name>
    <text>You may have Thorn Elemental assign its combat damage as though it weren't blocked.</text>
    <flavorText>Rain from this storm leaves you pinned to the ground like an insect.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0124</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Elder</name>
    <text>When Yavimaya Elder is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may search your library for up to two basic land cards, reveal them, and put them into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.
{2}, Sacrifice Yavimaya Elder: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0125</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Enchantress</name>
    <text>Yavimaya Enchantress gets +1/+1 for each enchantment on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>From each seed, a world. From each world, a thousand seeds.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0126</id>
    <name>Braidwood Cup</name>
    <text>{T}: You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"I think it no accident that every civilized people has discovered the art of distillation."
—Rofellos of Llanowar</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0127</id>
    <name>Braidwood Sextant</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Braidwood Sextant: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0128</id>
    <name>Brass Secretary</name>
    <text>{2}, Sacrifice Brass Secretary: Draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>The students disliked the secretary for its unfailing memory—until they discovered it couldn't dodge thrown objects.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0129</id>
    <name>Caltrops</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature attacks, Caltrops deals 1 damage to it.</text>
    <flavorText>Toward the end, Gatha struggled to keep his experiments in and his patrons out.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0130</id>
    <name>Extruder</name>
    <text>Echo {4} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
Sacrifice an artifact: Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>As the invasion drew closer, Urza's means began to resemble Phyrexia's end.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0131</id>
    <name>Fodder Cannon</name>
    <text>{4}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Fodder Cannon deals 4 damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Step 1: Find your cousin.
Step 2: Get your cousin in the cannon.
Step 3: Find another cousin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0132</id>
    <name>Junk Diver</name>
    <text>Flying
When Junk Diver is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return another target artifact card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Garbage in, treasure out.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0133</id>
    <name>Mantis Engine</name>
    <text>{2}: Mantis Engine gains flying until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
{2}: Mantis Engine gains first strike until end of turn. (It deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>Tawnos left a legacy of animal designs in many of Urza's creations.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0134</id>
    <name>Masticore</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Masticore unless you discard a card.
{2}: Masticore deals 1 damage to target creature.
{2}: Regenerate Masticore.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0135</id>
    <name>Metalworker</name>
    <text>{T}: Reveal any number of artifact cards in your hand. Add {2} to your mana pool for each card revealed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"At this rate I fully expect to be replaced by a clockwork golem by year's end."
—Barrin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0136</id>
    <name>Powder Keg</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a fuse counter on Powder Keg.

{T}, Sacrifice Powder Keg: Destroy each artifact and creature with converted mana cost equal to the number of fuse counters on Powder Keg.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0137</id>
    <name>Scrying Glass</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Choose a number greater than 0 and a color. Target opponent reveals his or her hand. If that opponent reveals exactly the chosen number of cards of the chosen color, you draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0138</id>
    <name>Storage Matrix</name>
    <text>As long as Storage Matrix is untapped, each player chooses artifact, creature, or land during his or her untap step. That player can untap only permanents of the chosen type this step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0139</id>
    <name>Thran Dynamo</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {3} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Urza's metathran children were conceived, birthed, and nurtured by an integrated system of machines.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0140</id>
    <name>Thran Foundry</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}, Exile Thran Foundry: Target player shuffles his or her graveyard into his or her library.</text>
    <flavorText>"What we do not use up, we use again."
—Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0141</id>
    <name>Thran Golem</name>
    <text>As long as Thran Golem is enchanted, it gets +2/+2 and has flying, first strike, and trample.</text>
    <flavorText>Karn felt more secure about his value to Urza when he realized he didn't need regular trimming.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0142</id>
    <name>Urza's Incubator</name>
    <text>As Urza's Incubator enters the battlefield, choose a creature type.
Creature spells of the chosen type cost {2} less to cast.</text>
    <flavorText>"Stop thinking like an artificer, Urza, and start thinking like a father"
—Rayne, Academy Chancellor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>UDS0143</id>
    <name>Yavimaya Hollow</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.

{G}, {T}: Regenerate target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>For all its traps and defenses, Yavimaya has its havens, too.</flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>