<cards name="Urza's Saga">
  <item>
    <id>USG0001</id>
    <name>Absolute Grace</name>
    <text>All creatures have protection from black.</text>
    <flavorText>In pursuit of Urza, the Phyrexians sent countless foul legions into Serra's realm. Though beaten back, they left it tainted with uncleansable evil.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0002</id>
    <name>Absolute Law</name>
    <text>All creatures have protection from red.</text>
    <flavorText>The strength of law is unwavering. It is an iron bar in a world of water.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0003</id>
    <name>Angelic Chorus</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature enters the battlefield under your control, you gain life equal to its toughness.</text>
    <flavorText>The very young and the very old know best the song the angels sing.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0004</id>
    <name>Angelic Page</name>
    <text>Flying
{T}: Target attacking or blocking creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>If only every message were as perfect as its bearers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0005</id>
    <name>Brilliant Halo</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+2.
When Brilliant Halo is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Brilliant Halo to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0006</id>
    <name>Catastrophe</name>
    <text>Destroy all lands or all creatures. Creatures destroyed this way can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>Radiant's eyes flashed. "Go, then," the angel spat at Serra, "and leave this world to those who truly care."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0007</id>
    <name>Clear</name>
    <text>Destroy target enchantment.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0008</id>
    <name>Congregate</name>
    <text>Target player gains 2 life for each creature on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"In the gathering there is strength for all who founder, renewal for all who languish, love for all who sing."
—Song of All, canto 642</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0009</id>
    <name>Defensive Formation</name>
    <text>Rather than the attacking player, you assign the combat damage of each creature attacking you. You can divide that creature's combat damage as you choose among any of the creatures blocking it.</text>
    <flavorText>"Your enemies will pound upon the door of your defenses, but only you shall have the key, and it is the key of life."
—Song of All, canto 873</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0010</id>
    <name>Disciple of Grace</name>
    <text>Protection from black
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>Beauty is beyond law.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0011</id>
    <name>Disciple of Law</name>
    <text>Protection from red
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>A religious order for religious order.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0012</id>
    <name>Disenchant</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let Phyrexia breed evil in the darkness; my holy light will reveal its taint."
—Serra</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0013</id>
    <name>Elite Archers</name>
    <text>{T}: Elite Archers deals 3 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Arrows fletched with the feathers of angels seldom miss their mark.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0014</id>
    <name>Faith Healer</name>
    <text>Sacrifice an enchantment: You gain life equal to the sacrificed enchantment's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>The power of faith is quiet. It is the leaf unmoved by the hurricane.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0015</id>
    <name>Glorious Anthem</name>
    <text>Creatures you control get +1/+1.</text>
    <flavorText>Once heard, the battle song of an angel becomes part of the listener forever.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0016</id>
    <name>Healing Salve</name>
    <text>Choose one — Target player gains 3 life; or prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Xantcha is recovering. The medicine is slow, but my magic would have killed her."
—Serra, to Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0017</id>
    <name>Herald of Serra</name>
    <text>Flying, vigilance
Echo {2}{W}{W} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0018</id>
    <name>Humble</name>
    <text>Target creature loses all abilities and becomes 0/1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is not your place to rule, Radiant. It may not even be mine."
—Serra</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0019</id>
    <name>Intrepid Hero</name>
    <text>{T}: Destroy target creature with power 4 or greater.</text>
    <flavorText>"We each have our own strengths, Radiant," Serra said with a sly smile. "If all of my people were like this one, who would carry your scrolls?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0020</id>
    <name>Monk Idealist</name>
    <text>When Monk Idealist enters the battlefield, return target enchantment card from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Belief is the strongest mortar."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0021</id>
    <name>Monk Realist</name>
    <text>When Monk Realist enters the battlefield, destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>"We plant the seeds of doubt to harvest the crop of wisdom."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0022</id>
    <name>Opal Acrolith</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a creature spell, if Opal Acrolith is an enchantment, Opal Acrolith becomes a 2/4 Soldier creature.
{0}: Opal Acrolith becomes an enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0023</id>
    <name>Opal Archangel</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts a creature spell, if Opal Archangel is an enchantment, Opal Archangel becomes a 5/5 Angel creature with flying and vigilance.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0024</id>
    <name>Opal Caryatid</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts a creature spell, if Opal Caryatid is an enchantment, Opal Caryatid becomes a 2/2 Soldier creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0025</id>
    <name>Opal Gargoyle</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts a creature spell, if Opal Gargoyle is an enchantment, Opal Gargoyle becomes a 2/2 Gargoyle creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0026</id>
    <name>Opal Titan</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts a creature spell, if Opal Titan is an enchantment, Opal Titan becomes a 4/4 Giant creature with protection from each of that spell's colors.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0027</id>
    <name>Pacifism</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature can't attack or block.</text>
    <flavorText>"Fight? I cannot. I do not care if I live or die, so long as I can rest."
—Urza, to Serra</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0028</id>
    <name>Pariah</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
All damage that would be dealt to you is dealt to enchanted creature instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"It is not sad," Radiant chided the lesser angel. "It is right. Every society must have its outcasts."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0029</id>
    <name>Path of Peace</name>
    <text>Destroy target creature. Its owner gains 4 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"When the sword becomes a burden, let the warrior lay it aside that another with a truer heart might take it up."
—Radiant, archangel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0030</id>
    <name>Pegasus Charger</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>"The clouds came alive and dove to the earth Hooves flashed among the dark army, who fled before the spectacle of fury."
—Song of All, canto 211</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0031</id>
    <name>Planar Birth</name>
    <text>Return all basic land cards from all graveyards to the battlefield tapped under their owners' control.</text>
    <flavorText>"From womb of nothingness sprang this place of beauty, purity, and hope realized."
—Song of All, canto 3</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0032</id>
    <name>Presence of the Master</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts an enchantment spell, counter it.</text>
    <flavorText>Peace to all. Peace be all.
—Great Hall floor inscription</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0033</id>
    <name>Redeem</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt this turn to up to two target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"That they are saved from death is immaterial. What is important is that they know the source of their benefaction."
—Radiant, archangel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0034</id>
    <name>Remembrance</name>
    <text>Whenever a nontoken creature you control is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, you may search your library for a card with the same name as that creature, reveal it, and put it into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0035</id>
    <name>Rune of Protection: Artifacts</name>
    <text>{W}: The next time an artifact source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0036</id>
    <name>Rune of Protection: Black</name>
    <text>{W}: The next time a black source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0037</id>
    <name>Rune of Protection: Blue</name>
    <text>{W}: The next time a blue source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0038</id>
    <name>Rune of Protection: Green</name>
    <text>{W}: The next time a green source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0039</id>
    <name>Rune of Protection: Lands</name>
    <text>{W}: The next time a land source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0040</id>
    <name>Rune of Protection: Red</name>
    <text>{W}: The next time a red source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0041</id>
    <name>Rune of Protection: White</name>
    <text>{W}: The next time a white source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0042</id>
    <name>Sanctum Custodian</name>
    <text>{T}: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Serra told them to guard Urza as he healed. Five years they stood.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0043</id>
    <name>Sanctum Guardian</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Sanctum Guardian: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to target creature or player this turn, prevent that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>"Protect our mother in her womb."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0044</id>
    <name>Seasoned Marshal</name>
    <text>Whenever Seasoned Marshal attacks, you may tap target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>There are only two rules of tactics: never be without a plan, and never rely on it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0045</id>
    <name>Serra Avatar</name>
    <text>Serra Avatar's power and toughness are each equal to your life total.
When Serra Avatar is put into a graveyard from anywhere, shuffle it into its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0046</id>
    <name>Serra Zealot</name>
    <text>First strike</text>
    <flavorText>"The humans are useful in their way, but they must be commanded as the builder commands the stone. Be soft with them, and they will become soft."—Radiant, archangel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0047</id>
    <name>Serra's Embrace</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and has flying and vigilance.</text>
    <flavorText>"Lifted beyond herself, for that battle Brindri was an angel of light and fury."
—Song of All, canto 524</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0048</id>
    <name>Serra's Hymn</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a verse counter on Serra's Hymn.
Sacrifice Serra's Hymn: Prevent the next X damage that would be dealt this turn to any number of target creatures and/or players, divided as you choose, where X is the number of verse counters on Serra's Hymn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0049</id>
    <name>Serra's Liturgy</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a verse counter on Serra's Liturgy.
{W}, Sacrifice Serra's Liturgy: Destroy up to X target artifacts and/or enchantments, where X is the number of verse counters on Serra's Liturgy.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0050</id>
    <name>Shimmering Barrier</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
First strike
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0051</id>
    <name>Silent Attendant</name>
    <text>{T}: You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"The answer to life should never be death; it should always be more life, wrapped tight around us like precious silks."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0052</id>
    <name>Songstitcher</name>
    <text>{1}{W}: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn by target attacking creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>The true names of birds are songs woven into their souls.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0053</id>
    <name>Soul Sculptor</name>
    <text>{1}{W}, {T}: Target creature becomes an enchantment and loses all abilities until a player casts a creature spell.</text>
    <flavorText>Does the stone mimic life, or did it once live?</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0054</id>
    <name>Voice of Grace</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from black</text>
    <flavorText>"Opposite Law is Grace, and Grace must be preserved. If the strands of Grace are unraveled, its design will be lost, and the people with it."
—Song of All, canto 167</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0055</id>
    <name>Voice of Law</name>
    <text>Flying, protection from red</text>
    <flavorText>"Life's balance is as a star: on one point is Law, and Law must be upheld. If the knots of order are loosened, chaos will spill through."
—Song of All, canto 167</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0056</id>
    <name>Waylay</name>
    <text>Put three 2/2 white Knight creature tokens onto the battlefield. Exile them at the beginning of the next cleanup step.</text>
    <flavorText>"You reek of corruption," spat the knight. "Why are you even here?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0057</id>
    <name>Worship</name>
    <text>If you control a creature, damage that would reduce your life total to less than 1 reduces it to 1 instead.</text>
    <flavorText>"Believe in the ideal, not the idol."
—Serra</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0058</id>
    <name>Academy Researchers</name>
    <text>When Academy Researchers enters the battlefield, you may put an Aura card from your hand onto the battlefield attached to Academy Researchers.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0059</id>
    <name>Annul</name>
    <text>Counter target artifact or enchantment spell.</text>
    <flavorText>The most effective way to destroy a spell is to ensure it was never cast in the first place.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0060</id>
    <name>Arcane Laboratory</name>
    <text>Each player can't cast more than one spell each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>It soon became obvious that some experiments were best overseen by fireproof teachers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0061</id>
    <name>Attunement</name>
    <text>Return Attunement to its owner's hand: Draw three cards, then discard four cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"The solution can hide for only so long."
—Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0062</id>
    <name>Back to Basics</name>
    <text>Nonbasic lands don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</text>
    <flavorText>"A ruler wears a crown while the rest of us wear hats, but which would you rather have when it's raining?"
—Barrin, Principia</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0063</id>
    <name>Barrin, Master Wizard</name>
    <text>{2}, Sacrifice a permanent: Return target creature to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Knowledge is no more expensive than ignorance, and at least as satisfying."
—Barrin, master wizard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0064</id>
    <name>Catalog</name>
    <text>Draw two cards, then discard a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Without order comes errors, and errors kill on Tolaria."
—Barrin, master wizard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0065</id>
    <name>Cloak of Mists</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature is unblockable.</text>
    <flavorText>"All we could lose, we did. All we could keep, we do. And both are shrouded by mists."
—Barrin, master wizard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0066</id>
    <name>Confiscate</name>
    <text>Enchant permanent (Target a permanent as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that permanent.)
You control enchanted permanent.</text>
    <flavorText>"I don't understand why he works so hard on a device to duplicate a sound so easily made with hand and armpit."
—Barrin, progress report</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0067</id>
    <name>Coral Merfolk</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>It is not unusual for a single family of coral merfolk to spend centuries carefully guiding the growth of the reefs where they make their home.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0068</id>
    <name>Curfew</name>
    <text>Each player returns a creature he or she controls to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>". . . But I'm not tired"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0069</id>
    <name>Disruptive Student</name>
    <text>{T}: Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1}.</text>
    <flavorText>"Teferi is a problem student. Always late for class. No appreciation for constructive use of time."
—Barrin, progress report</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0070</id>
    <name>Douse</name>
    <text>{1}{U}: Counter target red spell.</text>
    <flavorText>The academy's libraries were protected by fire-prevention spells. Even after the disaster, the books were intact—though forever sealed in time.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0071</id>
    <name>Drifting Djinn</name>
    <text>Flying
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Drifting Djinn unless you pay {1}{U}.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0072</id>
    <name>Enchantment Alteration</name>
    <text>Attach target Aura attached to a creature or land to another permanent of that type.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0073</id>
    <name>Energy Field</name>
    <text>Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you by sources you don't control.
When a card is put into your graveyard from anywhere, sacrifice Energy Field.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0074</id>
    <name>Exhaustion</name>
    <text>Creatures and lands target opponent controls don't untap during his or her next untap step.</text>
    <flavorText>The mage felt as though he'd been in the stasis suit for days. Upon his return, he found it was months.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0075</id>
    <name>Fog Bank</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Flying
Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by Fog Bank.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0076</id>
    <name>Gilded Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
When Gilded Drake enters the battlefield, exchange control of Gilded Drake and up to one target creature an opponent controls. If you don't make an exchange, sacrifice Gilded Drake. This ability can't be countered except by spells and abilities. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)</text>
    <flavorText>Buyer beware.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0077</id>
    <name>Great Whale</name>
    <text>When Great Whale enters the battlefield, untap up to seven lands.</text>
    <flavorText>"As a great whale dies, it flips onto its back. And so an island is born."
—Mariners' legend</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0078</id>
    <name>Hermetic Study</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has "{T}: This creature deals 1 damage to target creature or player."</text>
    <flavorText>"Books can be replaced; a prize student cannot. Be patient."
—Urza, to Barrin</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0079</id>
    <name>Hibernation</name>
    <text>Return all green permanents to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>On its way to the cave, the armadillo brushed by a sapling. It awoke to find a full-grown tree blocking its path.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0080</id>
    <name>Horseshoe Crab</name>
    <text>{U}: Untap Horseshoe Crab.</text>
    <flavorText>In the final days before the disaster, all the crabs on Tolaria migrated from inlets, streams, and ponds back to the sea. No one took note.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0081</id>
    <name>Imaginary Pet</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you have a card in hand, return Imaginary Pet to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"It followed me home. Can I keep it?"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0082</id>
    <name>Launch</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has flying.
When Launch is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Launch to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0083</id>
    <name>Lilting Refrain</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a verse counter on Lilting Refrain.
Sacrifice Lilting Refrain: Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}, where X is the number of verse counters on Lilting Refrain.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0084</id>
    <name>Lingering Mirage</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Enchanted land is an Island.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>Birds frozen in flight. Sea turned to glass. Tolaria hidden in a mirror.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0085</id>
    <name>Morphling</name>
    <text>{U}: Untap Morphling.
{U}: Morphling gains flying until end of turn.
{U}: Morphling gains shroud until end of turn. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)
{1}: Morphling gets +1/-1 until end of turn.
{1}: Morphling gets -1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0086</id>
    <name>Pendrell Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>The mages of Tolaria found strange ways to spend their free time. Occasionally they had contests to see whose kite was eaten last.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0087</id>
    <name>Pendrell Flux</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature has "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice this creature unless you pay its mana cost."</text>
    <flavorText>Devoured by the mists, Tolaria was stuck in time, trapped between two eternal heartbeats.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0088</id>
    <name>Peregrine Drake</name>
    <text>Flying
When Peregrine Drake enters the battlefield, untap up to five lands.</text>
    <flavorText>That the Tolarian mists parted for the drakes was warning enough to stay away.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0089</id>
    <name>Power Sink</name>
    <text>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}. If he or she doesn't, that player taps all lands with mana abilities he or she controls and empties his or her mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0090</id>
    <name>Power Taint</name>
    <text>Enchant enchantment
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted enchantment's controller, that player loses 2 life unless he or she pays {2}.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0091</id>
    <name>Recantation</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a verse counter on Recantation.
{U}, Sacrifice Recantation: Return up to X target permanents to their owners' hands, where X is the number of verse counters on Recantation.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0092</id>
    <name>Rescind</name>
    <text>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0093</id>
    <name>Rewind</name>
    <text>Counter target spell. Untap up to four lands.</text>
    <flavorText>"Time flows like a river. In Tolaria we practice the art of building dams."
—Barrin, master wizard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0094</id>
    <name>Sandbar Merfolk</name>
    <text>Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>You are not prey until a predator knows of your existence.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0095</id>
    <name>Sandbar Serpent</name>
    <text>Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>Treacherous and unpredictable currents around Tolaria earned the nickname "serpent wakes."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0096</id>
    <name>Show and Tell</name>
    <text>Each player may put an artifact, creature, enchantment, or land card from his or her hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>At the academy, "show and tell" too often becomes "run and hide."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0097</id>
    <name>Somnophore</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Somnophore deals damage to a player, tap target creature that player controls. That creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step for as long as Somnophore remains on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0098</id>
    <name>Spire Owl</name>
    <text>Flying
When Spire Owl enters the battlefield, look at the top four cards of your library, then put them back in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0099</id>
    <name>Stern Proctor</name>
    <text>When Stern Proctor enters the battlefield, return target artifact or enchantment to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"I preferred the harsh tutors—they made mischief all the more fun."
—Teferi, third-level student</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0100</id>
    <name>Stroke of Genius</name>
    <text>Target player draws X cards.</text>
    <flavorText>After a hundred failed experiments, Urza was stunned to find that common silver passed through the portal undamaged. He immediately designed a golem made of the metal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0101</id>
    <name>Sunder</name>
    <text>Return all lands to their owners' hands.</text>
    <flavorText>The flow of time was disrupted; like a flooding river it rose from its banks. Tolaria was drowned in an instant that stretched toward infinity.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0102</id>
    <name>Telepathy</name>
    <text>Your opponents play with their hands revealed.</text>
    <flavorText>"The most disappointing thing about learning telepathy is finding out how boring people really are."
—Teferi, fourth-level student</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0103</id>
    <name>Time Spiral</name>
    <text>Exile Time Spiral. Each player shuffles his or her graveyard and hand into his or her library, then draws seven cards. You untap up to six lands.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0104</id>
    <name>Tolarian Winds</name>
    <text>Discard all the cards in your hand, then draw that many cards.</text>
    <flavorText>Afterward, Tolaria's winds were like the whispers of lost wizards, calling for life.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0105</id>
    <name>Turnabout</name>
    <text>Choose artifact, creature, or land. Tap all untapped permanents of the chosen type target player controls, or untap all tapped permanents of that type that player controls.</text>
    <flavorText>The best cure for a big ego is a little failure.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0106</id>
    <name>Veil of Birds</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts a spell, if Veil of Birds is an enchantment, Veil of Birds becomes a 1/1 Bird creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>When wind marries sky, even the bride's veil sings her praises.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0107</id>
    <name>Veiled Apparition</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts a spell, if Veiled Apparition is an enchantment, Veiled Apparition becomes a 3/3 Illusion creature with flying and "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Veiled Apparition unless you pay {1}{U}."</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0108</id>
    <name>Veiled Crocodile</name>
    <text>When a player has no cards in hand, if Veiled Crocodile is an enchantment, Veiled Crocodile becomes a 4/4 Crocodile creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Some roads are paved with bad intentions.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0109</id>
    <name>Veiled Sentry</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts a spell, if Veiled Sentry is an enchantment, Veiled Sentry becomes an Illusion creature with power and toughness each equal to that spell's converted mana cost.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0110</id>
    <name>Veiled Serpent</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts a spell, if Veiled Serpent is an enchantment, Veiled Serpent becomes a 4/4 Serpent creature that can't attack unless defending player controls an Island.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0111</id>
    <name>Windfall</name>
    <text>Each player discards his or her hand, then draws cards equal to the greatest number of cards a player discarded this way.</text>
    <flavorText>"To fill your mind with knowledge, we must start by emptying it."
—Barrin, master wizard</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0112</id>
    <name>Wizard Mentor</name>
    <text>{T}: Return Wizard Mentor and target creature you control to their owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Although some of the students quickly grasped the concept, the others could summon only blackboards.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0113</id>
    <name>Zephid</name>
    <text>Flying; shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>Once you've seen one, you'll understand why spells won't go near them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0114</id>
    <name>Zephid's Embrace</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and has flying and shroud. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>Spells will shun you, as will everyone else.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0115</id>
    <name>Abyssal Horror</name>
    <text>Flying
When Abyssal Horror enters the battlefield, target player discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>It has no face of its own—it wears that of its latest victim.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0116</id>
    <name>Befoul</name>
    <text>Destroy target land or nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>"The land putrefied at its touch, turned into an oily bile in seconds."
—Radiant, archangel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0117</id>
    <name>Bereavement</name>
    <text>Whenever a green creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, its controller discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Grief is as useless as love."
—Gix, Yawgmoth praetor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0118</id>
    <name>Blood Vassal</name>
    <text>Sacrifice Blood Vassal: Add {B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"They are bred to suffer and born to die. Much like humans."
—Gix, Yawgmoth praetor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0119</id>
    <name>Bog Raiders</name>
    <text>Swampwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"Let weak feed on weak, that we may divine the nature of strength."
—Phyrexian Scriptures</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0120</id>
    <name>Breach</name>
    <text>Target creature gets +2/+0 and gains fear until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0121</id>
    <name>Cackling Fiend</name>
    <text>When Cackling Fiend enters the battlefield, each opponent discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Its windpipe is only the first to amplify its maddening laughter.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0122</id>
    <name>Carrion Beetles</name>
    <text>{2}{B}, {T}: Exile up to three target cards from a single graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>It's all fun and games until someone loses an eye.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0123</id>
    <name>Contamination</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Contamination unless you sacrifice a creature.
If a land is tapped for mana, it produces {B} instead of any other type and amount.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0124</id>
    <name>Corrupt</name>
    <text>Corrupt deals damage equal to the number of Swamps you control to target creature or player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt this way.</text>
    <flavorText>Yawgmoth brushed Urza's mind, and Urza's world convulsed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0125</id>
    <name>Crazed Skirge</name>
    <text>Flying, haste</text>
    <flavorText>They are Phyrexia's couriers; the messages they carry are inscribed on their slick hides.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0126</id>
    <name>Dark Hatchling</name>
    <text>Flying
When Dark Hatchling enters the battlefield, destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0127</id>
    <name>Dark Ritual</name>
    <text>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"From void evolved Phyrexia. Great Yawgmoth, Father of Machines, saw its perfection. Thus The Grand Evolution began."
—Phyrexian Scriptures</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0128</id>
    <name>Darkest Hour</name>
    <text>All creatures are black.</text>
    <flavorText>"Yawgmoth spent eons wrapping Phyrexians in human skin. They are the sleeper agents, and they are everywhere."
—Xantcha, to Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0129</id>
    <name>Despondency</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets -2/-0.
When Despondency is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Despondency to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0130</id>
    <name>Diabolic Servitude</name>
    <text>When Diabolic Servitude enters the battlefield, return target creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.
When the creature put onto the battlefield with Diabolic Servitude is put into a graveyard, exile it and return Diabolic Servitude to its owner's hand.
When Diabolic Servitude leaves the battlefield, exile the creature put onto the battlefield with Diabolic Servitude.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0131</id>
    <name>Discordant Dirge</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a verse counter on Discordant Dirge.
{B}, Sacrifice Discordant Dirge: Look at target opponent's hand and choose up to X cards from it, where X is the number of verse counters on Discordant Dirge. That player discards those cards.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0132</id>
    <name>Duress</name>
    <text>Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You choose a noncreature, nonland card from it. That player discards that card.</text>
    <flavorText>"We decide who is worthy of our works."
—Gix, Yawgmoth praetor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0133</id>
    <name>Eastern Paladin</name>
    <text>{B}{B}, {T}: Destroy target green creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Their fragile world. Their futile lives. They obstruct the Grand Evolution. In Yawgmoth's name, we shall excise them."
—Oath of the East</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0134</id>
    <name>Exhume</name>
    <text>Each player puts a creature card from his or her graveyard onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>"Death—an outmoded concept. We sleep, and we change."
—Sitrik, birth priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0135</id>
    <name>Expunge</name>
    <text>Destroy target nonartifact, nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0136</id>
    <name>Flesh Reaver</name>
    <text>Whenever Flesh Reaver deals damage to a creature or opponent, Flesh Reaver deals that much damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>Though the reaver is horrifyingly effective, its dorsal vents spit a highly corrosive cloud of filth.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0137</id>
    <name>Hollow Dogs</name>
    <text>Whenever Hollow Dogs attacks, it gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A hollow dog is never empty. It is filled with thirst for the hunt.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0138</id>
    <name>Ill-Gotten Gains</name>
    <text>Exile Ill-Gotten Gains. Each player discards his or her hand, then returns up to three cards from his or her graveyard to his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Urza thought it a crusade. Xantcha knew it was a robbery.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0139</id>
    <name>Looming Shade</name>
    <text>{B}: Looming Shade gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The shade tracks victims by reverberations of the pipes, as a spider senses prey tangled in its trembling web.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0140</id>
    <name>Lurking Evil</name>
    <text>Pay half your life, rounded up: Lurking Evil becomes a 4/4 Horror creature with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"Ash is our air, darkness our flesh."
—Phyrexian Scriptures</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0141</id>
    <name>Mana Leech</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Mana Leech during your untap step.
{T}: Tap target land. It doesn't untap during its controller's untap step for as long as Mana Leech remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0142</id>
    <name>No Rest for the Wicked</name>
    <text>Sacrifice No Rest for the Wicked: Return to your hand all creature cards in your graveyard that were put there from the battlefield this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"The soul? Here, we have no use for such frivolities."
—Sitrik, birth priest</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0143</id>
    <name>Oppression</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a spell, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Do not presume to speak for yourself."
—Gix, to Xantcha</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0144</id>
    <name>Order of Yawgmoth</name>
    <text>Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)
Whenever Order of Yawgmoth deals damage to a player, that player discards a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0145</id>
    <name>Parasitic Bond</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, Parasitic Bond deals 2 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>"All bonds are parasitic. Only rulership is pure."
—Gix, Yawgmoth praetor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0146</id>
    <name>Persecute</name>
    <text>Choose a color. Target player reveals his or her hand and discards all cards of that color.</text>
    <flavorText>"My finest warrior was lost to the Phyrexians. I pray that Lady Selenia died honorably."
—Radiant, archangel</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0147</id>
    <name>Pestilence</name>
    <text>At the beginning of the end step, if no creatures are on the battlefield, sacrifice Pestilence.
{B}: Pestilence deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0148</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Ghoul</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: Phyrexian Ghoul gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Phyrexia wastes nothing. Its food chain is a spiraling cycle.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0149</id>
    <name>Planar Void</name>
    <text>Whenever another card is put into a graveyard from anywhere, exile that card.</text>
    <flavorText>"Planeswalking isn't about walking. It's about falling and screaming."
—Xantcha, Phyrexian outcast</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0150</id>
    <name>Priest of Gix</name>
    <text>When Priest of Gix enters the battlefield, add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>"Gix doesn't want a people to rule but puppets to entertain his madness."
—Xantcha, Phyrexian outcast</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0151</id>
    <name>Rain of Filth</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, lands you control gain "Sacrifice this land: Add {B} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>"When I say it rained, it was not small drops, but a thick, greasy drool pouring from the heavens."
—Urza, journal</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0152</id>
    <name>Ravenous Skirge</name>
    <text>Flying
Whenever Ravenous Skirge attacks, it gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Hunger is a kind of madness—and here, all madness flourishes.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0153</id>
    <name>Reclusive Wight</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control another nonland permanent, sacrifice Reclusive Wight.</text>
    <flavorText>There are places so horrible that even the dead hide their faces.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0154</id>
    <name>Reprocess</name>
    <text>Sacrifice any number of artifacts, creatures, and/or lands. Draw a card for each permanent sacrificed this way.</text>
    <flavorText>Everything will find its use in Phyrexia. Eventually.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0155</id>
    <name>Sanguine Guard</name>
    <text>First strike
{1}{B}: Regenerate Sanguine Guard.</text>
    <flavorText>"Father of Machines Your filigree gaze carves us, and the scars dance upon our grateful flesh."
—Phyrexian Scriptures</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0156</id>
    <name>Sicken</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets -1/-1.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>Urza dared to attack Phyrexia. Slowly, it retaliated.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0157</id>
    <name>Skirge Familiar</name>
    <text>Flying
Discard a card: Add {B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>The first Yawgmoth priest to harness their power was rewarded with several unique mutilations.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0158</id>
    <name>Skittering Skirge</name>
    <text>Flying
When you cast a creature spell, sacrifice Skittering Skirge.</text>
    <flavorText>The imps' warbling cries echo through Phyrexia's towers like those of mourning doves in a cathedral.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0159</id>
    <name>Sleeper Agent</name>
    <text>When Sleeper Agent enters the battlefield, target opponent gains control of it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, Sleeper Agent deals 2 damage to you.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0160</id>
    <name>Spined Fluke</name>
    <text>When Spined Fluke enters the battlefield, sacrifice a creature.
{B}: Regenerate Spined Fluke.</text>
    <flavorText>Its spines are prized as writing quills by the priests of Gix.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0161</id>
    <name>Tainted Æther</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature enters the battlefield, its controller sacrifices a creature or land.</text>
    <flavorText>Gix despised the sylvan morass. The gouge that the portal had torn in the forest was the only pleasing sight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0162</id>
    <name>Unnerve</name>
    <text>Each opponent discards two cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"If fear is the only tool you have left, then you'll never control me."
—Xantcha, to Gix</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0163</id>
    <name>Unworthy Dead</name>
    <text>{B}: Regenerate Unworthy Dead.</text>
    <flavorText>"Great Yawgmoth moves across the seas of shard and bone and rust. We exalt him in life, in death, and in between."
—Phyrexian Scriptures</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0164</id>
    <name>Vampiric Embrace</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and has flying.
Whenever a creature dealt damage by enchanted creature this turn is put into a graveyard, put a +1/+1 counter on that creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0165</id>
    <name>Vebulid</name>
    <text>Vebulid enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.
At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Vebulid.
When Vebulid attacks or blocks, destroy it at end of combat.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0166</id>
    <name>Victimize</name>
    <text>Choose two target creature cards in your graveyard. Sacrifice a creature. If you do, return the chosen cards to the battlefield tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>The priest cast Xantcha to the ground. "It is defective. We must scrap it."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0167</id>
    <name>Vile Requiem</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a verse counter on Vile Requiem.

{1}{B}, Sacrifice Vile Requiem: Destroy up to X target nonblack creatures, where X is the number of verse counters on Vile Requiem. They can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0168</id>
    <name>Western Paladin</name>
    <text>{B}{B}, {T}: Destroy target white creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Their weak laws. Their flawed systems. They inhibit the Grand Evolution. In Yawgmoth's name, we shall erase them."
—Oath of the West</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0169</id>
    <name>Witch Engine</name>
    <text>Swampwalk
{T}: Add {B}{B}{B}{B} to your mana pool. Target opponent gains control of Witch Engine. (Activate this ability only any time you could cast an instant.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0170</id>
    <name>Yawgmoth's Edict</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent casts a white spell, that player loses 1 life and you gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>"Phyrexia's purity permits no other."
—Xantcha, Phyrexian outcast</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0171</id>
    <name>Yawgmoth's Will</name>
    <text>Until end of turn, you may play cards from your graveyard.
If a card would be put into your graveyard from anywhere this turn, exile that card instead.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0172</id>
    <name>Acidic Soil</name>
    <text>Acidic Soil deals damage to each player equal to the number of lands he or she controls.</text>
    <flavorText>Phyrexia had tried to take Urza's soul. He was relieved that Shiv tried to claim only his soles.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0173</id>
    <name>Antagonism</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's end step, Antagonism deals 2 damage to that player unless one of his or her opponents was dealt damage this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0174</id>
    <name>Arc Lightning</name>
    <text>Arc Lightning deals 3 damage divided as you choose among one, two, or three target creatures and/or players.</text>
    <flavorText>Rainclouds don't last long in Shiv, but that doesn't stop the lightning.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0175</id>
    <name>Bedlam</name>
    <text>Creatures can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>Sometimes quantity, in the absence of quality, is good enough.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0176</id>
    <name>Brand</name>
    <text>Gain control of all permanents you own. (This effect lasts indefinitely.)
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>"By this glyph I affirm your role."
—Urza, to Karn</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0177</id>
    <name>Bravado</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 for each other creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"We drive the dragons from our home. Why should we fear you?"
—Fire Eye, viashino bey</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0178</id>
    <name>Bulwark</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Bulwark deals X damage to target opponent, where X is the number of cards in your hand minus the number of cards in that player's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"It will be the goblin's first bath, and its last."
—Fire Eye, viashino bey</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0179</id>
    <name>Crater Hellion</name>
    <text>Echo {4}{R}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
When Crater Hellion enters the battlefield, it deals 4 damage to each other creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0180</id>
    <name>Destructive Urge</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature deals combat damage to a player, that player sacrifices a land.</text>
    <flavorText>Red sky at night, dragon's delight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0181</id>
    <name>Disorder</name>
    <text>Disorder deals 2 damage to each white creature and each player who controls a white creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Then, just when the other guys were winnin', the sky threw up."
—Jula, goblin raider</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0182</id>
    <name>Dromosaur</name>
    <text>Whenever Dromosaur blocks or becomes blocked, it gets +2/-2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>They say dromosaurs are frightened of dogs, even little ones. There are no dogs in Shiv. Not even little ones.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0183</id>
    <name>Electryte</name>
    <text>Whenever Electryte deals combat damage to defending player, it deals damage equal to its power to each blocking creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Shivan inhabitants are hardened to fire, so their predators have developed alternative weaponry.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0184</id>
    <name>Falter</name>
    <text>Creatures without flying can't block this turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Like a sleeping dragon, Shiv stirs and groans at times.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0185</id>
    <name>Fault Line</name>
    <text>Fault Line deals X damage to each creature without flying and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>We live on the serpent's back.
—Viashino saying</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0186</id>
    <name>Fiery Mantle</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.
When Fiery Mantle is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Fiery Mantle to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0187</id>
    <name>Fire Ants</name>
    <text>{T}: Fire Ants deals 1 damage to each other creature without flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Visitors to Shiv fear the dragons, the goblins, or the viashino. Natives fear the ants.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0188</id>
    <name>Gamble</name>
    <text>Search your library for a card, put that card into your hand, discard a card at random, then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>When you've got nothing, you might as well trade it for something else.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0189</id>
    <name>Goblin Cadets</name>
    <text>Whenever Goblin Cadets blocks or becomes blocked, target opponent gains control of it. (This removes Goblin Cadets from combat.)</text>
    <flavorText>"If you kids don't stop that racket, I'm turning this expedition around right now"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0190</id>
    <name>Goblin Lackey</name>
    <text>Whenever Goblin Lackey deals damage to a player, you may put a Goblin permanent card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>All bark, someone else's bite.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0191</id>
    <name>Goblin Matron</name>
    <text>When Goblin Matron enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a Goblin card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>There's always room for one more.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0192</id>
    <name>Goblin Offensive</name>
    <text>Put X 1/1 red Goblin creature tokens onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>They certainly are.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0193</id>
    <name>Goblin Patrol</name>
    <text>Echo {R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Take the sharp metal stick and make a lotta holes."
—Jula, goblin raider</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0194</id>
    <name>Goblin Raider</name>
    <text>Goblin Raider can't block.</text>
    <flavorText>He was proud to wear the lizard skin around his waist, just for the fun of annoying the enemy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0195</id>
    <name>Goblin Spelunkers</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"It only short jump. You go first."
"AIIIEEEE"
"Hmm . . . we go different way now."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0196</id>
    <name>Goblin War Buggy</name>
    <text>Haste
Echo {1}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0197</id>
    <name>Guma</name>
    <text>Protection from blue</text>
    <flavorText>When the giant returned for the night, he found a dead merfolk on his pillow. Although he praised the little guma, he inwardly wondered where she had hid the head.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0198</id>
    <name>Headlong Rush</name>
    <text>Attacking creatures gain first strike until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A landslide of goblins poured towards the defenders—tumbling, rolling, and bouncing their way down the steep hillside.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0199</id>
    <name>Heat Ray</name>
    <text>Heat Ray deals X damage to target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>It's not known whether the Thran built the device to forge their wonders or to defend them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0200</id>
    <name>Jagged Lightning</name>
    <text>Jagged Lightning deals 3 damage to each of two target creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>The pungent smell of roasting flesh made both mages realize they'd rather break for dinner than fight.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0201</id>
    <name>Lay Waste</name>
    <text>Destroy target land.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0202</id>
    <name>Lightning Dragon</name>
    <text>Flying
Echo {2}{R}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
{R}: Lightning Dragon gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0203</id>
    <name>Meltdown</name>
    <text>Destroy each artifact with converted mana cost X or less.</text>
    <flavorText>Catastrophes happened so often at the mana rig that the viashino language had a special word to describe them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0204</id>
    <name>Okk</name>
    <text>Okk can't attack unless a creature with greater power also attacks.
Okk can't block unless a creature with greater power also blocks.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0205</id>
    <name>Outmaneuver</name>
    <text>X target blocked creatures assign their combat damage this turn as though they weren't blocked.</text>
    <flavorText>"Push one goblin into sight, an' run a lot. That's tactics."
—Jula, goblin raider</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0206</id>
    <name>Rain of Salt</name>
    <text>Destroy two target lands.</text>
    <flavorText>Here, rain does not wash the land; it desiccates it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0207</id>
    <name>Raze</name>
    <text>As an additional cost to cast Raze, sacrifice a land.
Destroy target land.</text>
    <flavorText>The viashino believe that the oldest mountains hate everyone equally.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0208</id>
    <name>Reflexes</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature has first strike. (It deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Here's how ya win. Don't let the other guy hit back first."
—Jula, goblin raider</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0209</id>
    <name>Retromancer</name>
    <text>Whenever Retromancer becomes the target of a spell or ability, Retromancer deals 3 damage to that spell or ability's controller.</text>
    <flavorText>"If one harm us, strike them in return. So sayeth the bey."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0210</id>
    <name>Rumbling Crescendo</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a verse counter on Rumbling Crescendo.
{R}, Sacrifice Rumbling Crescendo: Destroy up to X target lands, where X is the number of verse counters on Rumbling Crescendo.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0211</id>
    <name>Scald</name>
    <text>Whenever a player taps an Island for mana, Scald deals 1 damage to that player.</text>
    <flavorText>"Shiv may be surrounded by water, but the mountains go far deeper."
—Fire Eye, viashino bey</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0212</id>
    <name>Scoria Wurm</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, flip a coin. If you lose the flip, return Scoria Wurm to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>Late at night, ululations echo from deep under Shiv, as the wurms sing of times older than humanity.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0213</id>
    <name>Scrap</name>
    <text>Destroy target artifact.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0214</id>
    <name>Shiv's Embrace</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and has flying.
{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>"Wear the foe's form to best it in battle. So sayeth the bey."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0215</id>
    <name>Shivan Hellkite</name>
    <text>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)
{1}{R}: Shivan Hellkite deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</text>
    <flavorText>A dragon's scale can be carved into a mighty shield, provided you can procure a dragontooth to cut it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0216</id>
    <name>Shivan Raptor</name>
    <text>First strike, haste
Echo {2}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0217</id>
    <name>Shower of Sparks</name>
    <text>Shower of Sparks deals 1 damage to target creature and 1 damage to target player.</text>
    <flavorText>The viashino had learned how to operate the rig through trial and error—mostly error.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0218</id>
    <name>Sneak Attack</name>
    <text>{R}: You may put a creature card from your hand onto the battlefield. That creature gains haste. Sacrifice the creature at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>"Nothin' beat surprise—'cept rock."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0219</id>
    <name>Steam Blast</name>
    <text>Steam Blast deals 2 damage to each creature and each player.</text>
    <flavorText>The viashino knew of the cracked pipes but deliberately left them unmended to bolster the rig's defenses.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0220</id>
    <name>Sulfuric Vapors</name>
    <text>If a red spell would deal damage to a permanent or player, it deals that much damage plus 1 to that permanent or player instead.</text>
    <flavorText>It was the dragons who first learned to chase their prey into the vapors before igniting them.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0221</id>
    <name>Thundering Giant</name>
    <text>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)</text>
    <flavorText>The giant was felt a few seconds before he was seen.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0222</id>
    <name>Torch Song</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a verse counter on Torch Song.
{2}{R}, Sacrifice Torch Song: Torch Song deals X damage to target creature or player, where X is the number of verse counters on Torch Song.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0223</id>
    <name>Viashino Outrider</name>
    <text>Echo {2}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>"Give thy ration to thy mount, if the road be long. So sayeth the bey."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0224</id>
    <name>Viashino Runner</name>
    <text>Viashino Runner can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>"It moved this way, an' that way, an' then before I could stick it, it jumped over my head an' was gone."
—Jula, goblin raider</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0225</id>
    <name>Viashino Sandswimmer</name>
    <text>{R}: Flip a coin. If you win the flip, return Viashino Sandswimmer to its owner's hand. If you lose the flip, sacrifice Viashino Sandswimmer.</text>
    <flavorText>Few swim in a place of such thirst.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0226</id>
    <name>Viashino Weaponsmith</name>
    <text>Whenever Viashino Weaponsmith becomes blocked by a creature, Viashino Weaponsmith gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Within the rig settlement, those who have mastered the making of weapons earn highest honor.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0227</id>
    <name>Vug Lizard</name>
    <text>Mountainwalk
Echo {1}{R}{R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0228</id>
    <name>Wildfire</name>
    <text>Each player sacrifices four lands. Wildfire deals 4 damage to each creature.</text>
    <flavorText>"Shiv hatched from a shell of stone around a yolk of flame."
—Viashino myth</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0229</id>
    <name>Abundance</name>
    <text>If you would draw a card, you may instead choose land or nonland and reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal a card of the chosen kind. Put that card into your hand and put all other cards revealed this way on the bottom of your library in any order.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0230</id>
    <name>Acridian</name>
    <text>Echo {1}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>The elves of Argoth were trained to ride these creatures, even when their mounts traveled upside-down.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0231</id>
    <name>Albino Troll</name>
    <text>Echo {1}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)
{1}{G}: Regenerate Albino Troll.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0232</id>
    <name>Anaconda</name>
    <text>Swampwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Swamp.)</text>
    <flavorText>If you're smaller than the anaconda, it considers you food. If you're larger than the anaconda, it considers you a lot of food.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0233</id>
    <name>Argothian Elder</name>
    <text>{T}: Untap two target lands.</text>
    <flavorText>Sharpen your ears
—Elvish expression meaning "grow wiser"</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0234</id>
    <name>Argothian Enchantress</name>
    <text>Shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)
Whenever you cast an enchantment spell, draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0235</id>
    <name>Argothian Swine</name>
    <text>Trample</text>
    <flavorText>In Argoth, the shortest route between two points is the one the swine make.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0236</id>
    <name>Argothian Wurm</name>
    <text>Trample
When Argothian Wurm enters the battlefield, any player may sacrifice a land. If a player does, put Argothian Wurm on top of its owner's library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0237</id>
    <name>Blanchwood Armor</name>
    <text>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you cast this. This card enters the battlefield attached to that creature.)
Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 for each Forest you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Braid her branches, life fulfilling
Goddess loving, Goddess killing."
—Citanul chant</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0238</id>
    <name>Blanchwood Treefolk</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The massive Argivian attack on their rooted kindred was a declaration of war to the treefolk.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0239</id>
    <name>Bull Hippo</name>
    <text>Islandwalk</text>
    <flavorText>"How could you not hear it approach? It's a hippo"
—Argivian commander</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0240</id>
    <name>Carpet of Flowers</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each of your main phases, if you haven't added mana to your mana pool with this ability this turn, you may add up to X mana of any one color to your mana pool, where X is the number of Islands target opponent controls.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0241</id>
    <name>Cave Tiger</name>
    <text>Whenever Cave Tiger becomes blocked by a creature, Cave Tiger gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>The druids found a haven in the cool limestone tunnels beneath Argoth. The invaders found only tigers.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0242</id>
    <name>Child of Gaea</name>
    <text>Trample
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Child of Gaea unless you pay {G}{G}.
{1}{G}: Regenerate Child of Gaea.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0243</id>
    <name>Citanul Centaurs</name>
    <text>Shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)
Echo {3}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0244</id>
    <name>Citanul Hierophants</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have "{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool."</text>
    <flavorText>From deep in the caves beneath the forest, the hierophants planned the druids' raids against the enemy.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0245</id>
    <name>Cradle Guard</name>
    <text>Trample
Echo {1}{G}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>Mother, sleep / Dream our lives
Our roots your soul / Our leaves your bed.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0246</id>
    <name>Crosswinds</name>
    <text>Creatures with flying get -2/-0.</text>
    <flavorText>Harbin's ornithopter had been trapped for two days within the currents of the storm. When the skies cleared, all he could see was a horizon of trees.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0247</id>
    <name>Elvish Herder</name>
    <text>{G}: Target creature gains trample until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Before Urza and Mishra came to Argoth, the herders prevented their creatures from stampeding. During the war, they encouraged it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0248</id>
    <name>Elvish Lyrist</name>
    <text>{G}, {T}, Sacrifice Elvish Lyrist: Destroy target enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>Bring the spear of ancient briar;
Bring the torch to light the pyre.
Bring the one who trod our ground;
Bring the spade to dig his mound.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0249</id>
    <name>Endless Wurm</name>
    <text>Trample
At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Endless Wurm unless you sacrifice an enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>Ages ago, a party of elves took cover to let one pass. They're still waiting.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0250</id>
    <name>Exploration</name>
    <text>You may play an additional land on each of your turns.</text>
    <flavorText>The first explorers found Argoth a storehouse of natural wealth—towering forests grown over rich veins of ore.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0251</id>
    <name>Fecundity</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, that creature's controller may draw a card.</text>
    <flavorText>Life is eternal. A lifetime is ephemeral.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0252</id>
    <name>Fertile Ground</name>
    <text>Enchant land
Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds one mana of any color to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>The forest was too lush for the brothers to despoil—almost.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0253</id>
    <name>Fortitude</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Sacrifice a Forest: Regenerate enchanted creature.
When Fortitude is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Fortitude to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0254</id>
    <name>Gaea's Bounty</name>
    <text>Search your library for up to two Forest cards, reveal those cards, and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>The forest grew back so quickly that lumbering machines were suspended in the treetops.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0255</id>
    <name>Gaea's Embrace</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Enchanted creature gets +3/+3 and has trample.
{G}: Regenerate enchanted creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The forest rose to the battle, not to save the people but to save itself.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0256</id>
    <name>Gorilla Warrior</name>
    <text>
    </text>
    <flavorText>The gorilla beat its chest and threw great handfuls of leaves into the air. It howled challenge and showed its teeth. The mechanical soldier, not understanding, simply killed it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0257</id>
    <name>Greater Good</name>
    <text>Sacrifice a creature: Draw cards equal to the sacrificed creature's power, then discard three cards.</text>
    <flavorText>"We have more sprouts than they have hands."
—Gamelen, Citanul elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0258</id>
    <name>Greener Pastures</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, if that player controls more lands than each other player, the player puts a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0259</id>
    <name>Hawkeater Moth</name>
    <text>Flying; shroud (This permanent can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>Each day at dusk the birds above the canopy grow silent.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0260</id>
    <name>Hidden Ancients</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts an enchantment spell, if Hidden Ancients is an enchantment, Hidden Ancients becomes a 5/5 Treefolk creature.</text>
    <flavorText>The only alert the invaders had was the rustling of leaves on a day without wind.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0261</id>
    <name>Hidden Guerrillas</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts an artifact spell, if Hidden Guerrillas is an enchantment, Hidden Guerrillas becomes a 5/3 Soldier creature with trample.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0262</id>
    <name>Hidden Herd</name>
    <text>When an opponent plays a nonbasic land, if Hidden Herd is an enchantment, Hidden Herd becomes a 3/3 Beast creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0263</id>
    <name>Hidden Predators</name>
    <text>When an opponent controls a creature with power 4 or greater, if Hidden Predators is an enchantment, Hidden Predators becomes a 4/4 Beast creature.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0264</id>
    <name>Hidden Spider</name>
    <text>When an opponent casts a creature spell with flying, if Hidden Spider is an enchantment, Hidden Spider becomes a 3/5 Spider creature with reach. (It can block creatures with flying.)</text>
    <flavorText>It wants only to dress you in silk.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0265</id>
    <name>Hidden Stag</name>
    <text>Whenever an opponent plays a land, if Hidden Stag is an enchantment, Hidden Stag becomes a 3/2 Elk Beast creature.
Whenever you play a land, if Hidden Stag is a creature, Hidden Stag becomes an enchantment.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0266</id>
    <name>Hush</name>
    <text>Destroy all enchantments.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0267</id>
    <name>Lull</name>
    <text>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0268</id>
    <name>Midsummer Revel</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a verse counter on Midsummer Revel.
{G}, Sacrifice Midsummer Revel: Put X 3/3 green Beast creature tokens onto the battlefield, where X is the number of verse counters on Midsummer Revel.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0269</id>
    <name>Pouncing Jaguar</name>
    <text>Echo {G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>One pounce, she's hungry—you die quickly. Two, she's teaching her cubs—you're in for a long day.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0270</id>
    <name>Priest of Titania</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool for each Elf on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Titania rewards all who honor the forest by making them a living part of it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0271</id>
    <name>Rejuvenate</name>
    <text>You gain 6 life.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0272</id>
    <name>Retaliation</name>
    <text>Creatures you control have "Whenever this creature becomes blocked by a creature, this creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn."</text>
    <flavorText>A foul, metallic stench clogged Urza's senses. It was then he knew his brother was no more.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0273</id>
    <name>Sporogenesis</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a fungus counter on target nontoken creature.
Whenever a creature with a fungus counter on it is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield for each fungus counter on that creature.
When Sporogenesis leaves the battlefield, remove all fungus counters from all creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0274</id>
    <name>Spreading Algae</name>
    <text>Enchant Swamp
When enchanted land becomes tapped, destroy it.
When Spreading Algae is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Spreading Algae to its owner's hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0275</id>
    <name>Symbiosis</name>
    <text>Two target creatures each get +2/+2 until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Although the elves of Argoth always considered them a nuisance, the pixies made fine allies during the war against the machines.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0276</id>
    <name>Titania's Boon</name>
    <text>Put a +1/+1 counter on each creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>When the winds rock the trees, listen for voices in the creaking of the trunks. If you hear your name, you are one of the Goddess's chosen.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0277</id>
    <name>Titania's Chosen</name>
    <text>Whenever a player casts a green spell, put a +1/+1 counter on Titania's Chosen.</text>
    <flavorText>"What do a hero and an arrow have in common? In times of war are many more made."
—Elvish riddle</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0278</id>
    <name>Treefolk Seedlings</name>
    <text>Treefolk Seedlings's toughness is equal to the number of Forests you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The year that the brothers landed on Argoth, the trees produced five times as many seeds as normal.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0279</id>
    <name>Treetop Rangers</name>
    <text>Treetop Rangers can't be blocked except by creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>"If you can't catch them, cut the trees down from beneath them. Force them to fight on our terms."
—Mishra</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0280</id>
    <name>Venomous Fangs</name>
    <text>Enchant creature
Whenever enchanted creature deals damage to a creature, destroy the other creature.</text>
    <flavorText>All the pain of the shattered forest contained in a single drop.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0281</id>
    <name>Vernal Bloom</name>
    <text>Whenever a Forest is tapped for mana, its controller adds {G} to his or her mana pool (in addition to the mana the land produces).</text>
    <flavorText>Many cultures have legends of a lush, hidden paradise. The elves of Argoth had no need of such stories.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0282</id>
    <name>War Dance</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a verse counter on War Dance.

Sacrifice War Dance: Target creature gets +X/+X until end of turn, where X is the number of verse counters on War Dance.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0283</id>
    <name>Whirlwind</name>
    <text>Destroy all creatures with flying.</text>
    <flavorText>Urza tried to rule the air, but Gaea taught him that she controlled all the elements.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0284</id>
    <name>Wild Dogs</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, if a player has more life than each other player, the player with the most life gains control of Wild Dogs.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0285</id>
    <name>Winding Wurm</name>
    <text>Echo {4}{G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, if this came under your control since the beginning of your last upkeep, sacrifice it unless you pay its echo cost.)</text>
    <flavorText>Entire trees were stripped of their bark and branches by the wurm's writhing path.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0286</id>
    <name>Barrin's Codex</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a page counter on Barrin's Codex.
{4}, {T}, Sacrifice Barrin's Codex: Draw X cards, where X is the number of page counters on Barrin's Codex.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0287</id>
    <name>Cathodion</name>
    <text>When Cathodion is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, add {3} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Instead of creating a tool that would be damaged by heat, the Thran built one that was charged by it.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0288</id>
    <name>Chimeric Staff</name>
    <text>{X}: Chimeric Staff becomes an X/X Construct artifact creature until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>A snake in the grasp.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0289</id>
    <name>Citanul Flute</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: Search your library for a creature card with converted mana cost X or less, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0290</id>
    <name>Claws of Gix</name>
    <text>{1}, Sacrifice a permanent: You gain 1 life.</text>
    <flavorText>When the Brotherhood of Gix dug out the cave of Koilos they found their master's severed hand. They enshrined it, hoping that one day it would point the way to Phyrexia.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0291</id>
    <name>Copper Gnomes</name>
    <text>{4}, Sacrifice Copper Gnomes: You may put an artifact card from your hand onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Start with eleven gnomes and a room of parts, and come morning you'll have ten and a monster the likes of which you've never seen.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0292</id>
    <name>Crystal Chimes</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}, Sacrifice Crystal Chimes: Return all enchantment cards from your graveyard to your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>As Serra was to learn, the peace and sanctity of her realm were as fragile as glass.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0293</id>
    <name>Dragon Blood</name>
    <text>{3}, {T}: Put a +1/+1 counter on target creature.</text>
    <flavorText>Fire in the blood, fire in the belly.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0294</id>
    <name>Endoskeleton</name>
    <text>You may choose not to untap Endoskeleton during your untap step.
{2}, {T}: Target creature gets +0/+3 for as long as Endoskeleton remains tapped.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0295</id>
    <name>Fluctuator</name>
    <text>Cycling abilities you activate cost you up to {2} less to activate.</text>
    <flavorText>Fiko summoned only atogs for three straight sessions. The tutor couldn't decide whether to punish his failure or praise his consistency.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0296</id>
    <name>Grafted Skullcap</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your draw step, draw an additional card.
At the beginning of your end step, discard your hand.</text>
    <flavorText>"Let go your mind. Mine is fitter."
—Gix, Yawgmoth praetor</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0297</id>
    <name>Hopping Automaton</name>
    <text>{0}: Hopping Automaton gets -1/-1 and gains flying until end of turn.</text>
    <flavorText>Designed to carry equipment across rivers, the hopping automaton was soon pressed into service in the infantry.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0298</id>
    <name>Karn, Silver Golem</name>
    <text>Whenever Karn, Silver Golem blocks or becomes blocked, it gets -4/+4 until end of turn.
{1}: Target noncreature artifact becomes an artifact creature with power and toughness each equal to its converted mana cost until end of turn. (That artifact retains its abilities.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0299</id>
    <name>Lifeline</name>
    <text>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, if another creature is on the battlefield, return the first card to the battlefield under its owner's control at the beginning of the next end step.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0300</id>
    <name>Lotus Blossom</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a petal counter on Lotus Blossom.
{T}, Sacrifice Lotus Blossom: Add X mana of any one color to your mana pool, where X is the number of petal counters on Lotus Blossom.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0301</id>
    <name>Metrognome</name>
    <text>When a spell or ability an opponent controls causes you to discard Metrognome, put four 1/1 colorless Gnome artifact creature tokens onto the battlefield.
{4}, {T}: Put a 1/1 colorless Gnome artifact creature token onto the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0302</id>
    <name>Mishra's Helix</name>
    <text>{X}, {T}: Tap X target lands.</text>
    <flavorText>The helix was the finest example of Mishra's campaign strategy: if he couldn't have Argoth, no one could.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0303</id>
    <name>Mobile Fort</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
{3}: Mobile Fort gets +3/-1 until end of turn and can attack this turn as though it didn't have defender. Activate this ability only once each turn.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0304</id>
    <name>Noetic Scales</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, return to its owner's hand each creature that player controls with power greater than the number of cards in his or her hand.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0305</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Colossus</name>
    <text>Phyrexian Colossus doesn't untap during your untap step.
Pay 8 life: Untap Phyrexian Colossus.
Phyrexian Colossus can't be blocked except by three or more creatures.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0306</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Processor</name>
    <text>As Phyrexian Processor enters the battlefield, pay any amount of life.
{4}, {T}: Put an X/X black Minion creature token onto the battlefield, where X is the life paid as Phyrexian Processor entered the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0307</id>
    <name>Pit Trap</name>
    <text>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Pit Trap: Destroy target attacking creature without flying. It can't be regenerated.</text>
    <flavorText>Yotian soldiers were designed to fight, not watch their feet.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0308</id>
    <name>Purging Scythe</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, Purging Scythe deals 2 damage to the creature with the least toughness. If two or more creatures are tied for least toughness, you choose one of them.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0309</id>
    <name>Smokestack</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a soot counter on Smokestack.
At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player sacrifices a permanent for each soot counter on Smokestack.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0310</id>
    <name>Temporal Aperture</name>
    <text>{5}, {T}: Shuffle your library, then reveal the top card. Until end of turn, for as long as that card remains on top of your library, play with the top card of your library revealed and you may play that card without paying its mana cost. (If it has X in its mana cost, X is 0.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0311</id>
    <name>Thran Turbine</name>
    <text>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may add {1} or {2} to your mana pool. You can't spend this mana to cast spells.</text>
    <flavorText>When Urza asked the viashino what it did, they answered: "It hums."</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0312</id>
    <name>Umbilicus</name>
    <text>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player returns a permanent he or she controls to its owner's hand unless he or she pays 2 life.</text>
    <flavorText>It was the explorers' only tether to reality.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0313</id>
    <name>Urza's Armor</name>
    <text>If a source would deal damage to you, prevent 1 of that damage.</text>
    <flavorText>"Tawnos's blueprints were critical to the creation of my armor. As he once sealed himself in steel, I sealed myself in a walking crypt."
—Urza</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0314</id>
    <name>Voltaic Key</name>
    <text>{1}, {T}: Untap target artifact.</text>
    <flavorText>The key did not work on a single lock, yet it opened many doors.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0315</id>
    <name>Wall of Junk</name>
    <text>Defender (This creature can't attack.)
Whenever Wall of Junk blocks, return it to its owner's hand at end of combat. (Return it only if it's on the battlefield.)</text>
    <flavorText>Urza saw the wall and realized that even if he tore every Phyrexian to pieces, they would still resist him.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0316</id>
    <name>Whetstone</name>
    <text>{3}: Each player puts the top two cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</text>
    <flavorText>To hone swords and dull minds.
—Whetstone inscription</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0317</id>
    <name>Wirecat</name>
    <text>Wirecat can't attack or block if an enchantment is on the battlefield.</text>
    <flavorText>Its purr is the sound of iron filings sliding down satin.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0318</id>
    <name>Worn Powerstone</name>
    <text>Worn Powerstone enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {2} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0319</id>
    <name>Blasted Landscape</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0320</id>
    <name>Drifting Meadow</name>
    <text>Drifting Meadow enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0321</id>
    <name>Gaea's Cradle</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool for each creature you control.</text>
    <flavorText>"Here sprouted the first seedling of Argoth. Here the last tree will fall."
—Gamelen, Citanul elder</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0322</id>
    <name>Phyrexian Tower</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{T}, Sacrifice a creature: Add {B}{B} to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>Living metal encasing dying flesh.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0323</id>
    <name>Polluted Mire</name>
    <text>Polluted Mire enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0324</id>
    <name>Remote Isle</name>
    <text>Remote Isle enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0325</id>
    <name>Serra's Sanctum</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool for each enchantment you control.</text>
    <flavorText>A fragile cocoon of dreaming will.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0326</id>
    <name>Shivan Gorge</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.
{2}{R}, {T}: Shivan Gorge deals 1 damage to each opponent.</text>
    <flavorText>Both forge and pyre.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0327</id>
    <name>Slippery Karst</name>
    <text>Slippery Karst enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0328</id>
    <name>Smoldering Crater</name>
    <text>Smoldering Crater enters the battlefield tapped.
{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.
Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0329</id>
    <name>Thran Quarry</name>
    <text>At the beginning of the end step, if you control no creatures, sacrifice Thran Quarry.
{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0330</id>
    <name>Tolarian Academy</name>
    <text>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool for each artifact you control.</text>
    <flavorText>The academy worked with time—until time ran out.</flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0331</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0332</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0333</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0334</id>
    <name>Plains</name>
    <text>W</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0335</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0336</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0337</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0338</id>
    <name>Island</name>
    <text>U</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0339</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0340</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0341</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0342</id>
    <name>Swamp</name>
    <text>B</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0343</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0344</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0345</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0346</id>
    <name>Mountain</name>
    <text>R</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0347</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0348</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0349</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>USG0350</id>
    <name>Forest</name>
    <text>G</text>
    <flavorText>
    </flavorText>
  </item>
</cards>